<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640815-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640815</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11723071</doc-number>
<date>20070316</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-113252</doc-number>
<date>20060417</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862333</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Magnetostriction type torque sensor</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4300085</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Monma et al.</name>
<date>19811100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>318696</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4972728</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Yoshimura et al.</name>
<date>19901100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73862333</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4989460</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mizuno et al.</name>
<date>19910200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73862335</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5902934</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sprague et al.</name>
<date>19990500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73779</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6422095</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Shimizu et al.</name>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73862335</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6698299</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Cripe</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73862331</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6966232</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Asaumi et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73862333</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004-239652</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20040800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-321316</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-331453</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73862331-862338</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070283768</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071213</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoneda</last-name>
<first-name>Atsuhiko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shimizu</last-name>
<first-name>Yasuo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sueyoshi</last-name>
<first-name>Shunichiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oniwa</last-name>
<first-name>Yoshihiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="005" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Arimura</last-name>
<first-name>Yutaka</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="006" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Miyoshi</last-name>
<first-name>Takashi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Saitama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Arent Fox LLP.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Honda Motor Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Caputo</last-name>
<first-name>Lisa M</first-name>
<department>2855</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Davis</last-name>
<first-name>Octavia</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A magnetostriction type torque sensor is provided which includes magnetic property change material which is provided on a shaft and whose magnetic property changes in accordance with torque applied to the shaft, an excitation signal generator which generates an excitation signal whose voltage is converted into a predetermined voltage through a switching element, a plurality of detection coils to which the excitation signal generator applies the excitation signal, and which plurality of detection coils outputs voltage, which changes in accordance with change in the magnetic property of the magnetic property change material, between connection points between the detection coils, and an operational state monitor which monitors an operational state of the switching element.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="183.13mm" wi="168.06mm" file="US07640815-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="203.88mm" wi="170.35mm" file="US07640815-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="207.26mm" wi="181.86mm" file="US07640815-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="268.22mm" wi="178.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640815-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="154.77mm" wi="116.16mm" file="US07640815-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="237.07mm" wi="182.88mm" file="US07640815-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="226.23mm" wi="176.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640815-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="142.92mm" wi="142.58mm" file="US07640815-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the foreign priority benefit under Title 35, United States Code, &#xa7;119(a)-(d) of Japanese Patent Application No. 2006-113252, filed on Apr. 17, 2006 in the Japan Patent Office, the disclosure of which is herein incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a magnetostriction type torque sensor which detects magnetic property change of magnetic property change material which is attached around a shaft.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In an electric power steering device installed in a vehicle, a torque sensor detects torque which is given to a steering shaft by driver's steering. Thus, steering assist power is provided depending on torque signals output from the torque sensor. A magnetostriction type torque sensor is disclosed as such a torque sensor (See JP2004-239652A and JP2005-331453A). In this technology, a magnetostriction film having magnetic anisotropy is attached on a surface of the shaft. Then, the torque is applied to the shaft from the outside so that magnetic permeability change in the magnetostriction film corresponding to twisting force is detected as change in an impedance property of a detection coil. Moreover, in technologies disclosed in JP2005-331453A and JP2005-321316A, a pulse of excitation voltage is applied so that the change in the impedance property of the detection coil is detected. In the technologies, the pulse of the excitation voltage is applied so that a maximum of increasing current which flows in the detection coil is limited within a predetermined range.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, an ON-failure in which a switching element is short-circuited is not considered in the torque sensors described in JP2004-239652A, JP2005-331453A, or JP2005-321316A. Here, in a case where the excitation voltage is applied to a series circuit which includes two detection coils and a switching element, a potential state at a connection point between the two detection coils while the torque is not given are in particular discussed. In a normal state, an intermediate potential of a potential generated by the excitation voltage appears at the connection point of the detection coils. On the other hand, in the ON-failure state, direct current determined by internal resistance and applied DC voltage of the detection coil flows in the detection coil, and the intermediate potential appears at the connection point of the detection coils. In other words, the intermediate potential of the potential generated by the applied voltage appears at the connection point of the detection coils even in the normal state, as well as, in the ON-failure state. Therefore, it is difficult to distinguish the normal state from the ON-failure state. Moreover, it is preferable that the normal state is distinguished from an OFF-failure state.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In view of the above, an object of the present invention is to provide a magnetostriction type torque sensor which distinguishes a normal state from a failure state of a switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To solve the above-described problems, in one aspect of the present invention, there is provided a magnetostriction type torque sensor including magnetic property change material which is provided on a shaft and whose magnetic property changes in accordance with torque applied to the shaft, an excitation signal generator which generates an excitation signal whose voltage is converted into a predetermined voltage through a switching element, a plurality of detection coils to which the excitation signal generator applies the excitation signal, and which plurality of detection coils outputs voltage, which changes in accordance with change in the magnetic property of the magnetic property change material, between connection points between the detection coils, and an operational state monitor which monitors an operational state of the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In the magnetostriction type torque sensor, the magnetic property of the magnetic property change material changes in accordance with the torque applied to the shaft. Moreover, the excitation signal generator applies the excitation signal to the plurality of the detection coils. Accordingly, the change of the magnetic property is detected based on the voltage between the connection points between the detection coils. At this time, the operational state monitor monitors the operational states of the switching elements so as to prevent excessive current and disconnection due to an ON-failure in the switching element.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In the magnetostriction type torque sensor, the magnetic property change material may include a first magnetostriction film and a second magnetostriction film which are attached in an axial direction on two parts of the shaft which are close to each other. In addition, the first magnetostriction film and the second magnetostriction film may be anisotropic in opposite directions to each other. Moreover, the plurality of the detection coils may be placed separated from the shaft on which the first magnetostriction film and the second magnetostriction film are attached.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the magnetostriction type torque sensor, the first magnetostriction film and the second magnetostriction film which are respectively attached in the axial direction on the two parts of the shaft which are close to each other are anisotropic in the opposite directions to each other. Therefore, an intermediate potential before the torque is applied and a detected potential while the torque is being applied are compared so as to detect a direction of the torque and compensate thermal characteristics. The difference between the intermediate potential and the detected potential can be obtained from the change in voltage between the connection points between the detection coils. Moreover, the operational states of the switching elements are monitored. When the operational state is monitored, a voltage between both ends of each of the switching elements is monitored.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In the magnetostriction type torque sensor, the operational state monitor may monitor a monitoring signal taken between the detection coil and the switching element. Moreover, the operational state monitor may include a failure determiner which determines whether there is a failure in the switching element based on the monitoring signal.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In the magnetostriction type torque sensor, the failure determiner may determine that there is a failure in the switching element when the monitoring signal is kept at an earth potential or a power supply potential.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The object and features of the present invention will become more readily apparent from the following detailed description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a configuration diagram of a magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a configuration diagram of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to another embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing that detection coils wind around a shaft and how the detection coils are connected;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5E</figref> is a diagram showing a waveform in a part of the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to the embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a configuration diagram of an electric power steering device; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a configuration diagram of a torque detection circuit which is an example to be compared with the embodiments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Here will be described embodiments of the present invention in detail, referring to the accompanying drawings as needed.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A magnetostriction type torque sensor unit according to an embodiment of the present invention will be described, below.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">A magnetostriction type torque sensor unit <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is used to detect torque applied to a steering shaft in an electric power steering device which will be described later. The magnetostriction type torque sensor unit <b>100</b> includes magnetostriction films (magnetic property change material, or a first magnetostriction film and a second magnetostriction film) <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>which are attached in the axial direction on the two parts of the shaft (steering shaft) <b>20</b> which are close to each other, detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>which are connected in a series and detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>which are connected in a series in an opposite direction to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b</i>, a differential amplifier <b>50</b> which calculates a differential voltage between a connection point VS<b>1</b> between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b</i>, and a connection point VS<b>2</b> between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, a switching element <b>15</b><i>a </i>which applies excitation voltage to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b</i>, a switching element <b>15</b><i>b </i>which applies excitation voltage to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, and a CPU <b>60</b> which processes voltages output from the differential amplifier <b>50</b> as signals and outputs a torque signal T. In addition, the CPU <b>60</b> generates excitation signals which control the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b</i>. Meanwhile, monitoring signals A and B which respectively monitor the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are input to the CPU <b>60</b>. The CPU <b>60</b> determines states of the monitoring signals A and B and functions as an operational state monitor which monitors operational states of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b</i>. In addition, the CPU <b>60</b> also functions as a failure determiner which determines whether there is a failure in the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b</i>. Moreover, the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>function as detectors which detect the magnetic property change in the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>are films of the magnetic property change material which are magnetically anisotropic such as Fe&#x2014;Ni system and the Fe&#x2014;Cr system, for instance. Moreover, the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>are respectively attached in an axial direction on two parts of the shaft <b>20</b> which are close to each other so as to be anisotropic in opposite directions. Therefore, difference between magnetic permeabilities (change in a magnetic property) of the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>appears when the torque is applied to the shaft <b>20</b> in one direction, and difference between the magnetic permeabilities appears in the opposite direction when the torque is applied in the opposite direction.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Here, how to attach the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>and how to make the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>anisotropic are described. First of all, the shaft <b>20</b> is heat-treated so that Rockwell hardness becomes HRC40-65. Then, the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b</i>, which are plated or deposited in an axial direction on vertically separated two parts of an outer peripheral surface of the shaft <b>20</b>. Next, twisting the shaft <b>20</b> provides an anti-clockwise torque T (approximately 10 kgf&#xb7;m (98 N&#xb7;m), for instance) to the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a</i>. In this state, a coil is used to vibrate the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a </i>at a high frequency. Then, the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a </i>is heated at approximately 300&#xb0; C. for a several seconds and then cooled. After that, the torque T in the anti-clock direction is removed from the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a</i>. Consequently, the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a </i>becomes anisotropic. Next, the shaft <b>20</b> is twisted in the opposite direction so as to apply a clockwise torque T (approximately 10 kgf&#xb7;m (98 N&#xb7;m), for instance) to the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>b</i>. In this state, a coil is used to vibrate the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>b </i>at a high frequency similarly to the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a</i>. Thus, the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>b </i>is heated at approximately 300&#xb0; C. As a result, the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>b </i>becomes anisotropic in the opposite direction to the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">One of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a </i>and one of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>b </i>are connected to a non-inverting input (+) of the differential amplifier <b>50</b>, while one of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>c </i>and one of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>d </i>are connected to an inverting input (&#x2212;) of the differential amplifier <b>50</b>. In other words, a voltage signal between the connection point VS<b>1</b> in a series circuit which includes the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the connection point VS<b>2</b> in a series circuit which includes the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>is input to the differential amplifier <b>50</b>. Moreover, the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a </i>and the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>d </i>are connected to a detection coil power supply.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are transistors to apply the excitation voltages to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>and function as an excitation signal generator. A voltage signal at a connection point where the collector of the switching element <b>15</b><i>a </i>is connected to the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>b </i>is input to the CPU <b>60</b> as a monitoring signal B. Meanwhile, a voltage signal at a connection point where the collector of switching element <b>15</b><i>b </i>is connected to the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>c </i>is input to the CPU <b>60</b> as a monitoring signal A. The emitters of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are grounded and connected to free-wheeling diodes which are not shown in the figure.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The series circuit which includes the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>or the series circuit which includes the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>detects the difference between the magnetic permeabilities of the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>as an inductance difference. When the excitation voltage is applied to the both ends of the series circuits, change in the difference between the magnetic permeabilities of the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>is detected as change in a potential difference between the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b>. In other words, change in the torque is detected by the differences between the potentials at the connection points between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, and an intermediate potential which is a potential before the torque changes. The differences between the potentials at the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b> between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, and the intermediate potential can be obtained from the change in the potential difference (voltage) between the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b>. In this case, the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>are connected in the opposite direction to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b</i>. Therefore, the potential at the connection point VS<b>1</b> changes in the opposite way to the change in the potential at the connection point VS<b>2</b>. That is to say, comparing to a case of detecting change in an only potential at either connection point, the detection sensitivity is doubled.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The differential amplifier <b>50</b> amplifies the potential difference between the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b>. The CPU <b>60</b> includes an AMD converter <b>60</b><i>a </i>so as to convert an analog voltage output from the differential amplifier <b>50</b> into a digital signal for signal processes. In addition, the CPU <b>60</b> calculates a strength and direction of the torque applied to the shaft <b>20</b> to generate the torque signal T. Moreover, the CPU <b>60</b> generates the excitation signal which is a rectangular waveform signal. The excitation signal (the current signal) is input to each of the gates of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b</i>. The differential amplifier <b>50</b> is powered by an OP Amp power supply while the CPU <b>60</b> is powered by a CPU power supply. Both voltages of the power supplies are 5V.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Next, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2A-2D</figref>, a waveform in each part will be described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> shows a waveform of the excitation signal which is a rectangular waveform signal with a duty ratio of 1/2. The excitation signal controls ON and OFF of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>(See <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). In other words, when the excitation signal (the current signal) is at High level, each state of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>is ON, and each collector potential is equal to the earth potential. Meanwhile, when the excitation signal is at Low level, each state of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>is OFF, and each collector potential is equal to the power supply potential. By the way, when the state is changed to OFF, magnetic energy which has been accumulated in the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>or the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>is discharged through the free-wheeling diodes. As a result, it is possible to prevent a breakdown of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b</i>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> shows a waveform of the monitoring signal A which keeps a rectangular waveform identical to the collector voltage waveform itself of the switching element <b>15</b><i>b </i>in the normal state. However, a potential of the monitoring signal A is kept equal to the earth potential in the failure state of the switching element <b>15</b><i>b</i>. Therefore, whether potentials of the monitoring signals A and B are kept equal to the earth potential determines operational states of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2C</figref> shows a waveform of voltage in the detection coil. In the normal state, the rectangular waveform voltage whose maximum is not higher than a power supply voltage of the detection coil power supply is applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>. Meanwhile, in the ON-failure state, that is, the abnormal state, the power supply voltage is continuously applied.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2D</figref> shows a waveform of current in the detection coil. When the power supply voltage of the detection coil power supply is applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, the current monotonically increases with a proportionality factor, which is a reciprocal of an inductance of the detection coil. However, since the permeabilities of the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>are nonlinear, the current is not proportional. The maximum current is limited by a pulse width of the excitation signal. On the other hand, when the states of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are changed to OFF, the magnetic energy is discharged through the free-wheeling diodes. Therefore, no current flows in the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>or the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>in the OFF state.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Moreover, in the failure state, the power supply voltage is continuously applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>or the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>so that the current keeps increasing. Consequently, a steady-state current Is flows, which is limited by an internal resistance of the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>or the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, or excessive current.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As described above, according to the embodiment, the monitoring signals A and B which are voltage signals at ends of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are input to the CPU <b>60</b>. Thus, when the monitoring signals A and B are kept at the earth potential, it is determined that the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are in ON-failure. As a result, it is possible to prevent the excessive current from flowing in the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>so as to prevent a break.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">In the first embodiment, the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>are used to apply the positive rectangular waveform voltage to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>or the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>. On the other hand, a bridge circuit can be used to apply a rectangular waveform AC voltage.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Next, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a magnetostriction type torque sensor unit <b>150</b> according to a second embodiment of the present invention will be described. Here, the shaft <b>20</b>, the magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b</i>, the differential amplifier <b>50</b>, and the CPU <b>60</b> are similar to those in the first embodiment. Therefore, only different features from the first embodiment will be described, below.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A bridge circuit <b>10</b> includes four switching elements <b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>, <b>10</b><i>c</i>, and <b>10</b><i>d</i>. The switching elements <b>10</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>c </i>are p channel MOSFETs while the switching elements <b>10</b><i>b </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>are n channel MOSFETs. The drains of the switching elements <b>10</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>c </i>are connected to a detection coil power supply, while the sources of the switching elements <b>10</b><i>b </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>are grounded. In addition, the source of the switching element <b>10</b><i>a </i>and the drain of the switching element <b>10</b><i>b </i>are connected to a terminal S<b>1</b>. Meanwhile, the source of the switching element <b>10</b><i>c </i>and the drain of the switching element <b>10</b><i>d </i>are connected to a terminal S<b>2</b>. Moreover, the gates of the switching element <b>10</b><i>a </i>and the switching element <b>10</b><i>b </i>are connected to a gate terminal G<b>1</b>. Meanwhile, the gates of the switching element <b>10</b><i>c </i>and the switching element <b>10</b><i>d </i>are connected to a gate terminal G<b>2</b>. Thus, the switching elements <b>11</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>b </i>or the switching elements <b>11</b><i>c </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>form an inverter circuit. In the inverter circuit, when the gate terminals G<b>1</b> and G<b>2</b> are at the power supply potential, the terminals S<b>1</b> and S<b>2</b> are at the earth potential. On the other hand, when the gate terminals G<b>1</b> and G<b>2</b> are at the earth potential, the terminals S<b>1</b> and S<b>2</b> are at the power supply potential.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>themselves are similar to those in the first embodiment. However, how to connect the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>is different from that in the first embodiment. Specifically, a potential at the connection point where one end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>b </i>and one end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>c </i>are connected to the terminal S<b>1</b> of the bridge circuit <b>10</b> is input to the CPU <b>60</b> as a monitoring signal A. Similarly, a potential at the connection point where one end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a </i>and one end of detection coil <b>40</b><i>d </i>are connected to the terminal S<b>2</b> of the bridge circuit <b>10</b> is input to the CPU <b>60</b> as a monitoring signal B. Moreover, the connection point VS<b>1</b> between the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a </i>and the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>b </i>is connected to the non-inverting input (+) of the differential amplifier <b>50</b>. On the other hand, the connection point VS<b>2</b> between the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>c </i>and the other end of the detection coil <b>40</b><i>d </i>is connected to the inverting input (&#x2212;) of the differential amplifier <b>50</b>. The inverter <b>55</b> generates an inverted signal of the excitation signal I. The excitation signal I is input to the gate terminal G<b>2</b> of the bridge circuit <b>10</b> while the inverted signal of the excitation signal I is input to the gate terminal G<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">According to this configuration, in the bridge circuit <b>10</b>, when the terminal G<b>1</b> is at the earth potential, the terminal S<b>1</b> is at the power supply potential. Meanwhile, when the gate terminal G<b>1</b> is at the power supply potential of the detection coil power supply, the terminal S<b>1</b> is at the earth potential. Similarly, when the gate terminal G<b>2</b> is at the earth potential, the terminal S<b>2</b> is at the power supply potential. Meanwhile, when the gate terminal G<b>2</b> is at the power supply potential, the terminal S<b>2</b> is at the earth potential.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing that the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>wind around the shaft <b>20</b>. The magnetostriction films <b>30</b><i>a </i>and <b>30</b><i>b </i>are respectively attached in the axial direction on two parts of the shaft <b>20</b> which are close to each other. The detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>c </i>respectively surround two parts of the surface of the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>b </i>in the axial direction, separately from the shaft <b>20</b>. Meanwhile, the detection coils <b>40</b><i>b </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>respectively surround two parts of the surface of the magnetostriction film <b>30</b><i>a </i>in the axial direction, separately from the shaft <b>20</b>. The coils wind in the same direction so as not to cancel magnetic fields H<b>1</b>, H<b>2</b>, H<b>3</b>, and H<b>4</b>. Moreover, the rectangular waveform voltage is applied between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>and between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>b </i>and <b>40</b><i>c</i>. The connection point VS<b>1</b> between the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a </i>and the detection coil <b>40</b><i>b </i>is extended, while the connection point VS<b>2</b> between the detection coil <b>40</b><i>c </i>and the detection coil <b>40</b><i>d </i>is extended.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Next, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A-5E</figref>, a waveform of each part in the embodiment will be described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> shows a waveform of the excitation signal which is a continuous signal forming a rectangular wave with a pulse width of T<b>1</b> and a duty ratio of 1/2. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> shows a waveform of the monitoring signal A. In the normal state, the monitoring signal A forms a rectangular voltage waveform at the terminal S<b>1</b> of the bridge circuit <b>10</b>. On the other hand, in the abnormal state of the On-failure of the switching element <b>10</b><i>b</i>, the monitoring signal A is kept at the earth potential. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> shows a waveform of the monitoring signal B. In the normal state, the monitoring signal B forms a rectangular voltage waveform at the terminal S<b>2</b> of the bridge circuit <b>10</b>. On the other hand, in the abnormal state of the On-failure of the switching element <b>10</b><i>d</i>, the monitoring signal B is kept at the earth potential.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</figref> is a waveform of the voltage in the detection coil.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">A high-level signal of the excitation signal I is applied to the gate terminal G<b>2</b> of the bridge circuit <b>10</b>, while a low-level signal which is an inverted signal of the high-level signal is applied to the gate terminal G<b>1</b>. Then, the terminal S<b>2</b> is at the earth potential, and the terminal S<b>1</b> is at the power supply potential. On the other hand, a low-level signal of the excitation signal I is applied to the gate terminal G<b>2</b>, while a high-level signal which is an inverted signal of the low-level signal is applied to the gate terminal G<b>1</b>. Then, the terminal S<b>1</b> is at the earth potential, and the terminal S<b>2</b> is at the power supply potential. As a result, rectangular waveform AC voltage, which alternates between positive and negative voltage, is applied to the series circuit including the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the series circuit including the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d</i>. Meanwhile, in the failure state of the ON-failure of the switching elements <b>10</b><i>b </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>or the switching elements <b>10</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>c</i>, the voltage is not applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d. </i></p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5E</figref> shows a waveform of current in the detection coils. When positive voltage is applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, the current which monotonically increases with time with a proportionality factor, which is a reciprocal of an inductance flows. Meanwhile, when negative voltage is applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d</i>, the current which monotonically decreases with time. Here, the increasing current or the decreasing current is limited by a pulse width T<b>1</b> so that no saturation current is observed. Since magnetic permeability which determines the inductance is nonlinear, the current changes nonlinearly. On the other hand, in the failure state of the ON-failure of the switching elements <b>10</b><i>b </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>or the switching elements <b>10</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>c</i>, no current flows. Moreover, in the state where the excitation signal is kept at 5V, the potential of the gate terminal G<b>1</b> is equal to 0V and the potential of the gate terminal G<b>2</b> is equal to 5V. Thus, the switching elements <b>10</b><i>a </i>and <b>10</b><i>d </i>are kept conductive. In this case, the current from the detection coil power supply is continuously supplied to the detection coil.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">When the switching element <b>10</b><i>a </i>is in the ON-failure, the terminal S<b>1</b>, that is, the monitoring signal A is at the power supply potential though the waveform is not shown in the figure. Therefore, the rectangular waveform voltage between the power supply potential and the earth potential is applied to the detection coils, <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d</i>. Meanwhile, when the switching element <b>10</b><i>c </i>is in the ON-failure, the terminal S<b>2</b>, that is, the monitoring signal B is at the power supply potential. Therefore, the rectangular waveform voltage between the power supply potential and the earth potential is applied to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d</i>. In other words, according to the embodiment, whether the monitoring signals A and B are kept at the earth potential or the power supply potential determines whether the switching elements <b>10</b><i>a</i>, <b>10</b><i>b</i>, <b>10</b><i>c</i>, and <b>10</b><i>d </i>are in the ON-failure.</p>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">Example Use</heading>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Next, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, description will be given to an electric power steering device which employs the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit <b>100</b> or <b>150</b> according to the embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In an electric power steering device <b>200</b>, a steering wheel <b>210</b> is rotated. Then, the shaft <b>20</b>, which is a steering shaft directly connected to the steering wheel <b>210</b>, rotates a pinion <b>260</b> included in a rack-and-pinion <b>270</b>. Accordingly, a rack shaft <b>250</b> is moved so as to change a direction of the rolling wheel <b>220</b>. Then, a controller <b>230</b> controls to drive an electric motor <b>240</b> in accordance with a torque signal T which is detected by the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit <b>100</b> or <b>150</b> using detection coils <b>40</b>. The electric motor <b>240</b> rotates the pinion <b>260</b> through a force transmitter <b>280</b> and operates to reduce steering torque of the steering wheel <b>210</b>. There is the following relationship.
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?><i>TH=TP</i>/(1+<i>KA</i>),<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
<br/>
where steering torque of a driver is TH, torque transferred to the pinion <b>260</b> is TP, and a constant related to a magnitude of supplemental torque which is to be added by the electric motor <b>240</b> is KA. Moreover, it is possible to apply the magnetostriction type torque sensor unit <b>100</b> or <b>150</b> to Steer-By-Wire in which the steering wheel <b>210</b> is mechanically separated from the rolling wheel <b>220</b>.
</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">Comparative Example</heading>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Next, a comparative example relating to the present invention will be described.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In a torque detection circuit shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a resistor R<b>1</b>, a detection coil <b>40</b><i>a</i>, a detection coil <b>40</b><i>b</i>, and a resistor R<b>2</b> are connected in this order in a series. In other words, the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>are connected in a series in the same way with each of the embodiments. However, it is different in that the resistors R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b> are also connected in the series. The switching element <b>15</b><i>c </i>is a transistor. The collector is connected to a connection point between the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b</i>. The emitter of the switching element <b>15</b><i>c </i>is grounded while an excitation signal (a current signal) is input to the base. Moreover, one end of the resistor R<b>1</b> and one end of the resistor R<b>2</b> are connected to the detection coil power supplies. A connection point VS<b>1</b> between the other end of the resistor R<b>1</b> and the detection coil <b>40</b><i>a </i>is extended while a connection point VS<b>2</b> between the other end of the resistor R<b>2</b> and the detection coil <b>40</b><i>b </i>is extended.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In the normal state, when the excitation signal at the High level is input to the switching element <b>15</b><i>c </i>to turn the switching element <b>15</b><i>c </i>ON, exponentially increasing current flows in the detector coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the resistors R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b>. At this time, the maximum of the increasing current is limited by the pulse width of the excitation signal. It is possible to measure the inductances of the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>by measuring the maximum voltages between the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b>. Moreover, when the excitation signal at the Low level is input to the switching element <b>15</b><i>c </i>to turn the switching element <b>15</b><i>c </i>OFF, the increased current exponentially decreases. Then, as the inductance of the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>change, the potentials at the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b> change.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">On the other hand, in the abnormal state of the On-failure of the switching element <b>15</b><i>c</i>, the collector potential is kept equal to the earth potential. In the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the resistors R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b>, the current exponentially increase, and then the maximum current limited by the resistances of the resistors R<b>1</b> and R<b>2</b> keep flowing constantly. At this time, the potentials at the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b> are kept equal to the earth potential so that the abnormal state is detected.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">Modification Example</heading>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The present invention is not limited to the above-described embodiments but may be otherwise variously modified as below.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">(1) In the first embodiment, the voltage between the both ends of each of the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b </i>which are connected in the series to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d </i>is monitored. However, it is also possible to monitor the current which flows in the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a</i>, <b>40</b><i>b</i>, <b>40</b><i>c</i>, and <b>40</b><i>d</i>. Thus, the current monitor is included in the operational state monitor.
<br/>
(2) In each of the embodiments, the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>are connected in the opposite direction to the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b </i>and the differential between the connection points VS<b>1</b> and VS<b>2</b> is output. However, when the detection coils <b>40</b><i>c </i>and <b>40</b><i>d </i>are connected in the same direction with the detection coils <b>40</b><i>a </i>and <b>40</b><i>b</i>, the potentials change in the same way due to the applied torque so that the output differential is in a vicinity of a zero point. In other words, in the abnormal state, the output differential is out of the vicinity of the zero point. Therefore, the failure detector can detect this.
<br/>
(3) In the first embodiment, transistors are employed as the switching elements <b>15</b><i>a </i>and <b>15</b><i>b</i>, but an FET or an IGBT may be employed.
</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">According to the present invention, it is possible to provide a magnetostriction type torque sensor which distinguishes the failure state of the switching element from the normal state.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">While the described embodiments represent the preferred forms of the present invention, it is to be distinctly understood that the invention is not limited thereto but may be otherwise variously embodied within the spirit and scope of the following claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A magnetostriction type torque sensor comprising:
<claim-text>magnetic property change material which is provided on a shaft and whose magnetic property changes in accordance with torque applied to the shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an excitation signal generator which generates an excitation signal whose voltage is converted into a predetermined voltage through a switching element;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of detection coils to which the excitation signal generator applies the excitation signal, and which plurality of detection coils outputs a voltage in accordance with a change in the magnetic property of the magnetic property change material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an operational state monitor which monitors an operational state of the switching element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the operational state monitor monitors a monitoring signal taken between the detection coil and the switching element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the operational state monitor comprises a failure determiner which determines whether there is a failure in the switching element based on the monitoring signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The magnetostriction type torque sensor as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the magnetic property change material includes a first magnetostriction film and a second magnetostriction film both of which are attached in an axial direction respectively on two parts of the shaft which are close to each other,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first magnetostriction film and the second magnetostriction film are anisotropic in opposite directions to each other, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the plurality of the detection coils are placed separately from the shaft on which the first magnetostriction film and the second magnetostriction film are attached.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The magnetostriction type torque sensor as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the operational state monitor monitors a monitoring signal taken between the detection coil and the switching element, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the operational state monitor comprises a failure determiner which determines whether there is a failure in the switching element based on the monitoring signal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The magnetostriction type torque sensor as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the failure determiner determines that there is a failure in the switching element when the monitoring signal is kept at an earth potential or a power supply potential.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The magnetostriction type torque sensor as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the failure determiner determines that there is a failure in the switching element when the monitoring signal is kept at an earth potential or a power supply potential. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
