<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640790-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640790</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10575385</doc-number>
<date>20041030</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>10</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10353033</doc-number>
<date>20031113</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>235</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73 407</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Method for operating a hydrogen test leak unit</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5049168</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Danielson</name>
<date>19910900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 95 31</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6815107</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Inai et al.</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429 22</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>101 22 733</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 395 965</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>19901100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 503 925</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19920900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>02/47189</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00007">
<othercit>Table from &#x201c;Polymer Handbook&#x201d; containing Permeation Coefficients of Various Polymers 851-886.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73 407</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070261476</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071115</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hilgers</last-name>
<first-name>Heike</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bergisch Gladbach</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Marjama Muldoon Blasiak &#x26; Sullivan LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Inficon GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Hezron</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Shabman</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2004/012334</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20041030</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20070322</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2005/047844</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20050526</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">For operating a hydrogen test leak unit including a chamber defined by a membrane, a test gas mixture of hydrogen and an added gas is used. The added gas has a permeation coefficient relative to the material of the membrane ranging between 50% and 200% of that of hydrogen. In this manner, demixing of the test gas mixture is limited and significant concentration variations in the chamber are prevented. Preferably, helium is used as added gas.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="110.07mm" wi="143.68mm" file="US07640790-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="198.71mm" wi="172.13mm" file="US07640790-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="132.93mm" wi="145.97mm" file="US07640790-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a method for operating a hydrogen test leak unit comprising a chamber defined by a membrane, into which chamber a test gas mixture of hydrogen and at least one added gas is introduced.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Test leak units are used for calibrating leakage flow meters. A test leak unit comprises a container in which a volume of a test gas or a test gas mixture is kept at a controlled pressure. The chamber includes an outlet connected to a capillary or any other defined test leak leading into the surroundings. For pressure control purposes, the chamber comprises a membrane which is supported by a spring, and which, upon deflection, actuates a control valve which switches on and off a gas-supplying pressure source.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Hydrogen may not be used as a pure gas in test leak units due to its explosiveness. Therefore, normally an oxygen-free hydrogen/nitrogen mixture is used as a test gas mixture (forming gas). However, the membrane sealing the chamber of the pressure control valve is not gas-impermeable. It rather offers different permeabilities to different gases. Consequently, hydrogen escapes more quickly from the chamber than nitrogen such that the nitrogen concentration in the chamber increases. Normally, the test gas mixture comprises 95% N<sub>2 </sub>and 5% H<sub>2</sub>. The hydrogen content can amount to up to 10%. This leads to an explosion risk.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">It is an object of the invention to provide a method for operating a Hydrogen test leak unit which offers a high time constancy of the leak rate.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to the invention, a gas is selected as an &#x201c;added gas&#x201d; which has a permeation coefficient relative to the material of the membrane ranging between 50% and 200% of that of hydrogen.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The invention is based on the idea that the components of the test gas mixture should have approximately the same permeation coefficients relative to the membrane material in order to prevent demixing due to permeation. The permeation coefficients depend to a large extent, but not exclusively, on the molecule size. The hydrogen molecule is relatively small and generally has relatively high permeation coefficients. This applies, mutatis mutandis, to helium. On the other hand, it has been found that even relatively large molecules, such as CO<sub>2</sub>, CH<sub>4 </sub>or C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>6</sub>, may offer a high permeability.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Helium has turned out to be a particularly suitable gas to be added to hydrogen. Experiments have shown that permeation through a membrane proceeds at essentially the same rate for hydrogen and helium. This combination offers the advantage that the hydrogen content can be reduced to approximately 5%. This is of importance with regard to hazardous substance categories. Another boundary condition requires that the useful life of test leak units should be one year. So far, realization of a hydrogen content of 5% has not been feasible since too much gas escaped through the required bypass capillary, and it has not been possible to comply with the useful life.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Suitable gases to be added are helium (He), carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>), methane (CH<sub>4</sub>) and ethane (C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>6</sub>). This list is however not complete.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The gas to be added should be oxygen-free to prevent it from forming, together with hydrogen, an explosive mixture. This is however not a necessary condition. By reducing the hydrogen content, the explosiveness of the test gas mixture can be decreased.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">An embodiments of the invention will now be described in greater detail with reference to the drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a functional diagram of the hydrogen test leak unit; and</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a schematic configuration of the hydrogen test leak unit.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a test gas mixture <b>10</b> is introduced into a pressure control volume <b>11</b>. The pressure control volume <b>11</b> comprises a pressure reducing valve provided with a control membrane <b>12</b>. A pressure control valve <b>13</b> adjusts, with the aid of the control membrane <b>12</b>, the pressure in the pressure control volume <b>11</b> to a constant value. The pressure control valve is connected with a leak rate-determining capillary <b>14</b> from which the leakage flow <b>15</b> escapes at the test gas leak rate.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The pressure control volume <b>11</b> or the pressure control valve <b>13</b> is connected with a bypass capillary <b>16</b> which leads a bypass flow <b>17</b> into the surroundings for the purpose of ensuring a permanent flow through the pressure control volume <b>11</b> to prevent demixing.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the pressure controller <b>20</b> to which the test gas mixture <b>10</b> is supplied. The pressure controller <b>20</b> comprises a chamber <b>21</b> into which the test gas mixture is introduced. This chamber is sealed with a membrane <b>22</b>. The membrane <b>22</b> is made from an elastomeric material. The membrane <b>22</b> is supported by a spring <b>23</b> which counteracts the pressure prevailing in the chamber <b>21</b>. The pressure control valve <b>24</b> comprises a duct <b>25</b> for delivering the highly pressurized test gas mixture into the chamber <b>21</b>. The outlet of the duct <b>25</b> is opened and closed by a movable valve element <b>26</b>. Via a rod <b>27</b> defining a two-arm lever, the valve element <b>26</b> is connected with a coupling means <b>28</b> which connects one of the lever arms with the membrane <b>22</b>. The deflection movements of the membrane <b>22</b> cause the pressure control valve <b>24</b> to be opened or closed. In this manner, a pressure corresponding to the force of the spring <b>23</b> is adjusted and maintained in the chamber <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> further shows the test leak outlet <b>30</b> which is connected with a leak rate-determiningm capillary (not shown) leading to the surroundings.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Further, a bypass capillary <b>31</b> is provided at the chamber <b>21</b>, which bypass capillary permanently leads a leak flow into the surroundings.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The space below the membrane <b>22</b> is defined by a container <b>33</b> which supports the spring <b>23</b> and comprises a vent opening <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The small dots depicted pictorially in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> represent the mixed-gas volume and the larger dots represent the hydrogen molecules. The hydrogen molecules diffuse through the membrane <b>22</b> out of the chamber <b>21</b> and travel through the vent opening <b>34</b> into the surroundings.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The membrane <b>22</b> is a polymeric membrane. In one embodiment, the membrane is made from polybutadiene-co-acrylonitrile (Perbunan 18). In another embodiment, the membrane is made from 73/27 Perbunan.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The following table shows the permeation coefficient P for the stated membrane materials. In the table given below (from Yasuda, H., Stannet, V.: Polymer Handbook, J. Wiley &#x26; Sons, New York, 1975), the permeation coefficient P has the following dimension
<br/>
<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="lead"?>[cm<sup>3</sup>(STP)cm cm<sup>&#x2212;2</sup>s<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>(cm Hg)<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>]<?in-line-formulae description="In-line Formulae" end="tail"?>
</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="1">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="217pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" rowsep="1">TABLE</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Membrane material</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="161pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="56pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>P &#xd7; 10<sup>10</sup></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="1" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="4">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="126pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="56pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Poly(butadiene-co-acrylonitrile) 80/20</entry>
<entry>He</entry>
<entry>16.9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>25.2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>N<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>2.52</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>O<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>8.16</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>CO<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>63.1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>73/27 (Perbunan)</entry>
<entry>He</entry>
<entry>12.2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>H<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>15.9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>N<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>1.06</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>O<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>3.85</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>CO<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>30.8</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub></entry>
<entry>24.9</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>C<sub>3</sub>H<sub>8</sub></entry>
<entry>77.7</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="3" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Depending on the membrane material, the permeation coefficient P for hydrogen is 25.2 or 15.9. The gas to be added is selected such that its permeation coefficient ranges between 50 and 200% of that of hydrogen. For this purpose, other gases which are not indicated in the table can also be used as added gases. Preferably, the stated range of the coefficient lies between 50% and 150%.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for operating a hydrogen test leak unit comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>disposing an elastomeric membrane into a chamber of the hydrogen test leak unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>introducing a test gas mixture of hydrogen and at least one added gas wherein the added gas has a permeation coefficient (P) relative to the material of said elastomeric membrane ranging between 50% and 200% of that of hydrogen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>maintaining a constant pressure within said chamber through the movement of said elastomeric membrane; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>allowing said test gas mixture to exit said chamber through a test leak outlet without passing through said membrane.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the group comprising helium, carbon dioxide and methane is selected as the added gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the added gas is oxygen-free.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the hydrogen content of the test gas mixture is lower than 10%.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
