<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641398-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641398</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12048740</doc-number>
<date>20080314</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>67</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>6</main-group>
<subgroup>36</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 86</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Single boot for duplex fiber optic connectors</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6511230</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Connelly et al.</name>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 58</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7325980</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Pepe</name>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 86</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0136657</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ngo</name>
<date>20040700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0089049</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sedor</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439620</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0269194</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Luther et al.</name>
<date>20061100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 78</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>202006011910</doc-number>
<kind>U1</kind>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102006019335</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1074868</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1566674</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 0179904</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20011000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 53</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 56</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 58</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 59</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 76</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 86</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>385 89</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60894976</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20070315</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080226237</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080918</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>O'Riorden</last-name>
<first-name>Stephen</first-name>
<address>
<street>12 Davis Rd.</street>
<city>Stow</city>
<state>MA</state>
<postcode>01775</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Geldart</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<street>354 Ridge St.</street>
<city>Arlington</city>
<state>MA</state>
<postcode>02474</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nakamura</last-name>
<first-name>Kenichiro</first-name>
<address>
<street>14370 Caminito Lazanja</street>
<city>San Diego</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postcode>92127</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Pepper Hamilton LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Song</last-name>
<first-name>Sarah</first-name>
<department>2874</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus for holding a first fiber optic connector and a second fiber optic connector includes a housing configured to secure the first fiber optic connector and the second fiber optic connector at a first end and a strain relief boot connected to a second end of the housing. The housing and the strain relief boot are configured to form a passageway to receive a fiber optic cable that is connected to both the first fiber optic connector and the second fiber optic connector.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="159.17mm" wi="255.19mm" file="US07641398-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="179.32mm" wi="123.87mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641398-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="257.05mm" wi="161.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641398-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="128.35mm" wi="82.89mm" file="US07641398-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="135.55mm" wi="118.11mm" file="US07641398-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="150.37mm" wi="151.21mm" file="US07641398-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of priority to U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/894,976, filed Mar. 15, 2007 and entitled, &#x201c;Single Boot for Duplex Fiber Optic Connectors,&#x201d; which is herein incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This application discloses an invention that is related, generally and in various embodiments, to an apparatus for use with a fiber optic retaining system. Fiber optic cable systems provide a large bandwidth capacity for the transmission of voice and data. In order to extend such systems closer and closer to the premises of the end subscribers, more and more fiber optic connections are required, which often necessitates duplex cable connectors. Such connections are typically made by highly skilled field personnel utilizing specialized tools and equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A conventional way of pairing two connectors to accommodate increased transmission capacity requires many parts, and can make connection to an adapter a difficult task. Often, the connectors can rotate before connection to the adapters, which can cause damage to the hardware. Further, generally, a duplex LC connector includes two cables: one attached to each of the connectors, and these two connectors are held together by a clip. Multiple cables require multiple crimp rings, multiple heat shrink tubes, and multiple boots to attach. This can create a need for more space in order to secure attachment to fiber optic adapters.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In general, in an aspect, the invention is directed to an apparatus for holding a first fiber optic connector and a second fiber optic connector. The apparatus includes a housing configured to secure a first fiber optic connector and a second fiber optic connector at a first end and a strain relief boot connected to a second end of the housing, wherein the housing and the strain relief boot are configured to form a passageway to receive a fiber optic cable that is connected to the first fiber optic connector and the second fiber optic connector.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Aspects of the invention may include one or more of the following features. The apparatus can include a back post configured to secure the first fiber optic connector and the second fiber optic connector in a substantially fixed position. The back post can be configured to reside inside the housing. The housing and the back post can be integrally formed. The back post can include a first arcuate chamber to hold the first fiber optic connector and a second arcuate chamber to hold the second fiber optic connector. The apparatus can include a heat shrink tube configured to contain the fiber optic cable in the passageway. The apparatus can include a crimp ring configured to connect the heat shrink tube to the housing. The housing can include a thumb latch configured to release the first fiber optic connector and the second fiber optic connector.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In general, in another aspect, the invention is directed to a duplex fiber optic connector comprising a first fiber optic cable connector, a second fiber optic cable connector, a back post configured to secure the first fiber optic cable connector and the second fiber optic cable connector in a position adjacent one another, and a strain relief boot in connection with the back post and configured to receive a fiber optic cable that connects with the first and second fiber optic cable connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Aspects of the invention may include one or more of the following features. The connector can include a housing configured to encapsulate the back post and connect with the strain relief boot. The connector can include a heat shrink tube configured to create a conduit within the strain relief boot to hold the fiber optic cable. The heat shrink tube can be connected to the back post via a crimp ring. The back post can include a first arcuate chamber to secure the first fiber optic connector and a second arcuate chamber to secure the second fiber optic connector.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention is directed to a connection system by which two fiber optic cable connectors are positioned together for connection to a duplex adapter. The invention includes a single back post, housing and a strain relief boot by which the fiber optic connectors are securely positioned in proximity to one another. The invention may exhibit one or more of the following capabilities. The housing and back post can improve the ease with which a duplex LC connector is received by a duplex LC adapter. For example, the back post can prevent rotation of the duplex LC connector before the connector is connected to the adapter. The invention can decrease the amount of space required for a duplex LC connector or other duplex connectors in order to achieve connection to an adapter.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a duplex fiber optic cable connector and a strain relief boot and crimp ring with a heat shrink tube.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an assembly perspective view of a duplex fiber optic cable connector and the strain relief boot.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a duplex fiber optic cable connector back post.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a duplex fiber optic cable connector housing.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a strain relief boot for a duplex fiber optic cable connector.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">It is to be understood that at least some of the figures and descriptions of the invention have been simplified to focus on elements that are relevant for a clear understanding of the invention, while eliminating, for purposes of clarity, other elements that those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate may also comprise a portion of the invention. However, because such elements are well known in the art, and because they do not necessarily facilitate a better understanding of the invention, a description of such elements is not provided herein.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The invention is directed to a connection system by which two fiber optic cable connectors are positioned together for connection to a duplex adapter. Embodiments of the invention include a single back post, housing and a strain relief boot by which the fiber optic connectors are positioned in proximity to one another. Embodiments of the invention can be used for connecting two LC style connectors side-by-side. Embodiments of the back post and housing of the invention can accommodate LC connectors that are available on the market without the need for substantial alterations to the LC connectors themselves. The invention can be used to connect two connectors other than LC connectors, such as SC connectors. Other embodiments of the invention are possible and envisioned.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a duplex fiber optic cable connector apparatus <b>10</b> includes LC connectors <b>12</b>, a back post <b>20</b>, a crimp ring <b>30</b>, a shrink tube <b>32</b>, a housing <b>40</b> and a strain relief boot <b>60</b>. The LC connectors <b>12</b> are connected to be positioned side-by-side. The connectors <b>12</b> include a thumb latch <b>16</b>. The fiber optic connectors <b>12</b> may be any suitable type of connector (e.g., SC, LC, MT, ST, etc.). The back post <b>20</b> is configured to accept the connectors <b>12</b>. A first connector <b>12</b> is inserted into a first side <b>21</b> of the back post <b>20</b> and a second connector <b>12</b> is inserted into a second side <b>22</b> of the back post <b>20</b>. The crimp ring <b>30</b> connects the back post <b>30</b> to the shrink tube <b>32</b>. The shrink tube <b>32</b> is inserted through the housing <b>40</b> and the boot <b>60</b>. The shrink tube extends through the distal end <b>62</b> of the boot <b>60</b>. When assembled, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the back post <b>20</b> is positioned inside the housing <b>40</b>. The connectors <b>12</b> extend outside of the housing <b>40</b> on an end opposite the position of the boot <b>60</b>. The apparatus <b>10</b> may be fabricated from any suitable material. For example, according to various embodiments, the portions of the apparatus <b>10</b>, such as the back post <b>20</b> and the housing <b>40</b>, are fabricated from plastic (e.g., a thermoplastic).</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the back post <b>20</b> includes an arcuate receptacle <b>26</b> on each of the sides <b>21</b> and <b>22</b>. The back post <b>20</b> is substantially rectangular and is configured to receive the first LC connector <b>12</b> in a first arcuate opening <b>26</b> on the first side <b>21</b>, and the second LC connector <b>12</b> in a second arcuate opening <b>26</b> on the second side <b>22</b>. The connectors <b>12</b> are positioned to rest in the receptacle <b>26</b> such that the connectors <b>12</b> are substantially parallel to one another and contained within the back post <b>20</b> (i.e., such that the connectors <b>12</b> do not substantially extend outside of the sides <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> of the back post <b>20</b>). The connectors <b>12</b> are secured in the arcuate receptacles <b>26</b>. The back post <b>20</b> secures the LC connectors <b>12</b> in a duplex configuration such that the LC connectors <b>12</b> are connected into LC duplex adapters. Preferably, the LC duplex adapters are industry standard adapters. The back post <b>20</b> includes a lip <b>28</b> configured above the top flat of the connector body. The lip <b>28</b> is configured to substantially prevent the connectors <b>12</b> from rotating before positioning in the connection system.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The back post <b>20</b> includes a cylindrical connection port <b>24</b>. The port <b>24</b> is configured to connect to the crimp ring <b>30</b>. For example, the port <b>24</b> forms a male connection with the crimp ring <b>30</b> and allows for passage of a fiber optic cable into the back post <b>20</b> for connection to the connectors <b>12</b>. The crimp ring <b>30</b> is connected to the shrink tube <b>32</b>. The shrink tube <b>32</b> is configured to provide a conduit, or passageway, through which the fiber optic cable passes to the connectors <b>12</b> for connection. A fiber optic cable is fastened to the back post <b>20</b>, for example, using the crimp ring <b>30</b>, although other fasteners are possible and envisioned.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the housing <b>40</b> comprises a first end <b>41</b> into which the back post <b>20</b> is inserted, and a second end <b>43</b> that connects to the boot <b>60</b>. The housing <b>40</b> includes a body <b>44</b> having an opening <b>42</b>, a duplex thumb latch <b>50</b>, and a boot connector <b>46</b> having hooks <b>48</b>. The thumb latch <b>50</b> is positioned on the housing <b>40</b> such that individual thumb latches <b>16</b> for each of the respective LC connectors <b>12</b> are triggered by a single thumb latch <b>50</b> on the housing <b>40</b>. The duplex thumb latch <b>50</b> is configured to depress the thumb latch <b>16</b> of the first LC connector <b>12</b> and the thumb latch <b>16</b> of the second LC connector <b>12</b>, preferably at substantially the same time. The thumb latch <b>50</b> is configured to improve the efficiency in connection between the duplex LC connectors <b>12</b> and adapters (not shown). The LC connectors <b>12</b> and back post <b>20</b> are secured into the housing <b>40</b>. The back post <b>20</b> is substantially encapsulated within the housing <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the strain relief boot <b>60</b> is affixed to the housing <b>40</b> on an end opposite to the position of the back post <b>20</b>. The strain relief boot <b>60</b> is configured to reduce strain upon the cable inserted into the LC connectors <b>12</b>. The strain relief boot <b>60</b> includes a tapered body <b>61</b>. The body <b>61</b> includes slots <b>66</b> and snap holes <b>64</b>. The snap holes <b>64</b> are configured to accept the hooks <b>48</b> of the housing <b>40</b> such that the housing is secured into position with the boot <b>60</b>. The slots <b>66</b> are positioned along the length of the body <b>61</b> and provide flexibility to the boot <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The connection system of the duplex connector apparatus <b>10</b> operates to couple a fiber optic cable LC connector <b>12</b> with a second fiber optic cable LC connector <b>12</b> using the single housing <b>40</b>, the back post <b>20</b> and the strain relief boot <b>60</b>. In general, standard fiber optic connectors <b>12</b>, such as LC connectors <b>12</b> are secured together side-by-side in a duplex configuration. The back post <b>20</b> and the housing <b>40</b> are configured to secure the connectors <b>12</b> in position for efficient connection to an adapter. The boot <b>60</b> is configured to secure the fiber optic cables in position such that the cables are not kinked or crimped. The apparatus <b>10</b> is configured to improve the ease with which the connectors <b>12</b> are connected to an adapter. The apparatus <b>10</b> is configured to allow for the reduction of two fiber optic cables to a single cable method. The single cable method used in the apparatus <b>10</b> is configured to increase the efficiency in assembling the connector by reducing the parts required for the connection system. The back post <b>20</b> and the housing <b>40</b> can be comprised of an integrated part. The heat shrink tube <b>32</b> and the boot <b>60</b> can be comprised of an integrated part.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The foregoing is considered as illustrative only of the principles of the invention. Further, since numerous modifications and changes will readily occur to those skilled in the art, it is not desired to limit the invention to the exact construction and operation shown and described, and accordingly, all suitable modifications and equivalents may be resorted to, falling within the scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus for securing a first fiber optic connector and a second fiber optic connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a back post, having a first chamber for receiving a first fiber optic connector, and a second chamber for receiving a second fiber optic connector, said first and second chambers adapted and arranged to receive and hold said first and said second fiber optic connectors, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said back post further providing structure for preventing unwanted rotation of said first and second fiber optic connectors within said first and second chambers of the back post;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing that houses at least a portion of said back post and providing a conduit for a fiber optic cable through said housing, said housing further comprising a thumb latch arranged and configured to activate a latch in each of said first and second fiber optic connectors substantially at the same time.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a strain relief boot, coupled to said housing, and though which a fiber optic cable may be passed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said first and second chambers comprising first and second arcuate chambers sized and shaped to mechanically mate to a pair of corresponding fiber optic connectors of the type available on the market, without modification to said connectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, said first and second chambers comprising first and second arcuate chambers sized and shaped to mechanically mate to a pair of corresponding standard LC fiber optic connectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, said first and second chambers comprising first and second arcuate chambers sized and shaped to mechanically mate to a pair of corresponding standard SC fiber optic connectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a heat shrinkable sleeve coupled to said housing to securely hold a fiber optic cable passing through said sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, said housing comprising a cylindrical connection port for coupling said housing to said heat shrinkable sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said housing and said back post being integrally formed with one another as a unitary component of said apparatus.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An apparatus for securing a first fiber optic connector and a second fiber optic connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a back post and housing, integrally formed with one another, to provide a conduit through said housing for passage of a fiber optic cable through said housing and into said back post;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said back post being configured and arranged to receive and securely couple to a pair of fiber optic connectors of a type available in the market without modification to said connectors;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said back post comprising a first end through which said pair of connectors protrude; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said housing comprising a second end through which a fiber optic cable can be received for coupling to said pair of fiber optic connectors in a duplex configuration,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said housing further comprising a thumb latch configured to activate a latch in each of said first and second fiber optic connectors substantially at the same time.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a strain relief boot, coupled to said housing, and through which a fiber optic cable may be passed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, said housing comprising first and second chambers sized and shaped to mechanically mate to a pair of corresponding fiber optic connectors of the type available on the market, without modification to said connectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, said first and second chambers comprising first and second arcuate chambers sized and shaped to mechanically mate to a pair of corresponding standard LC fiber optic connectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, said first and second chambers comprising first and second arcuate chambers sized and shaped to mechanically mate to a pair of corresponding standard SC fiber optic connectors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, said back post comprising structure for preventing unwanted rotation of fiber optic connectors with respect to said first and second chambers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, said structure for preventing unwanted rotation comprising a flattened portion proximate to said chambers, which mechanically prevents rotation of said connectors once inserted into said chambers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, said chambers comprising a substantially rectangular cross section for receiving and securing fiber optic connectors having a corresponding substantially rectangular cross sectional body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, further comprising a heat shrinkable sleeve coupled to said housing to securely hold a fiber optic cable passing through said sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, said housing comprising a cylindrical connection port for coupling said housing to said heat shrinkable sleeve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said structure for preventing unwanted rotation of said connectors comprising a flattened portion proximate to said chambers, which mechanically prevents rotation of said connectors once inserted into said chambers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, said chambers comprising a substantially rectangular cross section for receiving and securing fiber optic connectors having a corresponding substantially rectangular cross sectional body. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
