<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640783-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640783</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11339748</doc-number>
<date>20060125</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>272</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>N</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73  106</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Self-calibrating gas detector and method</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4322964</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Melgaard et al.</name>
<date>19820400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73  106</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5092980</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Maurer et al.</name>
<date>19920300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204415</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5741413</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Capetanopoulos</name>
<date>19980400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205783</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6055840</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Warburton</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6370940</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Warburton</name>
<date>20020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73 2321</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0145644</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rabbett et al.</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0262924</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Wood et al.</name>
<date>20051200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73 3105</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2356708</doc-number>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>U.S. Appl. No. 10/908,737, filed May 24, 2005, Steven Eickhoff et al.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>PCT International Search Report and Written Opinion from corresponding PCT application, published Jul. 12, 2007.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>26</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>18</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73  102</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73  105</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73  106</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 73  125</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10908737</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20050524</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7174766</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11339748</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060266097</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20061130</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Eickhoff</last-name>
<first-name>Steven J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Plymouth</city>
<state>MN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fredrick</last-name>
<first-name>Kris T.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Honeywell International Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Morristown</city>
<state>NJ</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Larkin</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel S</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A portable, calibratible gas detector includes a multi-position gas inflow limiting orifice. When this orifice is in a calibrating position, a source of calibrating gas can be activated to provide a quantity of gas that diffuses into ambient atmosphere flowing through the orifice. The calibration gas can then be sensed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="118.19mm" wi="167.05mm" file="US07640783-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="169.33mm" wi="120.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640783-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="231.99mm" wi="179.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640783-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a Continuation-in-Part of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/908,737 filed May 24, 2005, now U.S. Pat. No. 7,174,766, entitled &#x201c;Calibration Device for Carbon Dioxide Sensor.&#x201d;</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention pertains to gas detectors. More particularly, the invention pertains to gas detectors which include a self-calibration function.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Gas sensors are known and have been used to sense various gases such as hydrogen, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide and the like. While known gas sensors are useful and effective for their intended purpose, it has been recognized that at times they can lose sensitivity over time. For example, in connection with electrochemical-type gas sensors, such sensors incorporate a catalytic electrode which is used in connection with detecting gas within the sensor. The activity of that electrode tends to be reduced gradually over time due to contamination and poisoning of the structure. Consequently, the sensitivity of the associated sensor tends to decrease or drift downward. As a result, it is desirable to be able to calibrate such sensors from time to time.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Structures which can generate calibration gases are of interest and have been developed. One such structure is disclosed in previously filed U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/856,363 filed May 28, 2004, now U.S. Pat. No. 7,037,368, for Calibration Device For Gas Sensors. That application has been assigned to the Assignee hereof and is hereby incorporated by reference. Another such structure has been disclosed in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 10/908,737 previously filed on May 24, 2005, now U.S. Pat. No. 7,174,766, entitled &#x201c;Calibration Device For Carbon Dioxide Sensor&#x201d;. That application has been assigned to the Assignee hereof and is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Beyond an apparatus and a method for generating calibration gas, there continues to be a need for gas sensors which can readily and conveniently calibrated. Preferably such units could be substantially self-contained. It would also be preferable if such units could incorporate a self-calibrating capability without significantly adding to the manufacturing costs, size or weight of such units, especially portable gas detectors.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a self-calibrating gas detector in accordance with the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a front elevational view of a self-contained, portable, gas detector in accordance with the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side elevational view of the detector of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">While embodiments of this invention can take many different forms, specific embodiments thereof are shown in the drawings and will be described herein in detail with the understanding that the present disclosure is to be considered as an exemplification of the principles of the invention, as well as the best mode of practicing same, and is not intended to limit the invention to the specific embodiment illustrated.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A self-calibrating gas detector which embodies the invention incorporates a flow path with a gas inlet end and an orifice associated therewith. A generator of calibration gas as well as a gas sensor are coupled to the path. Finally, if desired a pump can also be coupled to the path.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In accordance with the invention, to carry out a calibration process, the orifice is moved or switched to a state so that it restricts or constricts the inlet of the flow path. This restricts the flow of ambient atmosphere to the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The pump and source of calibration gas can both be activated. The pump, when activated, causes ambient atmosphere to pass a sensing region of the gas sensor at a reduced flow rate relative to normal operational flow past the gas sensor. The activated source of calibration gas generates a known amount of the calibration gas.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Those of skill in the art will understand that additional sensors that measure the ambient temperature, humidity, and pressure can be incorporated to further enhance the calibration process since these variables can affect the perceived concentration of a gas. A filter or selectively permeable membrane can also be provided to cover the inlet of the flow path and prevent an inflow of harmful particulates and gasses that might damage the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The calibration gas diffuses into the inflowing ambient atmosphere traversing the path. This mixture in turn flows into or through the sensing region of the gas sensor. The sensor responds thereto and generates an output signal corresponding thereto which can be used for calibration and making a determination as to the performance characteristics of the sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In accordance with the invention, a reduced flow rate in a range of 1 to 100 cc/min. is particularly advantageous as it reduces the amount of calibration gas required for the process. This can in turn reduce the size and power consumption of the gas generator.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The calibration gas can be generated by any one of a variety of known chemical or electrochemical reactions. For example, a select chemical can be heated until it decomposes. Other forms of gas generation come within the spirit and scope of the invention. Calibration gases can include hydrogen, hydrogen sulfide, carbon dioxide, methane, carbon monoxide and other gases to which the respective sensor will respond.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A detector which embodies the invention is also self-checking. For example, a determination can be made whether the flow path through which the ambient atmosphere is to be drawn is clear or whether it is exhibiting the symptoms of blockage. Further, it is also possible to determine if the sampling pump is functioning as expected.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In yet another aspect of the invention, the flow path can be restricted by a mechanically movable orifice. The orifice could be moved into a calibration position partly closing the inlet which significantly reduces the gas flow through the flow or sampling path. The orifice can be moved into a normal operational position once the calibration process has been concluded.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In another aspect of the invention, the sample pump could be implemented as a peristaltic, diaphragm pump or alternately an electronic pump all without limitation.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates a gas detector <b>10</b> in accordance with the invention. The detector <b>10</b> incorporates a flow path <b>12</b> with an inlet end <b>14</b> and an outlet end <b>16</b>. In normal operation ambient atmosphere can flow from the inlet end <b>14</b> of the flow path <b>12</b> through to the outlet end <b>16</b> in a direction <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The detector <b>10</b> can incorporate an orifice <b>24</b> which can exhibit at least two different states. In one state the orifice <b>24</b> restricts inflowing ambient atmosphere into the flow path <b>12</b>. In this state, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, ambient atmosphere can be expected to pass through the flow path <b>12</b> at a reduced flow rate relative to normal operation. When not carrying out a calibration function, the orifice <b>24</b> can be mechanically slid or rotated from the inlet <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Alternately, the orifice <b>24</b> can electrically assume a non-constricting state. The non-constricting state can be achieved by means of an electrically actuated transducer which will physically move the orifice <b>24</b>. The orifice <b>24</b> could also be switched electronically from a constricting state to a non-constricting state as would be understood by those of skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Detector <b>10</b> also incorporates a gas generator <b>26</b> and gas sensor <b>30</b>. The gas sensor <b>30</b> can be implemented with any desired technology. It will be understood that the details of the sensor <b>30</b> are not limitations of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The gas generator <b>26</b> can be electrically actuated so as to generate a predetermined quantity of a calibration gas, indicated generally at <b>32</b>, in the flow path <b>12</b>. Calibration gas <b>32</b> diffuses into the stream of ambient atmosphere flowing in the path <b>12</b>. A pump <b>34</b> can be coupled to outlet <b>16</b> to produce a flow of ambient atmosphere and calibration gas <b>32</b> through the flow path <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Control circuits <b>40</b> can be provided to provide electrical signals to actuate the generator <b>26</b>, receive inputs from the sensor <b>30</b> and to actuate pump <b>34</b>. The detector <b>10</b> can be carried in a housing <b>42</b> which can also contain a power supply, such as one or more batteries as would be understood by those of skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a front elevational view of a detector <b>10</b>&#x2032; which embodies the present invention. Elements of the detector <b>10</b>&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> which correspond to elements of the detector <b>10</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> have been assigned the same identification numeral. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in one embodiment of the invention, a movable plate <b>24</b><i>a </i>can be provided which has an orifice <b>24</b><i>b, </i>best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The plate <b>24</b><i>a </i>is movable in first and second directions, generally indicated at <b>44</b> relative to flow path <b>12</b>. In a calibrating or restricting position the plate <b>24</b><i>a </i>partly closes flow path <b>12</b>. Plate <b>24</b><i>a </i>permits an inflow of ambient atmosphere only through the orifice <b>24</b><i>b. </i>When in this state, the control electronics <b>40</b> can actuate calibration gas generator <b>26</b> as well as pump <b>34</b> which in turn provides a mixture of ambient atmosphere, drawn through opening <b>24</b><i>b, </i>and calibration gas <b>32</b> from generator <b>26</b>. That mixture is presented to gas sensor <b>30</b>, via path <b>12</b>. Calibration gas <b>32</b> can diffuse into or pass by sensor <b>30</b> and be detected thereby.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Outputs from sensor <b>30</b> which are coupled to a control electronics <b>40</b> provide an electrical signal indicative of the response of the sensor <b>30</b> to the calibration gas <b>32</b>. The electronics <b>40</b> can carry out either an automatic or a semi-automatic calibration of the sensor <b>32</b> in response to the signals received therefrom.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The electronics <b>40</b> can actuate display <b>46</b> to provide a concentration of the sensed calibration gas if desired. Alternatively, the display <b>46</b> can provide an indicium of sensed ambient gas, for example, parts per million, in normal operation where the plate <b>24</b><i>b </i>is located in a non-constricting state as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>. Power supply <b>48</b> can be implemented with rechargeable batteries or replaceable batteries as would be understood by those of skill in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In summary, use of the plate <b>24</b><i>a </i>with opening <b>24</b><i>b </i>significantly reduces the gas flow through the flow or sampling path <b>12</b>. This in turn reduces the amount of calibration gas which is needed to achieve a specific concentration. This in turn can reduce the size and power requirements of gas generator <b>26</b> as well as power supply <b>48</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">From the foregoing, it will be observed that numerous variations and modifications may be effected without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention. It is to be understood that no limitation with respect to the specific apparatus illustrated herein is intended or should be inferred. It is, of course, intended to cover by the appended claims all such modifications as fall within the scope of the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a gas sensor having at least one gas flow port, an orifice having at least two states and providing one of calibration flow, or non-calibration flow;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a source of a predetermined calibration gas, the source provides calibration gas when the orifice provides calibration gas flow and which includes an element which promotes a flow of ambient atmosphere into the gas sensor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> where the source provides a predetermined quantity of calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> where the calibration gas is selected from a class which includes at least hydrogen, hydrogen sulfide, carbon dioxide, carbon monoxide and methane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> where ambient atmosphere which flows into the gas sensor mixes with the calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> where ambient atmosphere which flows into the gas sensor mixes with a predetermined quantity of calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> where the element comprises a gas pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> where the gas sensor includes at least one internal flow path where the source is arranged so that calibration gas enters the flow of ambient atmosphere prior to entering a gas sensing region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> where the orifice, in response to a control signal, changes from a state that provides calibration flow to one that provides non-calibration flow.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> which includes a flow inducing pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> where the gas sensor includes a hollow housing with an internal gas sensing region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> where the orifice is in flow communication with the internal gas sensing region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> where the pump induces a gas flow through the orifice, past the source, and into the gas sensing region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref> which includes control circuits coupled at least to the pump and the orifice.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> where the control circuits are coupled to the source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> where the orifice, at least in part, moves from a state that provides calibration flow to one that provides non-calibration flow in response to at least one signal from the control circuits.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref> where the control circuits activate the source to provide calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. An apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> where the source provides a predetermined quantity of calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A calibratable gas detector comprising:
<claim-text>a housing, the housing including at least one gas inflow port with an internal gas flow path coupled thereto;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a source of calibration gas in flow communication with the gas flow path;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gas sensor where ambient atmosphere drawn through the gas inflow port flows into the gas sensor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump coupled to the gas flow path; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a multi-state orifice coupled to the inflow port, the orifice having a constricting state which limits flow into the flow path and a second, different state.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref> which includes control circuits to switch the orifice between states.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref> where control circuits activate the source to provide calibration gas while the orifice is in a constricting state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref> where the pump is activated at least while the source is activated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref> where the orifice is movable between states.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. A detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref> where the orifice is manually movable between states.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. A detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref> which includes a manually operable control member to activate the source thereby producing the calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A calibratable gas detector comprising:
<claim-text>an internal gas flow path coupled to at least one gas inflow port, ambient air drawn through the gas inflow port and flowing through the gas flow path;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an orifice coupled to the gas inflow port, the orifice having at least a calibration flow state and an non-calibration flow state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a source of a predetermined amount of a calibration gas, the source in flow communication with the gas flow path, the source providing calibration gas when the orifice is in the calibration flow state, the calibration gas diffusing into the ambient atmosphere in the gas flow path; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor, the calibration gas and the ambient atmosphere flowing into the sensor, the sensor sensing a concentration of the calibration gas.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. A calibratable gas detector as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> which includes a flow inducing pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
