<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640807-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640807</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11572384</doc-number>
<date>20050707</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004-212891</doc-number>
<date>20040721</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>393</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>P</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7351433</main-classification>
<further-classification> 7351438</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Semiconductor Sensor</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5734106</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Caillat</name>
<date>19980300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6848306</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kunda</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7351401</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7004030</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ikegami et al.</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7351438</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7100448</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ikegami</name>
<date>20060900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7351433</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0006508</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ikezawa et al.</name>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>02-151770</doc-number>
<date>19900600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>04-099964</doc-number>
<date>19920300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>05-256869</doc-number>
<date>19931000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>06-112510</doc-number>
<date>19940400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>09-089925</doc-number>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-166998</doc-number>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7351433</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7351438</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7351401</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7351436</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070234804</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071011</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tamura</last-name>
<first-name>Masahide</first-name>
<address>
<city>Toyama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ando</last-name>
<first-name>Masato</first-name>
<address>
<city>Toyama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ishikuro</last-name>
<first-name>Yuichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Toyama</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rankin, Hill &#x26; Clark LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hokuriku Electric Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Toyama-shi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chapman</last-name>
<first-name>John E</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2005/013362</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20050707</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20070221</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2006/009194</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20060126</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A semiconductor sensor of the present invention is capable of preventing a diaphragm portion of the sensor from being damaged if a weight collides against a semiconductor integrated circuit substrate of the sensor and is further capable of preventing the diaphragm portion from being bent significantly even when a semiconductor sensor element of the sensor is disposed inside a distorted or deformed casing. A rear surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> is joined onto a wall surface of the casing <b>9</b> that defines a receiving chamber of the casing. A support portion of the semiconductor sensor element is joined onto a front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>. A shock absorbing layer is formed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> at least on a part thereof facing the weight <b>3</b> of the semiconductor sensor element <b>7</b>, for suppressing the bouncing of the weight <b>3</b> when the weight <b>3</b> collides against the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7. </b></p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="77.81mm" wi="116.76mm" file="US07640807-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="251.04mm" wi="125.90mm" file="US07640807-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="201.76mm" wi="87.12mm" file="US07640807-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a semiconductor sensor, and especially to a semiconductor sensor capable of detecting acceleration in a predetermined direction that is caused by an externally-added force and gravitational acceleration in a predetermined direction that is applied with the semiconductor sensor being inclined in a stationary state, or relates to a semiconductor sensor used as a gyroscope.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Japanese Patent No. 3278926 (Patent Document 1) discloses a pressure sensor structure which comprises a semiconductor pressure sensor including a diaphragm portion in a central portion thereof and a cylindrical support portion in an outer peripheral portion thereof, a plate-like semiconductor integrated circuit substrate which is electrically connected with the semiconductor pressure sensor for processing a signal outputted therefrom, and a casing for receiving the semiconductor pressure sensor and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate. In the pressure sensor structure, the semiconductor pressure sensor is installed on the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate by joining the support portion of the semiconductor pressure sensor on a front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</p>
<p id="h-0003" num="0000">Patent Document 1: Japanese Patent No. 3278926</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">Problem to be Solved by the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As with the conventional pressure sensor structure, in a semiconductor sensor provided with a weight, it is contemplated that a support portion of a semiconductor sensor element of the semiconductor sensor may be installed on a semiconductor integrated circuit substrate. However, if the weight collides against the surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate and bounces largely, a diaphragm portion may be damaged by the motion of the weight.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An object of the present invention is to provide a semiconductor sensor capable of preventing the diaphragm portion from being damaged by the motion of the weight even if the weight collides against the surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Another object of the present invention is to provide a semiconductor sensor capable of preventing the diaphragm portion from being bent significantly even if the semiconductor sensor element is disposed in a distorted or deformed casing.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">Means for Solving the Problems</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A semiconductor sensor according to the present invention comprises a semiconductor sensor element, a semiconductor integrated circuit substrate, and a casing made of an electrical insulating material for receiving the semiconductor sensor element and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate. The semiconductor sensor element includes a support portion, a diaphragm portion having an outer peripheral portion which is supported by the support portion and made of a semiconductor material, a weight arranged in a central portion of the diaphragm portion, and a sensor element formed in the diaphragm portion and made of a diffused resistor. The semiconductor integrated circuit substrate is electrically connected with the semiconductor sensor element for processing a signal outputted therefrom. A rear surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate is joined onto a wall surface of the casing that defines a receiving chamber of the casing. The support portion of the semiconductor sensor element is joined onto a front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate. Furthermore, a shock absorbing layer is formed on the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate at least on a portion thereof facing the weight of the semiconductor sensor element, for suppressing bouncing of the weight when the weight collides against the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to the present invention, when the shock absorbing layer is formed on the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate on the portion thereof facing the weight, even if the weight collides against the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate, the shock absorbing layer buffers or absorbs an impact of the collision, thereby suppressing bouncing of the weight. In this manner, the motion of the weight is suppressed or restrained so that the diaphragm portion can be prevented from being damaged. Furthermore, since the semiconductor sensor element is disposed on the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate, even if the casing is distorted or deformed, an adhesive is applied to fill up an uneven gap formed between the distorted or deformed casing and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate, thereby maintaining flatness of the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate. With this arrangement, even when the semiconductor sensor element is disposed inside the distorted or deformed casing, the diaphragm portion of the semiconductor sensor element is prevented from being bent significantly.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is preferred that the shock absorbing layer may also work to protect the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate. In this manner, the diaphragm may be prevented from being damaged since the motion of the weight is suppressed, and additionally, a p-type layer, an n-type layer, and other layers, which are formed in the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate, may be protected from external forces.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Various kinds of materials may be used for the shock absorbing layer. It is preferred that the shock absorbing layer may be made of a polyimide resin since the motion of the weight may not only be suppressed but also the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate may be protected.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In this case, the shock absorbing layer may preferably be 1 to 10 &#x3bc;m in thickness. If the thickness thereof is less than 1 &#x3bc;m, it is hard for the shock absorbing layer to sufficiently suppress the bouncing of the weight. If the thickness exceeds 10 &#x3bc;m, the shock absorbing layer may crack easily.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is preferred that the support portion and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate may be adhered to each other with a silicon-based adhesive. In this manner, stress which is generated due to a change in temperature between the support portion and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate may be reduced, thereby alleviating the stress applied from the adhered portion to the semiconductor sensor element.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view of a semiconductor sensor according to one embodiment of the present invention, when applied to an acceleration sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view as taken along line II-II of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an enlarged partial cross-sectional view of the semiconductor sensor shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an enlarged partial cross-sectional view of a semiconductor sensor according to another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Preferred embodiments of the present Invention will now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view of the semiconductor sensor according to an embodiment of the present invention, when applied to an acceleration sensor. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view as taken along line II-II of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. For ease of understanding, a lid portion <b>11</b>, which will be described later, is omitted from the illustration in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the semiconductor sensor of this embodiment comprises: a semiconductor sensor element including a sensor body <b>1</b>, a weight <b>3</b>, and a pedestal portion <b>5</b>; a semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> on which the pedestal portion <b>5</b> is installed; a casing <b>9</b> for receiving the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> therein; and a lid portion <b>11</b> made of a metal which covers an opening of the casing <b>9</b>. The sensor body <b>1</b> is formed by anisotropic etching from a semiconductor crystal substrate made of single crystal silicon. The sensor body <b>1</b> includes a weight fixing portion <b>13</b> located in a central portion thereof, a cylindrical supporting part <b>15</b> located in an outer peripheral portion thereof, and a flexible diaphragm portion <b>17</b> located between the weight fixing portion <b>13</b> and the supporting part <b>15</b>. In this embodiment, the support portion is constituted by the supporting part <b>15</b> and the pedestal portion <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A plurality of sensor elements respectively made of a diffused resistor for detecting acceleration are formed on the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> on the surface of the sensor body <b>1</b>. A plurality of electrodes are formed on the supporting part <b>15</b>. In the semiconductor sensor of this embodiment, the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> is bent when the weight <b>3</b> is moved due to acceleration caused by an externally-added force or by a force based on gravitational acceleration applied with the semiconductor sensor being inclined in a stationary state. Resistance values of the respective diffused resistors constituting the sensor element will accordingly vary. Thus, three-axis accelerations are detectable based on the amount of the bending of the diaphragm portion.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The weight fixing portion <b>13</b> is shaped to protrude from the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> toward the weight <b>3</b>. The weight fixing portion <b>13</b> has a polygonal cross section, and its outer peripheral surface is Inclined away from the supporting part <b>15</b> as it is becoming more distant from a side where the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> is located.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The supporting part <b>15</b> is an annular rectangle in shape, and its inner peripheral surface is constituted by four trapezoidal inclined surfaces <b>19</b> of a substantially identical shape which are annularly combined so as to define an outer peripheral surf ace of a truncated pyramidal internal space of the supporting part <b>15</b>. The inclined surfaces <b>19</b> are inclined toward a centerline C, which will be described later, as they become closer to the side where the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> is located. With the above-described configuration of the inner peripheral surface of the supporting part <b>15</b>, the internal space of the supporting part <b>15</b> including the weight fixing portion <b>13</b> is a truncated pyramid in shape whose cross-sectional area becomes smaller toward the diaphragm portion <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The weight <b>3</b> is made of tungsten, having a disc-like outline. The weight is fixed to the weight fixing portion <b>13</b> in such a manner that the centerline C passing through the center of the weight fixing portion <b>13</b> and extending in a direction orthogonal to an extending direction of the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> may also pass through the center of gravity of the weight <b>3</b>. The weight <b>3</b> integrally includes a fixed portion <b>21</b> which is fixed to the weight fixing portion <b>13</b> and a body portion <b>23</b> disposed apart from the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> with a space therebetween. The fixed portion <b>21</b> is columnar in shape, having a top face fixed to the weight fixing portion <b>13</b>. The body portion <b>23</b> is substantially cylindrical in shape, having an annular top face <b>23</b><i>a </i>and a side face <b>23</b><i>b </i>defining the circumference of the body portion <b>23</b>. The top face <b>23</b><i>a </i>is located higher than the fixed portion <b>21</b>. An angle portion <b>25</b> formed between the top face <b>23</b><i>a </i>and the side face <b>23</b><i>b </i>closely faces the inclined surfaces <b>19</b> of the supporting part <b>15</b>. With this arrangement, if the weight <b>3</b> is caused to move more than necessary, the angle portion <b>25</b> of the weight <b>3</b> gets in contact with the inclined surfaces <b>19</b> of the supporting part <b>15</b> and displacement of the weight <b>3</b> will consequently be limited within a predetermined range.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The pedestal portion <b>5</b> is an annular rectangle in shape, and is connected with the supporting part <b>15</b> to receive the supporting part <b>15</b> thereon. An inner peripheral surface of the pedestal portion <b>5</b> is constituted by four trapezoidal inclined surfaces <b>27</b> of a substantially identical shape which are annularly combined so as to define an outer peripheral surface of a truncated pyramidal space. The inclined surfaces <b>27</b> are inclined toward the centerline C as they become closer to the side where the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> is located.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> has a substantially rectangular plate-like shape, including a flat front surface <b>7</b><i>a</i>. The semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> is formed in such a manner that a circuit including a p-type layer, an n-type layer, an electrode layer, and other layers is partially exposed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a</i>. The pedestal portion <b>5</b> is installed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a</i>, facing the weight <b>3</b>. In this embodiment, the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>and the pedestal portion <b>5</b> are adhered to each other by a silicon-based adhesive. A shock absorbing layer <b>29</b> is formed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>in an area thereof surrounded by the pedestal portion <b>5</b>. The shock absorbing layer <b>29</b> is made of a polyimide resin, and has a thickness dimension of 1 to 10 &#x3bc;m. The shock absorbing layer <b>29</b> works to suppress bouncing of the weight <b>3</b> when the weight <b>3</b> collides against the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>, and also to protect the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>. In this embodiment, although the shock absorbing layer <b>29</b> is formed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>only in the area surrounded by the pedestal portion <b>5</b>, it may be sufficient to form the shock absorbing layer on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> at least on a portion thereof facing the weight. Accordingly, the shock absorbing layer may be formed all over the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate, or all over the whole surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The casing <b>9</b> is made of a ceramics material and has a rectangular bottom wall <b>9</b><i>a </i>and four side walls <b>9</b><i>b </i>rising from the edge of the bottom wall <b>9</b><i>a</i>. A rectangular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>c</i>, on which the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> is disposed, is formed in a central portion of the bottom wall <b>9</b><i>a</i>. An annular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>d </i>is formed around the rectangular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>c </i>to be located in a different level from that of the rectangular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>c</i>. In this embodiment, a rear surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> and a wall surface of the bottom wall <b>9</b><i>a </i>of the casing <b>9</b> are adhered to each other with an epoxy-based adhesive. A plurality of electrodes are disposed on a surface of the annular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>d</i>. Some of the electrodes disposed on the annular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>d </i>and the plurality of electrodes disposed on the supporting part <b>15</b> are electrically connected by conductive wires <b>31</b>. Similarly, other electrodes disposed on the surface of the annular bottom portion <b>9</b><i>d </i>and the plurality of electrodes disposed on the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> are electrically connected by electric conduction wires <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to the semiconductor sensor of this embodiment, since the shock absorbing layer <b>29</b> is formed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>, even if the weight <b>3</b> moves up and down to collide against the semiconductor Integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>, the shook absorbing layer <b>29</b> may buffer or absorb an impact of the collision, thereby suppressing the bouncing of the weight <b>3</b>. In this manner, the motion of the weight <b>3</b> may be suppressed or restrained, thereby preventing the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> from being damaged. In addition, since the semiconductor sensor element is disposed on the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>, even if the bottom wall <b>9</b><i>a </i>of the casing <b>9</b> is distorted or deformed, an adhesive is applied to fill up an uneven gap formed between the distorted or deformed bottom wall <b>9</b><i>a </i>and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>, thereby preventing the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> from being distorted or deformed. Thus, the flatness of the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>can be maintained. In this manner, even if the semiconductor sensor element is disposed inside the distorted or deformed casing <b>9</b>, the diaphragm portion <b>17</b> of the semiconductor sensor element can be prevented from being significantly bent.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In the above-mentioned embodiment, the shock absorbing layer <b>29</b> is formed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b>. A protective layer <b>135</b> for protecting the circuit including a p-type layer etc, may be formed on the front surface <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate <b>7</b> and the shock absorbing layer <b>129</b> may be formed on the protective layer <b>135</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In the above-mentioned embodiment, the present invention is applied to the semiconductor sensor provided with the pedestal portion <b>5</b>. The present invention is also applicable to a semiconductor sensor without a pedestal portion. In this case, a supporting part will be installed on the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">According to the present invention, it is possible to suppress the bouncing of the weight even if the weight collides against the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate since the shock absorbing layer buffers or absorbs an impact of the collision, Accordingly, displacement of the weight is suppressed or restrained and the diaphragm portion can be prevented from being damaged. In addition, even if the semiconductor sensor element is disposed in the distorted or deformed casing, the diaphragm portion of the semiconductor sensor element can be prevented from being significantly bent.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A semiconductor sensor comprising:
<claim-text>a semiconductor sensor element including:
<claim-text>a support portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a diaphragm portion having an outer peripheral portion which is supported by the support portion, and made of a semiconductor material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a weight arranged in a central portion of the diaphragm portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensor element formed in the diaphragm portion and made of a diffused resistor;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a semiconductor integrated circuit substrate electrically connected with the semiconductor sensor element for processing a signal outputted therefrom; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a casing made of an electrical insulating material for receiving the semiconductor sensor element and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a rear surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate is joined onto a wall surface of the casing that defines a receiving chamber of the casing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the support portion of the semiconductor sensor element is joined onto a front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a shock absorbing layer made of polyimide resin having a thickness of 1-10 &#x3bc;m is formed on the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate at least on a portion thereof facing the weight of the semiconductor sensor element, for suppressing bouncing of the weight when the weight collides against the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The semiconductor sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the shock absorbing layer also works to protect the front surface of the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The semiconductor sensor according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the support portion and the semiconductor integrated circuit substrate are adhered to each other with a silicon-based adhesive. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
