<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641023-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641023</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11912265</doc-number>
<date>20060403</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>05008838</doc-number>
<date>20050422</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>242</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>10</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>18</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>181142</main-classification>
<further-classification> 84 941</further-classification>
<further-classification> 84 942</further-classification>
<further-classification> 84 98</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Mechanism generating at least one type of sonority</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>527811</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Richter</name>
<date>18941000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 84 98</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>560936</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Rodeck</name>
<date>18960500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 84 98</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4466328</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kitamura</name>
<date>19840800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 84 98</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5521321</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Liu</name>
<date>19960500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 84 951</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5962796</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nakamura et al.</name>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 84 97</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0150316</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Muramatsu</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0230188</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kaneko et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>129682</doc-number>
<date>19020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2777095</doc-number>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00010">
<othercit>International Search Report issued in corresponding application No. PCT/EP2006/003011, completed Jul. 12, 2006 and mailed Jul. 19, 2006.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>24</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>181142</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 84 941</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 84 942</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 84 951</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 84 952</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 84 97</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 84 98</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080185214</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080807</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hintze</last-name>
<first-name>Hans-George</first-name>
<address>
<city>Dippoldiswalde/OT Paulsdorf</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Griffin &#x26; Szipl, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Glash&#xfc;tter Uhrenbetrieb GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Glash&#xfc;tte/Sachsen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Donels</last-name>
<first-name>Jeffrey</first-name>
<department>2832</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Luks</last-name>
<first-name>Jeremy</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/EP2006/003011</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20060403</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20071022</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2006/111262</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20061026</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention concerns a sound generator mechanism including a control member (<b>10</b>) and a mechanism (<b>14</b>) for locking/unlocking the control member (<b>10</b>), the control member (<b>10</b>) being able to move between a first position in which the control member is held by the locking/unlocking member (<b>14</b>) and in which it holds the vibrating member (<b>12</b>) away from the rest position thereof, and a second position wherein the control member is released by the locking/unlocking mechanism (<b>14</b>) and wherein it simultaneously releases the vibrating member (<b>12</b>), which starts to vibrate and to produce a sound.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="93.81mm" wi="167.13mm" file="US07641023-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="101.26mm" wi="168.23mm" file="US07641023-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.91mm" wi="171.37mm" file="US07641023-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a National Phase Application in the United States of International Patent Application No. PCT/EP2006/003011 filed Apr. 3, 2006, which claims priority on European Patent Application No. 05008838.4, filed Apr. 22, 2005. The entire disclosures of the above patent applications are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention concerns a mechanism able to produce at least one sound, to be fitted, for example, to a timepiece such as a wristwatch.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A strike mechanism commonly used in wristwatches includes a hammer which strikes a gong. The hammer is moved away from its rest position, then released and strikes the base portion of the gong which is arranged in a circle around the movement. One drawback of this type of strike mechanism is that the intensity of the sound produced is weak.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A second type of strike mechanism is similar to the strike mechanisms used in music boxes. A mechanism of this type is shown schematically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> annexed to this patent application. This mechanism, designated as a whole by the general reference numeral <b>1</b>, essentially includes a rotating drum <b>2</b> at the surface of which are arranged lugs <b>4</b>. When drum <b>2</b> rotates, one of the lugs <b>4</b> lifts up a gong <b>6</b> and gradually moves it away from its rest position until gong <b>6</b> is released from lug <b>4</b> and abruptly relaxes. While relaxing, gong <b>6</b> vibrates and produces a sound. This mechanism has the advantage of producing sounds of greater intensity. However, driving rotating drum <b>2</b> requires a significant amount of energy, which makes it difficult to integrate this mechanism in a watch which has only a small energy reserve.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">It is an object of the present invention to overcome the aforementioned drawbacks in addition to others by providing a sound generating mechanism that can easily be integrated for example in a wristwatch and that produces a sound of great intensity.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention therefore concerns a sound generator mechanism including a control member, a vibrating member and a mechanism for locking/unlocking the control member, the control member being able to move between a first position in which it is retained by the locking/unlocking mechanism and a second position in which it is released by the locking/unlocking mechanism and in which it simultaneously releases the vibrating member, which starts to vibrate and to produce a sound.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Owing to these features, the present invention provides a sound generator mechanism, which, by moving the vibrating member away from its rest position then abruptly releasing it, is capable of producing a sound of great intensity.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a complementary feature of the invention, the sound generator mechanism is wound by an action of the user and is released when a time process reaches an end.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to another feature of the invention, the control member moves by pivoting between its first and second positions.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to yet another feature of the invention, the control member includes a cam and the locking/unlocking mechanism includes a spring with a catch.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">To release the cam and generate a sound, it is only sufficient to act on a spring element, which necessitates little energy and makes the sound generator mechanism of the invention particularly easy to integrate into a wristwatch for example.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Other features and advantages of the present invention will appear more clearly from the following detailed description of one embodiment of the sound generator mechanism according to the invention, this example being given purely by way of non-limiting illustration, in conjunction with the annexed drawing, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, already cited, is a schematic diagram of a strike mechanism of the prior art;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>is a schematic cross-section of the sound generator mechanism in accordance with the present invention in a locked position, and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>is a similar view to that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>showing the sound generator mechanism in the unlocked position thereof.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The present invention proceeds from the general inventive idea which consists in providing a sound generator mechanism able to produce sounds of high intensity while requiring little energy to be switched on, which makes this object particularly easy to integrate in a portable object such as, for example, a wristwatch. Thus, the sound generator mechanism according to the invention includes a control member, which, in a first locked position, moves a vibrating member away from its rest position and which, in a second unlocked position, releases the vibrating member which starts to vibrate and to produce a sound of high intensity.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Designated as a whole by the general reference numeral <b>8</b>, the sound generator mechanism according to the invention shown in cross-section in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>essentially includes a control member <b>10</b>, a vibrating member <b>12</b> and a locking/unlocking mechanism <b>14</b>. More specifically, the control member <b>10</b> takes the form of a cam fitted with two diametrically opposite lugs <b>16</b><i>a </i>and <b>16</b><i>b</i>. Locking/unlocking mechanism <b>14</b> takes the form of a strip spring secured at one of the ends thereof and having a catch <b>18</b> at the free end thereof. Finally, the vibrating member <b>12</b> is formed by a strip-shaped gong.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As can be seen upon examining the Figures, cam <b>10</b> is pivotably mounted on a drive arbour <b>20</b>. Thus, cam <b>10</b> has an aperture <b>22</b> formed of a central cylindrical passage <b>22</b><i>a </i>via which the cam <b>10</b> is mounted on drive arbour <b>20</b> and two cut portions in the shape of an arc of a circle <b>22</b><i>b </i>which open into central passage <b>22</b><i>a</i>. Cam <b>10</b> is coupled with drive arbour <b>20</b> via a retaining member <b>24</b> such as a key secured to drive arbour <b>20</b> and the role of which is described hereinafter.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>, cam <b>10</b> is locked, one of the lugs <b>16</b><i>a </i>abutting against catch <b>10</b> of strip spring <b>14</b>, whereas via the other end <b>16</b><i>b </i>thereof, cam <b>10</b> holds gong <b>12</b> away from its horizontal rest position shown in dot and dash lines for example along an angle &#x3b1; of approximately 18&#xb0;. At the end of a time process such as counting the time before the current time coincides with an alarm time, a motor mechanism (not shown) which may be driven by the watch movement moves spring <b>14</b> away downwards along arrow A. As cam <b>10</b> is no longer locked, it is free to pivot in the clockwise direction along arrow B via the effect of the bending force exerted by going <b>12</b> which is trying to return to its horizontal rest position by moving along arrow C. In order to facilitate the relative movement of cam <b>10</b> and gong <b>12</b>, gong <b>12</b> advantageously has at the free end thereof an over thickness in which an inclined plane <b>26</b> is arranged, along which lug <b>16</b><i>b </i>can slide.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Released from the hold of cam <b>10</b>, gong <b>12</b> can return to its horizontal rest position by vibrating and transmitting an acoustic signal of high intensity. As will have been understood, the only energy necessary for starting the sound generator mechanism according to the invention is that which has to be provided to move spring <b>14</b> away from the position in which it locks cam <b>10</b>. The quantity of energy to be provided is thus very low, which means that it is easy to envisage integrating the mechanism according to the invention for example in a watch, which, as is known, can only store a very limited quantity of energy.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As was seen above, when the spring with a catch <b>14</b> releases cam <b>10</b>, the latter pivots in the clockwise direction along arrow B. Cam <b>10</b> is however limited in its pivoting movement by retaining member <b>24</b> which is secured to drive arbour <b>20</b> and which will abut against the bottom of the portions cut out having the shape of an arc of a circle <b>22</b><i>b </i>formed in aperture <b>22</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>). The pivoting angle &#x3b2; of the cam is approximately 35&#xb0;.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The sound generator mechanism according to the invention is rewound by the user who can, for example, exert pressure on a button, via the effect of which drive arbour <b>20</b> makes a 180&#xb0; movement. As cam <b>10</b> has pivoted by approximately 35&#xb0; and abutted, via the edges of its portions cut out having the shape of an arc of a circle <b>22</b><i>b</i>, against retaining element <b>24</b>, drive arbour <b>20</b> will only start to drive cam <b>10</b> when the retaining element abuts against the opposite edges of the portions cut out in the arc of a circle <b>22</b><i>b </i>arranged in aperture <b>22</b>. While drive arbour <b>20</b> completes a rotation of 180&#xb0;, cam <b>10</b> will only move by 180&#x2212;35=135&#xb0; to return to its initial position illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">It will be noted that the present invention is not limited to the embodiment that has just been described and those skilled in the art could envisage various simple alterations and variations without departing from the scope of the present invention as defined by the annexed claims. In particular, the sound generator mechanism according to the invention could be wound by means of a motor. One could also envisage arranging several mechanisms in accordance with the invention, but with different sound frequencies produced by the respective gongs, in parallel in order to generate a melody.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A sound generator mechanism including:
<claim-text>a control member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vibrating member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and a mechanism for locking/unlocking the control member, wherein the control member is able to move between a first position in which the control member is held by the locking/unlocking mechanism and in which the control member holds the vibrating member in a bent position away from a rest position thereof, and a second position wherein the control member is released by the locking/unlocking mechanism and wherein the control member is pushed back via bending force effect by the vibrating member that returns to the rest position while starting to vibrate and to produce a sound.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said locking/unlocking mechanism is wound by an action of the user and started when a time process reaches an end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control member moves by pivoting between the first and second positions thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the control member moves by pivoting between the first and second positions thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control member includes a cam, the locking/unlocking mechanism includes a spring, and the vibrating member includes a gong.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the control member includes a cam, the locking/unlocking mechanism includes a spring, and the vibrating member includes a gong.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the control member includes a cam, the locking/unlocking mechanism includes a spring, and the vibrating member includes a gong.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the control member includes a cam, the locking/unlocking mechanism includes a spring, and the vibrating member includes a gong.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the cam is driven by a drive arbour with which said cam is coupled via a retaining member secured to the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the cam is driven by a drive arbour with which said cam is coupled via a retaining member secured to the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the cam is driven by a drive arbour with which said cam is coupled via a retaining member secured to the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the cam is driven by a drive arbour with which said cam is coupled via a retaining member secured to the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the cam has an aperture formed of a cylindrical central passage via which said cam is mounted on the drive arbour and two diametrically opposite portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle and both diametrically opposite portions open into the central passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the cam has an aperture formed of a cylindrical central passage via which said cam is mounted on the drive arbour and two diametrically opposite portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle and both diametrically opposite portions open into the central passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the cam has an aperture formed of a cylindrical central passage via which said cam is mounted on the drive arbour and two diametrically opposite portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle and both diametrically opposite portions open into the central passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the cam has an aperture formed of a cylindrical central passage via which said cam is mounted on the drive arbour and two diametrically opposite portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle and both diametrically opposite portions open into the central passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining member projects into the portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle made in the aperture of the cam that limits play of said cam around the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining member projects into the portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle made in the aperture of the cam that limits play of said cam around the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining member projects into the portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle made in the aperture of the cam that limits play of said cam around the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining member projects into the portions cut out in the shape of an arc of a circle made in the aperture of the cam that limits play of said cam around the drive arbour.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the portions cut out in the arc of a circle each form an angular sector substantially equal to 35&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the portions cut out in the arc of a circle each form an angular sector substantially equal to 35&#xb0;.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cam includes two lugs via which they respectively cooperate with a catch arranged at a free end of the spring for temporary immobilisation thereof, and with the gong to temporarily move the latter away from the rest position thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The sound generator mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the gong includes an inclined plane at a free end thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
