<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640625-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640625</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11975182</doc-number>
<date>20071018</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2007-0059485</doc-number>
<date>20070618</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>92</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>20</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15352</main-classification>
<further-classification> 15354</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Vacuum cleaner</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2283836</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>White</name>
<date>19420500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 55429</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2287921</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>White</name>
<date>19420600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 55357</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2287924</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>White</name>
<date>19420600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 55357</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6625845</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Matsumoto et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15353</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0172824</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yun et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15352</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>54103262</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19790800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-305015</doc-number>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005305014</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005305015</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006006674</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006020897</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>20060031442</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>1020060031442</doc-number>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15352</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15354</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60926832</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20070430</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080263816</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081030</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oh</last-name>
<first-name>Jang-Keun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gwangju</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-Gon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gwangju</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cha</last-name>
<first-name>Seung-Yong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gwangju</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ohlandt, Greeley, Ruggiero &#x26; Perle, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Gwangju Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Gwangju</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Muller</last-name>
<first-name>Bryan R</first-name>
<department>3727</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A vacuum cleaner includes a cyclone dust separating unit which includes a cyclone part to separate dust from a dust-laden air drawn from a surface being cleaned using a centrifugal force, a dust collecting part comprising a dust chamber to accommodate the dust separated at the cyclone part, and a compressing part to compress the dust accommodated in the dust chamber. The compressing part includes a driving part to rotatably drive a driving axis, and a compressing plate driven in a substantially perpendicular direction with respect to the driving axis according to the rotation of the driving axis, and to compress the dust accommodated in the dust chamber. As a result, a vacuum cleaner is provided, which requires a minimum space for the installation of a compressing part to compress dust inside the dust collecting part, and provides maximum compressing force of the compressing part.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="127.85mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="222.08mm" wi="170.94mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="175.68mm" wi="181.69mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="171.87mm" wi="150.88mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="139.36mm" wi="173.82mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="170.86mm" wi="157.90mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="156.63mm" wi="160.78mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="160.02mm" wi="157.82mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="157.90mm" wi="144.44mm" file="US07640625-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/926,832, filed Apr. 30, 2007, with the United States Patent and Trademark Office, and Korean Patent Application No. 10-2007-0059485, filed on Jun. 18, 2007, in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present disclosure relates to a vacuum cleaner, and more particularly, to a vacuum cleaner which requires a minimum space for the installation of a compressing part to compress dust collected in a dust receptacle, and which provides maximum compressing force.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A vacuum cleaner generally cleans a surface using a suction force.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In such a general vacuum cleaner, air containing dust is drawn into the vacuum cleaner, and dust is separated from the drawn-in air and stored in a predefined space. A variety of techniques have been applied to a vacuum cleaner to separate dust from air. One example is a cyclone type vacuum cleaner. A cyclone type vacuum cleaner causes the drawn air to rotate within a predefined space, generating a centrifugal force. Accordingly, dust is separated from the drawn air by use of centrifugal force. A general example of cyclone type vacuum cleaner includes a cyclone part which causes air to rotate and thus separates dust from the air using centrifugal force, and a dust collecting part which receives dust separated in the cyclone part.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Korean Patent No. 606794 discloses a technique to compress dust which is collected in a dust collecting part, by driving a compressing plate upward and downward. If dust collected in the dust collecting part is compressed, user convenience increases because users do not need to empty the dust collecting part frequently. KR606794 discloses a bar type plunger attached to the center of the compressing plate in a perpendicular relation, and the bar type plunger is driven upward and downward by the manipulation of a user. As the compressing plate is driven upward and downward within the dust collecting part, a part of the bar type plunger reciprocatingly moves out of the dust collecting part for a distance corresponding to the displacement of the compressing plate.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">However, a vacuum cleaner having the above structure requires not only a space for the installation of the dust collecting part, but also a space to accommodate the plunger at its maximum displacement. Accordingly, a relatively large space has to be prepared in the vacuum cleaner to provide a structure to compress the collected dust, compromising compactness of a vacuum cleaner. Additionally, a bar type plunger provides a limited force to drive the compressing plate.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure overcome the above disadvantages and other disadvantages not described above. Also, the present disclosure is not required to overcome the disadvantages described above, and an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure may not overcome any of the problems described above.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present disclosure provides a vacuum cleaner which requires small space for installation of a structure for compressing dust collected in a dust collecting part, and which provides strong compressing force of the compressing part.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">An aspect of the present disclosure provides a vacuum cleaner, including a cyclone dust separating unit which includes a cyclone part to separate dust from dust-laden air drawn from a surface being cleaned using a centrifugal force, a dust collecting part comprising a dust chamber to accommodate the dust separated at the cyclone part, and a compressing part to compress the dust accommodated in the dust chamber. The compressing part includes a driving part to rotatably drive a driving axis, and a compressing plate driven in a substantially perpendicular direction with respect to the driving axis according to the rotation of the driving axis, and to compress the dust accommodated in the dust chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The compressing part may further include a screw engaged with the driving axis in a substantially linear relation, and rotated together with the driving axis, and a connecting part engaged with the screw and the compressing plate, respectively, to transmit rotational force of the screw to the compressing plate.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The screw may be substantially horizontally arranged at the upper part of the dust collecting part, and may include a first thread formed in one direction and another thread formed opposite to the first thread with reference to the middle of the length. The compressing plate may be driven within the dust chamber upward and downward according to the rotation of the screw.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The connecting part may include a first driving slider and the second driving slider engaged with the threads of opposite directions of the screw, respectively, to slide towards or away from each other according to the rotation of the screw, a first driven slider and a second driven slider positioned right below the first and second driving sliders, to slide along an upper face of the compressing plate, a first connecting rod hinged with the first driving slider with one end and hinged with the second driven slider with the other end, and a second connecting rod hinged with the second driving slider with one end, and hinged with the first driven slider with the other end.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The first and second connecting rods may be hinged with each other at a point crossing each other.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A first guide and a second guide may be provided on the upper face of the compressing plate to guide the sliding movement of the first and second driven sliders.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The driving part may include a driving motor to generate a rotational force, a driving axis rotatably driven by the driving motor, and a rotation force transmitting part to transmit rotational force of the driving motor to the driving axis.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The rotation force transmitting part may include a driving gear rotatably driven by the driving motor, and a driven gear rotated in mesh with the driving gear, to drive the driving axis. The driven gear may include a smaller number of gears than the driving gear.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The cyclone part and the dust collecting part may be arranged in substantially parallel direction, and each may share one common wall.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The wall may be open at an upper end to allow dust separated at the cyclone part to flow therethrough into the dust collecting part.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The cyclone dust separating unit may further include a filter member mounted on an outer casing of the cyclone dust separating unit, to filter remaining dust from air being discharged from the cyclone dust separating unit after the dust is separated at the cyclone part.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The vacuum cleaner may further include a wire winding unit around which an electric wire is wound, to externally supply power into the vacuum cleaner, and a filter cleaning unit rotated by a rotation force being provided from the wire winding unit when the electric wire is released from the wire winding unit, to remove dust from the filter member.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The wire winding unit may include a winding member of a substantially cylindrical configuration, around which the electric wire is wound, and a winding gear engaged with an end of the winding member, and rotated along with the winding member. The filter cleaning unit may include a cleaning screw comprising a cleaning rib in a substantially spiral configuration to remove dust from the filter member upon contact with the outer circumference of the filter member, and a cleaning gear engaged with one end of the cleaning screw and rotated in mesh with the winding gear, to rotatably drive the cleaning gear.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The cyclone dust separating unit may further include a smaller dust chamber to accommodate the dust removed from the filter member by the cleaning screw.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The above and/or other aspects of the present disclosure will be more apparent by describing certain exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a vacuum cleaner according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a cyclone dust separating unit, an electric wire winding unit, and a filter cleaning unit, all of which being housed in a main cleaner body of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the cyclone dust separating unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> viewed from another direction;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross section illustrating the cyclone dust separating unit, the electric wire winding unit and the filter cleaning unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a compressing part provided in the cyclone dust separating unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates the interior of the cyclone dust separating unit before dust compression;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the interior of the cyclone dust separating unit after dust compression; and</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates the filter cleaning unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> removing dust from the filter member.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Certain exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure will now be described in greater detail with reference to the accompanying drawings. In the following description, same drawing reference numerals are used for the same elements even in different drawings. The matters defined in the description, such as detailed construction and elements, are provided to assist in a comprehensive understanding of the disclosure. Thus, it is apparent that the present disclosure can be carried out without those specifically defined matters. Also, well-known functions or constructions are not described in detail since they would obscure the disclosure with unnecessary detail.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a vacuum cleaner according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of a cyclone dust separating unit, an electric wire winding unit, and a filter cleaning unit, all of which being housed in a main cleaner body of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the cyclone dust separating unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> viewed from another direction, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross section illustrating the cyclone dust separating unit, the electric wire winding unit and the filter cleaning unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a compressing part provided in the cyclone dust separating unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a vacuum cleaner <b>1</b> according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure includes a main cleaner body <b>10</b>, an extension path <b>20</b>, and a suction port assembly <b>30</b>. The main cleaner body <b>10</b> causes a suction motor (not shown) housed therein to generate a suction force. The suction port assembly <b>30</b> draws in air and dust from a surface being cleaned, using the suction force generated within the main cleaner body <b>10</b>. The main cleaner body <b>10</b> and the suction port assembly <b>30</b> are connected with each other through the extension path <b>20</b>. The extension path <b>20</b> includes a handgrip <b>21</b> for a grip of a user, a suction hose <b>22</b> connecting the handgrip <b>21</b> with the main cleaner body <b>10</b>, and an extension pipe <b>23</b> connecting the handgrip <b>21</b> with the suction port assembly <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 5</figref>, the main cleaner body <b>10</b> includes a cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> which separates dust from drawn air and receives the separated dust. The cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> includes a cyclone part <b>50</b> to separate dust from the air drawn from the surface being cleaned, using a centrifugal force, a dust collecting part <b>60</b> having a dust chamber <b>61</b> housed therein to hold dust separated in the cyclone part <b>50</b>, and a compressing part <b>70</b> to compress dust collected in the dust chamber <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The cyclone part <b>50</b> induces rotational movement within the air, when the air is introduced into a separating chamber <b>51</b> through an air inlet <b>42</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</figref>) formed at a side of the cyclone unit <b>40</b>, so that dust is separated from the introduced air. Centrifugal force is generated as the drawn air is rotated, and as a result, dust is separated from the air.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The air inside the separating chamber <b>51</b> loses centrifugal force after a predetermined time, and is discharged out of the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> through an air outlet <b>43</b> formed at an upper part of the separating chamber <b>51</b>. The air then reaches a filter member <b>41</b> mounted on an outer casing <b>45</b> of the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> at the end of the air outlet <b>43</b>. The filter member <b>41</b> filters out remaining dust in the air.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The dust collecting part <b>60</b> shares one wall W with the cyclone part <b>50</b>. The dust collecting part <b>60</b> is adjoined with the cyclone part <b>50</b>, in substantially parallel relation. The wall W has an opening S of a predetermined height formed at the upper part, to allow the dust separated at the cyclone part <b>50</b> to pass through the opening S and to flow into the dust chamber <b>61</b> of the dust collecting part <b>60</b>. A compressing plate <b>77</b> is provided within the dust collecting part <b>60</b>. The compressing plate <b>77</b> reaches its uppermost displacement position, when dust moves from the cyclone part <b>50</b> into the dust collecting part <b>60</b> through the opening S at the upper part of the wall W.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The compressing part <b>70</b> compresses dust collected in the dust chamber <b>61</b> of the dust collecting part <b>60</b>, to minimize the volume of the dust. As a result, dust chamber <b>61</b> may have reduced capacity, and still be used for a longer period of time.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the compressing part <b>70</b> includes a screw <b>71</b> horizontally arranged at the upper part of the dust collecting part <b>60</b>, a driving part <b>72</b> to rotatably drive a driving axis <b>73</b><i>a</i>, the compressing plate <b>77</b> to be driven upward and downward within the dust chamber <b>61</b> according to the rotation of the screw <b>71</b>, and a connecting part <b>78</b> connected to the screw <b>71</b> and the compressing plate <b>77</b> to transmit the rotational force of the screw <b>71</b> to the compressing plate <b>77</b>. The screw <b>71</b> has a thread formed along the half of the length, and an opposite thread formed along the other half of the length. More specifically, and referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the screw <b>71</b> may include a first screw <b>71</b><i>a </i>having a thread along a left half of the length, and a second screw <b>71</b><i>b </i>having a thread opposite to the first screw <b>71</b><i>a </i>along a right half of the length.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The driving part <b>72</b> includes a driving motor <b>73</b> formed adjacent to one side of the screw <b>71</b> to generate a rotational force, a driving axis <b>73</b><i>a </i>driven by the driving motor <b>73</b> and engaged with the screw <b>71</b> in a linear relation, and a rotational force transmitting part <b>74</b> to transmit the rotational force of the driving motor <b>73</b> to the driving axis <b>73</b><i>a</i>. The rotational force transmitting part <b>74</b> includes a driving gear <b>75</b> rotatably driven by the driving motor <b>73</b>, and a driven gear <b>76</b> rotated in mesh with the driving gear <b>75</b> to rotate the screw <b>71</b>. It is desirable that the driven gear <b>76</b> may have a less number of gears than the driving gear <b>75</b>, because by doing so, larger rotational force can be transmitted to the screw <b>71</b> from the same output of the driving motor <b>73</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The compressing plate <b>77</b> may be implemented as a plate of a predetermined thickness, which is configured in conformity with a traverse cross section of the dust chamber <b>61</b>. The compressing plate <b>77</b> operates to compress dust collected inside the dust chamber <b>61</b>, by moving upward and downward within the dust chamber <b>61</b>. First and second driven sliders <b>78</b><i>c</i>, <b>78</b><i>d</i>, and first and second guides <b>77</b><i>a</i>, <b>77</b><i>b </i>to guide the sliding movement of the first and second driven sliders <b>78</b><i>c</i>, <b>78</b><i>d</i>, are mounted on the upper face of the compressing plate <b>77</b>. This will be explained below.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The connecting part <b>78</b> includes first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>sliding opposite to each other according to the rotation of the screw <b>71</b>, the first and second driven sliders <b>78</b><i>c</i>, <b>78</b><i>d </i>positioned right below the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>, and sliding on the upper face of the compressing plate <b>77</b>, a first connecting rod <b>78</b><i>e </i>hinged to the first driving slider <b>78</b><i>a </i>with one end, and hinged to the second driven slider <b>78</b><i>d </i>with the other end, and a second connecting rod <b>78</b><i>f </i>hinged with the second driving slider <b>78</b><i>b </i>with one end, and hinged to the first driven slider <b>78</b><i>c </i>with the other end.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As explained above, the screw <b>71</b> includes the first and second screws <b>71</b><i>a</i>, <b>71</b><i>b</i>, having threads opposite to each other. The first driving slider <b>78</b><i>a </i>is screw-engaged with the first screw <b>71</b><i>a</i>, and the second driving slider <b>78</b><i>b </i>is screw-engaged with the second screw <b>71</b><i>b</i>. Because the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>are engaged with the first and second screws <b>71</b><i>a</i>, <b>71</b><i>b </i>having threads opposite to each other, the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>slide opposite to each other when the screw <b>71</b> is rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The first and second driven sliders <b>78</b><i>c</i>, <b>78</b><i>d </i>are guided by the first and second guides <b>77</b><i>a</i>, <b>77</b><i>b </i>provided at the upper part of the compressing plate <b>77</b>, and slid along the upper face of the compressing plate <b>77</b>. During sliding movement of the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>and the first and second driven sliders <b>78</b><i>c</i>, <b>78</b><i>d</i>, the first driven slider <b>78</b><i>c </i>is positioned right below the first driving slider <b>78</b><i>a</i>, and the second driven slider <b>78</b><i>d </i>is positioned right below the second driving slider <b>78</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The first and second connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f </i>are hinged to each other at a crossing point. As the screw <b>71</b> rotates, an angle between the first and second connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f </i>is varied. In particular, the first and second connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f </i>may be at about 0 degrees when the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>are closest to each other. In this state, the compressing plate <b>77</b> is at the lowermost displacement position. As the screw <b>71</b> rotates the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>away from each other so the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b </i>are spaced apart from each other by a maximum distance, the first and second connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f </i>are at angle about 180 degrees. In this state, the compressing plate <b>77</b> is at an uppermost displacement position.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</figref>, the main cleaner body <b>10</b> may include a wire winding unit <b>80</b> to wind an electric wire C to supply power to the vacuum cleaner <b>1</b>, and a filter cleaning unit <b>90</b> to be transmitted with a rotational force of the wire winding unit <b>80</b> and to remove dust from the filter member <b>41</b> of the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The wire winding unit <b>80</b> includes a cylindrical winding member <b>81</b> around which wire is wrapped, and a winding gear <b>82</b> engaged with an end of the winding member <b>81</b> to be rotated along with the winding member <b>81</b>. In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a wire to supply power for the driving of the vacuum cleaner <b>1</b>, is wrapped around the winding member <b>81</b>. As a user pulls one end of the wire C from the winding member <b>81</b>, the winding member <b>81</b> rotates, and as a result, wire C is released from the winding member <b>81</b>. The winding gear <b>82</b>, engaged with the winding member <b>81</b>, is rotated together with the winding member <b>81</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The filter cleaning unit <b>90</b> includes a cleaning gear <b>92</b> rotated in mesh with the winding gear <b>82</b>, and a cleaning screw <b>91</b> having cleaning ribs <b>91</b><i>a </i>formed on the outer circumference. Accordingly, the cleaning gear <b>92</b>, in mesh with the winding gear <b>82</b>, is rotated together with the winding gear <b>82</b>, as a user releases a wire C from the winding member <b>81</b>. At the same time, the cleaning screw <b>91</b>, in mesh with the cleaning gear <b>92</b>, is rotated together with the cleaning gear <b>92</b>. In the rotating movement of the cleaning screw <b>91</b>, the cleaning ribs <b>91</b><i>a </i>on its outer circumference hit the outer side of the filter member <b>41</b>, and by the impact of the cleaning ribs <b>91</b><i>a </i>on the outer side of the filter member <b>41</b>, dust is removed from the inner side of the filter member <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> may have a separate dust chamber <b>44</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), which is generally smaller in size, to collect the dust removed from the filter member <b>41</b> by the impact of the cleaning ribs <b>91</b><i>a </i>on the outer side of the filter member <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The operation of the vacuum cleaner <b>1</b> constructed above according to the exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure will be explained below, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 to 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates the interior of the cyclone dust separating unit before dust compression, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the interior of the cyclone dust separating unit after dust compression, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates the filter cleaning unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> removing dust from the filter member.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The vacuum cleaner <b>1</b> starts driving, drawing in dust and air from a surface being cleaned through the suction port assembly <b>30</b>. The drawn air passes the extension path <b>20</b>, and is introduced into the main cleaner body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the drawn air in the main cleaner body <b>10</b> flows to the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> within the main cleaner body <b>10</b>. The air has a rotational movement inside the separating chamber <b>51</b> of the cyclone part <b>50</b>. Due to the rotational movement of the drawn air, dust is separated from the air by centrifugal force. The air eventually loses centrifugal force, and escapes the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> through the air outlet <b>43</b> formed at the upper part of the separating chamber <b>51</b>. At this time, the air meets the filter member <b>41</b> mounted on the outer casing <b>45</b> of the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b> at the end of the air outlet <b>43</b>, so that the filter member <b>41</b> filters out remaining dust of the air.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Dust centrifuged at the separating chamber <b>51</b> is introduced into the dust chamber <b>61</b> inside the dust collecting part <b>60</b>, through the opening S formed at the upper end of the wall W. At this time, the compressing plate <b>77</b> provided within the dust chamber <b>61</b> is at its uppermost displacement position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>). A user may drive the driving motor <b>73</b> of the compressing unit <b>70</b>, to compress the dust collected in the dust chamber <b>61</b>. As the driving motor <b>73</b> is operated, the screw <b>71</b>, provided horizontally at the upper side of the dust chamber <b>61</b>, is rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>, which are slidably engaged with the first and second screws <b>71</b><i>a</i>, <b>71</b><i>b</i>, are slid towards each other. Accordingly, an angle (&#x3ba;) decreases between the first and second connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f</i>, which are hinged with the first and second driving sliders <b>78</b><i>a</i>, <b>78</b><i>b</i>. Additionally, the second and the first driven sliders <b>78</b><i>d</i>, <b>78</b><i>c</i>, hinged to the first and second connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f</i>, slide along the upper face of the compressing plate <b>77</b> towards each other, thereby causing the compressing plate <b>77</b> at the upper part of the dust chamber <b>61</b> to be lowered. When the compressing plate <b>77</b> is lowered, dust is compressed in the dust chamber <b>61</b> by the force exerted by the compressing plate <b>77</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As explained above, relatively strong compressing force can be provided by the compressing plate <b>77</b>, by driving the compressing plate <b>77</b> upward and downward through the screw <b>71</b> and the connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f</i>. Because the driving force from the driving motor <b>73</b> is provided through the two connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f</i>, forces of the two connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f </i>are combined and applied to the compressing plate <b>77</b> when the compressing plate <b>77</b> is lowered.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Because the connecting rods <b>78</b><i>e</i>, <b>78</b><i>f </i>are most of times moved within the dust chamber <b>61</b>, the compressing part <b>70</b> to compress dust inside the dust chamber <b>61</b> can be provided to the vacuum cleaner <b>1</b>, with improved space utilization. The above feature is far more advantageous, when compared with a conventional case which moves a bar type plunger vertically engaged with the compressing plate <b>77</b> upward and downward to compress the dust. In particular, the plunger is impossible to move out of the dust chamber <b>61</b>, while maintaining the same displacement as that of the compressing plate <b>77</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">Meanwhile, dust may be removed from the inner side of the filter member <b>41</b>, before the vacuum cleaner <b>1</b> is driven. The winding member <b>81</b> and the winding gear <b>82</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) are rotated together, when the wire C (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) is released from the winding member <b>81</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and in this situation, the cleaning gear <b>92</b> is rotated in mesh with the winding gear <b>82</b>. Accordingly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the cleaning screw <b>91</b> engaged with the cleaning gear <b>92</b> is rotated, so that the cleaning ribs <b>91</b><i>a </i>formed on the outer circumference of the cleaning screw <b>91</b> hit the outer surface of the filter member <b>41</b>. Dust is removed from the inner side of the filter member <b>41</b> by hitting the outer surface of the filter member <b>41</b> with the cleaning ribs <b>91</b><i>a</i>, and dropped and collected in the smaller dust chamber <b>44</b> provided within the cyclone dust separating unit <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As explained above, by providing the cleaning screw <b>91</b> which automatically removes dust from the filter member <b>41</b> in association with the movement of the winding member <b>81</b> to release the wire C, user inconvenience of having to remove dust from the filter member <b>41</b> manually, is prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As explained above, according to the exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure, a vacuum cleaner is provided, which requires a small space for the installation of a compressing part to compress dust inside the dust collecting part, and provides a strong compressing force of the compressing part.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Furthermore, a vacuum cleaner is provided, which automatically removes dust from the filter member in association with the movement to release an electric wire, and which accordingly save user inconvenience of having to remove dust manually.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The foregoing embodiments are merely exemplary and are not to be construed as limiting the present disclosure. The present teaching can be readily applied to other types of apparatuses. Also, the description of the exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure is intended to be illustrative, and not to limit the scope of the claims, and many alternatives, modifications, and variations will be apparent to those skilled in the art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A vacuum cleaner, comprising:
<claim-text>a cyclone dust separating unit comprising,
<claim-text>a cyclone part to separate dust from dust-laden air drawn from a surface being cleaned using a centrifugal force,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a dust collecting part comprising a dust chamber to accommodate the dust separated at the cyclone part, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a compressing part to compress the dust accommodated in the dust chamber, the compressing part comprising,
<claim-text>a screw that is substantially horizontally arranged at the upper part of the dust collecting part, and comprises a first thread formed in one direction and a second thread formed opposite to the first thread with reference to a middle of a length of the screw;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving part to rotatably drive the screw, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a compressing plate driven in a substantially perpendicular direction with respect to the screw according to the rotation of the driving screw, and to compress the dust accommodated in the dust chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the compressing part further comprises:
<claim-text>a connecting part engaged with the screw and the compressing plate, respectively, to transmit rotational force of the screw to the compressing plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting part comprises:
<claim-text>a first driving slider and a second driving slider engaged with the first thread and the second thread of opposite directions of the screw, respectively, to slide towards or away from each other according to a rotation of the screw;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first driven slider positioned right below a first driving slider and a second driven slider positioned right below a second driving slider and the first driven slider and the second driven slider are configured to slide along an upper face of the compressing plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first connecting rod hinged with the first driving slider with one end and hinged with the second driven slider with the other end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connecting rod hinged with the second driving slider with one end, and hinged with the first driven slider with the other end.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first connecting rod and the second connecting rod are hinged with each other at a point crossing each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein a first guide and a second guide are provided on the upper face of the compressing plate to guide sliding movement of the first driven slider and the second driven slider.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the driving part comprises:
<claim-text>a driving motor to generate a rotational force and rotatably drive the screw; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotation force transmitting part to transmit rotational force of the driving motor to the screw.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the rotation force transmitting part comprises:
<claim-text>a driving gear rotatably driven by the driving motor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driven gear rotated in mesh with the driving gear, to drive the screw, and wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the driven gear comprises a smaller number of teeth than the driving gear.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cyclone part and the dust collecting part are arranged in adjacent to one another, and each shares one common wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the wall is open at an upper end to allow dust separated at the cyclone part to flow therethrough into the dust collecting part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cyclone dust separating unit further comprises:
<claim-text>a filter member mounted on an outer casing of the cyclone dust separating unit, to filter remaining dust from air being discharged from the cyclone dust separating unit after the dust is separated at the cyclone part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a wire winding unit around which an electric wire is wound, to externally supply power into the vacuum cleaner; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filter cleaning unit rotated by a rotation force being provided from the wire winding unit when the electric wire is released from the wire winding unit, to remove dust from the filter member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the wire winding unit comprises:
<claim-text>a winding member of a substantially cylindrical configuration, around which the electric wire is wound; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a winding gear engaged with an end of the winding member, and rotated along with the winding member, and wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the filter cleaning unit comprises,
<claim-text>a cleaning screw comprising a cleaning rib in a substantially spiral configuration to remove dust from the filter member in contact with an outer circumference of the filter member, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cleaning gear engaged with one end of the cleaning screw and rotated in mesh with the winding gear, to rotatably drive the cleaning gear.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The vacuum cleaner of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the cyclone dust separating unit further comprises a smaller dust chamber to accommodate the dust removed from the filter member by the cleaning screw. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
