<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640844-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640844</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11784225</doc-number>
<date>20070406</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99299</main-classification>
<further-classification> 99304</further-classification>
<further-classification> 99307</further-classification>
<further-classification> 99313</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Coffee machine with improved coffee outlet</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2451195</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brown</name>
<date>19481000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 99295</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4064795</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ackerman</name>
<date>19771200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 99304</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5711207</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wu</name>
<date>19980100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 99307</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5964143</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Driscoll et al.</name>
<date>19991000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 99299</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6543335</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lassota</name>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 99283</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>695183</doc-number>
<kind>A5</kind>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99275-277</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99279-307</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99323</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99452</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99495</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 99308-322</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070251395</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071101</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Mingchia</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tan Zi Hsiang</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Kuohsun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ren Teh Hsiang</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Shengfang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Anding Hsiang</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rabin &#x26; Berdo, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsann Kuen (China) Enterprise Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Fujian</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Simone</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy F.</first-name>
<department>3742</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A coffee machine includes: a base, a basal body locating above the base, a coffee pot located above the basal body, a first coffee exit located in the bottom of the coffee pot, a coffee outlet located under the first coffee exit, the coffee outlet includes a receiving water base, a top lid; a first pin joint part and a second pin joint part respectively located at both sides of the first coffee exit, one end of the receiving water base pivotally joins the first pin joint part, another end of the receiving water base extends to the second pin joint part and outside of the bottom of the coffee pot, a second coffee exit is beside the another end of the receiving water base, a third pin joint part is between the second coffee exit and the second pin joint part.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="165.78mm" wi="145.71mm" file="US07640844-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="175.60mm" wi="152.74mm" file="US07640844-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="130.39mm" wi="135.38mm" file="US07640844-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="187.37mm" wi="139.19mm" file="US07640844-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="222.08mm" wi="154.94mm" file="US07640844-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The utility model relates to a coffee machine, concretely to a coffee machine with improved coffee outlet.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF TECHNOLOGY</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Known coffee machine comprises a base, a basal body and a coffee pot, the basal body locates above one side of the base, the coffee pot locates at the side of the upside of the basal body, and the coffee pot and another side of the base correspond up and down, namely, the room for placing the coffee cup forms between the coffee pot and the another side of the base, so the coffee in the coffee pot dribbles into the coffee cup. Coffee bag with coffee powder sets in the coffee pot, the basal body also includes a hot-water heater and a water pump for driving the hot-water to the coffee pot, the coffee exit locates at the downside of the coffee pot, when the coffee cup set under the coffee pot to open the valve, the coffee will effuse from the coffee pot.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Above coffee machine has biggish limitation in the structure design, it can't break through the limitation of the coffee pot being above the coffee cup, which occupies biggish room. In addition, when the coffee cup is taken away from the coffee machine, although the valve is closed, but because it has some distance between the valve and the coffee exit, it also has some coffee between the valve and the coffee exit, consequently, it will cause the unnecessary waste and is inconvenient in use.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present utility model provides a coffee machine with an improved coffee outlet to break through the limitation of the coffee pot being above the coffee cup or carafe and make the coffee machine have an alterable structure to economize the size of the coffee machine for storage purposes. Another purpose of the utility model is to overcome the disadvantages of known coffee machines which waste coffee and are inconvenient to use.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present utility model adopts the technical proposal as follows: a coffee machine with improved coffee outlet, comprising a base, a basal body locating above the base, a coffee pot locating above the basal body, a first coffee exit locates in the bottom of the coffee pot, the coffee outlet locates under the first coffee exit, the coffee outlet comprises a receiving water base, a top lid, a hinge; a first pin joint part and a second pin joint part respectively locate at both sides of the first coffee exit, one end of the receiving water base pivotally joins with the first pin joint part, another end of the receiving water base extends to the second pin joint part and outside of the bottom of the coffee pot, a second coffee exit locates beside the another end of the receiving water base, the top lid covers the rest parts of the receiving water part other than the parts under the bottom of the coffee pot; a third pin joint part locates between the second coffee exit and the second pin joint part, one end of the hinge pivotally joins with the second pin joint part, the middle position of the hinge pivotally joins with the third pin joint part, another end of the hinge extends above the second coffee exit; a pole piece locates at the receiving water base and drills through the first coffee exit, the pole piece includes a first obturation piece tightly tipping the first coffee exit, the hinge includes a second obturation piece tightly tipping the second coffee exit; a compression spring locates between the coffee pot and the receiving water base.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">As a rule, in the effect of the elasticity of the compression spring, when the coffee outlet arrives at its lowest position, here the first obturation piece tightly tips the first coffee exit to make it close, on account of lever principle, the second obturation piece of the hinge tightly tips the second coffee exit to make it close, consequently, even if the coffee outlet has a little coffee, it will not effuse when the coffee cup is taken away; by contraries, when the coffee cup placed under the coffee outlet, the coffee cup overcomes the elasticity of the compression spring, the coffee cup tips the coffee outlet to make the first coffee exit and the second coffee exit open, so the coffee in the coffee pot inpours into the coffee cup through the coffee outlet.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Above coffee machine with improved coffee outlet wherein the first coffee exit protrudes downwards to form a round platform, the receiving water base includes several orientation pieces around the pole piece; the upside of the compression spring covers the exterior of the round platform, the downside of the compression spring is positioned by the orientation pieces.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Above coffee machine with improved coffee outlet wherein the coffee pot wedges into the upside of the basal body, the coffee outlet protrudes outside of the basal body, the base extends outward to form a pedestal for placing coffee cup underneath the coffee outlet, a placement space for coffee cup forms between the pedestal for placing coffee cup and the coffee outlet. Thus it can be seen, the coffee pot is not above the coffee cup but wedges into the basal body, merely one part of the coffee outlet protrudes outside of the basal body, which breaks through the localization of the conventional coffee machine and economizes the room of the coffee pot occupying.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Above coffee machine with improved coffee outlet wherein an overflow orifice locates above the receiving water base, the circumference of the overflow orifice forms a overflow room segregating with other parts of the coffee pot by a circle wall, the height of the circle wall is lower than the height of the coffee pot, when the height of the coffee in the coffee pot is higher than the circle wall, the coffee will effuses from the overflow orifice.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Above coffee machine with improved coffee outlet wherein the receiving water base includes a circle wall protruding upwards, the circle wall surrounds the second coffee exit and the pole piece, the part of the receiving water base in the circle wall forms a coffee launder.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present utility model has virtues as follows comparing with known technology: firstly, it breaks through the localization of the coffee pot being above the coffee cup, to make the coffee machine has alterable structure, to economize the room of the coffee machine occupying; Secondly, when the coffee cup is taken away from the underside of the coffee outlet, there will be no remnants coffee effuses from the coffee outlet, to accord with the require of economy and environmental protection.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a stereogram of the present utility model;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a stereogram of the coffee pot and the coffee outlet;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of the coffee pot and the coffee outlet;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cutaway view of the coffee pot and the coffee outlet, which shows the opposition of the coffee outlet; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cutaway view of the coffee pot and the coffee outlet, which shows the open position of the coffee outlet.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>, we will expound the embodiment of the present utility model.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the coffee machine with improved coffee outlet, comprising a base <b>1</b>, a basal body <b>2</b> locating above the base <b>1</b>, a coffee pot <b>6</b> locating above the basal body <b>2</b>, a coffee outlet <b>4</b> being below the coffee pot <b>6</b> and extending outside of one side of the coffee pot <b>6</b>. The coffee pot <b>6</b> wedges into the upside of the basal body <b>2</b>, the basal body <b>2</b> includes a lid <b>3</b> which covers the coffee pot <b>6</b>. The coffee outlet <b>4</b> protrudes outside of the basal body <b>2</b>, the base <b>1</b> extends outward to form a pedestal <b>11</b> for placing coffee cup underneath the coffee outlet <b>4</b>, a placement space for coffee cup forms between the pedestal <b>11</b> for placing coffee cup and the coffee outlet <b>4</b>, when the coffee cup <b>5</b> is placed in the placement space, the top of the coffee cup <b>5</b> jacks up the coffee outlet <b>4</b> to make the coffee outlet turn on so that the coffee inpours into the coffee cup <b>5</b> from the coffee pot <b>6</b>. The basal body <b>2</b> also includes a hot-water heater and a water pump for driving the hot-water to the coffee pot <b>6</b>, which is known technology, we do not expound here.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, a first coffee exit <b>60</b> locates in the bottom of the coffee pot <b>6</b>, the coffee outlet <b>4</b> locates under the first coffee exit <b>60</b>. The coffee outlet <b>4</b> comprises a receiving water base <b>41</b>, a top lid <b>42</b>, a hinge <b>43</b>; a first pin joint part <b>61</b> and a second pin joint part <b>62</b> respectively locate at both sides of the first coffee exit <b>60</b>, one end of the receiving water base <b>41</b> pivotally joins with the first pin joint part <b>61</b>, another end of the receiving water base <b>41</b> extends to the second pin joint part <b>62</b> and outside of the bottom of the coffee pot <b>6</b>, a second coffee exit <b>410</b> locates beside the another end of the receiving water base <b>41</b>, the top lid <b>42</b> covers the rest parts of the receiving water part <b>41</b> other than the parts under the bottom of the coffee pot <b>6</b>; a third pin joint part <b>44</b> locates between the second coffee exit <b>410</b> and the second pin joint part <b>62</b>, one end of the hinge <b>43</b> pivotally joins with the second pin joint part <b>62</b>, the middle position of the hinge <b>43</b> pivotally joins with the third pin joint part <b>44</b>, another end of the hinge <b>43</b> extends above the second coffee exit <b>410</b>; a pole piece <b>45</b> locates at the receiving water base <b>41</b> and drills through the first coffee exit <b>60</b>, the pole piece <b>45</b> includes a first obturation piece <b>451</b> tightly tipping the first coffee exit <b>60</b>, the hinge <b>43</b> includes a second obturation piece <b>431</b> tightly tipping the second coffee exit <b>410</b>, a compression spring <b>452</b> locates between the coffee pot <b>6</b> and the receiving water base <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the first coffee exit <b>60</b> protrudes downwards to form a round platform <b>601</b>, the receiving water base <b>41</b> includes three orientation pieces <b>453</b> around the pole piece <b>45</b>; the upside of the compression spring <b>452</b> covers the exterior of the round platform <b>601</b>, the downside of the compression spring <b>452</b> is positioned by the orientation pieces <b>453</b>. The receiving water base <b>41</b> includes a circle wall <b>46</b> protruding upwards, the circle wall <b>46</b> surrounds the second coffee exit <b>410</b> and the pole piece <b>45</b>, the part of the receiving water base <b>41</b> in the circle wall <b>46</b> forms a coffee launder. An overflow orifice <b>630</b> locates at one side of the bottom of the coffee pot <b>6</b>, the overflow orifice <b>630</b> locates above the receiving water base <b>41</b>, the circumference of the overflow orifice <b>630</b> forms a overflow room segregating with other parts of the coffee pot <b>6</b> by a circle wall <b>63</b>, the height of the circle wall <b>63</b> is lower than the height of the coffee pot <b>6</b>. When the height of the coffee in the coffee pot <b>6</b> is higher than the height of the circle wall <b>63</b>, the coffee will flow to the coffee outlet <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, when the coffee outlet <b>4</b> arrives at its lowest position the first obturation piece <b>45</b> tightly tips the first coffee exit <b>60</b> to make it close, on account of a lever principle, the second obturation piece <b>431</b> of the hinge <b>43</b> tightly tips the second coffee exit to make it close, consequently, even if the coffee outlet <b>4</b> has a little coffee, it will not effuse when the coffee cup <b>5</b> is taken away. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, when the coffee cup or carafe <b>5</b> placed under the coffee outlet <b>4</b>, the coffee cup <b>5</b> overcomes the elasticity of the compression spring <b>452</b>, the coffee cup <b>5</b> tips the coffee outlet <b>4</b> to make the first coffee exit <b>60</b> and the second coffee exit <b>410</b> open, so the coffee in the coffee pot <b>6</b> inpours into the coffee cup <b>5</b> through the coffee outlet <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">While the present utility model has been described in connection with what is considered the most practical and preferred embodiment, it is understood that present utility model is not limited to the disclosed embodiment but is intended to cover various arrangements included within the spirit and scope of the broadest interpretation so as to encompass all such modifications and equivalent arrangements.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A coffee machine with an improved coffee outlet, comprising:
<claim-text>a base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a basal body located above the base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coffee pot located above the basal body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first coffee exit located in a bottom of the coffee pot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coffee outlet located under the first coffee exit, the coffee outlet including a receiving water base, a top lid, and a hinge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first pin joint part and a second pin joint part are respectively located at both sides of the first coffee exit, one end of the receiving water base pivotally joins the first pin joint part, another end of the receiving water base extends to the second pin joint part and outside of the bottom of the coffee pot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second coffee exit is located beside the another end of the receiving water base, the top lid covers remaining parts of the receiving water base other than parts under a bottom of the coffee pot;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third pin joint part is located between the second coffee exit and the second pin joint part, one end of the hinge is pivotally joined with the second pin joint part, a middle position of the hinge is pivotally joined with the third pin joint part, another end of the hinge extends above the second coffee exit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pole piece is located at the receiving water base and extends through the first coffee exit, the pole piece includes a first obturation piece tightly tipping the first coffee exit, the hinge includes a second obturation piece tightly tipping the second coffee exit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a compression spring is located between the coffee pot and the receiving water base so that coffee flows from said first coffee exit and said second coffee exit only when a cu is placed under and engages the coffee outlet, said engagement of said cup with the coffee outlet simultaneously actuating said second obturation piece away from said second coffee exit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The coffee machine with an improved coffee outlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first coffee exit protrudes downwards to form a round platform, the receiving water base includes several orientation pieces around the pole piece; an upside of the compression spring covers the exterior of the round platform, a downside of the compression spring is positioned by the orientation pieces.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The coffee machine with an improved coffee outlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said coffee pot wedges into an upside of the basal body, the coffee outlet protrudes outside of the basal body, the base extends outward to form a pedestal for placing coffee cup underneath the coffee outlet, a placement space for coffee cup is formed between the pedestal for placing the coffee cup and the coffee outlet.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The coffee machine with an improved coffee outlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an overflow orifice is located above the receiving water base, a circumference of the overflow orifice forms an overflow room segregated with other parts of the coffee pot by a circular wall, the height of the circular wall is lower than the height of the coffee pot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The coffee machine with an improved coffee outlet according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said receiving water base includes a circular wall protruding upwards, the circular wall surrounds the second coffee exit and the pole piece, wherein a part of the receiving water base in the circular wall forms a coffee launder. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
