<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641102-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641102</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11442717</doc-number>
<date>20060530</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>653</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>45</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>232  1D</main-classification>
<further-classification>109 10</further-classification>
<further-classification>312137</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Private viewing case for I.D. cards and the like</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1568356</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vumbaca</name>
<date>19260100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>109 11</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4351247</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>19820900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4517901</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>19850500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5205224</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Durst</name>
<date>19930400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>D344841</doc-number>
<kind>S</kind>
<name>Rogers et al.</name>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5615624</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Terry et al.</name>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5799589</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6262843</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Marx</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359501</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6552850</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Dudasik</name>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>359501</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>232  1 D</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>232  1 E</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>232 19</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>232 431</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>232 44</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>109  5</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>109 10</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>109 11</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>109 19</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>109 66- 68</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>220476</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>220480</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3121401</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3121402</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>3122491</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>312137</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>312114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>211 42</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Alexander-Ramsey</last-name>
<first-name>Jonille</first-name>
<address>
<street>1613 Red Oak Trail</street>
<city>Anna</city>
<state>TX</state>
<postcode>75409</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Miller</last-name>
<first-name>William L.</first-name>
<department>3677</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A private viewing case includes a rear wall that extends upward from a support surface and has an orthogonally extending bottom flange formed therewith that is removably fastened to the support surface. First and second coextensive stabilizing arms have a rear end attached to oppositely seated top rear wall edges and are orthogonally registered therewith. First and second privacy panels are abutted to exterior sides of the stabilizing arms and extend downwardly therefrom in such a manner that an inner space defined therebetween, and have rear edges adjoining the rear wall. A dome-shaped top cover is pivotally connected to the rear wall, has a front edge traversing between the stabilizing arms, and includes a polarizing filter that eliminates light from passing therethrough, preventing bystanders from seeing through the cover. The user's card is seated beneath the top cover and between the privacy panels thus prohibiting bystanders from acquiring sight thereof.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="174.67mm" wi="192.11mm" file="US07641102-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="189.15mm" wi="193.55mm" file="US07641102-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="208.03mm" wi="193.04mm" file="US07641102-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="194.99mm" wi="185.25mm" file="US07641102-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="241.22mm" wi="146.81mm" file="US07641102-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="186.44mm" wi="185.42mm" file="US07641102-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Not Applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH OR DEVELOPMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not Applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">REFERENCE TO A MICROFICHE APPENDIX</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Not Applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">This invention relates to viewing cases and, more particularly, to a private viewing case for I.D. cards and the like for assisting a non-user to privately view and verify data printed on a user card.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">2. Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In recent years the fear of identity theft among the general population has increased as the occurrence of such theft has significantly increased as well. Typically, identity theft occurs when a criminal obtains a person's personal information, like their social security number and full name. The lawbreaker then uses this information to acquire credit cards in the name of the person whose information they have stolen and makes significant charges thereto. However, the criminal does not use the true person's address, but rather has the credit card bill sent to some other address. Thus, unless the person frequently checks their credit record, they will have no idea that purchases are being made in their name and are being added to their credit history.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Since these illegal purchases are never paid for by the criminals, the credit score, also known as the Fair Isaac Corporation (FICO) score, of the person whose identity was stolen suffers from these unpaid purchases. When the victim subsequently wishes to purchase a house, car or other item that requires a large loan, they will find that lenders will not give them a loan because of their seemingly poor credit history. It can take years for an unsuspecting identity theft victim to correct and overcome the damage caused by this heinous, but sickeningly common, crime. Many steps have been taken to lessen criminals' opportunities to illegally acquire a person's personal information. Generally, these steps have focused on electronic methods of stopping identity theft over the internet.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">On a daily basis, though, a person can display their credit and debit cards several times in public. These cards have account numbers on them that criminals can use to gain access to their private information, or to make on-line purchases. Certain steps have been taken in the prior art to prevent this from happening by introducing card holder devices that blocks an unauthorized person line of sight of the credit or debit card.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">One prior art example shows a card holder in the form of a shell or shield that has juxtaposed layers forming a slot or pocket into which a card is inserted. The pocket is made of relatively stiff plastic that resiliently resists flexure whereby a yielding friction grip is imposed upon the card inserted therein. The shell or shield has sides and an overhanging top that combined effectively shields the card from all but frontal view. Unfortunately, this example provide no convenient means for attaching the assembly to a counter top or similar surface, thus requiring a user to hold it in their hands or lay it flat on a support surface. When holding the assembly, the person may find it difficult to perform other tasks, and when laying the assembly flat the purpose thereof is defeated since the card held therein can then easily be viewed from afar.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Accordingly, a need remains for a private viewing case for I.D. cards and the like in order to overcome the above-noted shortcomings. The present invention satisfies such a need by providing a private viewing case that is convenient and easy to use, is durable yet lightweight in design, is conveniently portable between remote locations, and effectively prevents unauthorized persons from viewing the card held therein. Such a viewing case is conveniently attached to transaction counters and allows a transaction clerk to view a current customer's I.D., credit and/or debit card, while effectively preventing others in the immediate area from viewing the card. By attaching the assembly in an upright fashion to the counter, the transaction clerk advantageously retains the use of both hands for other tasks like using a register or writing down certain information from the card or cards.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In view of the foregoing background, it is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a private viewing case for I.D. cards and the like. These and other objects, features, and advantages of the invention are provided by a private viewing case for advantageously assisting a non-user to privately view and verify data printed on a user card.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The private viewing case includes a rear wall that has a planar outer surface vertically extending upwardly from a support surface. Such a rear wall further has a bottom flange monolithically formed therewith and registered orthogonal to a vertical plane. The bottom flange is securely fastened directly to the support surface such that the rear wall is conveniently statically anchored during operating conditions. Such a rear wall is removably connected to the support surface.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">First and second stabilizing arms have linear longitudinal lengths and coextensive shapes. Each of the first and second stabilizing arms has a rear end removably attached directly to oppositely seated top edges of the rear wall. Such first and second stabilizing arms are orthogonally registered with the rear wall and terminate forward thereof such that the first and second stabilizing arms are effectively disposed coplanar to each other. Each of the first and second stabilizing arms may be provided with a guide slot formed along the respective linear lengths thereof. The first and second stabilizing arms may further be independently detachable from the rear wall such that only one of the first and second stabilizing arms is attached to the rear wall during viewing conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">First and second privacy panels are removably abutted directly to exterior sides of the first and second stabilizing arms. Such first and second privacy panels extend downwardly from the first and second stabilizing arms and terminate at the ground surface in such a manner that an inner space defined between the first and second panels is advantageously and effectively invisible to bystanders. The first and second privacy panels have rear edges adjoining the rear wall. Each of the privacy panels is preferably vertically positioned along the first and second stabilizing arms such that the first and second privacy panels become interlocked therewith and maintained along the vertical plane during viewing conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A top cover has a linear rear edge pivotally connected directly to a top edge of the rear wall. Such a top cover has a dome shape and is provided with a linear front edge that traverses between the first and second stabilizing arms in such a manner that the top cover rests directly on the first and second stabilizing arms when articulated to a lowered position. The top cover preferably remains stationary when the first and second privacy panels are detached from the first and second stabilizing arms respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Such a top cover includes a polarizing filter that advantageously and effectively eliminates ambient light from passing through the top cover and conveniently prevents bystanders from maintaining a direct line of sight through the top cover. The user's card is removably seated beneath the top cover and between the first and second privacy panels so that the non-user can view the contents of the user's card while advantageously prohibiting bystanders from maintaining a clear line of sight to the user card.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The assembly may further include a non-linear support leg connected to an interior of the rear wall. Such a support leg extends forwardly from the rear wall and has an upwardly tapered front lip for conveniently maintaining the user card rearwardly tilted and supported against the rear wall during viewing operations. The support leg is elevated above the support surface. The interior of the rear wall is preferably further provided with a rearwardly stepped shoulder obliquely offset from the vertical plane. Such a shoulder slopes rearwardly towards an exterior of the rear wall for effectively allowing the user card to lie along a rearwardly sloping plane during viewing operations.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">There has thus been outlined, rather broadly, the more important features of the invention in order that the detailed description thereof that follows may be better understood, and in order that the present contribution to the art may be better appreciated. There are additional features of the invention that will be described hereinafter and which will form the subject matter of the claims appended hereto.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">It is noted the purpose of the foregoing abstract is to enable the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office and the public generally, especially the scientists, engineers and practitioners in the art who are not familiar with patent or legal terms or phraseology, to determine quickly from a cursory inspection the nature and essence of the technical disclosure of the application. The abstract is neither intended to define the invention of the application, which is measured by the claims, nor is it intended to be limiting as to the scope of the invention in any way.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The novel features believed to be characteristic of this invention are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The invention itself, however, both as to its organization and method of operation, together with further objects and advantages thereof, may best be understood by reference to the following description taken in connection with the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front perspective view showing a private viewing case for I.D. cards and the like, in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a rear perspective view of the assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side-elevational view of the assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, viewed along line <b>3</b>-<b>3</b>;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top plan view of the assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, taken along line <b>5</b>-<b>5</b>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The present invention will now be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which a preferred embodiment of the invention is shown. This invention may, however, be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiment set forth herein. Rather, this embodiment is provided so that this application will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the true scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout the figures.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The assembly of this invention is referred to generally in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> by the reference numeral <b>10</b> and is intended to provide a private viewing case for I.D. cards and the like. It should be understood that the assembly <b>10</b> may be used for the private viewing of many different types of items and should not be limited in use to only viewing I.D. cards.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Initially referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> and <b>5</b>, the assembly <b>10</b> includes a rear wall <b>20</b> that has a planar outer surface <b>21</b> vertically extending upwardly from a support surface <b>11</b>. Such a rear wall <b>20</b> further has a bottom flange <b>22</b> monolithically formed therewith and registered orthogonal to a vertical plane. The bottom flange <b>22</b> is securely fastened directly, without the use of intervening elements, to the support surface <b>11</b>, which is essential such that the rear wall <b>20</b> is conveniently statically anchored during operating conditions. Such a rear wall <b>20</b> is removably connected to the support surface <b>11</b>, which is an important feature for allowing the assembly <b>10</b> to quickly and easily be transferred between remotely located support surfaces <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b> and <b>5</b>, first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms have linear longitudinal lengths and coextensive shapes. Each of the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms has a rear end <b>31</b> removably attached directly, without the use of intervening elements, to oppositely seated top edges <b>23</b> of the rear wall <b>20</b>. Such first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms are orthogonally registered with the rear wall <b>20</b> and terminate forward thereof such that the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms are effectively disposed coplanar to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Each of the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms is provided with a guide slot <b>32</b> formed along the respective linear lengths thereof. Such first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms are further independently detachable from the rear wall <b>20</b> such that only one of the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms is attached to the rear wall <b>20</b> during viewing conditions. This is a crucial feature for allowing the assembly <b>10</b> to conveniently and easily be adjusted for use by left- and right-handed users, without having to detach the rear wall from <b>20</b> from the support surface.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b> and <b>5</b>, first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B privacy panels are removably abutted directly, without the use of intervening elements, to exterior sides <b>33</b> of the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms. Such first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B privacy panels extend downwardly from the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms and terminate at the ground surface in, which is vital such that an inner space <b>41</b> defined between the first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B panels is advantageously and effectively invisible to bystanders. The first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B privacy panels have rear edges <b>42</b> adjoining the rear wall <b>20</b>. Each of the privacy panels <b>40</b> is vertically positioned along the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms such that the first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B privacy panels become interlocked therewith and maintained along the vertical plane during viewing conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>, <b>4</b> and <b>5</b>, a top cover <b>50</b> has a linear rear edge <b>51</b> pivotally connected directly, without the use of intervening elements, to a top edge <b>23</b> of the rear wall <b>20</b>. Such a top cover <b>50</b> has a dome shape and is provided with a linear front edge <b>52</b> that traverses between the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms in such a manner that the top cover <b>50</b> rests directly, without the use of intervening elements, on the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms when articulated to a lowered position. The top cover <b>50</b> remains stationary when the first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B privacy panels are detached from the first <b>30</b>A and second <b>30</b>B stabilizing arms respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Again referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</figref>, such a top cover <b>50</b> includes a polarizing filter <b>53</b> that is vital for advantageously and effectively eliminating ambient light from passing through the top cover <b>50</b> and conveniently prevents bystanders from maintaining a direct line of sight through the top cover <b>50</b>. The user's card <b>12</b> is removably seated beneath the top cover <b>50</b> and between the first <b>40</b>A and second <b>40</b>B privacy panels, which is crucial so that the non-user can view the contents of the user's card <b>12</b> while advantageously prohibiting bystanders from maintaining a clear line of sight to the user's card <b>12</b>. The polarizing filter <b>53</b> may be purchased from 3M, Inc. Such polarizing filters may be after-market, clip-on attachments that are coupled to the interior or exterior of the top panel. Suitable polarizing filters may also be purchased from Ergonomic Supply, Inc. (1-888-493-9161).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>3</b> and <b>5</b>, the assembly <b>10</b> further includes a non-linear support leg <b>24</b> directly connected, without the use of intervening elements, to an interior <b>25</b> of the rear wall <b>20</b>. Such a support leg <b>24</b> extends forwardly from the rear wall <b>20</b> and has an upwardly tapered front lip <b>26</b> that is critical for conveniently maintaining the user's card <b>12</b> rearwardly tilted and supported against the rear wall <b>20</b> during viewing operations. The support leg <b>24</b> is elevated above the support surface <b>11</b>. The interior <b>25</b> of the rear wall <b>20</b> is further provided with a rearwardly stepped shoulder <b>27</b> obliquely offset from the vertical plane. Such a shoulder <b>27</b> slopes rearwardly towards an exterior of the rear wall <b>20</b> and is important for effectively allowing the user's card to lie along a rearwardly sloping plane during viewing operations so that the non-user is conveniently and effectively able to view the card <b>12</b> in a hands-free manner.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In use, the assembly is attached to the checkout counters of retail stores or any other type of business establishment in which consumers must share any form of their identity information with the employee. These identity information includes, but is not limited too, money orders, cashiers checks, bank checks, drivers licenses, credit cards, and insurance or social security cards. The assembly also helps business establishments to show concern for their patron by taking steps towards the prevention of identity theft, which has become one of the most frequent and costliest crimes against consumers and companies in the U.S.A. and the worldwide. For example, a consumer enters a grocery store to purchase some items and brings those items to the cashier in order to checkout.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As the items are scanned, other persons get in line behind the consumer to have their items scanned as well. The customer chooses to pay by check, and must present their driver's license to the cashier to verify their information. Generally, most cashiers do not take safety precautions in these situations, and simply lay the driver's license in plain sight for all surrounding persons to see.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">During this time the next person behind the initial consumer can easily memorize or inconspicuously write down the personal information contained on the driver's license. If employers use the assembly <b>10</b>, in conjunction with extensive identity theft training of their employees, the occurrence of such chance identity theft can be greatly reduced. Furthermore, when consumers realize that a certain establishment is actively trying to protect their identity while shopping there, they are more likely to return for follow-up business.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">While the invention has been described with respect to a certain specific embodiment, it will be appreciated that many modifications and changes may be made by those skilled in the art without departing from the spirit of the invention. It is intended, therefore, by the appended claims to cover all such modifications and changes as fall within the true spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In particular, with respect to the above description, it is to be realized that the optimum dimensional relationships for the parts of the present invention may include variations in size, materials, shape, form, function and manner of operation. The assembly and use of the present invention are deemed readily apparent and obvious to one skilled in the art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed as new and what is desired to secure by Letters Patent of the United States is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A private viewing case for assisting a non-user to privately view and verify data printed on a user card, said private viewing case comprising:
<claim-text>a rear wall having a planar outer surface vertically extending upwardly from a support surface, said rear wall further having a bottom flange monolithically formed therewith and registered orthogonal to a vertical plane, said bottom flange being securely fastened directly to the support surface such that said rear wall is statically anchored during operating conditions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second stabilizing arms having linear longitudinal lengths and the same dimensions, each of said first and second stabilizing arms having rear ends removably attached directly to opposite ends of a top edge of said rear wall, said first and second stabilizing arms being orthogonally registered with said rear wall and terminating forward thereof such that said first and second stabilizing arms are disposed coplanar to each other;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second privacy panels removably abutted directly to exterior sides of said first and second stabilizing arms, said first and second privacy panels extending downwardly from said first and second stabilizing arms and terminating at the ground surface in such a manner that an inner space defined between said first and second panels is invisible to bystanders, said first and second privacy panels having rear edges adjoining said rear wall; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top cover having a linear rear edge pivotally connected directly to said top edge of said rear wall, said top cover having a dome shape and being provided with a linear front edge traversing between said first and second stabilizing arms in such a manner that said top cover rests directly on said first and second stabilizing arms when articulated to a lowered position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the user card is removably seated beneath said top cover and between said first and second privacy panels whereby the non-user can view the contents of the user card while prohibiting bystanders from maintaining a clear line of sight to the user card.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of said first and second stabilizing arms is provided with a guide slot formed along the respective linear lengths thereof, each of said privacy panels being vertically positioned along said first and second stabilizing arms such that said first and second privacy panels become interlocked therewith and maintained along the vertical plane during viewing conditions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a non-linear support leg connected to an interior of said rear wall, said support leg extending forwardly from said rear wall and having an upwardly tapered front lip for maintaining the user card rearwardly tilted and supported against said rear wall during viewing operations, said support leg being elevated above the support surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said interior of said rear wall is provided with a rearwardly stepped shoulder obliquely offset from the vertical plane, said shoulder sloping rearwardly towards an exterior of said rear wall for allowing the user card to lay along a rearwardly sloping plane during viewing operations.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said top cover remains stationary when said first and second privacy panels are detached from said first and second stabilizing arms respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second stabilizing arms are independently detachable from said rear wall such that only one of said first and second stabilizing arms are attached to said rear wall during viewing conditions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A private viewing case for assisting a non-user to privately view and verify data printed on a user card, said private viewing case comprising:
<claim-text>a rear wall having a planar outer surface vertically extending upwardly from a support surface, said rear wall further having a bottom flange monolithically formed therewith and registered orthogonal to a vertical plane, said bottom flange being securely fastened directly to the support surface such that said rear wall is statically anchored during operating conditions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second stabilizing arms having linear longitudinal lengths and the same dimensions, each of said first and second stabilizing arms having rear ends removably attached directly to opposite ends of a top edge of said rear wall, said first and second stabilizing arms being orthogonally registered with said rear wall and terminating forward thereof such that said first and second stabilizing arms are disposed coplanar to each other;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second privacy panels removably abutted directly to exterior sides of said first and second stabilizing arms, said first and second privacy panels extending downwardly from said first and second stabilizing arms and terminating at the ground surface in such a manner that an inner space defined between said first and second panels is invisible to bystanders, said first and second privacy panels having rear edges adjoining said rear wall; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top cover having a linear rear edge pivotally connected directly to said top edge of said rear wall, said top cover having a dome shape and being provided with a linear front edge traversing between said first and second stabilizing arms in such a manner that said top cover rests directly on said first and second stabilizing arms when articulated to a lowered position, wherein said top cover comprises
<claim-text>a polarizing filter that eliminates ambient light from passing through said top cover and is adapted to prevent bystanders from maintaining a direct line of sight through said top cover;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the user card is removably seated beneath said top cover and between said first and second privacy panels whereby the non-user can view the contents of the user card while prohibiting bystanders from maintaining a clear line of sight to the user card.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein each of said first and second stabilizing arms is provided with a guide slot formed along the respective linear lengths thereof, each of said privacy panels being vertically positioned along said first and second stabilizing arms such that said first and second privacy panels become interlocked therewith and maintained along the vertical plane during viewing conditions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a non-linear support leg connected to an interior of said rear wall, said support leg extending forwardly from said rear wall and having an upwardly tapered front lip for maintaining the user card rearwardly tilted and supported against said rear wall during viewing operations, said support leg being elevated above the support surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said interior of said rear wall is provided with a rearwardly stepped shoulder obliquely offset from the vertical plane, said shoulder sloping rearwardly towards an exterior of said rear wall for allowing the user card to lay along a rearwardly sloping plane during viewing operations.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said top cover remains stationary when said first and second privacy panels are detached from said first and second stabilizing arms respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second stabilizing arms are independently detachable from said rear wall such that only one of said first and second stabilizing arms are attached to said rear wall during viewing conditions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A private viewing case for assisting a non-user to privately view and verify data printed on a user card, said private viewing case comprising:
<claim-text>a rear wall having a planar outer surface vertically extending upwardly from a support surface, said rear wall further having a bottom flange monolithically formed therewith and registered orthogonal to a vertical plane, said bottom flange being securely fastened directly to the support surface such that said rear wall is statically anchored during operating conditions, wherein said rear wall is removably connected to the support surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second stabilizing arms having linear longitudinal lengths and the same dimensions, each of said first and second stabilizing arms having rear ends removably attached directly to opposite ends of a top edge of said rear wall, said first and second stabilizing arms being orthogonally registered with said rear wall and terminating forward thereof such that said first and second stabilizing arms are disposed coplanar to each other;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second privacy panels removably abutted directly to exterior sides of said first and second stabilizing arms, said first and second privacy panels extending downwardly from said first and second stabilizing arms and terminating at the ground surface in such a manner that an inner space defined between said first and second panels is invisible to bystanders, said first and second privacy panels having rear edges adjoining said rear wall; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top cover having a linear rear edge pivotally connected directly to said top edge of said rear wall, said top cover having a dome shape and being provided with a linear front edge traversing between said first and second stabilizing arms in such a manner that said top cover rests directly on said first and second stabilizing arms when articulated to a lowered position, wherein said top cover comprises
<claim-text>a polarizing filter that eliminates ambient light from passing through said top cover and is adapted to prevent bystanders from maintaining a direct line of sight through said top cover;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the user card is removably seated beneath said top cover and between said first and second privacy panels whereby the non-user can view the contents of the user card while prohibiting bystanders from maintaining a clear line of sight to the user card.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein each of said first and second stabilizing arms is provided with a guide slot formed along the respective linear lengths thereof, each of said privacy panels being vertically positioned along said first and second stabilizing arms such that said first and second privacy panels become interlocked therewith and maintained along the vertical plane during viewing conditions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a non-linear support leg connected to an interior of said rear wall, said support leg extending forwardly from said rear wall and having an upwardly tapered front lip for maintaining the user card rearwardly tilted and supported against said rear wall during viewing operations, said support leg being elevated above the support surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein said interior of said rear wall is provided with a rearwardly stepped shoulder obliquely offset from the vertical plane, said shoulder sloping rearwardly towards an exterior of said rear wall for allowing the user card to lay along a rearwardly sloping plane during viewing operations.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said top cover remains stationary when said first and second privacy panels are detached from said first and second stabilizing arms respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The private viewing case of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said first and second stabilizing arms are independently detachable from said rear wall such that only one of said first and second stabilizing arms are attached to said rear wall during viewing conditions. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
