<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640620-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640620</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10843496</doc-number>
<date>20040510</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>10</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>698</us-term-extension>
<disclaimer>
<text>This patent is subject to a terminal disclaimer.</text>
</disclaimer>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>38</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15301</main-classification>
<further-classification> 15314</further-classification>
<further-classification> 15315</further-classification>
<further-classification> 15323</further-classification>
<further-classification>138118</further-classification>
<further-classification>138119</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e55">Retractable hose extension for a vacuum</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5526842</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Christensen</name>
<date>19960600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5740581</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Harrelson, II</name>
<date>19980400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6182327</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Gosselin</name>
<date>20010200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7306012</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Stockton et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>138119</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0098084</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ragner</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0246855</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Stockton et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 176 352</doc-number>
<date>20020100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 01/24677</doc-number>
<date>20010400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>168</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15301</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15314</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15315</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15323</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>138118</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>138119</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<us-classifications-ipcr>A47L 5/38</us-classifications-ipcr>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20050246854</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20051110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Stockton</last-name>
<first-name>John H.</first-name>
<address>
<street>601 W. Main Ave., Suite 714</street>
<city>Spokane</city>
<state>WA</state>
<postcode>99201</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fehr Law Firm</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fehr</last-name>
<first-name>Thompson E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Redding</last-name>
<first-name>David A</first-name>
<department>3723</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A retractable hose extension for a vacuum having an expandable hose within a containment structure, a first coupling at the first end of the hose and in the first end of the containment structure for connecting the hose to a vacuum, a valve at the second end of the hose, and either a door or other releasable retention device for the hose. Preferably, the valve is an iris valve. Two fixed embodiment and one portable embodiment exist. The first fixed embodiment is inserted within a wall. The second fixed embodiment is rotatably attached to a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from a vacuum system.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="53.09mm" wi="138.01mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="173.40mm" wi="138.26mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="210.40mm" wi="160.36mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="187.03mm" wi="152.65mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="225.30mm" wi="146.47mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="216.66mm" wi="145.71mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="176.95mm" wi="153.92mm" file="US07640620-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to a hose for a vacuum, especially a retractable hose.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A number of patents and published patent applications apply to retractable hoses for vacuum systems.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 5,740,581 applies to a vacuum hose where a horizontal partition is placed between two wall studs. The upper end of the hose has a handle. Below the handle the hose passes through a drive assembly for pulling the hose below the handle into the space below the partition and then extending the hose when desired.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In the device of U.S. Pat. No. 6,182,327, a handle of a hose is maintained on one side of a conduit through which the remainder of the hose passes into a basket. As the hose drops into the basket, the forces created thereby cause the basket to rotate and coil the hose.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The vacuum hose of U.S. Pat. No. 5,526,842 is retracted onto a spring-loaded reel, which may be located within a wall. A hinged door is urged by a spring toward a closed position. When it is open, the door bears against corrugations of the hose to prevent the hose from being retracted into the wall; it is not used to facilitate the retention of the hose within the wall or other container.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">International publication no. WO 01/24677 describes a hose which fits inside and has a head end extending from an open end of a conduit that also has a terminal end. An annular seal is attached to the foot end of the hose to minimize the flow of air past the hose. A cover is &#x201c;hingedley&#x201d; attached to the head end of the hose and is, preferably, spring biased to urge the cover closed when a handle is not attached. Then, when a vacuum is applied to the terminal end of the conduit, external air pressure pushes the hose into the conduit. An annular flange acts as a stop against a wall receptacle to preclude the entire hose from being pushed into the conduit. The length of the hose does, however, not vary.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The hose of European patent application no. 1 176 352 has a wall composed of a helical spring covered by two layers of material through which air does not pass. Such layers are bonded to one another around the spring but not in between windings of the spring, thereby creating a continuous helically channel between the windings of the spring. The spring is biased to retract. A pump pushes air into the channel when it is closed in order to extend the hose and withdraws such air to facilitate retraction of the hose.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Appearing most closely related to the present invention, though, is one embodiment of the device described in United States patent application publication no. US 2003/0098084.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The embodiment of interest is a vacuum hose which has a helical spring inside the wall of the hose. Between coils of the spring the wall bows inward. The spring &#x201c;. . . is biased to expand the hose . . . to its fully extended length. This means that in its compressed position . . . , spring 36b is under compression forces, with force needed to keep it in this retracted state (the force may come from either vacuum pressure and/or support housing). In its relaxed state, the hose . . . can be fully extended and bias spring 36b can still be exerting an extension force on the hose . . . .&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The free end of the hose incorporates a rather complex wand, the complexity of which suggests that a simple valve would be inadequate to retract the hose.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Both a wall-mounted version of the vacuum hose and a portable version are discussed.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The wall-mounted version holds the body of the compressed hose inside a tube with the wand being &#x201c;snapped (or locked, or clipped, etc.) into place in wand indentation 262&#x201d; so that the hose can be held in a retracted position without the vacuum operating. And &#x201c;a door . . . may be place[d] on holding case 260 to provide a clean finish look for the wall in which this hose system is installed. This door can also help hold hose wand 28 in place while not in use.&#x201d;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the portable version the hose has &#x201c;a locking end . . . on one end, and hose wand housing . . . on the other.&#x201d; The hose is locked to a vacuum source either with a tube around the hose extending from the wand or a tube inside the hose extending from the wand. The fact that the tube has a locking end at its end which is opposite to the end with the wand, therefore, unfortunately creates a rather lengthy (exceeding the length of the compressed hose) inflexible section of hose that is attached to the wand even when the hose is extended.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Finally, in U.S. Pat. No. 5,114,050 two embodiments of an elevated vacuum hose are shown. In a first embodiment the vacuum hose is held on a reel. In the second embodiment a short flexible hose hangs &#x201c;in the form of an inverted U&#x201d; and is retained in an elevated position by a spring so that it can be grasped and pulled to an operating position. The length of the hoses of this patent does not, however, vary, i.e., the length of the hoses cannot be extended or retracted.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Unlike the hoses of U.S. patent application Ser. Nos. 5,740,581; 6,182,327; and 5,526,842 and international publication no. WO 01/24677, the length of the hose in the present Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum is, as its name suggests, variable through extension and retraction.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Furthermore, retraction of the hose in the present invention is accomplished merely by closing a valve located at a second end of the hose while a vacuum is being applied to a first end of the hose. And, preferably, this valve is an iris valve so that it remains connected to the second end of the hose throughout operation and storage, in a containment structure, of the hose without impeding the movement of the second end of the hose into the containment structure since an iris valve, contrary to the situation with respect to the complex wand of United States patent application publication no. US 2003/0098084, tends to minimize the need to extend substantially beyond the cross-sectional area of the hose.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The present Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum comprises an expandable hose and a containment structure for the hose with a first end of a first coupling in a first end of the containment structure; a second end of the first coupling connected to a first end of the hose; and, as discussed above, a second end of the hose attached to a valve, actually to the first or downstream (relative to the direction of fluid flow when a vacuum is being applied) end of the valve. The second or upstream end of the valve is preferably connected to a first end of a second coupling; the second end of the coupling is preferably constructed to connect to, and be in fluid communication with, traditional vacuum attachments, unlike the apparent situation for the other expandable vacuum hoses discussed above. Clearly, United States patent application publication no. US 2003/0098084 utilizes the complex wand at the free end of the hose. And element number 29 of European patent application no. 1 176 352 would seem to preclude the use of traditional vacuum attachments.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Three embodiments&#x2014;two fixed and one portable&#x2014;exist for the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A first fixed embodiment is mounted within in a wall with the first end of the first coupling available for connection to a vacuum system, preferably by being connected to a tube leading to the vacuum of a central vacuum system, although the connection could be to an individual vacuum unit, itself.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In the second fixed embodiment a first end of the containment structure may alternatively be rotatably attached to a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from the vacuum system.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Both fixed embodiments further comprise a retention device in order to retain the hose within the containment structure when no vacuum is being applied to the first end of the hose.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">And the portable embodiment, in its most basic form, comprises simply the containment structure with the attached expandable hose and a retention device. Preferably, the portable embodiment further comprises a handle attached to the containment structure. Even more preferably, the containment structure is placed within a carrying case.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In any embodiment, it is preferable that the hose is subject to neither an extending nor a retracting force when the hose is fully extended and the valve is open.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Similarly, for any embodiment, the retention device need simply be any such device that will preclude the hose from leaving the containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of the containment structure. Furthermore, such retention device is either (a) attached to a wall from which the hose exits in the case of the first fixed embodiment, to the containment structure near the second end of the containment structure for any embodiment, or within a second end of a carrying case for the portable embodiment or, for any embodiment, (b) a first portion of a retention device is connected to the containment structure near the second end of the containment structure with a mating portion of the retention device attached to the valve (if there is no second coupling) or to the second coupling when one exists.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">This causes the retention device to be readily accessible to a user. Thus, unlike the situation with respect to the portable unit of United States patent application publication no. US 2003/0098084, locking does not occur at a distant location from the second end of the hose and therefore require an inflexible section of hose (in publication no. US 2003/0098084 a rigid structure projecting inside or around the extendable hose when locked and proceeding from the end of the extendable hose when unlocked) that is attached to the wand even when the hose is extended.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, in a cutaway view, portrays the basic elements of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum minus a releasable retention device.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a view looking at the second end of embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with a door attached to the containment structure near the second end of the containment structure.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows, in a cutaway view, the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum installed within a wall.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> depicts, in a cutaway view, the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with a door attached to the containment structure near the second end of the containment structure.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in a cutaway view, illustrates the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with a first portion of a locking device other than a door connected to the second end of the containment structure and a mating portion of the locking device attached to a valve at the second end of the hose.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in a cutaway view, displays the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with a first portion of a locking device other than a door connected to the second end of the containment structure and a mating portion of the locking device attached to a second coupling on the second end of the valve.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum with a first end of the containment structure rotatably attached to a tube within a ceiling where the containment structure is substantially horizontal.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> provides a view of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum with a first end of the containment structure rotatably attached to a tube within a ceiling where the containment structure is substantially vertical.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a version of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum with a first end of the containment structure rotatably attached to a tube within a ceiling where the containment structure is adjustable between a substantially horizontal position and an orientation where its second end is below horizontal alignment with its first end.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates, in a cutaway view, a first portable embodiment of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, in a cutaway view, depicts a second portable embodiment of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum utilizing a carrying case with a door.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is an end view of the second portable embodiment of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum utilizing a carrying case with an aperture without a door, in the second end of the carrying case, and without the optional structure for containing one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As indicated above and shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum comprises an expandable hose <b>1</b> and a containment structure <b>2</b> for the hose <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Preferably, the containment structure <b>2</b> is, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a tube <b>3</b> having an internal diameter <b>4</b> somewhat larger than the outer diameter <b>5</b> of the hose <b>1</b>. The containment structure <b>2</b>, however, merely needs to be any elongate container <b>6</b> (straight or curved) with a cross section of such dimension that the hose <b>1</b> substantially follows the longitudinal axis <b>7</b> of the container <b>6</b> even when no vacuum is being applied to the hose <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In a first end <b>8</b> the containment structure <b>2</b> has a first coupling <b>9</b> with a first end <b>10</b> available for connection to, and fluid communication with, a vacuum system and with a second end <b>11</b> connected to, and in fluid communication with, a first end <b>12</b> of the hose <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">At the second end <b>13</b> of the hose <b>1</b> is attached a first or downstream end <b>14</b> of a valve <b>15</b> in fluid communication with the hose <b>1</b>. Preferably this valve <b>15</b> is an iris valve, although it can be any valve which will seal the second end <b>13</b> of the hose <b>1</b>. Non-exclusive examples of such valves are ball valves, butterfly valves, a plate that screws onto a threaded ring attached to the hose, or a spring-loaded cover attached to the hose <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Preferably, attached to the end <b>16</b> of the valve <b>15</b> away from the hose <b>1</b>, i.e., the second or upstream end <b>16</b> of the valve <b>15</b>, is a first end <b>17</b> of a second coupling <b>18</b> such that the second coupling <b>18</b> is in fluid communication with the valve <b>15</b>. On its second end <b>19</b> the second coupling <b>18</b> is preferably constructed to connect to, and be in fluid communication with, traditional vacuum attachments in fluid communication with such second coupling <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The hose <b>1</b> is contracted, and thereby has its second end <b>12</b> drawn into the containment structure <b>2</b> through the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> (which second end <b>20</b> is sufficiently open that the hose <b>1</b>, valve <b>15</b>, and second coupling <b>18</b>&#x2014;when such second coupling <b>18</b> is utilized&#x2014;can pass through such second end <b>20</b>), by application of a vacuum to the first end <b>12</b> of the hose <b>1</b> when the valve <b>15</b> has been closed. After the vacuum has been deactivated, the hose <b>1</b> is releasably retained within the containment structure <b>2</b> by a releasable retention device <b>21</b>, which is either a door <b>21</b> that cannot be opened with a force that is exerted perpendicular to a plane containing the two longer orthogonal dimensions, i.e., the height <b>22</b> and width <b>23</b> of the door <b>21</b>, or other type of releasable retention device <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As stated above, in any embodiment, it is preferable that the hose <b>1</b> is subject to neither an extending nor a retracting force when the hose <b>1</b> is fully extended and the valve <b>15</b> is open.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The containment structure <b>2</b> may, in a first fixed embodiment, be installed within a wall <b>24</b>, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>; if so, the door <b>21</b> may be in a side <b>25</b> (For the purposes of this patent application, the term &#x201c;side&#x201d; of a wall is intended to mean any portion of the wall which has an external surface, such as an end or traditional lateral side.) of the wall <b>24</b> with the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> being located so close to such door <b>21</b> that, unless the door <b>21</b> is opened, the hose <b>1</b> cannot leave the containment structure <b>2</b> sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis <b>7</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>. Otherwise (for a containment structure <b>2</b> within a wall or elsewhere), either (a) the door <b>21</b> is attached to the containment structure <b>2</b> near the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, which second end <b>20</b> is otherwise&#x2014;as discussed above&#x2014;sufficiently open that the hose <b>1</b>, valve <b>15</b>, and second coupling <b>18</b>&#x2014;when such second coupling <b>18</b> is utilized&#x2014;can pass through such second end <b>20</b>, or (b) a first portion <b>26</b> of another type of releasable retention device <b>21</b> is connected to the containment structure <b>2</b> near the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> with a mating portion <b>27</b> of the releasable retention device <b>21</b> attached to the valve <b>15</b> (if there is no second coupling <b>18</b>), as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, or to the second coupling <b>18</b> when one exists, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. (Of course, in this latter case there must be some means of accessing the hose <b>1</b> through the side <b>25</b> of the wall <b>24</b> such as a door or an aperture.)</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">A first end <b>8</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> may alternatively be attached, preferably rotatably, to a free end <b>28</b> of a tube <b>29</b> contained within or running below a ceiling <b>30</b> and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system, creating a second fixed embodiment. In the rotatable embodiment, the containment structure <b>2</b> is moved horizontally with respect to the tube <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">At least three options exist for this second fixed embodiment of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum. The containment structure <b>2</b> can be substantially horizontal, as portrayed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>; substantially vertical, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, or adjustable between a substantially horizontal position and an orientation where its second end <b>20</b> is below horizontal alignment with its first end <b>8</b>, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Any technique that is well known in the art may be utilized to achieve these three configurations. However, the immediately following four paragraphs provide non-exclusive illustrative examples.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In each configuration, a first end <b>31</b> of a first elbow <b>32</b> is connected to the free end <b>28</b> of the tube <b>29</b> so that the first elbow is in fluid communication with the tube <b>29</b>. The second end <b>33</b> of the first elbow <b>32</b> is attached to a first end <b>34</b> of and is in fluid communication with a substantially vertical tube <b>35</b>. A first end <b>36</b> of a second elbow <b>37</b> is connected to, and is in fluid communication with, a second end <b>38</b> of the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b>. Either the second end <b>33</b> of the first elbow <b>32</b> is constructed, using any technique that is well known in the art, to permit the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> to rotate within such second end <b>33</b> or the first end <b>36</b> of the second elbow <b>37</b> is constructed, using any technique that is well known in the art, to rotate about the second end <b>38</b> of the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b>. Therefore, the second end <b>39</b> of the second elbow <b>37</b> can rotate in a substantially horizontal plane.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">For the first configuration, the first end <b>10</b> of the first coupling <b>9</b>, in the first end <b>8</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, is simply attached, in fluid communication, to the second end <b>39</b> of the second elbow <b>37</b>. Then the containment structure <b>2</b> is substantially horizontal, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In the second configuration, a first end <b>40</b> of a substantially horizontal tube <b>41</b> is connected to, and in fluid communication with, the second end <b>39</b> of the second elbow <b>37</b>. A first end <b>42</b> of a third elbow <b>43</b> is attached to, and in fluid communication with, a second end <b>44</b> of the substantially horizontal tube <b>41</b>. The first end <b>10</b> of the first coupling <b>9</b>, in the first end <b>8</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, is attached, in fluid communication, to the second end <b>45</b> of the third elbow <b>43</b>, making the containment structure <b>2</b> substantially vertical, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">And an exemplary structure for achieving the third configuration is, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the same as that for the first configuration with the exception that the second elbow <b>37</b> is flexible, allowing the containment structure <b>2</b> to rotate in a substantially vertical plane. Connected to the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> is a first end <b>46</b> of any device <b>47</b> which is well known in the art for exerting a force to return the containment structure <b>2</b> to a substantially horizontal position after the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> has been pulled below horizontal and which can be locked releasably to retain the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure in a lowered position. Two non-exclusive examples of such a device are (1) a ratchet connected to two substantially rigid arms, one of which is attached to the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> and the other of which is attached to the containment structure <b>2</b> with the end of the pawl that does not engage the ratchet connected either to a cord or an electromechanical lever for releasing the pawl from the ratchet and with a spring or gas cylinder connected to both the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> and the containment structure <b>2</b> to urge the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> and the containment structure to move angularly toward one another and (2) an electrically motorized screw within a housing where the either the housing or the screw is rotatably connected to the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> and the other is rotatably attached to the containment structure <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Of course, in any of the three preceding configurations, an additional tube can be inserted, in fluid communication, between the second end <b>39</b> of the second elbow <b>37</b> and the first end <b>10</b> of the first coupling <b>9</b> in order to increase the distance between the substantially vertical tube <b>35</b> and the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As indicated above, in addition to these two fixed embodiments of the Retractable Hose Extension for a Vacuum, a portable embodiment exists.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The portable embodiment may, as depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, involve simply attaching a handle <b>48</b> to the containment structure <b>2</b>, which contains the hose <b>1</b>, with the door <b>21</b> or one portion of a retention device <b>21</b> connected to the containment structure <b>2</b> near the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, as described above, or even just having the preceding embodiment without the handle <b>48</b>. Alternatively, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the containment structure <b>2</b> and hose <b>1</b> are placed within a carrying case <b>49</b>. The first end <b>8</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, to which is attached the first coupling <b>9</b>, then constitutes a portion <b>50</b> of a first end <b>51</b> of the carrying case <b>49</b>; the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> may be attached to the carrying case <b>49</b> sufficiently near a second end <b>52</b> of the carrying case <b>49</b> that the hose <b>1</b> cannot leave the containment structure <b>2</b> sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis <b>7</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>. In such a portable embodiment, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, a door <b>21</b> preferably exists for closing an aperture <b>53</b> in the second end <b>52</b> of the carrying case <b>49</b> through which, when the door <b>21</b> has been opened, the hose <b>1</b>, the valve <b>15</b>, and the second coupling <b>18</b> (when such second coupling <b>18</b> is used) can exit the carrying case <b>49</b>. Otherwise, when a carrying case <b>49</b> is utilized, the aperture <b>53</b> is, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, present in the second end <b>52</b> of the carrying case <b>49</b>; and either the door <b>21</b> is attached to the containment structure <b>2</b> near the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, or a first portion <b>26</b> of another type of retention device <b>21</b> is connected to the containment structure <b>2</b> near the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b> with a mating portion <b>27</b> of the retention device <b>21</b> attached to the valve <b>15</b> (if there is no second coupling <b>18</b>), as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, or to the second coupling <b>18</b> when one exists, as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">For any embodiment, the door <b>21</b>&#x2014;in a wall <b>24</b>, attached to the second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, or within the second end <b>52</b> of the carrying case <b>49</b>&#x2014;need simply be any type of door <b>21</b> that will, when closed, preclude the hose <b>1</b> from leaving the containment structure <b>2</b> sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis <b>7</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>; and the unmodified term &#x201c;door&#x201d; shall, for the purposes of this patent application, have such meaning. Thus, the door <b>21</b> could, for example, be a hinged door <b>21</b> with any type of lock that is well known in the art or a door <b>21</b> that slides along an external surface of a wall <b>24</b>, second end <b>20</b> of the containment structure <b>2</b>, or second end <b>52</b> of the carrying case <b>49</b> and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end <b>12</b> of the hose <b>1</b> to leave the containment structure <b>2</b>. For the carrying case <b>49</b> (when the carrying case <b>49</b> is constructed of fabric, although it can be constructed of any material known in the art to be suitable), the term &#x201c;door,&#x201d; for the purposes of this patent application, is intended to include a zipper or other well-know mechanism such as buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps (also called locking lugs and locking buttons), or hook and loop fasteners marketed under the trademarked name VELCRO that are used to close an aperture <b>53</b> in fabric.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Optionally, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, the carrying case <b>49</b> is constructed, using any structure that is well known in the art, to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The hose <b>1</b>, in any embodiment, can be any hose <b>1</b> that will expand and contract along its length. Most commonly, such hoses <b>1</b> have a helically wound wire within the material that forms the wall of the hose. For purposes of the present invention, it is immaterial whether when the hose <b>1</b> is fully extended, the helically wound wire exerts a retracting force, no force, or an extending force. It is, however, preferred that there be no force since either a retracting or an extending force would tend to impair the free movement of the hose <b>1</b> when it is being employed by a user to vacuum something.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">A non-exclusive list of acceptable hoses is taken from the catalog of McMaster-Carr and comprises a SUPERFLEX PVC, wire-reinforced hose (MC part no. 5500k33); a RUBBER TUFF hose (MC part no. 5136K13); a BULK-N-FUME SANTOPRENE hose (MC part no. 53145k61); a BLO-R-VAC, PVC hose (MC part no. 5666K14); and a PVC fiberglass hose (MC part no. 5501k31).</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As used herein, the term &#x201c;substantially&#x201d; indicates that one skilled in the art would consider the value modified by such terms to be within acceptable limits for the stated value. Also as used herein the term &#x201c;preferable&#x201d; or &#x201c;preferably&#x201d; means that a specified element or technique is more acceptable than another but not that such specified element or technique is a necessity.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A retractable hose extension for a vacuum, which comprises:
<claim-text>an expandable hose having a first end and a second end;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a containment structure having a first end, a second end which is sufficiently open that said hose can pass through it, and a longitudinal axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first coupling located in the first end of said containment structure, said first coupling having a first end available for connection to, and fluid communication with, a vacuum system and also having a second end that is connected to and in fluid communication with a first end of said hose;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve of such dimensions that said valve can pass through the second end of said containment structure, said valve having a first end attached to, and in fluid communication with, said hose and said valve also having a second end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, with such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment stucture&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said expandable hose is so constructed that, when fully extended, said expandable hose exerts neither a retracting nor and extending force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text>35. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, with such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036" num="00036">
<claim-text>36. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00035">claim 35</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037" num="00037">
<claim-text>37. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00035">claim 35</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038" num="00038">
<claim-text>38. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039" num="00039">
<claim-text>39. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040" num="00040">
<claim-text>40. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00039">claim 39</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041" num="00041">
<claim-text>41. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device, connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042" num="00042">
<claim-text>42. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00041">claim 41</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043" num="00043">
<claim-text>43. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said valve is an iris valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00044" num="00044">
<claim-text>44. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00045" num="00045">
<claim-text>45. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00046" num="00046">
<claim-text>46. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00047" num="00047">
<claim-text>47. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00048" num="00048">
<claim-text>48. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00047">claim 47</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00049" num="00049">
<claim-text>49. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00047">claim 47</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00050" num="00050">
<claim-text>50. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00051" num="00051">
<claim-text>51. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00050">claim 50</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00052" num="00052">
<claim-text>52. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00050">claim 50</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00053" num="00053">
<claim-text>53. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00054" num="00054">
<claim-text>54. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00053">claim 53</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00055" num="00055">
<claim-text>55. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00053">claim 53</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00056" num="00056">
<claim-text>56. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00057" num="00057">
<claim-text>57. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00056">claim 56</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00058" num="00058">
<claim-text>58. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00056">claim 56</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00059" num="00059">
<claim-text>59. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00058">claim 58</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00060" num="00060">
<claim-text>60. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment stucture&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00061" num="00061">
<claim-text>61. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00060">claim 60</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00062" num="00062">
<claim-text>62. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00063" num="00063">
<claim-text>63. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00062">claim 62</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00064" num="00064">
<claim-text>64. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00043">claim 43</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second coupling of such dimensions that said second coupling can pass through the second end of said containment structure, said second coupling having a first end and a second end with the first end of said second coupling attached to the second end of said valve so that said second coupling is in fluid communication with said valve, the second end of said second coupling being constructed to connect to, and be in fluid communication with, traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00065" num="00065">
<claim-text>65. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00066" num="00066">
<claim-text>66. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00067" num="00067">
<claim-text>67. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00068" num="00068">
<claim-text>68. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00069" num="00069">
<claim-text>69. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00068">claim 68</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00070" num="00070">
<claim-text>70. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00068">claim 68</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00071" num="00071">
<claim-text>71. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00072" num="00072">
<claim-text>72. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00071">claim 71</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the Second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00073" num="00073">
<claim-text>73. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00071">claim 71</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00074" num="00074">
<claim-text>74. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00075" num="00075">
<claim-text>75. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00074">claim 74</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00076" num="00076">
<claim-text>76. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00074">claim 74</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00077" num="00077">
<claim-text>77. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve and said second coupling can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00078" num="00078">
<claim-text>78. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00077">claim 77</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00079" num="00079">
<claim-text>79. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00077">claim 77</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00080" num="00080">
<claim-text>80. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00079">claim 79</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00081" num="00081">
<claim-text>81. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment stucture&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00082" num="00082">
<claim-text>82. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00081">claim 81</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00083" num="00083">
<claim-text>83. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00064">claim 64</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00084" num="00084">
<claim-text>84. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00083">claim 83</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00085" num="00085">
<claim-text>85. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second coupling of such dimensions that said second coupling can pass through the second end of said containment structure, said second coupling having a first end and a second end with the first end of said second coupling attached to the second end of said valve so that said second coupling is in fluid communication with said valve, the second end of said second coupling being constructed to connect to, and be in fluid communication with, traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00086" num="00086">
<claim-text>86. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00087" num="00087">
<claim-text>87. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00088" num="00088">
<claim-text>88. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00089" num="00089">
<claim-text>89. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00090" num="00090">
<claim-text>90. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00089">claim 89</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00091" num="00091">
<claim-text>91. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00089">claim 89</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00092" num="00092">
<claim-text>92. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00093" num="00093">
<claim-text>93. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00092">claim 92</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00094" num="00094">
<claim-text>94. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00092">claim 92</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00095" num="00095">
<claim-text>95. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00096" num="00096">
<claim-text>96. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00095">claim 95</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00097" num="00097">
<claim-text>97. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00095">claim 95</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00098" num="00098">
<claim-text>98. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve and said second coupling can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00099" num="00099">
<claim-text>99. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00098">claim 98</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00100" num="00100">
<claim-text>100. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00098">claim 98</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00101" num="00101">
<claim-text>101. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00100">claim 100</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00102" num="00102">
<claim-text>102. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment stucture&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00103" num="00103">
<claim-text>103. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00102">claim 102</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00104" num="00104">
<claim-text>104. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00085">claim 85</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00105" num="00105">
<claim-text>105. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00104">claim 104</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00106" num="00106">
<claim-text>106. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said valve is an iris valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00107" num="00107">
<claim-text>107. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00108" num="00108">
<claim-text>108. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00109" num="00109">
<claim-text>109. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00110" num="00110">
<claim-text>110. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00111" num="00111">
<claim-text>111. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00110">claim 110</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00112" num="00112">
<claim-text>112. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00110">claim 110</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00113" num="00113">
<claim-text>113. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00114" num="00114">
<claim-text>114. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00113">claim 113</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00115" num="00115">
<claim-text>115. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00113">claim 113</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00116" num="00116">
<claim-text>116. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00117" num="00117">
<claim-text>117. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00116">claim 116</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00118" num="00118">
<claim-text>118. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00116">claim 116</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00119" num="00119">
<claim-text>119. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, with such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00120" num="00120">
<claim-text>120. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00119">claim 119</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00121" num="00121">
<claim-text>121. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00119">claim 119</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00122" num="00122">
<claim-text>122. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00121">claim 121</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00123" num="00123">
<claim-text>123. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment stucture&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00124" num="00124">
<claim-text>124. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00123">claim 123</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00125" num="00125">
<claim-text>125. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00126" num="00126">
<claim-text>126. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00125">claim 125</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00127" num="00127">
<claim-text>127. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00106">claim 106</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second coupling of such dimensions that said second coupling can pass through the second end of said containment structure, said second coupling having a first end and a second end with the first end of said second coupling attached to the second end of said valve so that said second coupling is in fluid communication with said valve, the second end of said second coupling being constructed to connect to, and be in fluid communication with, traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00128" num="00128">
<claim-text>128. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00129" num="00129">
<claim-text>129. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00130" num="00130">
<claim-text>130. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00131" num="00131">
<claim-text>131. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00132" num="00132">
<claim-text>132. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00131">claim 131</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00133" num="00133">
<claim-text>133. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00131">claim 131</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00134" num="00134">
<claim-text>134. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00135" num="00135">
<claim-text>135. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00134">claim 134</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached said containment structure near to the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00136" num="00136">
<claim-text>136. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00134">claim 134</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00137" num="00137">
<claim-text>137. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00138" num="00138">
<claim-text>138. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00137">claim 137</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00139" num="00139">
<claim-text>139. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00137">claim 137</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00140" num="00140">
<claim-text>140. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve and said second coupling can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00141" num="00141">
<claim-text>141. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00140">claim 140</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00142" num="00142">
<claim-text>142. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00140">claim 140</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00143" num="00143">
<claim-text>143. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00142">claim 142</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00144" num="00144">
<claim-text>144. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00145" num="00145">
<claim-text>145. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00144">claim 144</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00146" num="00146">
<claim-text>146. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00127">claim 127</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00147" num="00147">
<claim-text>147. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00146">claim 146</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00148" num="00148">
<claim-text>148. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second coupling of such dimensions that said second coupling can pass through the second end of said containment structure, said second coupling having a first end and a second end with the first end of said second coupling attached to the second end of said valve so that said second coupling is in fluid communication with said valve, the second end of said second coupling being constructed to connect to, and be in fluid communication with, traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00149" num="00149">
<claim-text>149. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a side with a door in the side of the wall and with said containment structure being located so close to said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00150" num="00150">
<claim-text>150. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00151" num="00151">
<claim-text>151. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said containment structure is installed within a wall having a means for allowing access to said hose and further comprising:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00152" num="00152">
<claim-text>152. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00153" num="00153">
<claim-text>153. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00152">claim 152</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00154" num="00154">
<claim-text>154. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00152">claim 152</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00155" num="00155">
<claim-text>155. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a means for rotatably attaching the first end of said containment structure to a free end of a tube contained within or running below a ceiling and extending from, as well as being in fluid communication with, a vacuum system so that said containment structure can be moved horizontally with respect to the tube while having said containment structure remain substantially vertical.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00156" num="00156">
<claim-text>156. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00155">claim 155</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00157" num="00157">
<claim-text>157. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00155">claim 155</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00158" num="00158">
<claim-text>158. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a handle attached to said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00159" num="00159">
<claim-text>159. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00158">claim 158</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises, attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure, a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00160" num="00160">
<claim-text>160. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00158">claim 158</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00161" num="00161">
<claim-text>161. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing a door in an aperture, such aperture being of such dimensions that said hose and said valve and said second coupling can pass through such aperture when the door has been opened, and with the second end of said containment structure being attached to said carrying case sufficiently near said door that, unless said door is opened, said hose cannot leave said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00162" num="00162">
<claim-text>162. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00161">claim 161</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00163" num="00163">
<claim-text>163. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00161">claim 161</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said door is selected from the group consisting of a hinged door attached to the second end of said carrying case and having a lock, a sliding door that slides along an external surface of the second end of said carrying case and is slid upward from a stop to permit the second end of said hose to leave said containment structure, a zipper, buttons and mating apertures therefor, snaps, and hook and loop fasteners.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00164" num="00164">
<claim-text>164. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00163">claim 163</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00165" num="00165">
<claim-text>165. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises&#x2014;attached to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure&#x2014;a door that when closed, precludes said hose from leaving said containment structure sufficiently far to depart substantially from the longitudinal axis of said containment structure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00166" num="00166">
<claim-text>166. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00165">claim 165</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00167" num="00167">
<claim-text>167. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00148">claim 148</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a carrying case having a first end and a second end with said containment structure placed in said carrying case, with the first end of said containment structure constituting a portion of the first end of said carrying case, with the second end of said carrying case containing an aperture, and wherein said means for releasably retaining said hose within said containment structure comprises:
<claim-text>a first portion of a releasable retention device connected to said containment structure near the second end of said containment structure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating portion of said releasable retention device attached to said second coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00168" num="00168">
<claim-text>168. The retractable hose extension for a vacuum as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00167">claim 167</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>said carrying case is constructed to contain one or more traditional vacuum attachments.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
