<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640610-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640610</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12180339</doc-number>
<date>20080725</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>20</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5647</main-classification>
<further-classification>  5646</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Upper extremity support</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4805605</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Glassman</name>
<date>19890200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>602 24</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5125123</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Engle</name>
<date>19920600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  5648</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7017215</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Singer et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  5646</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>&#x201c;Material Safety Data Sheet AP1000,&#x201d; Atlantis Plastic Films, Inc., Mankato, MN, 3 pages, Jan. 2, 2007.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5632</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5636</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  5646-648</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60962331</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20070727</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090031499</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090205</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Mervar</last-name>
<first-name>Perry</first-name>
<address>
<city>Indianapolis</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>D'Hue Law LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>D'Hue</last-name>
<first-name>Cedric</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lante Medical, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Indianapolis</city>
<state>IN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Conley</last-name>
<first-name>Fredricki</first-name>
<department>3673</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A support for use with the upper extremity of a patient is disclosed. An upper extremity support including a wedge for supporting the upper extremity is provided. The upper extremity support may include a block for supporting the wedge. The upper extremity support may also include straps and may define apertures and grooves for fastening and positioning the upper extremity in relation to the upper extremity support, the patient or another support. The upper extremity support may position the upper extremity in a substantially scaption position.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="163.24mm" wi="402.17mm" file="US07640610-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.38mm" wi="171.03mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="221.40mm" wi="175.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="171.87mm" wi="163.66mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="192.79mm" wi="155.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="185.84mm" wi="139.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="203.20mm" wi="166.29mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="181.53mm" wi="165.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="212.34mm" wi="150.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640610-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application Ser. No. 60/962,331, filed Jul. 27, 2007, the entire disclosure of which is expressly incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a system and method for supporting the upper extremity of a human, such as a burn patient.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As a result of severe burns, a patient can suffer from a reduced range of motion about a joint. Scarring, swelling, and nerve damage may cause this loss of range of motion. In particular, burns formed in the axilla, also known as the armpit, or the gleno-humeral joint, also know as the shoulder, may limit flexion, abduction, and rotational motions of the upper extremities. Furthermore, burns to the chest, shoulder, and upper extremities often result in web like bands of scar tissue. With this condition, and as soft tissue and skin heals, the tissue shortens making it difficult to move the joints near this soft tissue and skin.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Correct positioning of a burned axilla, chest, shoulder and/or upper extremity aids in healing and can reduce loss of range of motion. Proper positioning of the upper extremity assists in reduction of swelling and regaining motion. Care should be exercised when positioning the upper extremity to avoid stress on nerves and vessels. A large bundle of nerves, including the brachial plexus, as well as blood vessels, pass through the axilla or joint to provide nerves (also known as innervate) and supply blood to the upper extremities. The brachial plexus is responsible for cutaneous and muscular innervation of almost the entire upper extremity; therefore, lesions of the plexus can lead to functional impairment, such as loss of touch or pain or other sensory functions.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Positioning the upper extremity away from the rest of the body, also known as abduction, aids in healing. While the upper extremity is abducted, moving the upper extremity toward the front of the body, a form of adduction, also aids in healing.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">According to one aspect of the present invention, an arm support is provided that includes a wedge for use with an upper extremity of a patient. The wedge defines an angle configured for use to abduct or adduct the upper extremity.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to another aspect of the present invention, another arm support is provided that includes a wedge and a block for use with an upper extremity of a patient. The wedge defines an angle configured for use to abduct or adduct the upper extremity. The block supports the wedge and is configured to horizontally adduct the upper extremity.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to yet another aspect of the present invention, a method of supporting an upper extremity of a patient is provided that includes the steps of abducting the upper extremity and providing a wedge supporting the upper extremity. The wedge defines an angle positioning the upper extremity.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Additional features of the present invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art upon consideration of the following detailed description of the presently perceived best mode of carrying out the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The above-mentioned and other features of this invention, and the manner of attaining them, will become more apparent and the invention itself will be better understood by reference to the following description of embodiments of the invention taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of an upper extremity support including a wedge and a block;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a cross sectional view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> showing the wedge and block in a first orientation;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> showing the wedge and block in a second orientation;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top plan view of the wedge of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shown in use with a patient with the wedge in a first orientation;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top plan view of the wedge of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shown in use in a second orientation;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in use;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top plan view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> showing the support coupled to the patient with straps;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a top plan view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> in use showing additional straps coupled to the patient; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a top plan view of the upper extremity support of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> in use showing the straps coupled to a support.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Corresponding reference characters indicate corresponding parts throughout the several views. The drawings represent embodiments of the present invention, the drawings are to scale, but certain features may be exaggerated in order to better illustrate and explain the present invention.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The embodiments disclosed below are not intended to be exhaustive or limit the invention to the precise forms disclosed in the following detailed description. Rather, the embodiments are chosen and described so that others skilled in the art may utilize their teachings.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, upper extremity support <b>10</b> is shown to include wedge <b>20</b> and optionally block <b>30</b>. It is understood that upper extremity support <b>10</b> may be a single piece incorporating wedge <b>20</b>, block <b>30</b>, or the combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to one embodiment, wedge <b>20</b> has a polygon geometry, such as a four sided polygon geometry. As illustrated, wedge <b>20</b> defines four sides <b>21</b>, <b>23</b>, <b>25</b>, and <b>27</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, sides <b>21</b>, <b>23</b>, <b>25</b>, and <b>27</b> are different from each other. Illustratively side <b>23</b> is substantially twenty (20) inches and side <b>25</b> is substantially twenty-four (24) inches. In other embodiments, sides <b>21</b>, <b>23</b>, <b>25</b>, and <b>27</b> may be other lengths or similar to each other. Also as illustrated wedge <b>20</b> defines a thickness <b>29</b>. Illustratively thickness is substantially six (6) inches.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Smaller versions of wedge <b>20</b> may also be provided for pediatric and youth applications. In a pediatric embodiment, the sizes are approximately cut in half. For example, side <b>23</b> is substantially ten (10) inches and side <b>25</b> is substantially twelve (12) inches. Thickness <b>29</b> is substantially three (3) inches.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As illustrated, wedge <b>20</b> defines four angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> are different from each other. Illustratively angle <b>22</b> is substantially 85&#xb0;, angle <b>24</b> is substantially 95&#xb0;, angle <b>26</b> is substantially 70&#xb0;, and angle <b>28</b> is substantially 110&#xb0;. Angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> may be other angles or similar to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Wedge <b>20</b> may define grooves <b>32</b>, <b>34</b> that receive an upper extremity as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 8</figref>. As illustrated grooves <b>32</b> and <b>34</b> align with sides <b>23</b> and <b>27</b>. Grooves <b>32</b> and <b>34</b> may include a substantially two (2) inch radius. For example, a pediatric application of wedge <b>20</b> may have at least one dimension including a substantially one (1) inch radius. In other embodiments, grooves <b>32</b> and <b>34</b> are not limited in position, orientation, or dimension.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As also illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, wedge <b>20</b> defines apertures <b>36</b> that may receive straps <b>40</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). Apertures <b>36</b> may include a substantially two (2) inch radius. For example, a pediatric application of wedge <b>20</b> may include a substantially one (1) inch radius. In other embodiments, apertures <b>36</b> are not limited in position, orientation, or dimension.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">During manufacturing, wedge <b>20</b> may be cut using cutting tools such as an electric knife. In the field or elsewhere, wedge <b>20</b> may be cut to adjust angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>. For example angle <b>26</b> may be cut to make angle <b>26</b> less than substantially 70&#xb0;. Additionally, wedge <b>20</b> may be cut to accommodate splints.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In other embodiments, wedge <b>20</b> is not limited in size, shape, or dimension. Larger versions of wedge <b>20</b> are envisioned. Multiple wedges <b>20</b> may be used in conjunction.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, block <b>30</b> has a triangular cross section including angle <b>38</b>. Angle <b>38</b> is illustrated as substantially 90&#xb0;. Block <b>30</b> may be other shapes, such as prism, tetrahedron, pyramid, cone, sphere, or cylinder. As illustrated, block <b>30</b> also includes angles <b>37</b>, <b>39</b> that are substantially 45 degrees. Angles <b>37</b>, <b>39</b> may be other angles including any angle including and between substantially 0 and substantially 90 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Block <b>30</b> may be any structure which provides abduction and/or adduction of an upper extremity, such as horizontal adduction. Block <b>30</b> may also be any support to wedge <b>20</b> which provides abduction and/or adduction of an upper extremity, such as horizontal adduction.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, upper extremity support <b>10</b>, wedge <b>20</b> and/or block <b>30</b> may be comprised of foam <b>31</b> and optionally coating <b>33</b>. Foam <b>31</b> may comprise several forms, such as open cell foam. Foam may also include polyurethane foam, also known as foam rubber. In one embodiment, polyurethane foam is Foamex distributed by Foamex International, Inc. of Linwood, Pa. Coating <b>33</b> may comprise several forms, such as cured vinyl coating, polymers, such as polyethylenes, plastic, resins such as thermoplastic resins.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In one embodiment, coating <b>33</b> is known as AP1000 distributed by Atlantis Plastics of Mankato, Minn. AP1000 may include polyvinyl chloride, dodecyl sodium sulfate, polyester adipate, silicone dioxide, synthetic amorphous silica, acetic acid ethenyl ester, and/or paraffin waxes and hydrocarbon waxes. In this embodiment, coating <b>33</b> comprises a thin film produced from a blend of low density and linear low density polyethylenes. In this embodiment, coating <b>33</b> may include amorphous silica, cristobalite, flux-calcinated diatomaceous earth, crystalline silica, and/or erucyl amide up to 0.5% weight percentage.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As show in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, block <b>30</b> supports wedge <b>20</b> at angle <b>37</b>, illustratively substantially 45 degrees. Additionally block <b>30</b> may support wedge <b>20</b> at angle <b>39</b>. Block <b>30</b> provides various degrees of abduction and horizontal adduction by positioning blocks with different angles <b>37</b>, <b>39</b> under wedge <b>20</b> for various positions of skin and/or soft tissue stretch.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Block <b>30</b> also provides various degrees of abduction and horizontal adduction by adjusting angles <b>37</b>, <b>39</b>. As previously mentioned, angles <b>37</b>, <b>39</b> may be other angles including any angle including and between substantially 0 and substantially 90 degrees. Therefore block <b>30</b> may support wedge <b>20</b> at any angle including and between substantially 0 and substantially 90 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, block <b>30</b> partially supports wedge <b>20</b>, providing additional degrees of abduction and horizontal adduction. For example, wedge <b>20</b> may be moved back or forth in relation to block <b>30</b> to provide additional degrees of abduction and horizontal adduction. Alternatively block <b>30</b> may also provide further degrees of abduction and horizontal adduction by placing block <b>30</b> upon end <b>35</b>. Block <b>30</b> may support wedge <b>20</b> in this fashion when patient is lying on their back, also known as a supine position. Block <b>30</b> may also support wedge <b>20</b> in this fashion when patient is standing and/or seated in a chair, such as a cardiac chair. Block <b>30</b> may also support wedge <b>20</b> in this fashion when patient is adjacent to a table, such as a tilt table. Block <b>30</b> may be placed on end <b>35</b> to provide support to wedge <b>20</b> at additional angles, such as substantially 0 degrees to substantially 180 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, upper extremity support <b>10</b> is helpful for pre- and post-grafting or early post-injury to help preserve joint motion, and to positively influence scar tissue elongation and mobility. Upper extremity support <b>10</b> may be used to reduce swelling by keeping the arm elevated above the level of your heart. Upper extremity support <b>10</b> may also keep post burn skin around axilla <b>56</b> stretched.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, wedge <b>20</b> is shown in use with patient <b>50</b>. For example, wedge <b>20</b> may be placed between patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> and patient's torso <b>54</b>. Patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> may be abducted to various degrees by any one of angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, and <b>28</b> of wedge <b>20</b>. As shown, patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> is located within groove <b>34</b>. Patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> could be located within either of grooves <b>32</b> and <b>34</b>. As illustrated patient's arm <b>52</b> is abducted by angle <b>24</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, wedge <b>20</b> is shown with patient's arm located within groove <b>32</b> and patient's arm abducted by angle <b>28</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, block <b>30</b> supports wedge <b>20</b> at angle <b>37</b> or <b>39</b>. The patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> is abducted away from patient's torso <b>54</b> and also horizontally adducted towards the front of patient <b>50</b>. When positioning patient <b>50</b> using block <b>30</b> fully positioned under wedge <b>20</b>, the patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> may be positioned in a substantially scaption position, also known as the plane of the scapula. The plane of the scapula may put the patient's arm <b>52</b> in its most optimal position to minimize stress on shoulder <b>58</b> or axilla <b>56</b> while continuing to stretch the skin and tissue around shoulder <b>58</b> or axilla <b>56</b> to retain range of motion, reduce swelling and reduce functional impairment.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In operation, a care provider positions wedge <b>20</b> so that patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> is positioned at any of angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, or <b>28</b> to adduct patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> to any one of substantially 85, substantially 95, substantially 70 or substantially 110 degrees of abduction, respectively. For example, the choice of angle <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, or <b>28</b> depends on patient's <b>50</b> tolerance and/or burn intensity. Depending on the location of the burn and the desired tissue stretch, inserting block <b>30</b> under wedge <b>20</b> may achieve between about 0 and about 90 degrees of horizontal adduction. Horizontal adduction may be preferably between 15 and 45 degrees of horizontal adduction, most preferably 30 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">A clean barrier, such as bandaging, liner, or external layer such as coating <b>33</b>, could be placed between wedge <b>20</b> and the patient <b>50</b> or the patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> to allow a clean support environment. The clean barrier may be separate from or incorporated into wedge <b>20</b> or block <b>30</b>. Wedge <b>20</b> or block <b>30</b> each may include features to aid in providing a clean support environment, such as a covering. Wedge <b>20</b> or block <b>30</b> each may also include a writeable surface upon which a care provide may write to indicate correct anatomical placement by other health workers.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, upper extremity support <b>10</b> may include straps <b>40</b> that retain upper extremity <b>52</b> to upper extremity support <b>10</b> and/or wedge <b>20</b>, as well as other things. Straps <b>40</b>, similar to upper extremity support <b>10</b>, may include a clean barrier, such as bandaging, liner, or external layer such as coating <b>33</b> to allow a clean support environment. As illustrated, straps <b>40</b> wrap around patient's arm <b>52</b> retaining patient's arm <b>52</b> within groove <b>32</b>. Straps <b>40</b> allow for support of patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> by wedge <b>20</b> or block <b>30</b>. Straps <b>40</b> may help prevent antecubital fossa contractures, also known as deformation of the forearm.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Straps <b>40</b> may also allow for continual abduction of patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> with or without upper extremity adduction, such as by use of block <b>30</b>. Straps <b>40</b> are not limited in width. In one embodiment, straps <b>40</b> are four (4) inches in width to disperse pressure on upper extremities <b>52</b>. Straps <b>40</b> may provide for positioning patient's upper extremity <b>52</b> in supination, where the patient's palm is facing up, which is recommended per patient tolerance. Hook-and-loop type fasteners, such as Velcro brand hook-and-loop type fasteners, may be utilized to secure straps <b>40</b> upon themselves or to secure wedge <b>20</b> to block <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, straps <b>40</b> may aid in retaining patient's arm <b>52</b> within groove <b>34</b>. Additionally straps <b>40</b> may aid in retaining patient's arm <b>52</b> within groove <b>32</b>. Straps <b>40</b> may also be utilized to secure wedge <b>20</b> to torso <b>54</b> of patient <b>50</b>. In operation straps <b>40</b> retain wedge <b>20</b> into axilla <b>56</b> of patient <b>50</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, straps <b>40</b> may retain any of angles <b>22</b>, <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> of wedge <b>20</b> into axilla <b>56</b> of patient <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, wedge <b>20</b> may be fastened to support <b>60</b> by use of straps <b>40</b>. Support <b>60</b> may be a rail of a bed, a chair, a table or any other support structure. Wedge <b>20</b> can also be fastened to a bedside table and used when patient <b>50</b> is either in bed or sitting in a chair. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, straps <b>40</b> are shown restraining wedge <b>20</b> away from patient <b>50</b>. By fastening wedge <b>20</b> to support <b>60</b>, wedge <b>20</b> may be kept away from torso <b>54</b> reducing shear on axilla and torso grafts on patient <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">While this invention has been described as having an exemplary design, the present invention may be further modified within the spirit and scope of this disclosure. This application is therefore intended to cover any variations, uses, or adaptations of the invention using its general principles. Further, this application is intended to cover such departures from the present disclosure as come within known or customary practice in the art to which this invention pertains.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An upper extremity support for use with an upper extremity of a patient lying on their back, where said upper extremity is abducted away from the torso of said patient, the support comprising:
<claim-text>a wedge substantially supporting the upper extremity, the wedge including foam providing cushion for the upper extremity, the wedge having a four sided polygon cross-sectional shape, each side of the four sided polygon cross-sectional shape defining an end, any two adjacent ends of the four ends defining an angle to abduct or adduct the upper extremity, one of the two adjacent ends defining a groove for positioning the upper extremity, a second end of the two adjacent ends defining a relatively flat surface, the second end in contact with the torso of said patient.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the wedge defines a plurality of different angles of abduction and adduction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the wedge defines a plurality of grooves.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the wedge defines an aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> further comprising a strap for fastening the upper extremity to the wedge, the strap being at least partially located in the aperture.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the strap fastens the torso of the patient to the wedge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An upper extremity support for use with an upper extremity of a patient lying on their back, where said upper extremity is abducted away from the torso of said patient, the support comprising:
<claim-text>a wedge substantially supporting the upper extremity, the wedge including foam providing cushion for the upper extremity, the wedge having a four sided polygon cross-sectional shape, each side of the four sided polygon cross-sectional shape defining an end, any two adjacent ends of the four ends defining an angle to abduct or adduct the upper extremity, one of the two adjacent ends defining a groove for positioning the upper extremity, a second end of the two adjacent ends defining a relatively flat surface, the second end in contact with the torso of said patient, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a block substantially supporting the wedge, the block including foam, the block having a triangular cross section, the triangular cross section defining three sides, any one of the three sides configured to support the wedge, the wedge at least partially stacked upon the block, the block positioning the wedge to horizontally adduct the upper extremity out of the plane of the torso of the patient.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the block defines an angle of abduction or adduction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the wedge is supported at an angle between about 15 and at about 45 degrees from horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> wherein the partially stacked wedge provides a plurality of angles of horizontal adduction out of the plane of the torso.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the wedge is supported at an angle substantially about 30 degrees from horizontal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The arm support of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the wedge is supported substantially at the plane of the scapula.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A method of supporting an upper extremity of a patient comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>abducting the upper extremity away from the torso of the patient, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a wedge supporting the upper extremity, the wedge including foam providing cushion for the upper extremity, the wedge having a four sided polygon cross-sectional shape, each side of the four sided polygon cross-sectional shape defining an end, any two adjacent ends of the four ends defining an angle of abduction or adduction, one of the two adjacent ends defining a groove for positioning the upper extremity, second end of the two adjacent ends defining a relatively flat surface, the second end in contact with the torso of said patient.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of fastening the upper extremity to the wedge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of fastening the wedge to a support.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of providing a block supporting the wedge, the block having a triangular cross section, the triangular cross section defining three sides, any one of the three sides configured to support the wedge, the wedge at least partially stacked up on the block, the block positioning the wedge to horizontally adduct the upper extremity out of the plane of the torso of the patient.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of supporting the upper extremity in a horizontal adduction position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of fastening the upper extremity to the wedge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of fastening the wedge to a support.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> further comprising the step of supporting the upper extremity in a substantially scaption position.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
