<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640626-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640626</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11903604</doc-number>
<date>20070924</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2007-0047078</doc-number>
<date>20070515</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>137</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>47</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15387</main-classification>
<further-classification> 15385</further-classification>
<further-classification> 15321</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Suction brush of vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6792648</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lee</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15377</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6823558</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lee</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15391</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6842941</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lee</name>
<date>20050100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15385</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0221281</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Oh</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15387</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0223522</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Song et al.</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15387</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0157422</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Oh et al.</name>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15387</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>20-2003-0008207</doc-number>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>20-2006-0006026</doc-number>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>12</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15385</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15387</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15375-377</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15379</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15380</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15321</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 15322</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080282490</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081120</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Oh</last-name>
<first-name>Jang-Keun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gwangju</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ohlandt, Greeley, Ruggiero &#x26; Perle, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung Gwangju Electronics Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Gwangju</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Dung Van</first-name>
<department>3723</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning is provided. The suction brush includes a brush main body connected to a cleaner main body; a steam generating unit for heating water being supplied from a water storage tank mounted on the brush main body and spraying steam generated by heating the water on the surface to be cleaned; a turbine fan, installed in the brush main body, for generating a rotating force by the drawn-in air that flows into the brush main body; a power transfer unit for being driven by the rotating force of the turbine fan; and at least one pair of duster rotating plates, arranged on a lower part of the suction brush, for being rotated by power being transferred through the power transfer unit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="197.78mm" wi="152.32mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="228.09mm" wi="153.59mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="131.74mm" wi="134.70mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="206.76mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="142.32mm" wi="158.67mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="127.51mm" wi="81.28mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="133.52mm" wi="109.05mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="212.85mm" wi="140.80mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="244.86mm" wi="160.78mm" file="US07640626-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2007-0047078, filed May 15, 2007, in the Korean Intellectual Property Office, the entire disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present disclosure relates generally to a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning. More particularly, the present disclosure relates to a suction brush, which can perform both vacuum cleaning using a suction force and steam cleaning including steam spray on a surface to be cleaned and wiping of the steamed surface.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Generally, a vacuum cleaner, and particularly, a canister type vacuum cleaner, is composed of a main body and a brush, which are separably connected together through a connection tube and a flexible hose, and performs cleaning so as to draw in dust and other foreign materials through the brush, along with the operation of a motor, a filter, and so forth, installed in the main body.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A conventional vacuum cleaner collects dust existing on a surface to be cleaned through a suction brush by using a suction force generated by a suction motor installed in the main body, filters air drawn-in with the dust, and discharges the filtered gas to outside.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, the vacuum cleaner as described above performs cleaning through the suction only, and thus it is difficult to remove dirt or stains stuck on the floor, tile, window, and so forth, using the vacuum cleaner. Accordingly, it is required to directly wipe the dirty region with a wed duster in addition to the vacuum cleaning using the vacuum cleaner, and this causes a user inconvenience.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In order to solve this problem, Korean Patent Registration No. 470320 discloses a steam cleaner that has a vacuum cleaning function and performs both vacuum suction cleaning and steam cleaning at a time. This conventional cleaner for both the steam cleaning and vacuum cleaning is provided with a vacuum suction cleaning part installed in a front portion of the cleaner to draw-in and collect dust, and a steam cleaning part installed in the rear portion of the cleaner to directly spray steam on a duster that rotates to wipe the dirty floor.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">However, according to the conventional cleaner, duster rotating plates are inserted into the bottom surface of the brush. In order to attach/detach dusters to/from the rotating plates, a user must turn the heavy brush over so that the bottom surface of the brush is turned upward and then detach the dusters from the rotating plates.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Also, a water storage tank for supplying water to a steam generating means is non-detachably buried in the brush. Thus, a user can see the water remaining in the water tank only through a narrow inlet of the water tank, when the cap of the tank is removed. Accordingly, it is difficult for the user to accurately grasp the amount of water remaining in the water tank and to recognize when to refill the water tank.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In addition, since the conventional cleaner is of a water tank heating type, a long preheating time for preheating the water, e.g., at least two to four minutes, is required to perform the steam cleaning. Also, since the water always remains in the heater for generating the steam, the heater may corrode or a steam spray nozzle of the heater may be choked due to mold forming in the remaining water.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In addition, any safety device for interrupting the power supply to the heater when the heater is overheated is not provided, and this may cause the damage of a product or the occurrence of fire due to the overheat of the heater.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Embodiments of the present disclosure have been developed in order to substantially solve the above and other problems associated with the conventional arrangement and provide the objectives listed below. An aspect of embodiments of the present disclosure is to provide a suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning that can improve the whole function of the vacuum cleaner.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The foregoing and other objects and advantages are substantially realized by providing a suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning, according to embodiments of the present disclosure, which comprises a brush main body, connected to a cleaner main body having a suction motor and a dust collecting unit, for drawing-in dust existing on a surface to be cleaned together with air by using a suction force generated by the suction motor and guiding the drawn-in dust and air to the dust collecting unit; a steam generating unit for heating water being supplied from a water storage tank mounted on the brush main body and spraying steam generated by heating the water on the surface to be cleaned; a turbine fan, installed in the brush main body, for generating a rotating force by the drawn-in air that flows into the brush main body; a power transfer unit for being driven by the rotating force of the turbine fan; and at least one pair of duster rotating plates, arranged on a lower part of the suction brush, for being rotated by power being transferred through the power transfer unit; wherein each of the at least one pair of duster rotating plates has a part that is detachably attached to the power transfer unit to attach/detach a duster to/from a bottom surface of the duster rotating plate.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The at least one pair of duster rotating plates may be arranged to project over a rear outer part of the brush main body, so as to facilitate separation of projection parts of the pair of duster rotating plates from the brush main body when a user steps on the projection parts.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The power transfer unit may comprise a pair of worm gears extendingly formed on both sides of a shaft of the turbine fan; and worm wheels meshed with the worm gears, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The pair of duster rotating plates may be provided with a pair of coupling protrusions formed on their upper surfaces and detachably coupled to coupling holes formed on the pair of worm wheels. First and second non-slip parts having screw threads may be formed on outer peripheries of the pair of coupling protrusions, respectively, and third and fourth non-slip parts corresponding to the first and second non-slip parts of the coupling protrusions may be formed on inner peripheries of the coupling holes formed on the pair of worm wheels, respectively, wherein the first and second non-slip parts are meshed with the third and fourth non-slip parts, respectively, when the coupling protrusions are coupled to the first and second worm wheels.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The coupling protrusions of the pair of duster rotating plates may be made of an elastic material, and the diameter D<b>2</b> of the coupling protrusions of the pair of duster rotating plates may be larger than the diameter D<b>1</b> of the coupling holes so that the pair of coupling protrusions are pressedly coupled to the coupling holes of the pair of worm wheels.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A part of the water storage tank may be made of a transparent material so that its interior can be seen in a state that the water storage tank is mounted on the brush main body. Accordingly, a user can grasp an amount of water remaining in the water storage tank.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The steam generating unit may comprise a micro-pump, connected to the water storage tank, for micro-pumping the water stored in the water storage tank; and a heater unit for steaming the water being supplied from the micro-pump by instantaneously heating the water and spraying the steam on the surface to be cleaned through a spray nozzle.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The heater unit may comprise an upper case having an inflow tube formed thereon to receive the water being supplied from the micro-pump; and a lower case detachably coupled to the upper case and having a heater that is arranged under an instantaneous heating region of the heater unit to heat the water. Here, the instantaneous heating region may be formed to be continuously inclined downward as the water in the inflow tube flows from a water supply point to a water spray point by gravity.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Accordingly, the water being supplied from the micro-pump may be instantaneously heated, and thus the preheating time can be greatly reduced in comparison to the conventional vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning. In this case, the instantaneous heating region may be formed as a &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove to secure the largest heating area corresponding to a size of the heater unit, and the heater may be formed in a &#x201c;U&#x201d; shape along the instantaneous heating region.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The heater unit may further comprise a temperature control device for intercepting a power being supplied to the heater unit if a sensed temperature of the heater unit is higher than a predetermined temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The suction brush of a vacuum cleaner according to embodiments of the present disclosure may further comprise a bimetal device for preventing overheat of the heater unit when the temperature control device is out of order.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The section brush of a vacuum cleaner according to embodiments of the present disclosure may further comprise a temperature fuse for intercepting the power being supplied to the heater unit to prevent the overheat of the heater unit when the temperature control device and the overheat preventing device are out of order. Consequently, through a multistage safety device, the overheat of the heater unit can be surely prevented.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The above aspects and features of embodiments of the present disclosure will become more apparent by describing certain exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic plan view illustrating the inside of the suction brush illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>:</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic perspective view illustrating a turbine fan and a power transfer unit installed inside a cover illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view of a suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view illustrating another example of a duster support plate and a pinion coupled to each other as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a partially enlarged sectional view illustrating a water storage tank detachably attached to a suction brush;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref> is a plan view of a heater unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7B</figref> is a bottom view of a heater unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref> is a side sectional view of a heater unit illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8B</figref> is a plan view illustrating a heater unit with its upper housing and a heater removed as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Throughout the drawings, like reference numerals will be understood to refer to like parts, components and structures.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure will now be described in detail with reference to the annexed drawings. In the drawings, the same elements are denoted by the same reference numerals throughout the drawings. In the following description, detailed descriptions of known functions and configurations incorporated herein have been omitted for conciseness and clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic plan view illustrating the inside of the suction brush illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic perspective view illustrating a turbine fan and a power transfer unit installed inside a cover illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 3</figref>, comprises a brush main body <b>10</b>, a turbine fan <b>20</b>, a power transfer unit <b>30</b>, first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b>, a water storage tank <b>50</b>, a steam generating unit <b>60</b>, a temperature control device <b>81</b>, an overheat preventing device <b>83</b>, and a temperature fuse <b>85</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The brush main body <b>10</b> comprises an upper main body <b>11</b> and a lower main body <b>13</b>, and a connection tube <b>10</b><i>a </i>that is connected to a suction port <b>13</b><i>a </i>is rotatably coupled to the rear part of the brush main body <b>10</b>. The connection tube <b>10</b><i>a </i>is connected to a connection tube (not illustrated) connected to a cleaner main body (not illustrated) in which a suction motor (not illustrated) and a dust-collecting unit (not illustrated) are installed.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The upper main body <b>11</b> is detachably attached to the lower main body <b>13</b>, and serves to protect various components installed in the lower main body <b>13</b>. In addition, the upper main body <b>11</b> has an accommodating groove <b>14</b> formed thereon to accommodate the water storage tank <b>50</b>, and the accommodating groove <b>14</b> has side walls <b>14</b><i>a </i>and <b>14</b><i>b </i>that are in close contact with both side surfaces of the water storage tank <b>50</b> and a rear wall <b>14</b><i>c </i>that is in close contact with a rear surface of the water storage tank <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The lower main body <b>13</b> has the suction port <b>13</b><i>a </i>formed on a bottom surface thereof to drawn-in air together with dust existing on a surface to be cleaned, and first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b> are provided in the rear of the suction port <b>13</b><i>a</i>. In addition, the lower main body <b>13</b> is provided with the turbine fan <b>20</b>, the power transfer unit <b>30</b>, and the steam generating unit <b>60</b> installed therein. In the lower main body <b>13</b>, a first cover <b>18</b><i>a </i>for covering the turbine fan <b>20</b> and the power transfer unit <b>30</b> to accommodate them separately from the steam generating unit <b>60</b>. In front of the first cover <b>18</b><i>a</i>, a second cover <b>18</b><i>b </i>for guiding the air flow from the suction port <b>13</b><i>a </i>to the first cover <b>18</b><i>a </i>is installed. The first and second covers <b>18</b><i>a </i>and <b>18</b><i>b </i>limit a suction path to the shortest distance between the suction port <b>13</b><i>a </i>and the connection part <b>10</b><i>a </i>so that the dust and air drawn-in from the surface to be cleaned to the suction port <b>13</b><i>a </i>are guided to the connection part <b>10</b><i>a </i>with a minimum pressure loss.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The turbine fan <b>20</b> is rotatably installed on the suction path of the lower main body <b>13</b> that is adjacent to the connection part <b>10</b><i>a</i>, and is rotated by the drawn-in air flowing into the connection part <b>10</b><i>a</i>. In addition, the turbine fan <b>20</b> serves as a rotation power source of the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The power transfer unit <b>30</b> comprises first and second worm gears <b>31</b> and <b>32</b> and first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b>, and serves to transfer the rotating force of the turbine fan <b>20</b> to the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b>. In this case, the first and second worm gears <b>31</b> and <b>32</b> are fixed to both sides of a shaft of the turbine fan <b>20</b>, and extend by a specified length along the shaft of the turbine fan <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b> are meshed with the first and second worm gears <b>31</b> and <b>32</b>, respectively, and first and second rotation support shafts <b>35</b> and <b>36</b> extendingly formed on the lower parts of the worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b> are movably inserted into first and second rotation support protrusions <b>19</b><i>a </i>and <b>19</b><i>b </i>formed on the lower main body. Also, first and second coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b> formed in the center of the first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b> pierce the first worm wheel <b>33</b> and the first rotation support shaft <b>35</b>, and the second worm wheel <b>34</b> and the second rotation support shaft <b>36</b>, respectively. In this case, first and second non-slip parts <b>38</b><i>a </i>and <b>39</b><i>a </i>having screw threads are formed on inner peripheries of the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Dusters <b>71</b> and <b>72</b> are detachably attached to the bottom surfaces of the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b>, and coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> snap-coupled to the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b> of the first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b> are formed on the upper surfaces of the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b> with a specified length.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Third and fourth non-slip parts <b>43</b><i>a </i>and <b>44</b><i>a </i>having screw threads are formed on outer peripheries of the pair of the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> in the same manner as the first and second non-slip parts <b>38</b><i>a </i>and <b>39</b><i>a </i>of the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b>. When the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> are snap-coupled to the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b>, the third and fourth non-slip parts <b>43</b><i>a </i>and <b>44</b><i>a </i>of the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> are meshed with the first and second non-slip parts <b>38</b><i>a </i>and <b>39</b><i>a </i>of the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b>. Accordingly, the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b> accurately receive the rotating force of the first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b>, and thus are rotated together with the first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In addition, the coupling protrusion <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> are provided with snap-coupling parts <b>43</b><i>b </i>and <b>44</b><i>b </i>formed on upper ends of the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b>, of which the diameter is somewhat larger than the diameter of the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b>. It is preferable that the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> of the snap-coupling parts <b>43</b><i>b </i>and <b>44</b><i>b </i>are made of an elastic material having the elasticity so as to facilitate the attachment/detachment of the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> to/from the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Further, parts of the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b> are projected in the rear of the brush main body <b>10</b>, and this is to consider that the user's cleaning position is in the rear of the brush main body <b>10</b>. For example, in order to separate the dusters <b>71</b> and <b>72</b> from the first and second rotating plates for replacement of the dusters, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a user can easily separate the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> from the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b> of the first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b> by stepping on parts of the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b> projected in the rear of the brush main body <b>10</b> (as shown by arrow A) in a state that the user lifts up the rear part of the brush main body <b>10</b> for a specified distance on the basis of the front part of the brush main body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In an alternate embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, in order to receive the rotating force from the first and second worm wheels <b>33</b> and <b>34</b>, the first to fourth non-slip parts <b>38</b><i>a</i>, <b>39</b><i>a</i>, <b>43</b><i>a</i>, and <b>44</b><i>a </i>formed on the coupling holes <b>38</b> and <b>39</b> and the coupling protrusions <b>43</b> and <b>44</b> may be omitted. In this embodiment, the coupling protrusion <b>143</b> of the first duster rotating plate <b>41</b> may be made of an elastic material. In this case, the diameter D<b>2</b> of the coupling protrusion <b>143</b> is somewhat larger than the diameter of the coupling hole <b>138</b> of the first worm wheel <b>33</b>. Accordingly, the coupling protrusion <b>143</b> is pressedly coupled to the coupling hole <b>138</b>, and thus the coupling protrusion <b>143</b> can accurately transfer the rotating force to the first and second duster rotating plates <b>41</b> and <b>42</b> without slipping in the coupling hole <b>138</b>. Although not illustrated in the drawing, the coupling protrusion of the second duster rotating plate <b>42</b> and the coupling hole of the second worm wheel <b>34</b> may be formed in the same manner as the coupling protrusion <b>143</b> and the coupling hole <b>138</b> as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, and <b>6</b>, the water storage tank <b>50</b> has a transparent window <b>51</b> installed thereon so that a user can grasp the amount of water remaining in the water storage tank <b>50</b>, while the water storage tank is mounted in accommodating groove <b>14</b>. A discharge port <b>53</b> for discharging the water stored in the water storage tank <b>50</b> projects from a part of the bottom surface of the water storage tank <b>50</b>. The discharge port <b>53</b> is inserted into a docking protrusion <b>15</b><i>a </i>fixed to the lower main body <b>13</b>, and a connection protrusion <b>15</b><i>b </i>projectingly formed in the docking protrusion <b>15</b><i>a </i>is inserted into the discharge port <b>53</b>. Accordingly, the water stored in the water storage tank <b>50</b> is supplied to the micro-pump <b>61</b> through a first pipe <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In addition, the water storage tank <b>50</b> is locked or unlocked by a locking unit <b>17</b> formed on a rear wall <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the accommodating groove <b>14</b> when it is mounted in the accommodating groove <b>14</b>. The locking unit <b>17</b> comprises a latch <b>17</b><i>a</i>, a coil spring <b>17</b><i>b</i>, and a slide button <b>17</b><i>c</i>. In this case, a front end of the latch <b>17</b><i>a </i>penetrates the rear wall <b>14</b><i>c </i>of the accommodating groove <b>14</b>, and its rear end is resiliently supported by the coil spring <b>17</b><i>b </i>of which one side is supported by a support wall <b>11</b><i>a </i>formed inside the upper main body <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The slide button <b>17</b><i>c </i>is arranged outside the upper main body <b>11</b> for user's easy manipulation, and is movable along a sliding groove <b>11</b><i>b</i>. The slide button <b>17</b><i>c </i>is connected to a part of the latch <b>17</b><i>a</i>, and inserts/separates the latch <b>17</b><i>a </i>into/from a hook groove <b>54</b> formed on the rear part of the water storage tank <b>50</b> to lock/unlock the water storage tank <b>50</b> in/from the accommodating groove <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, <b>7</b>A and <b>7</b>B, the steam generating unit <b>60</b> comprises the micro-pump <b>61</b> and a heater unit <b>63</b>. As described above, the micro-pump <b>61</b> is connected to the water storage tank <b>50</b> through the first pipe <b>62</b>, and pumps the water stored in the water storage tank <b>50</b> into the heater unit <b>63</b> through a second pipe <b>64</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The heater unit <b>63</b> generates steam by heating the water being supplied from the micro-pump <b>61</b>, and sprays the generated steam toward the surface to be cleaned. The heater unit <b>63</b> comprises an upper case <b>64</b>, a lower case <b>65</b>, and a heater <b>66</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The upper case <b>64</b> is detachably coupled to the lower case <b>65</b>, and the upper case <b>64</b> and the lower case <b>65</b> cover the heater <b>66</b> to protect the heater <b>66</b>. The upper case <b>64</b> has an inflow tube <b>64</b><i>a </i>installed therethrough to supply the water transferred from the micro-pump <b>61</b> to the heater unit <b>63</b>. The front end of the inflow tube <b>64</b><i>a </i>that penetrates the upper case <b>64</b> extends to a position corresponding to a water supply point A (See <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7A</figref>) of a &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a </i>of the lower case <b>65</b> to be explained later. Accordingly, a small amount of water flowing into the heater unit <b>63</b> through the inflow tube <b>64</b><i>a </i>is always supplied to a fixed position, i.e., the water supply point A.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In the lower case <b>64</b>, the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped heater <b>66</b>, which corresponds to the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a</i>, is arranged under the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a </i>that has a specified width. The &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a </i>is continuously inclined downward, passing through the water supply points A, B, and C. Accordingly, the water supplied to the water supply point A through the inflow tube <b>64</b><i>a </i>is instantaneously heated by the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped heater <b>66</b> that corresponds to the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a </i>as the water flows from the point A to the point C along the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a</i>. In addition, a spray hole <b>65</b><i>b </i>for guiding the steam to an outside is formed on a part adjacent to the point C of the &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove <b>65</b><i>a</i>, and a spray nozzle <b>65</b><i>c </i>connected to the spray hole <b>65</b><i>b </i>is formed on the outer part of the lower case <b>65</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The temperature control device <b>81</b> may be implemented by a positive temperature coefficient (PTC) thermistor of which the resistance value is increased as the temperature is heightened. The temperature control device <b>81</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, is electrically connected to a power line (not shown) connected to the heater unit <b>63</b>, and serves to sense the temperature of the heater unit <b>63</b> and to interrupt the power being supplied to the heater unit <b>63</b> if the sensed temperature is higher than a predetermined temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The overheat preventing device <b>83</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, is electrically connected to the power line connected to the heater unit <b>63</b>, and serves as a safety device that uses a bimetal and takes the place of the temperature control device <b>81</b> when the temperature control device <b>81</b> is out of order.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The temperature fuse <b>85</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8A</figref>, is electrically connected to the power line connected to the heater unit <b>63</b>, and serves to intercept the power being supplied to the heater unit <b>63</b> so as to prevent the overheat of the heater unit <b>63</b> when both the temperature control device <b>81</b> and the overheat preventing device <b>83</b> are out of order.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">According to the present disclosure, there are provided a microcomputer (not illustrated) and a sensor (not illustrated) for sensing the existence/nonexistence of the water in the water storage tank <b>50</b> or the first pipe <b>62</b>, and if the temperature control device <b>81</b>, the overheat preventing device <b>83</b>, and the temperature fuse <b>85</b> are all out of order, the power supply to the heater unit <b>63</b> is finally intercepted to protect the heater unit <b>63</b> in multiple stages.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As described above, according to the present disclosure, the duster rotating plates are separated from the brush main body by one touch, and thus a user can easily detach or replace the dusters.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Also, since a part of the water storage tank is made of a transparent material, the user can easily grasp the amount of water remaining in the water storage tank, and thus can easily recognize a water supplement time.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In addition, since the water is instantaneously heated as a small amount of water is continuously supplied to the heater unit by the micro-pump, the preheating time can be reduced in comparison to the conventional water tank heating type cleaner. Since no water remains in the heater unit with the end of the steaming, fur forming due to the remaining water is prevented, and the steam spray nozzle of the heater unit is prevented from being clocked due to the fur.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In addition, the damage of a product or the occurrence of fire due to the overheat of the heater unit can be safely prevented in multistage through a plurality of safety devices installed in the heater unit.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The foregoing embodiments and advantages are merely exemplary and are not to be construed as limiting the present disclosure. The present teaching can be readily applied to other types of apparatuses. Also, the description of the exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure is intended to be illustrative, and not to limit the scope of the claims, and many alternatives, modifications, and variations will be apparent to those skilled in the art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A suction brush of a vacuum cleaner for both vacuum cleaning and steam cleaning, comprising:
<claim-text>a brush main body connected to a cleaner main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a steam generating unit heating water being supplied from a water storage tank mounted on the brush main body and spraying steam generated by heating the water on a surface to be cleaned;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a turbine fan, installed in the brush main body, generating a rotating force by drawn-in air that flows into the brush main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power transfer unit driven by the rotating force of the turbine fan; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one pair of duster rotating plates, arranged on a lower part of the brush main body, the least one pair of duster rotating plate being rotated by power being transferred through the power transfer unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the at least one pair of duster rotating plates has a part that is detachably attached to the power transfer unit to attach/detach a duster to/from a bottom surface of the duster rotating plate,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the steam generating unit comprises a micro-pump connected to the water storage tank, the micro-pump pumping the water stored in the water storage tank and a heater unit for steaming the water being supplied from the micro-pump by instantaneously heating the water and spraying the steam on the surface to be cleaned through a spray nozzle, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the heater unit comprises an upper case having an inflow tube formed thereon to receive the water being supplied from the micro-pump and a lower case detachably coupled to the upper case and having a heater that is arranged under an instantaneous heating region of the heater unit to heat the water.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one pair of duster rotating plates are arranged to project over a rear outer part of the brush main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the power transfer unit comprises:
<claim-text>a pair of worm gears extendingly formed on both sides of a shaft of the turbine fan; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>worm wheels meshed with the worm gears, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the pair of duster rotating plates are provided with a pair of coupling protrusions formed on their upper surfaces and detachably coupled to coupling holes formed on the pair of worm wheels.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein outer peripheries of the pair of coupling protrusions comprise first and second non-slip parts having screw threads are formed thereon, respectively, and the coupling protrusions comprise third and fourth non-slip parts formed on inner peripheries of the coupling holes formed on the pair of worm wheels, respectively;
<claim-text>wherein the first and second non-slip parts are meshed with the third and fourth non-slip parts, respectively, when the coupling protrusions are coupled to the first and second worm wheels.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the coupling protrusions of the pair of duster rotating plates are made of an elastic material, and the coupling protrusions having a diameter is larger than a diameter of the coupling holes so that the pair of coupling protrusions are pressedly coupled to the coupling holes of the pair of worm wheels.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the water storage tank comprises a part made of a transparent material so that an interior of the water storage tank can be seen when the water storage tank is mounted on the brush main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the instantaneous heating region is formed to be continuously inclined downward as the water in the inflow tube flows from a water supply point to a water spray point by gravity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the instantaneous heating region is formed as a &#x201c;U&#x201d;-shaped guide groove to secure the largest heating area corresponding to a size of the heater unit, and the heater is formed in a &#x201c;U&#x201d; shape along the instantaneous heating region.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the heater unit further comprises a temperature control device for interrupting a power being supplied to the heater unit if a sensed temperature of the heater unit is higher than a predetermined temperature.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The suction brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the heater unit further comprises a bimetal device for preventing overheat of the heater unit when the temperature control device is out of order.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The section brush of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the heater unit further comprises a temperature fuse for intercepting the power being supplied to the heater unit to prevent the overheat of the heater unit when the temperature control device and the overheat preventing device are out of order. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
