<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640613-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640613</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12424143</doc-number>
<date>20090415</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>A</section>
<class>43</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 12142S</main-classification>
<further-classification> 12142 R</further-classification>
<further-classification> 36 115</further-classification>
<further-classification> 36 34 R</further-classification>
<further-classification> 36 25 R</further-classification>
<further-classification> 36105</further-classification>
<further-classification> 36140</further-classification>
<further-classification> 36142</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Apparatus and method for providing open-heeled foot apparel with improved heel support</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1516840</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Butler</name>
<date>19241100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2362010</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Huff</name>
<date>19441100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2780013</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Voss</name>
<date>19570200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3121962</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gullo</name>
<date>19640200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3413977</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Soble et al.</name>
<date>19681200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 36142</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5481814</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Spencer</name>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6526676</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ledergerber</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6708426</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Erickson et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6792697</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wright et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 12142 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 12142 S</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 36 115</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 36 34 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 36 25 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 36105</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 36140</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 36142</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11609800</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20061212</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7552546</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12424143</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60749894</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20051213</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090199353</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090813</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cockburn</last-name>
<first-name>Alistair</first-name>
<address>
<street>1814 Ft. Douglas Cir.</street>
<city>Salt Lake City</city>
<state>UT</state>
<postcode>84103</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kunzler &#x26; McKenzie</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kavanaugh</last-name>
<first-name>Ted</first-name>
<department>3728</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method of manufacturing an article of foot apparel that includes a platform curved to anticipate the natural movement of a foot. The method includes forming the platform with a heel pad having a geometric center point. The method also includes connecting a retaining covering to the platform that is configured to retain a foot at the front of the platform and to allow the heel of the foot to move freely relative to the heel pad. The article of foot apparel conforms more closely to the actual physiology of the foot and allows the heel of the foot to remain centered in the heel pad when worn.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="180.26mm" wi="114.64mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="202.61mm" wi="94.32mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="224.96mm" wi="109.90mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="219.29mm" wi="118.11mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="211.07mm" wi="117.60mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="214.55mm" wi="107.61mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="210.14mm" wi="102.53mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="196.26mm" wi="128.52mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="217.59mm" wi="104.65mm" file="US07640613-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCES TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional application of U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/609,800, filed Dec. 12, 2006, now U.S. Pat. No. 7,552,546 which claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/749,894, filed Dec. 13, 2005. These applications are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention relates to footwear and more particularly relates to open-heeled foot apparel.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Open-heeled or backless footwear such as sandals, flip-flops, clogs, or the like are a popular clothing item worn by people of all ages in many areas around the world. Though popular as footwear, open-heeled foot apparel often causes discomfort to the wearer because the heel pad of the foot-receiving platform typically does not line up accurately with the actual contact area of the heel. Particularly when the foot is raised, such as when walking, the foot-receiving platform tends to swing toward the outer edge of the foot. As the foot comes down on the foot-receiving platform, the heel tends to contact the platform near the inner edge, which provides minimal support to the foot and often creates a worn heel-contact area off-centered from the available heel pad.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1B</figref> illustrate one embodiment of a flip-flop <b>100</b> similar to those currently available on the market. Flip-flops <b>100</b> typically are a backless sandal held to the foot by a thong between the big toe and the second toe. The flip-flop <b>100</b> commonly comprises a platform <b>110</b>, a heel pad <b>112</b>, and a retaining covering <b>114</b> such as straps <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In certain embodiments, the platform <b>110</b> is made of a flat foam rubber with straps <b>114</b> attached at three contact points <b>116</b> and is generally shaped to contour the foot. Alternatively, flip-flops <b>100</b> and/or open-heeled foot apparel may be made from a variety of materials such as leather, wood, plastic, elastomer and the like. Some backless sandals even include a spiked heel and/or an inclined platform <b>110</b>. The retaining covering <b>114</b> may comprise a single strap <b>114</b> or an intricate infrastructure. Those of skill in the art will recognize that flip-flops <b>100</b> and other backless footwear may be configured from a variety of materials. In addition, the platform <b>110</b>, heel pad <b>112</b>, and retaining covering <b>114</b> may be configured in a variety of styles and/or arrangements.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The retaining covering <b>114</b> may facilitate defining a centerline <b>118</b> that divides the area within the retaining covering <b>114</b> approximately equally. In the depicted embodiment, the centerline <b>118</b> passes through an approximate center of the platform <b>110</b> beginning from a midpoint <b>120</b> located between contact points <b>116</b><i>b </i>and <b>116</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The heel pad <b>112</b> may include the lower portion of the platform <b>110</b>. A geometric center point <b>122</b> may be identified for the heel pad <b>112</b>. A line <b>124</b> passing through the center point <b>122</b> and the midpoint <b>120</b> may facilitate defining an angle <b>126</b>. In certain embodiments, the angle <b>126</b> may represent the natural curve in the foot. Generally, the angle <b>126</b> may be insubstantial and may be about 180 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> illustrates an actual heel contact area <b>128</b> that has a center point <b>129</b>. The heel contact area <b>128</b> is typically located near the inner edge <b>130</b> of the flip-flop <b>100</b>. As the platform <b>110</b> swings during movement, the heel makes contact near the edge <b>130</b> of the platform <b>110</b>, which offers a diminished amount of support to the heel. The inner edge <b>130</b> tends to break down quicker than the outer edge <b>132</b>, creating an uneven, sloped platform <b>110</b>. The user typically experiences discomfort as the heel pad <b>112</b> wears unevenly. In addition, the outer edge <b>132</b> of the flip-flop <b>100</b> typically boasts an excess of unused platform material. The excess material may annoy the user.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In shoes or footwear that have a heel retaining device or back, the problem is somewhat mitigated. In such an embodiment, the platform <b>110</b> and/or sole of the shoe is generally bound to the foot and does not typically swing, as is common with open-heeled footwear. As a result, the foot-receiving platform <b>110</b> generally remains in line with the foot, particularly the heel. Yet the demand for open-heeled footwear continues to remain high.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">From the foregoing discussion, it should be apparent that a need exists for an open-heeled article of foot apparel that anticipates the swinging movement of the foot-receiving platform and positions the center of the heel pad where the heel of the foot is most likely to strike. Beneficially, such an article of foot apparel would provide popular open-heeled footwear that is comfortable to wear and is long-lasting. Providing a heel pad centered where the heel of the foot is most likely to strike would provide better heel support to the user and would potentially increase the life of the foot apparel.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The present invention has been developed in response to the present state of the art, and in particular, in response to the problems and needs in the art that have not yet been fully solved by currently available open-heeled footwear. Accordingly, the present invention has been developed to provide an article of foot apparel that overcomes many or all of the above-discussed shortcomings in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The apparatus, in one embodiment, is configured to provide a curved platform for receiving a foot that anticipates the natural movement of the foot and comprises a heel pad having a geometric center point. The apparatus further comprises a retaining covering connected to the platform that retains a foot at the front of the platform and allows the heel of the foot to move freely. The retaining covering has a center line wherein a substantial angle is created at the point of intersection of a line passing through the geometric center point of the heel pad and the center line of the retaining covering. In certain embodiments, the substantial angle is more severe than the natural curve of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A method of the present invention is also presented for manufacturing an article of foot apparel. In one embodiment, the method includes providing a platform and a retaining covering having a centerline connected to the platform. The method also includes determining a heel contact area and aligning a heel pad to a center point of a heel contact area wherein a substantial angle is created at the point of intersection of a line passing through the geometric center point of the heel pad and the center line.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Reference throughout this specification to features, advantages, or similar language does not imply that all of the features and advantages that may be realized with the present invention should be or are in any single embodiment of the invention. Rather, language referring to the features and advantages is understood to mean that a specific feature, advantage, or characteristic described in connection with an embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of the present invention. Thus, discussion of the features and advantages, and similar language, throughout this specification may, but do not necessarily, refer to the same embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Furthermore, the described features, advantages, and characteristics of the invention may be combined in any suitable manner in one or more embodiments. One skilled in the relevant art will recognize that the invention may be practiced without one or more of the specific features or advantages of a particular embodiment. In other instances, additional features and advantages may be recognized in certain embodiments that may not be present in all embodiments of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">These features and advantages of the present invention will become more fully apparent from the following description and appended claims, or may be learned by the practice of the invention as set forth hereinafter.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In order that the advantages of the invention will be readily understood, a more particular description of the invention briefly described above will be rendered by reference to specific embodiments that are illustrated in the appended drawings. Understanding that these drawings depict only typical embodiments of the invention and are not therefore to be considered to be limiting of its scope, the invention will be described and explained with additional specificity and detail through the use of the accompanying drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref> is a plan view illustrating one embodiment of a typical flip-flop with a centralized heel pad;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref> is a plan view illustrating one embodiment of a typical flip-flop with an offset heel contact area;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> is a plan view illustrating one embodiment of a flip-flop in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> is a plan view illustrating one embodiment of a flip-flop in accordance with the present invention relative to the flip-flop illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1B</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view illustrating one embodiment of a sandal in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plan view illustrating another embodiment of a sandal in accordance with the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic flow chart diagram illustrating one embodiment of a method for providing open-heeled foot apparel with improved support in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a plan view illustrating one embodiment of the sandal in accordance with the present invention;</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Reference throughout this specification to &#x201c;one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;an embodiment,&#x201d; or similar language means that a particular feature, structure, or characteristic described in connection with the embodiment is included in at least one embodiment of the present invention. Thus, appearances of the phrases &#x201c;in one embodiment,&#x201d; &#x201c;in an embodiment,&#x201d; and similar language throughout this specification may, but do not necessarily, all refer to the same embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Furthermore, the described features, structures, or characteristics of the invention may be combined in any suitable manner in one or more embodiments. In the following description, numerous specific details are provided to give a thorough understanding of embodiments of the invention. One skilled in the relevant art will recognize, however, that the invention may be practiced without one or more of the specific details, or with other methods, components, materials, and so forth. In other instances, well-known structures, materials, or operations are not shown or described in detail to avoid obscuring aspects of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> depicts one embodiment of a flip-flop <b>200</b> in accordance with the present invention. The flip-flop <b>200</b> is similar to the flip-flop <b>100</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1A-1B</figref>; however, a platform <b>210</b> includes a heel pad <b>212</b> angled to provide improved support to the heel of the wearer. In certain embodiments, the platform <b>210</b> is curved to anticipate the natural curvature and movement of the foot.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The curved platform <b>210</b>, according to one embodiment, positions the heel pad <b>212</b> relative to the predicted heel contact area <b>128</b>. In certain embodiments, the center point <b>129</b> of the heel contact area <b>128</b> comprises the approximate geometric center point of the heel pad <b>212</b>. Aligning the heel pad <b>212</b> with the heel contact area <b>128</b> enables the heel to have substantial support on all sides. In addition, the heel pad <b>212</b> wears more evenly as the inner edge <b>130</b> receives about equal wear as the outer edge <b>132</b>. Accordingly, the heel contact area <b>128</b> wears longer than with a traditional heel pad <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As mentioned, the traditional heel pad <b>112</b> may be aligned with the natural curvature of the foot represented by angle <b>126</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>. In theory, the heel pad <b>112</b> should provide centralized support to the heel. However, the movement and shape of the foot as well as the retaining covering <b>114</b> affect where the heel actually contacts the platform <b>110</b> and <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In the depicted embodiments, the straps <b>114</b> exert uneven pressure on opposing sides of the foot. The inner strap <b>114</b><i>a </i>typically exerts less pressure on the foot than the outer strap <b>114</b><i>b </i>under certain conditions. In one embodiment, when the foot is pressed down against the platform <b>110</b> and generally aligned with the shape of the platform <b>110</b>, the outer strap <b>114</b><i>b </i>retains the foot by providing tension against the corresponding side of the foot. In contrast, the inner strap <b>114</b><i>a </i>under the same condition typically remains relatively loose.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">When the wearer lifts her foot, however, the tension generally shifts from the outer strap <b>114</b><i>b </i>and becomes more balanced between the two straps <b>114</b><i>a </i>and <b>114</b><i>b</i>, causing the heel pad <b>112</b> of the platform <b>110</b> to swing outward. As the wearer steps down again, the tension of both straps <b>114</b><i>a </i>and <b>114</b><i>b </i>cause the heel to contact the platform in an offset position at about where the heel contact area <b>128</b> is outlined with a dotted line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1B</figref>. Altering the configuration of the straps <b>114</b> would alter the tension on the foot, but the problem of outward movement and uneven wear on the heel pad <b>112</b> would remain.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, rather than altering the straps <b>114</b>, the flip-flop in the depicted embodiment adjusts the heel pad <b>212</b> to mitigate the problem. As a result, the user experiences greater comfort and improved heel support. The heel pad <b>212</b> is aligned with the movement of the foot in conjunction with the flip-flop <b>200</b>. Uneven wear and related pains are minimized and extraneous platform material may be eliminated.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The intersection of the centerline <b>118</b> and a line <b>216</b> passing through the geometric center point <b>129</b> preferably creates a substantial angle <b>218</b>. The upper portion of the flip-flop <b>200</b> with the retaining covering <b>114</b> may function as described above. Yet the curved platform <b>210</b> provides additional support to the heel when the wearer steps down on the platform <b>210</b>. The curvature of the heel pad <b>212</b> prevents the outer edge <b>220</b> from swinging past the heel of the foot in certain embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The platform <b>210</b> and the heel pad <b>212</b> may or may not be a single unit. The heel pad <b>212</b> may be attached to the platform <b>210</b> in certain embodiments. In one embodiment, the heel pad <b>212</b> is personalized for the wearer and may be applied to an existing article of open-heeled footwear. The platform <b>210</b> may be altered to suit an individual wearer. In one embodiment, the superfluous platform material on the outer edge <b>132</b> may be removed and may be used to increase the support provided to the inner edge <b>130</b>, creating a substantial angle <b>218</b>. In another embodiment, additional material may be added to the inner edge <b>130</b> of an existing flip-flip <b>100</b> to increase the amount of support provided to the heel contact area <b>128</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In the depicted embodiment, the heel pad <b>212</b> curves at about where the retaining covering <b>114</b> contacts the platform at holes <b>116</b><i>b </i>and <b>116</b><i>c</i>. In certain embodiments, the curve or angle <b>218</b> is more severe than the natural curve of the foot illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, which is commonly emulated in footwear.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2B</figref> illustrates the improved flip-flop <b>200</b> relative to the traditional flip-flop <b>100</b>. The angle <b>222</b> may represent the amount of alteration of the curve <b>218</b> from the natural curve <b>126</b> of the foot illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>. In certain embodiments, the curve <b>218</b> may be more severe than the natural curve of the foot by greater than 20 degrees with a preferred difference of about 30 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates an alternative embodiment of a backless sandal <b>300</b> with a platform <b>310</b> for receiving a foot, a heel pad <b>312</b>, a retaining covering <b>314</b>, contact points <b>316</b>, a centerline <b>318</b>, a midpoint <b>320</b>, and a geometric center point <b>322</b>, which may align with the center point <b>129</b> of the heel contact area <b>128</b> in certain embodiments. The retaining covering <b>314</b> and the contact points <b>316</b> may facilitate defining the centerline <b>318</b>, which approximately equally divides the area between the retaining covering <b>314</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In addition, the contact points <b>316</b><i>a </i>and <b>316</b><i>b </i>may define the midpoint <b>320</b> in certain embodiments. Alternatively, the midpoint <b>320</b> may be located above or below the line <b>321</b> that passes through contact point <b>316</b><i>a </i>and <b>316</b><i>b</i>. The midpoint <b>320</b> may be defined by the centerline <b>318</b> and the intersection point of line <b>324</b> in one embodiment. In the depicted embodiment, the line <b>324</b> passes through the geometric center point <b>322</b> and defines the approximate centerline of the heel pad <b>312</b>. The heel pad <b>312</b> may be positioned relative to the heel contact area <b>128</b> as discussed above.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In certain embodiments, the geometric center point <b>322</b> of the heel pad <b>312</b> and the center point <b>129</b> of the heel contact area may be encompassed within the heel contact area <b>128</b> and/or within a central area <b>326</b> of the heel pad <b>312</b> and are not necessarily directly aligned. Those of skill in the art will recognize a benefit of the invention without precise alignment of well-defined points, such as the referenced geometric points <b>322</b>, <b>129</b>. Thus a projected central area <b>326</b> containing the geometric center point <b>322</b> and the heel contact center point <b>129</b> is within the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The retaining covering <b>314</b> may comprise various shapes and forms as is known in the art. In the depicted embodiment, the retaining covering <b>314</b> comprises a single strap <b>314</b> connected to the platform <b>310</b>. The foot may slide and the platform <b>310</b> may shift as discussed above. A heel contact area <b>128</b> may be determined and the heel pad <b>312</b> may be adjusted to support the heel and to anticipate regular motion.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an alternative embodiment of a backless sandal <b>400</b>. The sandal <b>400</b> as depicted includes a curved platform <b>410</b>, a heel pad <b>412</b>, a retaining covering <b>414</b>, contact points <b>416</b>, a centerline <b>418</b>, a midpoint <b>420</b>, and a geometric center point <b>422</b>. The retaining covering <b>414</b>, which comprises a toe strap <b>414</b><i>a </i>and an angled strap <b>414</b><i>b</i>, has an approximate centerline <b>418</b> that intersects with line <b>424</b> at about the midpoint <b>420</b>, creating a substantial angle <b>426</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The midpoint <b>420</b> may be relative to the main strap <b>414</b><i>b </i>extending between contact point <b>416</b><i>a </i>and <b>416</b><i>b </i>in certain embodiments. Alternatively, the midpoint <b>420</b> may be relative to the established centerline <b>418</b> and the platform <b>410</b>. The line <b>424</b>, in the depicted embodiment, defines a line passing through the determined midpoint <b>420</b> and the geometric center point <b>422</b> of the heel pad <b>412</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The depicted style of sandal <b>400</b> benefits from substantially aligning the heel pad <b>412</b> with the heel contact area <b>128</b>. The geometric center point <b>422</b> of the heel pad <b>412</b> consequently is located at a substantial angle from the center line <b>418</b> of the retaining covering <b>414</b>. The angled heel pad <b>412</b> provides greater comfort and support to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The schematic flow chart diagram that follows is generally set forth as a logical flow chart diagram. As such, the depicted order and labeled steps are indicative of one embodiment of the presented method. Other steps and methods may be conceived that are equivalent in function, logic, or effect to one or more steps, or portions thereof, of the illustrated method. Additionally, the format and symbols employed are provided to explain the logical steps of the method and are understood not to limit the scope of the method. Although various arrow types and line types may be employed in the flow chart diagrams, they are understood not to limit the scope of the corresponding method. Additionally, the order in which a particular method occurs may or may not strictly adhere to the order of the corresponding steps shown.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates one embodiment of a method <b>500</b> for providing open-heeled footwear with improved heel support. The method <b>500</b> begins <b>502</b> and includes providing <b>504</b> an article of foot apparel having a platform and a retaining covering, determining <b>506</b> an actual heel contact area, and substantially aligning <b>508</b> the heel pad with the center of the heel contact area. Then the method <b>500</b> ends <b>510</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In certain embodiments, an article of open-heeled foot apparel may be customized to suit a particular foot and/or walking pattern. The heel pad may be aligned such that a substantial angle is created at the point of intersection of a line passing through the geometric center point of the heel pad and the center line of the retaining covering. The platform may be curved to anticipate the natural movement of the foot relative to the article of foot apparel.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In certain embodiments, the heel pad may be attached to the platform in order to substantially align <b>508</b> the heel pad with the center point of a heel contact area. In another embodiment, a platform may be formed as a single unit with a heel pad substantially aligned <b>508</b> with a center point of a heel contact area. In one embodiment, a platform material may be attached to the platform to supplement the support of the existing heel pad.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a further way of describing the curvature of the flip-flop <b>200</b> of the present invention. In this depiction, the intersection of the centerline <b>119</b> and the line <b>216</b> passing through the geometric center point <b>129</b> preferably creates a substantial angle <b>219</b>. In certain embodiments, the curve or angle <b>219</b> is more severe than the natural curve of the foot illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1A</figref>, which is commonly emulated in footwear. In certain embodiments, the curve <b>219</b> may be more severe than the natural curve of the foot by greater than 20 degrees. In one embodiment, the angle <b>219</b> is about 30 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The present invention may be embodied in other specific forms without departing from its spirit or essential characteristics. The described embodiments are to be considered in all respects only as illustrative and not restrictive. The scope of the invention is, therefore, indicated by the appended claims rather than by the foregoing description. All changes which come within the meaning and range of equivalency of the claims are to be embraced within their scope.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of manufacturing an article of foot apparel, the method comprising:
<claim-text>forming a platform for receiving a foot, the platform comprising a forward portion and a heel pad;</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting a retaining covering to the platform, the retaining covering configured to retain a foot at the front of the platform and to allow the heel of a foot retained by the retaining covering to move freely relative to the heel pad; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>defining a first heel contact area and a second heel contact area on the heel pad, the second heel contact area being inwardly offset from the first heel contact area, and the heel pad being inwardly curved relative to the forward portion to define the second heel contact area about an approximate geometric center of the heel pad; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein connecting the retaining covering to the platform comprises positioning the retaining covering on the platform such that the retaining covering positions a heel of a foot retained by the retaining covering substantially over the first heel contact area of the heel pad when the foot is initially retained by the retaining covering prior to a stepping event and causes the platform to move outwardly away from the foot such that after the stepping event the heel of the foot is substantially over the second heel contact area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the platform is curved to anticipate the natural movement of the foot during a stepping event.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming the platform comprises shaping the platform such that the forward portion is longitudinally aligned with a first centerline extending through a geometric center of the first heel contact area and the heel pad is longitudinally aligned with a second centerline extending through the geometric center of the heel pad, and wherein an acute angle defined between the first and second centerlines is greater than zero.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the retaining covering comprises a pair of straps, and wherein connecting the pair of straps to the platform comprises positioning the straps relative to the platform such that the first centerline approximately equally divides the area between the straps.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the straps are positioned on the platform such that the straps exert uneven pressure on opposing sides of the foot when the foot is initially retained by the straps prior to a stepping event and exert a substantially even pressure on opposing sides of the foot during the stepping event.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein forming the platform comprises shaping the platform such that the acute angle defined between the first and second centerlines is more than 20 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein forming the platform comprises forming the heel pad and the forward portion as a single unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method of manufacturing an article of foot apparel, the method comprising:
<claim-text>forming a platform for supporting a foot, the platform comprising a forward portion and a rearward heel pad, the heel pad having a geometric center point; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting at least first and second straps to the platform for retaining a foot against the forward portion of the platform, a first end of the first strap being connected at a first location on the platform and a second end of the first strap being connected at a second location on the platform, and a first end of the second strap being connected at approximately the first location on the platform and a second end of the second strap being connected at a third location on the platform, wherein the second and third locations are spaced-apart;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein connecting the first and second straps to the platform comprises positioning the straps relative to the platform such that an acute angle defined between a first line passing through the first location and a midpoint between the spaced-apart second and third locations and a second line passing through the geometric center point of the heel pad and the midpoint between the spaced-apart second and third locations is at least approximately 20 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the acute angle is at least approximately 30 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein forming the platform comprises shaping the platform such that the geometric center point of the heel pad is substantially the same as the geometric center point of a heel contact area on the heel pad associated with the location a heel of a foot retained by the straps contacts following a stepping event.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the straps are positioned on the platform such that the straps exert uneven pressure on opposing sides of a foot when the foot is initially retained by the straps prior to a stepping event and exert a substantially even pressure on opposing sides of the foot during the stepping event.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein forming the platform comprises forming the forward portion and rearward heel pad as a monolithic one-piece construction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second straps allow a heel of a foot retained by the straps to move freely relative to the heel pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising defining a first heel contact area and a second heel contact area on the heel pad, the second heel contact area being inwardly offset from the first heel contact area, and the heel pad being inwardly curved relative to the forward portion to define the second heel contact area about the approximate geometric center of the heel pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
