<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07644450-20100112.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091229" date-publ="20100112">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07644450</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100112</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11152134</doc-number>
<date>20050613</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>646</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>03</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>052</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100112</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4213</main-classification>
<further-classification>  4216</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Toilet ventilation system</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>136105</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Smith</name>
<date>18730200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>955518</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lauphear</name>
<date>19100400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1563691</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>De Cola</name>
<date>19251200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2329221</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sanford</name>
<date>19430900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>  4213</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3735429</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bondonio</name>
<date>19730500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3805304</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ikehata</name>
<date>19740400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3939506</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pearson</name>
<date>19760200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3942200</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pearson</name>
<date>19760300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4103370</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Arnold</name>
<date>19780800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4133060</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Webb</name>
<date>19790100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4168553</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Studer</name>
<date>19790900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4800596</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Menge</name>
<date>19890100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5029346</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fernald, Sr.</name>
<date>19910700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5255395</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Millette</name>
<date>19931000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5321856</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gatesi</name>
<date>19940600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5351344</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Phillips</name>
<date>19941000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5539938</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tubbs</name>
<date>19960700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00018">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5570477</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Rodriguez</name>
<date>19961100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00019">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6073275</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Klopocinski</name>
<date>20000600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00020">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6237163</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Guzzo et al.</name>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00021">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6295656</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tillen</name>
<date>20011000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4213</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>  4216</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60579011</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20040612</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20050273917</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20051215</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lapossy</last-name>
<first-name>Kenneth A.</first-name>
<address>
<street>18039 Falling Leaves Rd.</street>
<city>Strongsville</city>
<state>OH</state>
<postcode>44136</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>D.A. Stauffer Patent Services</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Fetsuga</last-name>
<first-name>Robert M</first-name>
<department>3751</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A premium ventilated toilet having an automated toilet ventilation system for removing noxious fumes from a bowl area of the toilet is disclosed. The ventilation system is mostly built-in to the toilet (e.g., ventilation ducts, and sensors) so that it is unobtrusive and attractive looking, however the active parts (e.g., a blower unit containing a blower impeller, a backflow shutoff valve, and electronic control circuitry) are contained in an simple housing that is unobtrusively and removably attached to the surface (preferably on the side) of the toilet base for simplified installation, maintenance, and replacement as needed. Automated operation is enabled by a non-contact occupancy (proximity) sensor and a flush sensor, both preferably built into a flush handle of the toilet. Detection of occupancy causes the ventilation system to operate and flushing turns it off.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="106.85mm" wi="146.39mm" file="US07644450-20100112-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="223.35mm" wi="149.94mm" file="US07644450-20100112-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="212.26mm" wi="168.74mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07644450-20100112-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="211.33mm" wi="161.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07644450-20100112-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="203.54mm" wi="150.37mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07644450-20100112-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="219.63mm" wi="166.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07644450-20100112-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/579,011, filed Jun. 12, 2004 by Kenneth A. Lapossy, and which is incorporated in its entirety by reference herein.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to water closets (e.g., lavatory), more particularly to those having ventilation for exhaust of noxious fumes, and most particularly wherein the ventilation means are physically associated with a flush toilet.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">It has long been desirable to ventilate noxious fumes from toilet enclosures (witness the half-moon cutout in outhouse doors). It has become even more desirable since the advent of indoor plumbing, as evidenced by U.S. Pat. No. 136,105 (Smith; 1873) which discloses an exhaust flue connected at an upward angle to the bottom of a toilet bowl, before the trap.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Typically, the problem is resolved by providing a ventilation fan that exhausts air from the toilet enclosure, but it is not always convenient or even possible to vent the exhausted air to the outside of a building. A less common alternative is to cause the fumes to be passed into the sewage outlet of a toilet beyond a fume trap (typically a water filled drain trap). According to typical building codes and common practice the sewage outlet leads directly to a sewer stack that is vented to the outside.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A relatively simple way to implement this kind of ventilation is by using a retrofittable device such as is disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,570,477 (Rodriguez; 1996) wherein a portable ventilator draws air from the toilet bowl and exhausts it via a tube that extends through the water trap and into the sewer pipe.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Additional work is required (e.g., replacing the floor flange) in order to install a retrofit device as disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 5,351,344 (Phillips; 1994) wherein an evacuation system can be retrofitted on a standard water closet (see FIGS. 1, 2, 4). A wet/dry vacuum bypass motor pulls air (or overflow fluid) from under the toilet seat and exhausts into a modified closet ring (37) (floor flange) having a down-angled exhaust outlet (42). A pressure switch mounts under the toilet seat for automatic operation limited by a timer. A manual override switch is also provided. The system plugs into an AC power wall outlet. U.S. Pat. No. 6,295,656 (Tillen; 2001) discloses a retrofittable system with an upper insert (24) mountable between the tank and top of the bowl, and a lower insert (30) mountable between the bowl and the floor for communicating with the sewer pipe opening. A fan (26) between the inserts draws gases in through the bowl water spray openings under the rim. A backflow valve flap (82) is used to prevent backflow. The fan can be operated by water, a hand-cranked spring drive, or a battery-operated electric motor. Manual activation of the fan is by means of a push button switch (98, see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>) that is incorporated into the tank flush handle, and the fan is deactivated by flushing.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Other ventilation systems are less visible due to being built into a toilet, thereby requiring replacement of the toilet with a new toilet having a built-in ventilation system. U.S. Pat. No. 4,800,596 (Menge; 1989) discloses a built-in system drawing gas from the bowl through passages into the water storage tank, through a liquid seal, a vacuum blower, and out into the sewer pipe. The blower is operated by a float switch in the tank. A major concern of this patent appears to be the liquid seal for preventing backflow of sewer gases. U.S. Pat. No. 4,103,370 (Arnold; 1978) discloses a toilet with a built-in system including an intake manifold interposed between the seat and top periphery of the bowl. A suction blower is mounted inside the tank and blows air out through a one way, rubber flap-type check valve (107, FIGS. 10-14) and a deflector (104<i>c</i>) into the discharge duct (105) after the trap, and leading to the sewer pipe. It is automated with a pressure switch under the seat and an optional pressure pad on the floor. A timer continues running the blower for a predetermined time after a user leaves. U.S. Pat. No. 6,073,275 (Klopocinski; 2000) discloses a built-in system that draws gases from the bowl, through a fan (64), an odor extraction trap and valve assembly (66), and vents through a downward angled nozzle (53) into the sewer pipe flange shared by the toilet outlet (50). It uses the trap 66 instead of an outlet valve to prevent backflow. U.S. Pat. No. 3,805,304 (Ikehata; 1974) discloses a built-in system providing a separate exhaust channel (7) under the bowl lip, a fan blade (15) in a chamber (11) built-in to the toilet, the fan being driven by an external motor (13), and an exit passage (16) from the chamber into the sewer drain. There does not appear to be any separate backflow prevention devices. The fan is controlled by a floor mounted pressure switch (17).</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is an object of the present invention to provide a high quality, premium toilet with a toilet ventilation system that automatically operates to remove odors from the toilet bowl area in a direct and efficient manner. It is an object to make the ventilation system mostly built in so that it is relatively unobtrusive in appearance. It is an object to removably attach the active parts unobtrusively on the exterior of the toilet for simplified installation, maintenance, and replacement as needed. It is an object to automatically prevent backflow of sewer gases and/or sewage through the toilet ventilation system. It is an object to enable normal toilet use when the active parts are not attached to the toilet.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to the invention a ventilated toilet for exhausting fumes from a bowl area of the toilet to a sewage stack vent associated with the toilet comprises: a built-in vent exhaust duct extending upward from a bowl vent hole and then downward to an exhaust duct outlet hole; a built-in vent exit duct extending downward from an exit duct opening to a toilet drain duct; a blower unit removably attached to an external surface of the ventilated toilet, and communicating with the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening, wherein the blower unit comprises: a housing containing a motor/electrical compartment and a separate sealed airway extending from a blower intake hole downward to a blower output hole; a fan impeller in the airway; a motor mounted in the motor/electrical compartment, but sealingly connected to the fan impeller; a backflow shutoff valve comprising a stopper in the airway and an actuator linked for moving the stopper; and a control circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises a flush detecting sensor electrically connected to the control circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises a proximity sensor electrically connected to the control circuit. Preferably the proximity sensor is built-in to a flush handle of the ventilated toilet. Also preferably the ventilated toilet further comprises a flush detecting sensor electrically connected to the control circuit wherein the flush detecting sensor is built-in to the flush handle; and the proximity sensor and the flush detecting sensor are connected to the control circuit by a sensor cable that is detachably connected to the blower unit.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises the blower unit being removably attached to a side surface of a base of the ventilated toilet.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises the exhaust duct outlet hole exiting through the external surface at a downward angle; wherein the exit duct opening is below the exhaust duct outlet hole and enters through the external surface at a downward angle; the blower output hole has a downward and outward hooking lower mounting finger for hooking over the bottom of the exit duct opening, thereby aligning the blower output hole with the exit duct opening; and the blower intake hole has a vertically adjustable upper mounting finger that hooks upward and outward for adjustably hooking over the top of the exhaust duct outlet hole, thereby aligning the blower intake hole with the exhaust duct outlet hole. Preferably the ventilated toilet further comprises a flat mounting surface around the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises a service cover shaped to sealingly cover the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises an electric actuator for the backflow shutoff valve that is a solenoid built into the motor.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to the invention the ventilated toilet further comprises a mechanical actuator for the backflow shutoff valve, wherein the actuator comprises: an externally threaded arbor extending from a drive shaft of the motor and contained within a hub of the impeller; a spline on the inside diameter of the impeller hub; a nut-hub extending from a stopper of the backflow shutoff valve; an internal thread in the nut-hub that screwingly mates with the external threads on the arbor; and a spline on the outside diameter of the nut-hub such that the nut-hub spline slidingly but non-rotatingly fits within the spline on the inside diameter of the impeller hub.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to the invention a toilet ventilation system for exhausting fumes from a bowl area of a toilet to a sewage stack vent associated with the toilet comprises: a vent exhaust duct built-in to the toilet and extending upward from a bowl vent hole and then downward to an exhaust duct outlet hole; a vent exit duct built-in to the toilet and extending downward from an exit duct opening to a toilet drain duct; a blower unit removably attached to an external surface of the toilet, and communicating with the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening, wherein the blower unit comprises: a housing containing a motor/electrical compartment and a separate sealed airway extending downward from a blower intake hole to a blower output hole; a fan impeller in the airway; a motor mounted in the motor/electrical compartment, but sealingly connected to the fan impeller; a backflow shutoff valve comprising a stopper in the airway and an actuator linked for moving the stopper; and a control circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to the invention the toilet ventilation system further comprises a flush detecting sensor electrically connected to the control circuit, and positioned to detect flushing of the toilet.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to the invention the toilet ventilation system further comprises a proximity sensor electrically connected to the control circuit, and positioned to detect an occupant sitting on a seat of the toilet. Preferably the toilet ventilation system further comprises a flush detecting sensor electrically connected to the control circuit, and positioned to detect flushing of the toilet; wherein: the flush detecting sensor and the proximity sensor are built-in to a flush handle of the ventilated toilet; and the proximity sensor and the flush detecting sensor are connected to the control circuit by a sensor cable that is detachably connected to the blower unit.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to the invention the toilet ventilation system further comprises a construction wherein: the exhaust duct outlet hole exits through the external surface at a downward angle; the exit duct opening is below the exhaust duct outlet hole and enters through the external surface at a downward angle; the blower output hole has a downward and outward hooking lower mounting finger for hooking over the bottom of the exit duct opening, thereby aligning the blower output hole with the exit duct opening; and the blower intake hole has a vertically adjustable upper mounting finger that hooks upward and outward for adjustably hooking over the top of the exhaust duct outlet hole, thereby aligning the blower intake hole with the exhaust duct outlet hole.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">According to the invention the toilet ventilation system further comprises an electric actuator for the backflow shutoff valve that is a solenoid built into the motor.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to the invention the toilet ventilation system further comprises a mechanical actuator for the backflow shutoff valve, wherein the actuator comprises: an externally threaded arbor extending from a drive shaft of the motor and contained within a hub of the impeller; a spline on the inside diameter of the impeller hub; a nut-hub extending from a stopper of the backflow shutoff valve; an internal thread in the nut-hub that screwingly mates with the external threads on the arbor; and a spline on the outside diameter of the nut-hub such that the nut-hub spline slidingly but non-rotatingly fits within the spline on the inside diameter of the impeller hub.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">According to the invention a method for exhausting fumes from a bowl area of a toilet to a sewage stack vent associated with the toilet comprises the steps of: building a vent exhaust duct into the toilet, the duct extending upward from a bowl vent hole then back downward to an exhaust duct outlet hole; building a vent exit duct into the toilet, the duct extending from an exit duct opening located below the exhaust duct outlet hole, downward to a toilet drain duct; removably attaching a blower unit to an external surface of the toilet, such that the blower unit communicates with the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening, wherein the blower unit comprises: a housing containing a motor/electrical compartment and a separate airway extending from a blower intake hole downward to a blower output hole; a fan impeller in the airway; a motor mounted in the motor/electrical compartment, but sealingly connected to the fan impeller; a backflow shutoff valve comprising a stopper in the airway and an actuator linked for moving the stopper; and a control circuit; and using the control circuit to initiate a ventilation activity including the steps of: opening the backflow shutoff valve, thereby moving the stopper to open the blower unit airway; and turning on the motor for rotating the fan impeller to draw fumes from the bowl through the vent exhaust duct, out the exhaust duct outlet hole and thereby into the communicating blower unit airway; and to direct the fumes past the open backflow shutoff valve stopper, thereafter to pass out of the blower output hole of the airway and thereby through the communicating exit duct opening into the vent exit duct thereby to pass out through the toilet drain duct into a sewage stack which has the sewage stack vent.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to the invention the method further comprises the steps of: using a non-contact proximity sensor to trigger the control circuit to initiate the ventilation activity whenever the proximity sensor detects a user that is close enough to sit on a seat of the toilet; and using a flush detecting sensor to trigger the control circuit to halt the ventilation activity when the toilet is flushed, wherein the step of halting the ventilation activity comprises turning off the motor and causing the backflow shutoff valve stopper to close in a way that blocks passage of gaseous, liquid or solid material through the blower unit airway.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Other objects, features and advantages of the invention will become apparent in light of the following description thereof.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Reference will be made in detail to preferred embodiments of the invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawing figures. The figures are intended to be illustrative, not limiting. Although the invention is generally described in the context of these preferred embodiments, it should be understood that it is not intended to limit the spirit and scope of the invention to these particular embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Certain elements in selected ones of the drawings may be illustrated not-to-scale, for illustrative clarity. The cross-sectional views, if any, presented herein may be in the form of &#x201c;slices&#x201d;, or &#x201c;near-sighted&#x201d; cross-sectional views, omitting certain background lines which would otherwise be visible in a true cross-sectional view, for illustrative clarity.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Elements of the figures can be numbered such that similar (including identical) elements may be referred to with similar numbers in a single drawing. For example, each of a plurality of elements collectively referred to as <b>199</b> may be referred to individually as <b>199</b><i>a</i>, <b>199</b><i>b</i>, <b>199</b><i>c</i>, etc. Or, related but modified elements may have the same number but are distinguished by primes. For example, <b>109</b>, <b>109</b>&#x2032;, and <b>109</b>&#x2033; are three different elements which are similar or related in some way, but have significant modifications, e.g., a tire <b>109</b> having a static imbalance versus a different tire <b>109</b>&#x2032; of the same design, but having a couple imbalance. Such relationships, if any, between similar elements in the same or different figures will become apparent throughout the specification, including, if applicable, in the claims and abstract.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The structure, operation, and advantages of the present preferred embodiment of the invention will become further apparent upon consideration of the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a ventilated toilet having an automated toilet ventilation system according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is side cross-sectional view of a ventilated toilet having an automated toilet ventilation system according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a front view of a flush handle for the ventilated toilet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3B</figref> is a top view of the flush handle of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref>, showing it mounted for use on a tank (partially shown in cross-section) of the ventilated toilet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3C</figref> is a schematic representation of sensors and wiring inside the flush handle of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side cross-sectional view of a blower unit removably mounted on the side of the ventilated toilet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective front view of a mounting surface for the blower unit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side cross-sectional view of a base of the ventilated toilet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with a blower unit (cover removed to show inside details) superimposed in front of the toilet base where it is mounted according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a side cross-sectional view of a portion of a blower unit showing a second embodiment of a backflow valve (cross-section shaded partly omitted for clarity) according to the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8A</figref>, <b>8</b>B, and <b>8</b>C are outside, side, and inside views, respectively, of a service cover for the ventilated toilet of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> according to the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The embodiments of the present invention as described herein show a premium ventilated toilet <b>100</b> having an automated toilet ventilation system <b>10</b> for removing noxious fumes from a bowl area <b>112</b> of the toilet <b>100</b>. The system <b>10</b> is mostly built-in to the toilet <b>100</b> so that it is unobtrusive and attractive looking, however the active parts (e.g., a blower unit <b>200</b> containing a blower impeller <b>212</b>, a backflow valve <b>215</b>, and electronics <b>264</b>) are contained in an simple housing <b>202</b> that is unobtrusively and removably attached to a toilet base <b>109</b> for simplified installation, maintenance, and replacement as needed.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-2</figref>, the ventilated toilet <b>100</b> is shown in perspective and side cross-section views. Certain parts are omitted or moved in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> for the sake of clarity. Other parts are shown differently in the two. figures according to different embodiments. For example, the blower unit <b>200</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> as being mounted on the rear of the base <b>109</b>, but the preferred location is on the side <b>110</b> of the base <b>109</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> (preferred due to easier access for mounting or removing or maintenance).</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As is normal for a flush toilet design, the toilet <b>100</b> has a water storage tank <b>106</b> with a flush handle <b>102</b>, the tank <b>106</b> being mounted above the base <b>109</b> that rests on the floor of the enclosed toilet area. A toilet bowl <b>112</b> having a rim <b>114</b> around the top, is integrally formed with the base <b>109</b>. A standard toilet seat <b>108</b> is hingedly attached on top of the rim <b>114</b>. A toilet drain duct <b>122</b>, also integrally formed with the base <b>109</b> (i.e., built-in when cast), extends from a lower portion of the bowl <b>112</b>, up around a water trap <b>126</b> and back down to an exit hole <b>124</b> that has the usual formation of a protruding nozzle for seating and sealing in a mating floor flange (e.g., <b>908</b>, not part of the toilet) that is part of the sewage stack <b>910</b> in the building. The sewage stack <b>910</b> has a toilet branch sewage line (pipe) <b>902</b> extending from the floor flange <b>908</b> to join with the stack drain line <b>906</b>. The sewage stack <b>910</b> also has a stack vent pipe <b>904</b> and this is what allows fumes to be exhausted from the toilet <b>100</b> into the sewage stack <b>910</b> and out of the building through the vent pipe <b>904</b>. The water trap <b>126</b> prevents sewer gas (fumes in the sewage stack) from flowing back out of a toilet into the enclosed toilet area, therefore an important consideration in any toilet ventilation system is that the ventilation system should also prevent backflow of sewer gas.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The inventive toilet ventilation system <b>10</b> includes components that are hidden by being built-in to the ventilated toilet <b>100</b> (e.g., a vent exhaust duct <b>116</b>, and an occupancy sensor <b>104</b>); and also includes components that are unobtrusively mounted on the toilet exterior (e.g., a blower unit <b>200</b>). These and other components are described in detail hereinbelow. A preferred embodiment is disclosed, but is not to be considered limiting, especially in terms of obviously variable specifications such as dimensions and materials, which are disclosed simply as non-limiting examples.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Ducting Details</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-7</figref> air passages (ventilation ducts) are cast into the toilet bowl (built-in). Starting at the ventilation inlet side, one or more bowl vent hole(s) <b>118</b>, e.g., a series of five 1 inch diameter holes in a row, are located high up at the back of the bowl <b>112</b> but under the rim <b>114</b>. These will join together and combine into one vent exhaust duct <b>116</b> of about 2 inches in diameter and run upward so that any water entering the exhaust duct <b>116</b> will drain back toward the bowl <b>112</b>. After reaching the highest possible and practical point within the toilet bowl casting the exhaust duct <b>116</b> will run downward to an exhaust duct outlet hole <b>120</b>, which aligns with an intake hole <b>218</b> of the blower unit <b>200</b>, entering an airway <b>230</b> of the blower unit <b>200</b> at a somewhat downward angle, again to allow any water in the duct <b>116</b> to drain. There should be no low cavities or pockets to trap water or any debris in the ductwork such as the exhaust duct <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">A vent exit duct <b>127</b> extends from an exit duct opening <b>128</b> at the blower unit <b>200</b> to the toilet drain duct <b>122</b> near the bottom of the toilet base <b>109</b>, and will generally be fairly short so as not to interfere with the flushing action of the toilet, perhaps 1 inch long more or less. It is also the same 2 inches in diameter, runs downward, and is free of water trapping pockets. The exit duct opening <b>128</b> is aligned with a blower output hole <b>220</b> which is the exit of the blower unit airway <b>230</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Blower Mounting</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Another consideration regarding the bowl casting is the mounting of the blower unit <b>200</b>. Referring particularly to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-6</figref>, a flat surface <b>111</b> is provided around the exhaust duct outlet hole <b>120</b> and the exit duct opening <b>128</b> for the blower unit <b>200</b> to seal and rest against. Exemplary dimensions are as follows: the two duct openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b> are 2 inches in diameter and spaced vertically a distance of 4 inches, center to center. The flat surface <b>111</b> around each opening will be at least &#xbd; inch wide and in the same plane. Alternately, there can be one flat surface <b>111</b> at the duct openings as described above, forming an oblong shape while maintaining at least &#xbd; inch of flat surface around each of the openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b>. For example, the flat surface <b>111</b> is approximately the same overall shape and dimensions as the blower unit <b>200</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The angle that the air ducts <b>116</b>, <b>127</b> intersect the plane of the mounting surface <b>111</b> should be about 45 degrees. This will form a lip at the top of the upper opening (exhaust duct outlet hole <b>120</b>) and at the bottom of the lower opening (exit duct opening <b>128</b>). Mounting fingers on the blower unit <b>200</b> will engage these lips to secure the blower unit <b>200</b> to the side of the toilet bowl <b>110</b> by hooking behind the lips and pulling the blower unit <b>200</b> snugly against the mounting surface <b>111</b>. The interface of the blower unit <b>200</b> to the toilet bowl side <b>110</b> is sealed with a fairly soft, closed cell neoprene or similar material gasket <b>222</b> (for example, the gasket <b>222</b> is optionally two O-rings as shown). The gasket <b>222</b> will encircle both duct openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b>, is at least about &#x215c; inch wide and about &#x215b; inch thick for conforming to surface irregularities.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">For securing to the lower exit duct opening <b>128</b>, two lower mounting fingers <b>224</b> molded as part of the base of the blower housing <b>202</b> hook behind the lip at the bottom of the exit duct opening <b>128</b>. The lower fingers <b>224</b> are positioned at roughly the 5 and 7 o'clock positions around the exit duct opening <b>128</b>, or somewhat wider, to aid in centering the blower unit <b>200</b> side to side when mounting. The space between these two lower mounting fingers <b>224</b>, being at the lowest point in the blower housing <b>202</b>, will allow unrestricted drainage.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">An upper mounting fork <b>226</b> is vertically movable to enable mounting and removing the blower unit <b>200</b>. The fork <b>226</b> has two fingers that are part of a stainless steel metal stamping resembling a letter &#x201c;Y&#x201d; inverted. The forked lower end is formed so both fingers <b>226</b> hook onto the upper edge of the exhaust duct outlet hole <b>120</b>. This forked hook <b>226</b> acts, as the two bottom hooks <b>224</b> do, to center the blower unit <b>200</b> side to side by engaging the round duct opening <b>120</b> at the 1 and 11 o'clock positions. A shank mid-portion of the forked fingers <b>226</b> fits and can slide in a channel in the blower housing <b>202</b>. A seal is formed of closed cell neoprene, or similar material, around the shank at a point where it passes under the duct gasket at the 12 o'clock position on the upper duct opening <b>120</b>. This seal sits in a recessed area formed in the base of the blower housing <b>202</b>. The top end of the forked fingers <b>226</b> is formed at a right angle away from the toilet bowl, going a short distance into the blower unit <b>200</b>. A tapped hole in the top end works with a screw <b>228</b> held in the blower housing <b>202</b> to move the forked fingers <b>226</b> up or down to engage with the lip in the exhaust duct outlet hole <b>120</b>. Tightening the screw <b>228</b> will both pull the blower unit <b>200</b> downward and also draw the blower unit <b>200</b> tightly against the mounting surface <b>111</b> as the fingers <b>224</b>, <b>226</b> grip the angled openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">This mounting method keeps the bowl <b>112</b> casting somewhat simple as no other mounting holes are needed for screws and the like. The dimensional tolerance of the bowl casting as it pertains to interfacing with the blower unit <b>200</b> should be as good as possible and practical for work in that trade. Normal variations in flatness of the mounting surface <b>111</b> will be allowed for by a conforming seal of the gasket <b>222</b> between the two surfaces. The distance between, and size of, the two duct openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b> is most important as it affects the engagement of the mounting fingers <b>224</b>, <b>226</b>. However, the blower unit <b>200</b> design includes the adjustable upper forked finger <b>226</b> to accomplish removably mounting it.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Backflow Valve Details (First Embodiment)</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The blower housing <b>202</b> contains a backflow shutoff valve <b>215</b> (backflow valve). Its purpose is to close off the ventilation ducts <b>116</b>, <b>127</b> when the blower <b>200</b> is not operating, thereby stopping sewer gases from backing out of the ventilated toilet <b>100</b>. Therefore, closed is the normal state of the backflow valve <b>215</b>. A stopper for the backflow valve <b>215</b> may be a butterfly <b>217</b>, a poppet <b>216</b>, a flapper (not shown), or other related valve mechanisms. A design choice should consider one with enough flow capacity to offer minimum resistance to the airflow in the open position. In a first embodiment, the backflow valve <b>215</b> is opened, and held open, by an actuator (e.g., a solenoid) <b>214</b> when energized. The closed position is maintained by a spring bias in the solenoid <b>214</b> or at some other point in the linkage between the solenoid <b>214</b> and stopper <b>216</b>, but preferably not in the airway <b>230</b>. Between the airway <b>230</b> and a sealed motor/electrical compartment <b>231</b> of the blower unit <b>200</b> the linkage or shaft must pass through a seal to exclude moisture. The linkage or shaft, stopper <b>216</b>, <b>217</b>, and seal must be of materials resistant to moisture and chemical attack as well as having good mechanical wear characteristics. The design could use a shaft seal the same as or similar to one around a shaft <b>242</b> of the motor <b>210</b> if a rotating design is used. If an axial motion design is used a wiper type of seal or a bellows type boot can be used. Other important considerations in choosing a design are the ability to not trap water or debris, and to have a long operating life.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The solenoid <b>214</b> needs to have a long enough travel for opening the backflow valve <b>215</b> wide. It must also be strong enough to overcome the possibility of accidental water filling in behind the stopper <b>216</b>, <b>217</b>, i.e., a sewer backup. An air damped, or cushioned, action will reduce the noise of operation. The solenoid's coil is to be resin dipped for moisture resistance. As part of the solenoid <b>214</b>, or linked mechanically, is a set of electrical contacts the purpose of which is to turn on the motor <b>210</b>. (In a second embodiment, disclosed hereinbelow, the electrical contacts are not needed because the motor <b>210</b> and solenoid <b>214</b> are combined.) The solenoid <b>214</b> has been described as one embodiment of a variety of electro-mechanical actuators <b>214</b> that could be used. Other embodiments include, for example, a rotary or a piezoelectric actuator <b>214</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Backflow Valve Details (Second Embodiment)</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Referring in particular to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a second embodiment of the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; is shown built into the blower housing <b>202</b> which is shown in a partial cross-sectional view with a housing inlet duct <b>232</b> portion of the airway <b>230</b> leading into the blower unit <b>200</b> from the blower intake hole <b>218</b> (not shown), and a housing outlet duct <b>234</b> portion of the airway <b>230</b> leading out of the blower unit <b>200</b> to the blower output hole <b>220</b> (not shown). The second embodiment of the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; is simpler than the electromechanical first embodiment backflow valve <b>215</b> described hereinabove, and should give equal or better overall performance and be less costly to manufacture.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The basic operation of the second embodiment of the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; is to use rotary torque from the blower motor <b>210</b> to obtain linear motion to open a port in the airway <b>230</b> (e.g., housing inlet duct <b>232</b>), allowing air to flow into the modified impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; and thereby be moved through the toilet ventilation system <b>10</b>. When the motor <b>210</b> is deactivated, a return spring <b>240</b> supplies energy to close the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; to airflow. Linear motion is obtained by the action of a specialized screw and nut arrangement in a hub <b>250</b> of the modified blower impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032;. The torque of the motor <b>210</b> working against the resistance offered by the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; causes the screw and nut to pull the nose <b>236</b> of the hub <b>250</b> (i.e., the nose <b>236</b> is the backflow valve stopper) toward the motor <b>210</b> and away from the airway <b>230</b> (e.g., housing inlet duct <b>232</b>) while compressing or winding up the spring <b>240</b> that will return the stopper <b>236</b> to the extended position, sealed against a duct opening <b>233</b>, thereby blocking the airway <b>230</b> (e.g., housing inlet duct <b>232</b>). Although shown blocking the housing inlet duct <b>232</b>, it should be apparent that the second embodiment backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; could alternatively be implemented to block the housing outlet duct <b>234</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">A description of the main parts of the second embodiment of the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; and their functions follows.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The motor shaft <b>242</b> is fitted with an arbor <b>244</b> having its length containing a coarse helical thread <b>246</b> and a thrust-bearing flange <b>248</b> at the end toward the motor <b>210</b>. The size and length of the arbor <b>244</b> is sufficient to accept the motor shaft with a secure fit and have enough range of travel for a nut-hub <b>250</b> to travel over. The threads <b>246</b> can have any of a variety of profiles (e.g., Vee or rounded) and a fairly steep pitch of about 45 degrees, an angle that will afford the same mechanical advantage to the return spring <b>240</b> as the screw thread <b>246</b> has in pulling in the nut-hub <b>250</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The nut-hub <b>250</b> has internal threads <b>252</b> to engage with the external threads <b>246</b> of the motor shaft arbor <b>244</b> with a close slip fit so as to screw onto the arbor <b>244</b> and compress the return spring <b>240</b>, and then to allow spring pressure to push the nut-hub <b>250</b> back out. The outer diameter of the nut-hub <b>250</b> has a splined surface <b>257</b> to transfer rotary motion between the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; and the nut-hub <b>250</b> and to allow the nut-hub <b>250</b> to slide toward the motor <b>210</b> and back again. The fit between these parts must be close enough not to rattle and have rotating parts go out of balance, but still to allow an easy sliding motion. The nose <b>236</b> of the nut-hub <b>250</b> is shaped to act as a stopper <b>236</b> of the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; within the duct opening <b>233</b>. It should have a rounded or pointed end to aid air flowing over it. To limit wear between the hub nose and its seat in the duct opening it may be necessary to have the nose free to spin on a bearing <b>254</b>. This will greatly reduce the friction between valve surfaces when the motor <b>210</b> de-energizes and the return spring <b>240</b> forces the nose <b>236</b> of the nut-hub <b>250</b> (which is rotating with the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032;) into the valve seat (duct opening <b>233</b>, preferably having a gasket <b>238</b>, such as an O-ring).</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The modified impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; has a hub <b>255</b> with a splined inside diameter <b>256</b> to mate with the splined outside diameter <b>257</b> of the nut-hub <b>250</b>. As the nut-hub <b>250</b> screws onto the arbor <b>244</b> and slides into the impeller hub <b>255</b> the return spring <b>240</b> is compressed. The modified impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; is held in position along the motor shaft <b>242</b> axis by the flange <b>248</b> on the arbor <b>244</b>. The pressure of the return spring <b>240</b> holds the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; against this flange <b>248</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">The return spring <b>240</b> is positioned between the nut-hub <b>250</b> and the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032;. The return spring <b>240</b> may be one spring or more arranged in a balanced pattern around the motor shaft <b>242</b> axis and held in position by blind holes in either the nut-hub <b>250</b> or the modified impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032;. The nut-hub <b>250</b> is preferred, as to offer the best containment method and to shield the return spring <b>240</b> from damage and contamination. Another arrangement would use one spring around the outside of the nut-hub <b>250</b> between a flange near the nose <b>236</b> and against the modified impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032;. The spring force is used to hold the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; against the arbor flange <b>248</b> and to close the backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; by forcing the nose (stopper) <b>236</b> of the nut-hub <b>250</b> into the seat around the duct opening <b>233</b>. This force must be less than that obtained by the linear thrust from the arbor screw threads <b>246</b>. Since load variations will occur with the blower unit <b>200</b> a range of operation must be allowed for. The characteristics of the blower performance should be considered carefully for this design. It is preferred that the torque requirements of the blower unit <b>200</b> be constant for various air loads (volumes) placed on it.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">An alternative arrangement would eliminate the return spring <b>240</b> by making the flange <b>248</b> part of the impeller hub <b>255</b>, but the flange <b>248</b> would be rotatingly connected to the motor shaft <b>242</b> while being trapped between the arbor <b>244</b> and a ridge on the shaft <b>242</b> thereby preventing axial movement of the flange <b>248</b> and thus the modified impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032;. For this arrangement, starting the motor <b>210</b> would rotate the arbor <b>244</b> which would pull the nut-hub <b>250</b> back into the impeller hub <b>255</b> until it was fully retracted, at which point the nut-hub <b>250</b> would rotate and also cause the impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; to rotate due to the mating splined surfaces <b>255</b>, <b>257</b>. When the motor <b>210</b> is stopped, the process reverses as inertia causes the linked impeller <b>212</b>&#x2032; and nut hub <b>250</b> to continue rotating and unscrewing on the stopped arbor <b>244</b> until the stopper <b>236</b> lodges against the duct opening <b>233</b> (and/or gasket <b>238</b>) and is held there by friction and by the arbor <b>244</b> that is held in place by the stopped motor <b>210</b>. If necessary, the motor <b>210</b> can have a brake on it that prevents the shaft <b>242</b> and arbor <b>244</b> from turning when the motor <b>210</b> is not powered on.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Flush Handle Details</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">Referring particularly to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3C</figref> and <b>6</b>, the flush handle <b>102</b> is intended to serve additional functions. Its primary role to operate the toilet flush valve is unchanged, but added to it are two sensor switches <b>104</b>, <b>105</b>. An electrical cable <b>258</b> for the sensors <b>104</b>, <b>105</b> has a plug <b>260</b> that plugs into a sealed receptacle <b>262</b> in the blower housing <b>202</b> and connects to a control circuit <b>264</b>. This small sized, flexible sensor cable <b>258</b> leads up the back side of the toilet water tank <b>106</b>, passes under the lid, and enters the back of the special flush handle <b>102</b>. A notch or some other clearance for the sensor cable <b>258</b> should be formed into the top edge of the tank <b>106</b>. The flush handle <b>102</b> is to be a completely sealed device, especially where the sensor cable <b>258</b> enters it from the inside of the water storage tank <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Sealed within the flush handle <b>102</b> is a proximity detector <b>104</b> (e.g., infrared or ultrasonic) and a flush detector (e.g., a flush handle position sensor) <b>105</b>. (This combination is preferred, although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a less sophisticated embodiment wherein the proximity detector <b>104</b> is mounted on the front of the toilet tank <b>106</b>, and the flush detector <b>105</b> is mounted inside the tank <b>106</b>.) The proximity detector <b>104</b> looks for (detects) the presence (proximity) of an occupant on the toilet seat <b>108</b> and if so, will signal the start of the blower unit <b>200</b>. Since the handle <b>102</b> is to one side of the water tank <b>106</b> the proximity sensor <b>104</b> needs to view the area of the occupant at an angle from the flush handle to the occupant. The position of the flush handle <b>102</b> to the side also offers a clear view around the toilet seat <b>108</b> when it is in a raised position. For these reasons the proximity detector <b>104</b> is lensed and angled suitably to have an angled viewing range aimed at an occupant on the toilet seat <b>108</b> with a sensing distance of about one foot (12 inches) more or less.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The flush handle position sensor switch <b>105</b> will indicate when the toilet is flushed and signal the blower unit <b>200</b> to stop. An exemplary design for the flush sensor <b>105</b> would be to use a tilt sensor such as a hall effect transistor <b>140</b> activated by a steel ball <b>142</b> rolling in a tubular cage <b>144</b> wherein the cage <b>142</b> is tilted down away from the transistor <b>140</b> when the flush handle <b>102</b> is in its normal level position, and is tilted down toward the transistor <b>140</b> when the flush handle <b>102</b> is pushed down to initiate flushing. An alternative to the caged ball <b>142</b> would be to use a swinging or hinged steel weight performing the same function as the steel ball <b>142</b>. The flush sensor <b>105</b> signals the control circuit <b>264</b> to turn the blower unit <b>200</b> off. Other types of switches could be used for this function. A fully mechanical design could be used but would be bulky and less reliable. A mercury tilt switch would be an alternative but raises concerns about the chemical hazards of mercury should the device be broken open or recycled.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">Blower Unit Details</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The blower unit housing <b>202</b> is preferably made of a molded plastic resin, one meeting the mechanical requirements of the device. It must have good moisture characteristics and resistance to common cleaning agents. The appearance is also important. A finely textured surface is desired along with the ability to be colored to match the various bathroom fixture colors.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Given the possibility of water entering the exhaust duct <b>116</b> and thus the blower unit <b>200</b>, certain precautions must be taken in the design and construction of the toilet ventilation system <b>10</b>. All air passages will be such that water entering the ventilation system <b>10</b> will drain by gravity when the blower unit <b>200</b> is attached in its normal operating position. Also any parts extending into the airway <b>230</b>, for example the shaft <b>242</b> between the motor <b>210</b> and the impeller <b>212</b>, are sealed. These seals must be resistant to mechanical wear due to the motion of the shaft and have chemical resistance to water and cleaning agents. The entire ventilation duct system (<b>116</b>, <b>230</b>, <b>122</b>) must maintain a sealed condition from the room as well as the electrical/motor compartment <b>231</b> of the blower unit <b>200</b>. The sealed motor/electrical compartment <b>231</b> of the housing <b>202</b> contains the motor <b>210</b>, a valve solenoid <b>214</b> (possibly combined with the motor <b>210</b>), and the control circuit (electronics) <b>264</b>, therefore the compartment <b>231</b> is also externally sealed sufficiently to resist cleaning solutions as well as the possibility of being splashed with water or urine. Special consideration is to be given to the entry into the housing <b>202</b> of a <b>120</b> volt AC electrical supply cord <b>204</b>, and of a plug connector <b>260</b> used for the sensor cable <b>258</b>. These must be liquid tight or at least moisture resistant. In the event the shaft seals <b>243</b> should fail and allow moisture to enter the motor/electrical compartment <b>231</b>, and to allow normal breathing of this area, a small drain hole will be located at the lowest point of the housing. A diameter of about 3/32 inch and covered on the inside of the housing with a synthetic fiber pad to act as a dust filter will accomplish this. The adjustment screw <b>228</b> on the mounting fork <b>226</b> is also sealed with a sleeve or boot or gasket as shown for example in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The possibility of heat buildup from the electrical equipment inside the sealed compartment <b>231</b> should not be a problem under normal circumstances due to the intermittent nature of use. If it is determined that heat is a problem, the plastic housing <b>202</b> may have to include heat transferring panels. These could be of anodized aluminum with internal and/or external fins.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The blower impeller <b>212</b> and related motor <b>210</b> will be of a design that delivers about 20 to 30 cubic feet of air per minute, free air rating. It will be at a reduced flow rate in actual use due to the drag imposed by the ductwork. Given this situation and the possibility of slight air pressure in the sewer system <b>910</b> with its outside vent <b>904</b>, the blower design should be one with good displacement characteristics, one that is good at working against a backpressure. The impeller <b>212</b> is made from a material (e.g., plastic resin) that is suitable for use in a wet environment and resistant to the common chemicals used in toilet bowl cleaning.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The blower motor <b>210</b> is a shaded pole, impedance protected design, of sufficient power for the air impeller <b>212</b> and robust enough to withstand a short period of time in a stalled or near stalled rotor state. The coil on the motor <b>210</b> should be dip coated or encapsulated for moisture resistance. A rotor shaft <b>242</b> of stainless steel with permanently lubricated bearings are preferred.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">A possible variation in design is to join the motor <b>210</b> and actuator (solenoid) <b>214</b> into one device, thereby simplifying the system. By modifying the basic shaded pole motor frame so that part of the frame, which is actually a magnetic circuit, is made of a movable section, it will act as a solenoid. When energized the solenoid plunger would pull in and complete the magnetic circuit so that the motor will run. The motion of the plunger will be used to operate the backflow valve <b>215</b>, through mechanical linkage. This design eliminates the need for a separate solenoid coil <b>214</b> and electric circuitry for it.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The sealed motor/electrical compartment <b>231</b> of the housing <b>202</b> is made to hold the motor <b>210</b> in such a way as to not adversely affect airflow necessary for its cooling. A small fan blade or impeller (not shown) in the compartment <b>231</b> as part of the motor <b>210</b> aids in heat dissipation, as this is a sealed compartment <b>231</b>. Where the motor shaft <b>242</b> enters the airway <b>230</b>, the housing <b>202</b> retains a high quality rotary shaft sealed bearing <b>243</b> to rotationally support the impeller <b>212</b> while excluding moisture from the bearing <b>243</b> and from leaking out from the airway <b>230</b> into the sealed motor/electrical compartment <b>231</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Control Circuit Details</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Inside the sealed motor/electrical compartment <b>231</b>, the blower unit <b>200</b> will contain a control circuit <b>264</b> (e.g., a printed circuit board), which will control all of the electrical and logic functions of the ventilation system <b>10</b>. From the outside of the housing <b>202</b> a vertical row of small indicator lights <b>208</b> (e.g., light emitting diodes&#x2014;LEDs) can be viewed through holes in the housing <b>202</b> that are covered with part of a product label <b>206</b>. For example, the indicator lights <b>208</b> will display &#x201c;green&#x201d; for power supplied, &#x201c;red&#x201d; for faults, and perhaps other status indications.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">It will be recommended that power be supplied from a GFCI protected line. AC power of 120 volts will power the device, brought in on a 3-conductor cord <b>204</b> fitted with a standard NEMA 5-15 plug. Ground fault protection is preferably designed into the control circuit <b>264</b> as well. The voltage used for the sensor switches must be low (e.g., 12 volts DC for safety). Also, isolation from the AC power source and grounding must be considered.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">A number of logical operations need to be performed. An infrared or other suitable proximity sensor <b>104</b> indicating, &#x201c;toilet occupied&#x201d; turns the blower unit <b>200</b> on, whereupon the backflow valve actuator <b>214</b> is energized to open the backflow valve <b>215</b>, and to close a set of (relay) contacts, which in turn energize the blower motor <b>210</b>. If the combined motor and solenoid are used this operation is more direct to just energizing the one coil that drives both functions. Likewise, if the second embodiment of backflow valve <b>215</b>&#x2032; is used, then everything is accomplished by simply turning on the motor <b>210</b>. The blower motor <b>210</b> runs until a signal is received from the flush detection sensor <b>105</b>, indicating the toilet has been flushed. This immediately turns the motor <b>210</b> (and solenoid <b>214</b> if present) off, thereby closing the backflow valve <b>215</b>, <b>215</b>&#x2032; so that the toilet <b>100</b> can flush normally without concern about sewage backing up into the ventilation system <b>10</b>. Also, if the person leaves the occupancy sensor <b>104</b> range (leaves the toilet <b>100</b>), then the blower unit <b>200</b> turns off in the same way. Some delay timing can be used to keep the system <b>10</b> from turning on and off rapidly.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">For improved safety and functionality, two other functions are performed. A temperature sensor on the circuit board <b>264</b> checks for overheating in the housing <b>202</b> and shuts the system <b>10</b> down if it occurs. This condition initiates display of a red fault light (LED) <b>208</b> if present, and may automatically reset or require an operator to perform a power off to reset the system. Also, a run timer may be used to shut the system down after 10 to 15 minutes, as it is doubtful longer running time will do any good. After timing out, the controller <b>264</b> will reset itself to the normal off state ready to start again upon receiving a signal from the occupancy sensor <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Product Label</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">A high quality multifunction label <b>206</b> will be adhered to the outward face of the housing <b>202</b>. A flat area to contain the label <b>206</b> is molded into the face of the housing <b>202</b>, as are holes for the LEDs <b>208</b>. In the locations of the LEDs <b>208</b>, the label <b>206</b> will have clear or translucent windows. The product label <b>206</b> contains all or part of the following: copyrighted and registered product name; patent notification; manufacture's name, address, and phone number; safety warnings; model and serial numbers; and legends for the LED status indicator(s) <b>208</b>. Alternatively, the label <b>206</b> could simply be printed on, or molded into the face of the housing <b>202</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Servicing and the Service Cover</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">The blower unit <b>200</b> can be easily removed (e.g., for servicing) by unplugging the AC power cord <b>204</b> from the wall outlet, unplugging the sensor cable <b>258</b> from the housing <b>202</b>, and loosening the forked mounting finger tensioning screw <b>228</b>. The blower unit <b>200</b> can then be packaged and shipped for service or replaced with a new unit <b>200</b>. After removal of the blower unit <b>200</b> a service cover <b>300</b> is installed in its place to close off the two duct openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b>, thereby allowing normal operation of the ventilated toilet <b>100</b> without an operational toilet ventilation system <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The service cover <b>300</b> is a one-piece molded plastic panel made with fingers <b>304</b>, <b>306</b> that allow it to snap on to and hold itself in position over the two duct openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b> on the toilet base <b>109</b>. The fingers <b>304</b>, <b>306</b> are formed so that they give some spring action as they engage the duct openings <b>120</b>, <b>128</b> and allow for dimensional variations. The locations of these fingers <b>304</b>, <b>306</b> are similar to those of the fingers <b>224</b>, <b>226</b> for the blower unit <b>200</b> mounting. The oblong panel of the cover <b>300</b> is ribbed (e.g., circumferential rib <b>308</b>) for stiffness to provide even pressure over a closed cell foam rubber gasket <b>310</b>. This gasket material needs to be soft enough to compress easily and seal the space between the cover and the toilet bowl.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Installing or removing the flush handle <b>102</b> with its sensors <b>104</b>, <b>105</b> is similar to any other common flush handle and requiring only simple mechanical skills and tools. The only added considerations are threading the electrical cable and connector plug through some hardware and down the backside of the toilet tank. (Hardware to thread through includes all or part of the flush valve lift arm, retaining washer, and retaining nut.) There may be a cable support device at the lower edge of the toilet tank to clip into. The connector plug <b>260</b> fits a socket <b>262</b> on the blower unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Although the invention has been illustrated and described in detail in the drawings and foregoing description, the same is to be considered as illustrative and not restrictive in character&#x2014;it being understood that only preferred embodiments have been shown and described, and that all changes and modifications that come within the spirit of the invention are desired to be protected. Undoubtedly, many other &#x201c;variations&#x201d; on the &#x201c;themes&#x201d; set forth hereinabove will occur to one having ordinary skill in the art to which the present invention most nearly pertains, and such variations are intended to be within the scope of the invention, as disclosed herein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A ventilated toilet for exhausting fumes from a bowl area of the toilet to a sewage stack vent into which a toilet drain duct empties the ventilated toilet through a water trap, the ventilated toilet comprising:
<claim-text>a built-in vent exhaust duct extending upward from a bowl vent hole and then downward to an exhaust duct outlet hole that exits through a mounting surface provided on the exterior of the ventilated toilet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a built-in vent exit duct extending downward from an exit duct opening in the mounting surface to the toilet drain duct;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower unit removably attached to the mounting surface of the ventilated toilet, and communicating with the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening, wherein the blower unit comprises: a housing containing a motor/electrical compartment and a separate sealed airway extending from a blower intake hole downward to a blower output hole; a fan impeller in the airway; a motor mounted in the motor/electrical compartment, but sealingly connected to the fan impeller; a backflow shutoff valve comprising a stopper in the airway and an actuator linked for moving the stopper; and a control circuit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a blower unit removable attachment apparatus comprising: a lower mounting finger extending outward from the blower output hole and shaped and sized for hooking into the exit duct opening, thereby aligning the blower output hole with the exit duct opening; an upper mounting finger extending outward from the blower intake hole and shaped and sized for hooking into the exhaust duct outlet hole, thereby aligning the blower intake hole with the exhaust duct outlet hole; and an adjuster that adjusts the position of one of the lower mounting finger and the upper mounting finger, thereby enabling removable attachment of the blower unit to the mounting surface of the ventilated toilet.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a flush detecting sensor electrically connected to the control circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a proximity sensor electrically connected to the control circuit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the proximity sensor is built-in to a flush handle of the ventilated toilet.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a flush detecting sensor electrically connected to the control circuit wherein the flush detecting sensor is built-in to the flush handle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the proximity sensor and the flush detecting sensor are connected to the control circuit by a sensor cable that is detachably connected to the blower unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the mounting surface is a side surface of a base of the ventilated toilet.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the exhaust duct outlet hole exits through the mounting surface at a downward angle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the exit duct opening is below the exhaust duct outlet hole and enters through the mounting surface at a downward angle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the lower mounting finger of the blower unit is downward and outward hooking for hooking over the bottom of the exit duct opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the upper mounting finger of the blower unit hooks upward and outward for adjustably hooking over the top of the exhaust duct outlet hole, such that adjusting the upper mounting finger upward, removably draws the blower unit against the mounting surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a flat portion of the mounting surface around the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sealing gasket on the flat portion of the mounting surface.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a service cover shaped to sealingly cover the exhaust duct outlet hole and the exit duct opening in place of the blower unit when it is removed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The ventilated toilet of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the backflow shutoff valve actuator further comprises an electric solenoid. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
