<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640974-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640974</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11114617</doc-number>
<date>20050427</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>171</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166 852</main-classification>
<further-classification>166 881</further-classification>
<further-classification>166 50</further-classification>
<further-classification>166115</further-classification>
<further-classification>2851234</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Spool apparatus to connect to underground well pipe</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1539236</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Black</name>
<date>19250500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>277329</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3270818</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pugh, Jr.</name>
<date>19660900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166 852</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4042020</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wellstein</name>
<date>19770800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166 852</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4056144</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wellstein</name>
<date>19771100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166 852</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4940087</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lien et al.</name>
<date>19900700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166 881</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5669442</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gibson</name>
<date>19970900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166 852</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5934370</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hoeptner, III</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166 50</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5997046</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hoeptner, III</name>
<date>19991200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>285 27</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>25</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166 852</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166 881</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166 50</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166115</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2851234</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hoeptner, III</last-name>
<first-name>Herbert W.</first-name>
<address>
<street>7796 Oak Springs Cir.</street>
<city>Gilroy</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postcode>95020</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Haefliger</last-name>
<first-name>William W.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gay</last-name>
<first-name>Jennifer H</first-name>
<department>3672</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Coy</last-name>
<first-name>Nicole A</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising a body sized for travel in the well casing, the body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit, there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via the entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing, and there being means to latch connect the body to the well casing in a position for well fluid delivery from the body via the exit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="207.94mm" wi="156.29mm" file="US07640974-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="201.85mm" wi="140.63mm" file="US07640974-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="217.17mm" wi="156.80mm" file="US07640974-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="212.26mm" wi="163.75mm" file="US07640974-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates generally to apparatus for obtaining flow of water for underground wells, and more particularly to retrievable apparatus enabling pumping of water upwardly in a well and then laterally into underground pipes.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In the past, plastic pitless spools and housings have experienced difficulty when metal pipe was threaded into the spool or housing. Both male and female pipe threads are tapered so that when a metal pipe thread is secured into a plastic female pipe thread, and over tightened, the plastic will split. When the plastic spool splits, the entire drop pipe and pump would fall into the well. Also when the housing splits, the waterline would leak into the soil and then contaminate the well.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Manufacturers have tried unsuccessfully to &#x201c;educate&#x201d; the plumber to prevent them from over tightening the metal pipe. They have added fiberglass for strength to the plastic resin, molded metal rings into the plastic near the threads and even added an external banding around the outside of the plastic threaded area, all in an effort to prevent the plastic from splitting. The inability to correct this problem has forced manufacturers to withdraw their plastic pitless spools and housings from the market place.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">There is need for simplifying improvements in apparatus referred to above, and particularly facilitating ease of retrieval of the underground pump, and without interference with sideward duct connection to lateral underground pipe which enables water delivery without freezing in winter. No apparatus of which I am aware embodies the improvements in construction, functioning and results, as are now provided by the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">After much testing and research, it has been found that by placing a stop or shoulder at the base of the plastic threads it automatically prevents splitting of the plastic by limiting the travel of the metal pipe. A second solution to the problem is to mold the plastic threads as a male pipe thread. This forces a plumber to use a metal coupling before securing the metal pipe. The metal coupling, which has a female pipe thread, will have a clamping force on the molded plastic male pipe thread, thus preventing the plastic from splitting.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is a major object of the invention to provide improved apparatus meeting the above needs. Basically, spool apparatus is provided for use in an underground well having casing, and comprises:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">d) and there being means to latch connect the body to the well casing in a position for well fluid delivery from the body via said exit.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another object is to provide latch means in the form of a snap ring to disconnect the body from the well casing in response to upward displacement of said carrier structure. A locking shoulder may be associated with the casing, to be engaged by a cam on the snap ring.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A further object is to provide an annular seal carried by the body to engage and seal off against a bore associated with the casing and at a level above said duct exit. In this regard, a second annular seal may be carried by the body to engage and seal off against a bore associated with the casing, and at a level below the duct exit. The casing may have a through port in registration with the flow duct exit. A transverse, underground flow defining pipe may be in registration with the through port to deliver water pumped upwardly in the well and into the body. A water pump may be carried by the lower well pipe to be retrieved upwardly from the well upon raising of the carrier structure and said body.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Yet another object is to provide the carrier structure in the form of upper well pipe attached to the ducted body, the locus of attachment normally being underground.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">These and other objects and advantages of the invention, as well as the details of an illustrative embodiment, will be more fully understood from the following specification and drawings, in which:</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DRAWING DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an elevation showing a water well and associated apparatus; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged section taken through <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> showing preferred apparatus incorporating the invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a modification.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring first to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, it shows a well <b>10</b> in the underground formation <b>11</b>, with casing <b>12</b> installed in the well bore <b>10</b><i>a</i>. A pump <b>13</b> is installed in a lower well pipe <b>14</b> and operates to pump water in the well upwardly in pipe <b>14</b>, as indicated by arrows <b>15</b>. Such water flow enters a flow body <b>16</b> at lower entrance <b>17</b>, to flow upwardly in a duct <b>18</b>. Water then flows sidewardly in duct section <b>18</b><i>a</i>, leaving the body at exit <b>19</b>. Water then passes to a transverse underground pipe <b>20</b> for delivery to a user or users. Such underground operations, including water flow, prevents freezing of water delivery during cold weather as in winter. Ground surface level is indicated at <b>21</b>. A lower connector, as at <b>22</b> couples body <b>16</b> to lower well pipe <b>14</b>; and an upper connector <b>23</b> couples the body <b>16</b> to upper carrier structure, such as including upper pipe <b>24</b> used for raising and lowering body <b>16</b> in the well.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Extending the description to the preferred device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, an annular casing sub, or annular adapter <b>26</b>, is provided for landing body <b>16</b> at a predetermined level upon its being lowered in the casing. Sub <b>26</b> may be carried by casing <b>12</b>, as shown, i.e. as between casing shoulders <b>12</b><i>a </i>and <b>12</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Means is provided for latch connecting the body to the well casing in a position, and at said operating level, for well fluid delivery from the body via duct <b>18</b><i>a </i>to exit <b>19</b>. In the example, such means may preferably include a snap ring <b>30</b> carried by an annular groove <b>31</b> in body <b>16</b>, the ring compressed radially by the casing bore <b>12</b><i>c</i>, as body <b>16</b> is lowered in the casing. When the body arrives in water delivery position or level, the snap ring self expands into an annular space or groove <b>32</b> defined by the sub <b>26</b>, whereby the ring lands on upward facing surface <b>26</b><i>a </i>on <b>26</b>. The body thereby becomes installed in position for water delivery to transverse pipe <b>20</b>, via ducts <b>18</b> and <b>18</b><i>a </i>in body <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">At such time as the body <b>16</b> and pump <b>13</b> are to be pulled from the well, the upper well pipe <b>24</b> is elevated, as by elevating means <b>36</b>, causing tapered cam surface <b>30</b><i>a </i>on ring <b>30</b> to engage casing downward facing locking shoulder <b>37</b>, acting to deflect the ring radially inwardly for travel lengthwise upwardly in the casing. Once the pump is pulled from the well, it can be repaired or replaced. Note that as the body is pulled upwardly, it travels past a through port <b>41</b> in the side of the casing, via which well water is delivered to pipe <b>20</b>. Note annular recess <b>70</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">An upper annular seal <b>42</b> is carried by the body <b>16</b> to engage and seal off against a casing sub bore <b>43</b>, associated with the casing, at a level above the duct <b>18</b><i>a </i>exit and above the level of through port <b>41</b>. This prevents water escape upwardly in the well above the body. A second annular seal <b>44</b> is carried by the body <b>16</b> to engage and seal off against a bore associated with the casing, as for example sub-bore <b>43</b>, and at a level below the duct <b>18</b><i>a </i>exit <b>19</b> and the casing through port <b>41</b>. This blocks pressurized water escape from duct exit <b>19</b> downwardly into the space <b>48</b> in the well bore, below body <b>16</b>. It will be noted that duct exit <b>19</b> may extend annularly about the body vertical axis <b>90</b>, so as to register with the casing through port <b>41</b> and the entrance to pipe <b>20</b>, at any angle of the body about axis <b>90</b>, upon installation.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A shoulder <b>60</b> in flange <b>61</b> stops the end of pipe <b>20</b> to prevent damage to the sub <b>26</b>, which is typically plastic. That pipe end is typically threaded. Likewise, a shoulder <b>62</b> in body <b>16</b> stops the upper end of pipe <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Sub or housing <b>26</b> has tubular sections <b>26</b><i>c </i>and <b>26</b><i>d </i>to receive casing <b>11</b> and to form shoulders to seat <b>12</b><i>a </i>and <b>12</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is like <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, but shows a stem <b>80</b> protruding downwardly from plastic body <b>16</b>, with threads at <b>81</b>. A lower threaded pipe may be connected to <b>81</b>. Also a threaded nipple <b>82</b> is carried by the end of pipe <b>20</b>, to thread connect to <b>84</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for longitudinal travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) and there being means to latch connect the body to the well casing in a position for well fluid delivery from the body via said exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) and wherein said latch means includes a snap ring positioned to disconnect the body from the well casing in response to upward displacement of said carrier structure, the snap ring being expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the ring defining a cam surface engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the ring radially for upward travel in the casing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said carrier structure includes upper well pipe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> including a locking shoulder associated with the casing, to be engaged by a cam on the snap ring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> including an annular seal carried by the body to engage and seal off against a bore associated with the casing and at a level above said duct exit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> including a second annular seal carried by the body to engage and seal off against a bore associated with the casing, and also level below said duct exit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> including said casing having a through port in registration with the flow duct exit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> including flow delivery pipe in registration with said port.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> including a water pump below said body to displace water upwardly in the wall to said body duct entrance.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the duct exit extends annularly about a vertical axis defined by the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> including said lower well pipe, and a water pump carried by said lower well pipe to be retrieved upwardly from the well upon raising of said carrier structure and said body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said means includes a casing sub to which the lower well pipe is connected.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said lower connection includes a threaded tubular stem protruding downwardly from said body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the body includes a port in registration with said exit, to receive the end of a sidewardly extending pipe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> including a stop shoulder in said port to be engaged by the end of said pipe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> including a threaded nipple threadably received in said port.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) and there being means to latch connect the body to the well casing in a position for well fluid delivery from the body via said exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) said lower connection including a threaded bore in said body, there being a stop shoulder in a recess,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) the stop shoulder protruding to overhang the lower well pipe upper end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>g) and wherein said latch means includes a snap ring expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the ring engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the ring generally radially for upward travel in the casing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) said lower connection including a threaded tubular stem protruding downwardly from said body,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) and there being latch means that includes a snap ring positioned to disconnect the body from the well casing in response to upward displacement of said carrier structure, the snap ring being expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the ring defining a cam surface engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the ring radially for upward travel in the casing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) said lower connection including a threaded bore in said body, there being a stop shoulder in a recess in the body, to stop the upper end of the lower well pipe, the stop shoulder overhanging that upper end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) there being latch means to connect the body to well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) and wherein said latch means includes a snap ring expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the ring engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the ring generally radially for upward travel in the casing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing, said lower connection including a threaded bore in said body, there being a stop shoulder in a recess in the body, to stop the upper end of the lower well pipe, the stop shoulder overhanging that upper end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) said body including a port in registration with said exit, to align with the end of a sidewardly extending pipe that is received by a housing port defining a second stop shoulder to be engaged by said end of the pipe,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) there being latch means to connect the body well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) and wherein said latch means includes a snap ring expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the ring engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the ring generally radially for upward travel in the casing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein said second stop shoulder is axially spaced from the body exit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> including a plastic nipple received in said housing port.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The combination of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein the lower connection includes a plastic tubular stem that extends downwardly from said body, and is integrally molded with said body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing, said lower connection including a threaded bore in said body, there being a stop shoulder in a recess in the body, to stop the upper end of the lower well pipe, the stop shoulder overhanging that upper end,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) said lower connection including a plastic tubular nipple that extends downwardly from said body, and has integrally molded connection with said body,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) there being latch means to connect the body to well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) and wherein said latch means includes a snap ring expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the ring engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the ring generally radially for upward travel in the casing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) and there being latch means to connect the body to the well casing in a position for well fluid delivery from the body via said exit, and wherein said latch means includes a holder positioned to disconnect the body from the well casing in response to upward displacement of said carrier structure, the holder being expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the holder defining a cam surface engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the holder laterally for upward travel in the casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) said lower connection including a threaded bore in said body, there being a stop shoulder in a body recess, said body and stop shoulder consisting of plastic material,</claim-text>
<claim-text>f) the stop shoulder located at the base of female threads in the plastic body to receive upward compressive loading transmitted by the upward terminal of metallic well pipe having threaded interfit with said threaded bore, below the level of the stop shoulder, thereby to prevent excessive tightening of said interfit the threaded bore aligned with said upper connection.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. Spool apparatus for use in an underground well having casing, comprising
<claim-text>a) a body sized for travel in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) said body defining a well fluid flow duct having a downward facing entrance and a sidewardly facing exit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) there being a lower connection for coupling the body to lower well pipe to pass fluid into the body via said entrance, and an upper connection for coupling the body to upper carrier structure used for raising and lowering the body in the well casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) and there being means to connect the body to the well casing in a position for well fluid delivery from the body via said exit, and wherein said latch means includes a holder positioned to disconnect the body from the well casing in response to upward displacement of said carrier structure, the holder being expansible laterally in a body groove and into a position to land on an upward facing surface on a sub, the holder defining a cam surface engagable with a locking shoulder to deflect the holder laterally for upward travel in the casing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) said lower connection including an externally threaded nipple integral with said body, said body and nipple consisting of plastic material, said nipple protruding downwardly, and in axial alignment with said upper connection, said nipple adapted for connection with lower well pipe below said body, with the lower end of the nipple in engagement with the lower well pipe to block excessive tightening of said nipple external threading. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
