<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640986-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640986</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11957123</doc-number>
<date>20071214</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>29</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166297</main-classification>
<further-classification> 89  7</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Device and method for reducing detonation gas pressure</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3054938</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Meddick</name>
<date>19620900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>102310</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4635733</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vann et al.</name>
<date>19870100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5303633</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Guthrie et al.</name>
<date>19940400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89  8</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5355802</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Petitjean</name>
<date>19941000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5505260</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Andersen et al.</name>
<date>19960400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5551344</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Couet et al.</name>
<date>19960900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6336408</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Parrott et al.</name>
<date>20020100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>102312</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6598682</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Johnson et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6874579</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Johnson et al.</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6966377</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Johnson et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7036594</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Walton et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7044225</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Haney et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1663081</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7121340</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Grove et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166297</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7165614</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Bond</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166297</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7243725</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>George et al.</name>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0173118</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Li et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>166297</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>22</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166297</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166 55</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>166 551</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>175  454</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090151948</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090618</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Behrmann</last-name>
<first-name>Lawrence A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Grove</last-name>
<first-name>Brenden M.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Missouri City</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>McGoff</last-name>
<first-name>Kevin Brayton</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kurka</last-name>
<first-name>James L.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Curington</last-name>
<first-name>Tim</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Schlumberger Technology Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Sugar Land</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bagnell</last-name>
<first-name>David J</first-name>
<department>3672</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Sayre</last-name>
<first-name>James G</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A perforating gun has a gun carrier extending in a longitudinal direction and a loading tube located within the gun carrier. The loading tube extends in the longitudinal direction and a shape charge is supported by the loading tube. The shape charge has a casing, an explosive, and a liner, the casing opening in a first direction and having a centerline extending in the first direction, the first direction being essentially perpendicular to the longitudinal direction. A liquid implant is located adjacent to the shape charge in the first direction and intersecting the centerline.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="71.80mm" wi="88.14mm" file="US07640986-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="194.73mm" wi="141.14mm" file="US07640986-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application relates to perforating, and more particularly to creating a transient underbalanced condition in connection therewith.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">To complete a well, one or more formation zones adjacent a wellbore are perforated to allow fluid from the formation zones to flow into the well for production to the surface or to allow injection fluids to be applied into the formation zones. A perforating gun string may be lowered into the well and the guns fired to create openings in a casing and to extend perforations into the surrounding formation.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The explosive nature of the formation of perforation tunnels shatters sand grains of the formation. A layer of &#x201c;shock damaged region&#x201d; having a permeability lower than that of the virgin formation matrix can form around each perforation tunnel. The process may also generate a tunnel full of rock debris mixed in with the perforator charge debris. The extent of the damage, and the amount of loose debris in the tunnel, may be dictated by a variety of factors including formation properties, explosive charge properties, pressure conditions, fluid properties, and so forth. The shock damaged region and loose debris in the perforation tunnels may impair the productivity of production wells or the injectivity of injector wells.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">One method of obtaining clean perforations is underbalanced perforating, referred by Schlumberger proprietarily as &#x201c;PURE&#x201d;. The perforating process results in a wellbore pressure which drops rapidly to a value below the formation pressure. This dynamic, or transient underbalance, cleans the perforation damage, thereby improving well performance.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">There is a continuing need to improve that process to optimize fluid communication with reservoirs in formations of a well. The present application describes a number of embodiments addressing a number of issues associated therewith.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">An embodiment of the present application is directed to a perforating gun, comprising: a gun carrier extending in a longitudinal direction; a loading tube located within the gun carrier, the loading tube extending in the longitudinal direction; a shape charge being supported by the loading tube, the shape charge having a casing, an explosive, and a liner, the shape charge aiming in a first direction and having a centerline extending along the first direction, the first direction being essentially perpendicular to the longitudinal direction; and</p>
<p id="h-0004" num="0000">a liquid implant, the liquid implant being located adjacent to the shape charge in the first direction and intersecting the centerline.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a cross section of an embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a chart illustrating thermal conductivity of various materials.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a side view schematic of an embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In the following description, numerous details are set forth to provide an understanding of the present invention. However, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that the present invention may be practiced without these details and that numerous variations or modifications from the described embodiments may be possible.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">As used here, the terms &#x201c;uphole&#x201d;, &#x201c;downhole&#x201d;, &#x201c;up&#x201d; and &#x201c;down&#x201d;; &#x201c;upper&#x201d; and &#x201c;lower&#x201d;; &#x201c;upwardly&#x201d; and &#x201c;downwardly&#x201d;; &#x201c;upstream&#x201d; and &#x201c;downstream&#x201d;; &#x201c;above&#x201d; and &#x201c;below&#x201d; and other like terms indicating relative positions above or below a given point or element are used in this description to more clearly described some embodiments of the invention. However, when applied to equipment and methods for use in wells that are deviated or horizontal, such terms may refer to a left to right, right to left, or other relationship as appropriate.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">U.S. Pat. No. 7,121,340 describes a Method and Apparatus for Reducing Pressure in a Perforating Gun and is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. As described therein and discussed in the present application, treatment of perforation damage and removal of perforation generated (charge and formation) debris from the perforation tunnels can be accomplished by increasing the local pressure drop (increasing the local transient underbalance).</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In operation, a well operator identifies or determines a target transient underbalance condition that is desired in a wellbore interval relative to a wellbore pressure (which may be set by reservoir pressure). The target transient underbalance condition can be identified in one of several ways, such as based on empirical data from previous well operations or on simulations performed with modeling software. The configured control tool string is then lowered to a wellbore interval, where the tool string is activated to detonate explosives in the tool string. Activation causes the target transient underbalanced condition to be achieved.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A major factor in the transient underbalance is hot gas resulting from the shape charge detonation. As gas becomes hot, pressure increases generally according the relationship PV&#x221d;nRT. Thus, one way to increase the transient underbalance is to lower the temperature (T) of the hot gas resulting from detonation.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a schematic longitudinal cross section of a representative perforating gun <b>1</b> that is used in connection with creation of transient underbalanced conditions. A loading member <b>200</b> is located inside a gun carrier <b>100</b>. The loading member <b>200</b> supports shape charges <b>400</b>. The shape charge <b>400</b> opens in a first direction and has a centerline (shown) extending in the first direction. The loading member <b>200</b> is shown in tube form, but the loading member <b>200</b> can take many forms so long as the shape charges are adequately supported and oriented. When the shape charge <b>400</b> detonates, explosives <b>430</b> that are held between a casing <b>420</b> and a liner <b>410</b> detonate. The liner <b>410</b> is propelled outward in a direction away from the shape charge <b>400</b> in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A liquid implant <b>300</b> is positioned adjacent to the shape charge <b>400</b> and intersects the centerline. The liquid implant <b>300</b> can be placed in many locations so long as the liquid container is in a path of trajectory of the liner <b>410</b> upon detonation, e.g., intersects the centerline. The liquid implant <b>400</b> is a container containing liquid. The liquid implant has an outer barrier <b>310</b> containing the liquid <b>320</b>. The barrier <b>310</b> can be made from almost any material capable of containing liquid <b>320</b> and withstanding down hole conditions. The barrier <b>310</b> can be made from metal, glass, ceramics, polymers, plastics or elastomers. The liquid <b>320</b> in the barrier <b>310</b> can be almost any liquid <b>320</b> having the proper thermal conductivity and specific heat capacity. Preferably, water is the liquid <b>320</b> because water has particularly good thermal conductivity and specific heat capacity compared to other liquids and materials. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a chart illustrating thermal conductivities and specific heat capacities for a number of materials.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">After detonation, the liner <b>410</b> forms a jet which is propelled into the liquid implant <b>300</b> thereby opening the barrier <b>310</b> and releasing the contents of liquid implant <b>300</b>. Preferably, the barrier <b>310</b> of the liquid implant <b>300</b> is punctured, thereby placing the liquid <b>320</b> in contact with both the jet and the hot gasses resulting from the detonation. The jet continues though the gun carrier <b>100</b>, through the casing <b>100</b> and into formation. The liquid <b>320</b> in the liquid implant <b>300</b> acts as a heat sink thereby cooling the hot gasses and helping create/increase an optimal underbalanced condition.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In operation of an embodiment, as the jet penetrates the gun carrier <b>100</b> and the casing <b>500</b>, the pressure differential between the area outside the gun carrier <b>100</b> and inside the gun carrier <b>100</b> produces a flow through the holes in the casing <b>500</b> into the interior of the casing <b>500</b> and the interior of the gun carrier <b>100</b>. The liquid <b>320</b> in the barrier <b>310</b> of the liquid implant <b>300</b>, preferably water, increases cooling of the hot gasses inside the gun carrier <b>100</b>, thereby increasing the pressure differential between inside the gun carrier <b>100</b> and outside the gun carrier <b>100</b>, thereby increasing the underbalanced condition. Preferably the water is vaporized thereby approaching optimum performance.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The shape charge <b>400</b> can have a casing <b>420</b>, a liner <b>410</b> and explosive <b>430</b> kept between the casing <b>420</b> and the liner <b>410</b>. The casing <b>420</b> can have a generally concave shape and define an inner volume where the explosive <b>430</b> is located. The casing <b>420</b> opens in a first direction, shown by the arrow in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The first direction can be generally perpendicular to a longitudinal direction that the gun carrier <b>100</b> and loading tube <b>200</b> extend in. The casing <b>420</b> has a rim that forms a perimeter of an opening leading into the interior volume where the explosive <b>430</b> is located. The perimeter can be in a circular shape and define a planer area.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The liquid implant <b>300</b> is located adjacent to the shape charge <b>400</b> in the first direction. The liquid implant <b>300</b> is located so that when the shape charge <b>400</b> detonates, the liner <b>410</b> is propelled in the first direction and contacts the liquid implant <b>300</b>. The liner <b>410</b> strikes the liquid implant <b>300</b> and breaks barrier <b>310</b> thereby releasing the water <b>320</b> contained in the liquid implant <b>300</b>. The barrier <b>310</b> could break without contacting the liner <b>410</b>, for example, under pressure or heat from the detonation of the shape charge or an alternate mechanism. The liquid implant <b>300</b> can be located so that the implant <b>300</b> at least partially overlaps the interior planar area defined by the rim <b>430</b> in the first direction. The liner <b>300</b> can entirely overlap the area defined by the rim <b>430</b> in the first direction.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The preceding description relates to certain embodiments and does not in any way limit the scope of the claims recited herein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A perforating gun, comprising:
<claim-text>A gun carrier extending in a longitudinal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a loading tube located within the gun carrier, the loading tube extending in the longitudinal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shape charge being supported by the loading tube, the shape charge having a cup-shaped casing having a rim that defines an opening to an interior volume of the casing, a liner located inside the casing, and an explosive between the casing and the liner, the shape charge aiming in a first direction and having a centerline extending along the first direction, the first direction being essentially perpendicular to the longitudinal direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a liquid implant, the liquid implant being located outside of the interior volume of the cup-shaped casing and adjacent to the shape charge in the first direction and intersecting the centerline;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the liquid implant contains water.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the outer rim forms a perimeter defining an interior area of the perimeter in the first direction,
<claim-text>the liquid implant overlapping the entire inside area of the perimeter in the first direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant overlaps the interior area of the perimeter in the first direction and extends outside the interior of the perimeter uphole in the longitudinal direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant overlaps the interior area of the perimeter in the first direction and extends outside the interior area of the perimeter downhole in the longitudinal direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant overlaps the interior area of the perimeter in the first direction and extends outside the interior area of the perimeter uphole and downhole in the longitudinal direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is positioned adjacent to the shape charge so that when the shape charge detonates the liner is propelled into contact with the liquid implant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant has a barrier that defines an internal area, the internal area containing liquid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the barrier defines a single internal area in the liquid implant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of perforating, comprising:
<claim-text>placing a perforating gun downhole, the perforating gun comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a gun carrier extending in a longitudinal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a loading tube located within the gun carrier, the loading tube extending in the longitudinal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shape charge being supported by the loading tube, the shape charge having a cup-shaped casing having a rim that defines an opening to an interior volume of the casing, a liner within the casing and an explosive between the casing and the liner, the shape charge aiming in a first direction, the first direction being essentially perpendicular to the longitudinal direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a liquid implant, the liquid implant being located outside of the interior volume of the cup-shaped casing and adjacent to the shape charge in the first direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the liquid implant contains water;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the method comprising, detonating the shape charge thereby forming the liner into a jet, the jet being propelled in the first direction thereby contacting and rupturing the liquid implant and releasing liquid in the liquid implant, thereby contacting the liquid with gas produced from the detonation of the shape charge.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the shape charge has a centerline extending in the first direction, the liquid implant intersecting the centerline.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the shape charge has a centerline extending in the first direction, the liquid implant surrounding the centerline.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is made from plastic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is made from metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is made from polymer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is ceramic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is made from elastomer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant has a barrier that defines an internal area, the internal area containing liquid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the barrier defines a single internal area in the liquid implant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A perforating gun, comprising:
<claim-text>a gun carrier extending in a longitudinal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a loading tube located within the gun carrier, the loading tube extending in the longitudinal direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shape charge being supported by the loading tube, the shape charge having a cup-shaped casing having a rim that defines an opening to an interior volume of the cup-shaped casing, a liner inside the casing, and an explosive located between the casing and the liner, the shape charge aiming in a first direction, the first direction being essentially perpendicular to the longitudinal direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a liquid implant, the liquid implant being located outside of the interior volume of the cup-shaped casing and adjacent to the shape charge in the first direction and intersecting the centerline and poisoned so that upon detonation of the shape charge the liner becomes a jet, the jet being projected into contact with the liquid implant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the liquid implant contains water.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the liquid implant is a container having a single interior volume holding liquid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, comprising at least one shape charge and only one liquid implant corresponding to each of the at least one shape charge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The perforating gun of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, comprising at least one shape charge and only one liquid implant corresponding to each of the at least one shape charge.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
