<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07644538-20100112.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091229" date-publ="20100112">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07644538</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100112</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11761298</doc-number>
<date>20070611</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>IT</country>
<doc-number>TO2006A0435</doc-number>
<date>20060615</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>131</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100112</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 49192</main-classification>
<further-classification> 49193</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Turn/tilt closure</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3994093</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mayer et al.</name>
<date>19761100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 49192</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4602457</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kreusel</name>
<date>19860700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 49192</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7017301</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Balbo Di Vinadio</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 49192</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>3225049</doc-number>
<date>19840100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2722527</doc-number>
<date>19960100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 49193</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 49192</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 49382</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080016774</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080124</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Balbo Di Vinadio</last-name>
<first-name>Aimone</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiusa San Michele</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>IT</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Patterson &#x26; Sheridan, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>SAVIO S.p.A.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Turin</city>
<country>IT</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Strimbu</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory J.</first-name>
<department>3634</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A closure includes a frame that is selectively pivotable about a vertical axis and a horizontal axis. A drive assembly is disposed in a groove of the frame to selectively determine which axis the frame pivots about as the frame pivots between an open position and a closed position. The drive assembly includes a plurality of actuating members and a plurality of transmission rods that operatively connect adjacent actuating members to each other. Each of the actuating members and each of the transmission rods has a single tenon which is disposed in only one side of the groove.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="223.27mm" wi="274.74mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="234.27mm" wi="156.80mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="238.51mm" wi="122.26mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.71mm" wi="132.08mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="226.31mm" wi="128.86mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="224.03mm" wi="131.83mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="227.33mm" wi="145.29mm" file="US07644538-20100112-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims benefit of Italian patent application number TO2006A000435, filed Jun. 15, 2006, which is herein incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to door and window frames.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The invention was developed for the application to door or window frames constituted by extruded section bars made of aluminium or similar metallic alloys, constituted by a quadrangular frame formed by four section bars defining a pair of uprights and a pair of cross members. The section bars forming the frames are constituted by bars with complex section, produced by extrusion, drawing or profiling. Each of said section bars is provided on an outer side of the frame with a longitudinal groove to be used for mounting the articulation hinges and the drive assembly of the door or window frame. In the remainder of the description and in the claims, &#x201c;drive assembly&#x201d; means the set of devices and components that allow to transmit the opening/closing motion from the handle to the various closure elements.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Door and window frames are classified as door and window frames with wing opening, with swivel opening and with wing and swivel opening. Wing opening is defined as an opening movement that takes place by rotation around a vertical axis. Swivel opening means an opening movement that takes place by rotation around a horizontal axis. Door and window frames with wing and swivel opening can be opened selectively by means of rotation around a vertical axis or by means of rotation around a horizontal axis.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the case of door window frames within wing opening only or with swivel opening only, the drive assembly enables to select the closed or open position of the door or window frame. In the case of door or window frames with wing and swivel opening, the drive assembly enables selectively to activate closed positions, wing opening positions or swivel opening positions, under the command of a cremone bolt device.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The standard conformation of the metal section bars for doors or windows comprises on the outer side of the frame a longitudinal groove with undercut profile formed by a base, two parallel lateral walls and two edges oriented against each other and defining an undercut engagement area at each of the lateral walls of the longitudinal groove. Mounting the components of the drive assembly in the longitudinal slots of the section bars of the frame is an operation that has a considerable impact on the time required to assemble the door or window frames. In the most traditional solutions, the members comprising the drive assembly are provided with two longitudinal tenons that engage the two undercut engagement areas of the respective longitudinal grooves. This solution is not very attractive to the manufacturers of window and door frames because it entails the need to obtain notches at the end of each groove to allow the insertion of the actuating members in the longitudinal direction.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">To overcome this drawback, the document FR-A-2722527 proposed a solution in which each actuating member is provided with a single tenon that engages only one undercut area of the longitudinal groove. According to the solution described in FR-A-2722527, the actuating members are arranged contiguous in alternated fashion, so that the first actuating member has its tenon engaging a first undercut engagement area of the groove and the actuating member adjacent to it has its own tenon engaging a second undercut engagement area opposite the first one. Arranging the actuating members in alternating fashion aims to solve the problem of the stability of the engagement between the actuating members and the groove of the frame. When two or more adjacent actuating members are fastened to each other, the set constituted by the series of mutually fastened actuating members comprises at least one tenon that engages the first undercut engagement area and at least one tenon that engages the second undercut engagement area of the groove.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The drawback of this solution is that the alternated mounting of the actuating members is inconvenient and it may require repeatedly upsetting the frame.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">European patent application no. 05425179 by the same Applicant (not yet published as of the filing date of the present application) describes a drive assembly for door and window frames provided with actuating members with a single tenon which are inserted in transverse direction into the respective longitudinal slots of the frame. Said document does not describe that the actuating members all engage a same undercut engagement area of the respective groove.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The document DE-A-3225049 describes a door or window frame in which the longitudinal groove comprises a single undercut engagement area and with a lateral wall of the groove with a T shape engaged at opposite sides by two opposite tenons of the actuating members.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The object of the present invention is to provide actuating members for door and window frames that can be mounted with greater simplicity relative to prior art solutions.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to the present invention, said object is achieved by a door or window. that includes a movable quadrangular frame formed by four section bars each having a longitudinal groove. Each of the longitudinal grooves comprising a base, two parallel lateral walls and two edges oriented towards each other, wherein the edges and the lateral walls define a first undercut engagement area adjacent to a first face of the frame and a second undercut engagement area adjacent to a second face of the frame. The door or window further includes a drive assembly for opening/closing the movable quadrangular frame. The drive assembly comprising a plurality of actuating members and a plurality of transmission rods that operatively connect adjacent actuating members to each other, wherein each of the actuating members and each of the transmission rods has a single integral tenon, and wherein the tenons of all the actuating members and the tenons of all the transmission rods engage the first undercut engagement area.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the solution according to the present invention, the actuating members have a single tenon and they all engage the undercut engagement area situated on the same side of the respective groove.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Thanks to this solution idea, during the assembly of the actuating members in the grooves of the section bars, it is not necessary repeatedly to upset the frame to mount the actuating members in alternated fashion.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The present invention shall now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings, provided purely by way of non limiting example, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a window or door frame according to the present invention,</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partially sectioned perspective view showing the mounting sequence of an actuating member indicated by the arrow II in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is also a partially sectioned perspective view showing the mounting sequence of an actuating member indicated by the arrow II in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref> are sections respectively according to the lines IV-IV and V-V of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a partially sectioned perspective view showing the mounting sequence of the actuating member indicated by the arrow VI in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is also a partially sectioned perspective view showing the mounting sequence of the actuating member indicated by the arrow VI in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref> are sections respectively according to the lines VIII-VIII and IX-IX of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a partially sectioned perspective view showing the actuating member indicated by the arrow X in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in the mounted position, and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a section according to line XI-XI of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the number <b>10</b> designates a door or window frame according to the present invention. The door or window frame <b>10</b> comprises a quadrangular frame <b>12</b> formed by four section bars <b>14</b> preferably constituted of aluminium or alloys thereof. Each of the section bars <b>14</b> has an outer side provided with a longitudinal groove <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the frame <b>12</b> has two front faces designated respectively by the numbers <b>18</b> and <b>20</b>. The section bars <b>14</b> have respective front bearing edges <b>22</b> aligned to the first face <b>18</b> of the frame <b>12</b> and projecting outwards beyond the respective groove <b>16</b>. The front bearing edges <b>22</b> have respective grooves <b>24</b> able to receive a front sealing gasket (not shown) which in the closed position of the window or door frame is pressed against a front surface of the fixed frame of the door or window.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">With reference for example to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</figref>, the longitudinal groove <b>16</b> of each section bar <b>14</b> comprises a base <b>26</b>, two lateral walls <b>28</b> and two longitudinal edges <b>30</b> oriented towards each other. The two longitudinal ends of the edges <b>30</b> facing each other define the outer opening of the longitudinal groove <b>16</b>. The longitudinal edges <b>30</b> define an undercut engagement area at each lateral wall <b>28</b> of the groove <b>16</b>. A first undercut engagement area <b>32</b> is adjacent to the first face <b>18</b> of the frame <b>12</b> and a second undercut engagement area <b>34</b> is adjacent to the second face <b>20</b> of the frame <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Each undercut engagement area <b>32</b>, <b>34</b> has substantially &#x201c;C&#x201d; shape and is defined between the inner surfaces of the edge <b>30</b>, of the lateral wall <b>28</b> and by the lateral portion of the base <b>26</b>. The shape of the longitudinal groove <b>16</b> is standardised and it is used by most metallic section bars for door or window frames.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the window or door frame <b>10</b> is provided with a drive assembly globally designated by the number <b>36</b>. The drive assembly <b>36</b> comprises a plurality of actuating members <b>38</b>, <b>40</b>, <b>42</b>, <b>46</b> <b>49</b> and a plurality of transmission rods <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> that operatively connect adjacent actuating members to each other. The drive assembly <b>36</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is that of a door or window frame with wing and swivel opening and it comprises a vertical fulcrum <b>38</b>, an angled transmission <b>40</b>, a scissors arm <b>42</b> a cremone bolt coupling and a cursor <b>49</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">According to the present invention, each actuating member and each transmission rod is provided with a single integral tenon for engagement with the respective groove <b>16</b>, so that all the components of the drive assembly <b>36</b> can be mounted frontally in the respective grooves. The tenons of the actuating members and of the transmission rods all engage the undercut engagement area <b>32</b> of the respective groove <b>16</b> adjacent to the first wall <b>18</b> of the frame <b>12</b>, i.e. the wall provided with front bearing edge <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 to 11</figref> schematically show some details and the manners of mounting of some actuating members <b>40</b>, <b>42</b>, <b>49</b> comprising the drive assembly <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref>, the actuating member <b>49</b> (cursor) has a single tenon <b>52</b> obtained in integral form with the body of the actuating member <b>49</b> and engaging the first undercut engagement area <b>32</b> of the groove <b>16</b>. The actuating member <b>49</b> is mounted by positioning the tenon <b>52</b> into the first undercut engagement area <b>32</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 4</figref> and then making the engagement member <b>49</b> oscillate towards the interior of the groove <b>16</b> obtaining the frontal insertion of the actuating member <b>49</b> into the groove <b>16</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</figref>. On the opposite side of the tenon <b>52</b>, the actuating member <b>49</b> is provided with a bearing longitudinal edge <b>54</b> that bears on the outer side of the edge <b>30</b> situated at the second undercut engagement area <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The actuating member <b>49</b> is fastened to the transmission rod <b>50</b> by means of a screw <b>56</b>. The manner in which each actuating member <b>38</b>, <b>40</b>, <b>42</b>, <b>46</b> and <b>49</b> is fastened to the respective transmission rods <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> is described in detail in a contemporaneous patent application by the same Applicant.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 through 9</figref> show the way in which the frontal mounting of the angled transmission <b>40</b> is carried out. In this case, too, the angled transmission <b>40</b> is provided with a single integral tenon <b>52</b> that engages the first undercut engagement area <b>32</b> of the longitudinal groove <b>16</b>. The mounting operation is carried out by frontally inserting the angled transmission <b>40</b> into the groove <b>16</b> as indicated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 8</figref> and then making the angled transmission <b>40</b> oscillate towards the interior of the groove <b>16</b> until it reaches the position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 9</figref>. On the opposite side of the tenon <b>52</b> there is a bearing edge <b>54</b> that bears on the outer side of the edge <b>30</b> situated at the second undercut engagement area <b>34</b>. The angled transmission <b>40</b> can also be provided with a recessing tooth <b>58</b> that engages in snap-in fashion the edge <b>30</b> during the frontal insertion into the groove <b>16</b>. The recessing tooth <b>58</b> is thrust elastically outwards and it has the purpose of holding the angled transmission <b>40</b> inside the groove <b>16</b> during the assembly. Similar retaining teeth can also be provided on other actuating members of the assembly <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>, the scissors arm <b>42</b> is also mounted in the manner described previously. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref> show the scissors arm <b>42</b> at the end of the mounting in the groove <b>16</b>. The insertion takes place frontally, positioning the single integral tenon <b>52</b> in engagement with the first undercut engagement portion <b>32</b> and then making the scissors arm <b>42</b> oscillate towards the interior of the groove <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The fact that all the actuating members and all the transmission rods are provided with a single tenon for connection to the section bars <b>14</b> could cause instability problems due to pressures on the door or window frame. However, said problems are solved thanks to the fact that all the actuating members engage the undercut engagement area <b>32</b> of the groove <b>16</b> that is oriented towards the face <b>18</b> of the frame <b>12</b> provided with the front bearing edge <b>22</b>. In the case of inward opening door and window frames, the face <b>18</b> is the inner face of the door or window frame whilst in the case of outward opening door and window frames, the face <b>18</b> is the outer face of the door or window frame.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The fact that all the tenons of the drive assembly <b>36</b> engage the inner portion of the groove <b>16</b> in the case of inward opening door and window frames and the outer portion of the groove <b>16</b> in the case of outward opening door and window frames determines a complete stability, even without a tenon with structural function on the opposite side of the groove <b>16</b>. It can be demonstrated that the connection between the actuating members and the section bars <b>14</b> is perfectly stable in the case of thrusts directed from the outside inwards, in the case of inwardly opening door and window frames, or under the action of thrusts directed from the inside outwards, in the case of outwardly opening door and window frames.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The fact that all the tenons of the drive assembly <b>36</b> engage the same side of the groove <b>16</b> enables to carry out the frontal mounting of the actuating members and of the transmission rods without upsetting the frame <b>12</b>, i.e. keeping the frame <b>12</b> with the face <b>18</b> bearing on a horizontal plane during the entire assembly operation.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">While the foregoing is directed to embodiments of the present invention, other and further embodiments of the invention may be devised without departing from the basic scope thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A closure, comprising:
<claim-text>a movable quadrangular frame formed by four section bars each having a generally U-shaped longitudinal groove, said frame being selectively pivotable about one of a generally horizontal axis and a generally vertical axis, each of said longitudinal grooves comprising: a base, two parallel lateral walls and two ledges extending from distal ends of said walls towards each other, said ledges and said lateral walls defining a first undercut engagement area adjacent to a first face of the frame and a second undercut engagement area adjacent to a second face of the frame, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drive assembly for controlling which of said axes the movable quadrangular frame will pivot about, said drive assembly comprising a plurality of movable actuating members and a plurality of movable transmission rods that operatively connect adjacent ones of said actuating members to each other, wherein each of said actuating members and each of said transmission rods has only one tenon, each of said tenons forming a one piece unitary element with a respective one of said transmission rods and said actuating members and wherein the tenons of all the actuating members and the tenons of all the transmission rods are disposed in said first undercut engagement area, and wherein all the actuating members and all the transmission rods each have a longitudinal projection opposite to a respective one of said tenons that bears on an outer side surface of a respective one of said ledges defining said second undercut engagement area, wherein each of said projections forming a one piece unitary element with a respective one of said transmission rods and said actuating members.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The closure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the window or door is an inwardly opening closure and said first face of the movable quadrangular frame is an inner face of the movable quadrangular frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The closure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the window or door is an outwardly opening closure and said first face of the movable quadrangular frame is an outer face of the movable quadrangular frame.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The closure as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of said actuating members comprises at least one snap-in engagement tooth elastically engaging a corresponding one of said ledges. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
