<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07644610-20100112.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091229" date-publ="20100112">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07644610</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100112</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11844506</doc-number>
<date>20070824</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>109</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>49</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100112</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7315223</main-classification>
<further-classification>702  6</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Automated formation fluid clean-up to sampling switchover</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3490480</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Parsons</name>
<date>19700100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4032781</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Arnold</name>
<date>19770600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4809790</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Manchak, Jr.</name>
<date>19890300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4860581</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Zimmerman et al.</name>
<date>19890800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5803186</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Berger et al.</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6047239</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Berger et al.</name>
<date>20000400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6157893</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Berger et al.</name>
<date>20001200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6268911</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tubel et al.</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6558901</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Catanzariti et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>435  6</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6581455</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Berger et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6659177</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bolze et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6668924</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bolze et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6688390</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bolze et al.</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6799117</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Proett et al.</name>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7204309</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Segura et al.</name>
<date>20070400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7398159</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Venkataramanan et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>702 11</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0166961</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Means et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00018">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0155472</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Venkataramanan et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>702 10</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00019">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0156088</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hsu et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7315223</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00020">
<othercit>International Search Report for International Application PCT/US2008/074020. Mailed Nov. 6, 2008.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00021">
<othercit>Written Opinion of the International Searching Authority for International Application PCT/US2008/074020. Mailed Nov. 6, 2008.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>32</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7315223</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090049904</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090226</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Meister</last-name>
<first-name>Matthias</first-name>
<address>
<city>Niedersachsen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cantor Colburn LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Baker Hughes Incorporated</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Houston</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Williams</last-name>
<first-name>Hezron</first-name>
<department>2856</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Frank</last-name>
<first-name>Rodney T</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Apparatus and method for downhole formation fluid sampling include conveying a carrier into a well borehole that traverses a subterranean formation of interest, the carrier having a port and placing the port in fluid communication with the subterranean formation of interest. The method includes urging a fluid into the port using a fluid control device, the fluid containing a formation fluid and a contaminant, generating a first signal indicative of a first fluid characteristic of the fluid using a first test device in communication with the fluid, and generating a second signal indicative of a second fluid characteristic of the fluid using a second test device in communication with the fluid. The first signal and the second signal are processed using a processing device to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid, and a control signal is generated when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value, the control signal actuating the fluid control device to direct fluid having a level of contamination at about or below the predetermined value to a fluid sampling chamber carried by the carrier.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="232.75mm" wi="175.34mm" file="US07644610-20100112-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="196.68mm" wi="135.89mm" file="US07644610-20100112-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.74mm" wi="176.45mm" file="US07644610-20100112-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="230.38mm" wi="149.52mm" file="US07644610-20100112-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="238.84mm" wi="172.80mm" file="US07644610-20100112-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="230.12mm" wi="172.80mm" file="US07644610-20100112-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure generally relates to well bore tools and in particular to apparatus and methods for downhole fluid sampling.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Background Information</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the oil and gas industry, formation testing tools have been used for monitoring formation pressures along a well borehole, obtaining formation fluid samples from the borehole and predicting performance of reservoirs around the borehole. Such formation testing tools typically contain an elongated body having an elastomeric packer and/or pad that is sealingly urged against a zone of interest in the borehole to collect formation fluid samples in fluid receiving chambers placed in the tool.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Downhole multi-tester instruments have been developed with extensible sampling probes for engaging the borehole wall at the formation of interest for withdrawing fluid samples from the formation and for measuring pressure. In downhole instruments of this nature an internal pump or piston may be used after engaging the borehole wall to reduce pressure at the instrument formation interface causing fluid to flow from the formation into the instrument.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Formation fluid sampling during drilling operations requires a clean-up process for removing contaminants, such as borehole fluid containing drilling fluid and formation fluid, from the fluid entering a sampling tool. Likewise, sampling processes using wireline tools need to remove contaminants from fluid samples. Once the clean-up process is complete, a sampling process may begin where clean formation fluid is transferred to sampling chambers. Traditionally, an application engineer at the well site sends a command to switch over from the clean-up process to the sampling process. The clean-up process is sometimes a timed process whereby the application engineer waits a predetermined length of time and assumes that the fluid stream entering the tool is free of contaminants at the end of the time period for clean-up. Some sampling processes include fluid measurements that are interpreted by an application engineer who then decides when to switch from the clean-up process to the sampling process. Pump rates are typically selected as a fixed rate low enough to maintain pressure above the fluid bubble-point during the draw down.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The following presents a general summary of several aspects of the disclosure in order to provide a basic understanding of at least some aspects of the disclosure. This summary is not an extensive overview of the disclosure. It is not intended to identify key or critical elements of the disclosure or to delineate the scope of the claims. The following summary merely presents some concepts of the disclosure in a general form as a prelude to the more detailed description that follows.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Disclosed is a downhole fluid sampling apparatus that includes a carrier conveyable into a well borehole that traverses a subterranean formation of interest, the carrier having a port that is placed in fluid communication with the subterranean formation of interest. A fluid control device urges a fluid into the port, the fluid containing a formation fluid and a contaminant. A first test device is in communication with the fluid, the first test device generating a first signal indicative of a first fluid characteristic of the fluid. A second test device is in communication with the fluid, the second test device generating a second signal indicative of a second fluid characteristic of the fluid. A processing device receives the first signal and the second signal, the processing device processing the first signal and the second signal to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid, the processing device generating a control signal when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value, the control signal actuating the fluid control device to direct fluid having a level of contamination at about or below the predetermined value to a fluid sampling chamber carried by the carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another aspect, a method for downhole fluid sampling includes conveying a carrier into a well borehole that traverses a subterranean formation of interest, the carrier having a port and placing the port in fluid communication with the subterranean formation of interest. The method includes urging a fluid into the port using a fluid control device, the fluid containing a formation fluid and a contaminant, generating a first signal indicative of a first fluid characteristic of the fluid using a first test device in communication with the fluid, and generating a second signal indicative of a second fluid characteristic of the fluid using a second test device in communication with the fluid. The first signal and the second signal are processed using a processing device to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid, and a control signal is generated when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value, the control signal actuating the fluid control device to direct fluid having a level of contamination at about or below the predetermined value to a fluid sampling chamber carried by the carrier.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">For a detailed understanding of the present disclosure, reference should be made to the following detailed description of the several non-limiting embodiments, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, in which like elements have been given like numerals and wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exemplary logging-while drilling system useful for several embodiments of the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a non-limiting example of a down hole fluid sampling tool according to the disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a non-limiting example of a downhole fluid analysis device used in several embodiments;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates another example of a down hole fluid sampling tool according to the disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a method for formation fluid sampling according to the disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> schematically illustrates a non-limiting example of a drilling system <b>100</b> in a measurement-while-drilling (MWD) arrangement according to one embodiment of the disclosure. A derrick <b>102</b> supports a drill string <b>104</b>, which may be a coiled tube or drill pipe. The drill string <b>104</b> may carry a bottom hole assembly (BHA) <b>106</b> and a drill bit <b>108</b> at a distal end of the drill string <b>104</b> for drilling a borehole <b>110</b> through earth formations.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Drilling operations according to several embodiments may include pumping drilling fluid or &#x201c;mud&#x201d; from a mud pit <b>122</b>, and using a circulation system <b>124</b>, circulating the mud through an inner bore of the drill string <b>104</b>. The mud exits the drill string <b>104</b> at the drill bit <b>108</b> and returns to the surface through an annular space between the drill string <b>104</b> and inner wall of the borehole <b>110</b>. The drilling fluid is designed to provide the hydrostatic pressure that is greater than the formation pressure to avoid blowouts. The pressurized drilling fluid may further be used to drive a drilling motor, provides lubrication to various elements of the drill string and is used for cleaning cuttings from the borehole.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In one non-limiting example, subs <b>114</b> and <b>116</b> may be positioned as desired along the drill string <b>104</b>. As shown, a sub <b>116</b> may be included as part of the BHA <b>106</b>. Each sub <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> may include one or more components <b>118</b> adapted to provide formation tests while drilling (&#x201c;FTWD&#x201d;) and/or functions relating to drilling parameters. Sometimes drilling progression and bit rotation may be stopped for certain tests, although these tests are generally considered as while-drilling tests. The subs <b>114</b>, <b>116</b> may be used to obtain parameters of interest relating to the formation, the formation fluid, the drilling fluid, the drilling operations or any desired combination. Characteristics measured to obtain to the desired parameter of interest may include pressure, flow rate, resistivity, dielectric, temperature, optical properties, viscosity, density, chemical composition, pH, salinity, tool azimuth, tool inclination, drill bit rotation, weight on bit, etc. These characteristics may be processed by a processor (not shown) downhole to determine the desired parameter. Signals indicative of the parameter may then be transmitted to the surface via a transmitter in a transceiver <b>112</b> used for bi-directional communication with the surface. The transceiver <b>112</b> may be located in the BHA <b>106</b> or at another location on the drill string <b>104</b>. These signals may also, or in the alternative, be stored downhole in a data storage device and may also be processed and used downhole for geosteering or for any other suitable downhole purpose. As used herein, the term parameter refers to the result of any useful measurement, calculation, estimation, or the like relating to drilling operations. For example, drilling parameters may include drilling speed, direction, weight on bit (WOB), mud characteristics (e.g. mud density, composition, etc . . . ), torque, inclination and any other parameter relating to drilling. Other examples of parameters are formation parameters including rock type and composition, porosity, fluid composition produced from a formation, pressure, temperature, mobility, water content, gas content, lithology, density, porosity and other aspects of subterranean formations and fluid properties produced from such formations. Obtaining these drilling and formation parameters provides useful information for further drilling operations and helps to determine the viability of a reservoir for producing hydrocarbons.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Many downhole operations include sampling formation fluid for testing. The samples obtained may be tested downhole using instruments carried by wireline, by the drill string, coiled tubing or wired pipe. Formation fluid samples may be brought to the surface for testing on-site or in a laboratory environment.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, one non-limiting example of a sub <b>116</b> component <b>118</b> may include a fluid sampling tool <b>200</b>. In several embodiments, the fluid sampling tool <b>200</b> may include a sampling probe <b>204</b> having a durable rubber pad <b>202</b> at a distal end of the sampling probe <b>204</b>. The pad <b>202</b> may be mechanically pressed against the borehole wall adjacent a formation <b>206</b> hard enough to form a hydraulic seal between the wall and probe <b>204</b>. A probe extension and retraction device <b>242</b> may be used to extend and retract the sampling probe <b>204</b>. Any number of extension and retraction devices <b>242</b> may be used and remain within the scope of the disclosure. In the non-limiting example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the extension and retraction device <b>242</b> includes a hydraulic pump <b>244</b> that pumps hydraulic fluid contained in a reservoir <b>246</b> to and from a probe housing <b>248</b>. The sampling probe <b>204</b> is movably disposed in the probe housing <b>248</b>, such that hydraulic fluid pressure in the housing <b>248</b> causes the fluid sampling probe <b>204</b> to move in or out with respect to the tool <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The pad <b>202</b> includes an opening or port <b>208</b> leading to a cavity <b>214</b> formed by an inner wall <b>216</b> of the probe <b>204</b>. A pump <b>218</b> may be used to reduce pressure within the cavity <b>214</b> to urge formation fluid into the port <b>208</b> and cavity <b>214</b>. A flow line <b>220</b> may be used to convey fluid from the cavity <b>214</b> to the borehole annulus <b>110</b>. In one non-limiting example, a fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may be used to determine type and content of fluid flowing in the flow line <b>220</b>. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may include any number of testing devices, and is shown schematically here as a single box for simplicity. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may be located on either side of the pump <b>218</b> or the several test devices may be located on both the inlet and outlet of the pump <b>218</b> as desired. A more detailed description of the fluid analysis device <b>240</b> is provided below with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Formation fluid may be received into any number of probe configurations. In the non-limiting example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a sleeve-like member, or simply sleeve, <b>222</b> is disposed within the cavity <b>214</b> and is in fluid communication with fluid entering the cavity <b>214</b>. As used herein, the term sleeve means a member having a length, an outer cross-section perimeter and an inner cross-section perimeter creating a volume within the member. In the example of a cylindrical sleeve, the outer cross-section perimeter may be referred to as an outer diameter (OD) and the inner cross-section perimeter may be referred to as an inner diameter (ID). The term sleeve however, includes any useful cross-section shaped member that may not be circular as in the case of a cylinder, but may include shapes including eccentric. Several examples of a probe <b>204</b> having a substantially coaxial sleeve <b>222</b> are described in U.S. provisional patent application 60/894,720 for &#x201c;METHOD AND APPARATUS FOR COLLECTING SUBTERRANEAN FORMATION FLUID&#x201d; filed on Mar. 14, 2007, the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A second pump <b>224</b> may be used to control fluid pressure within the sleeve <b>222</b>. A flow path <b>226</b> within the sleeve <b>222</b> allows fluid to be conveyed from the sleeve <b>222</b> flow path <b>226</b> through flow lines <b>228</b>, which may lead to a sampling chamber <b>230</b>, and optionally to a dump line <b>234</b> leading back to the borehole annulus. The dump line <b>234</b> may be routed to any suitable location as shown, above the sampling chamber <b>230</b> or in-line with the sampling chamber <b>230</b>. A controllable valve <b>210</b> may be used to control fluid flow from the second pump <b>224</b> to either the sampling chamber <b>230</b> or to the dump line <b>234</b>. In one non-limiting example, a second fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may be used to determine type and content of fluid flowing in the flow line <b>228</b>. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may include any number of testing devices as mentioned above. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may be located on either side of the pump <b>240</b> or the several test devices may be located on both the inlet and outlet of the pump <b>240</b> as desired.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Each of the pumps <b>218</b>, <b>224</b> may be independently controlled by one or more surface controllers (see <b>120</b> <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), or by one or more downhole controllers <b>236</b> as shown and by programmed instructions that are stored in a memory within the controller <b>236</b> and executed by a processor in the controller <b>236</b>. Bi-directional communication between the surface and the tool <b>200</b> may be accomplished using a transceiver <b>112</b> in communication with the controller <b>120</b>, <b>236</b>. As mentioned above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the transceiver <b>112</b> may utilize any number of communication media, including drilling fluid pulse telemetry and wired telemetry. The tool may be disposed on a wired pipe or a wireline tool carrier may be used where a communication cable extends to the surface.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Addressable pump actuators <b>250</b> may be coupled to each pump <b>218</b>, <b>224</b> for receiving pump-specific communication from the controller <b>236</b>. The controller may issue control commands such as on/off commands, pump rate commands and/or pump direction commands to control fluid flow within the tool <b>200</b>. An addressable pump actuator may be coupled to the probe extension pump <b>244</b> so that the controller <b>236</b> may be used to control probe extension as well. Any suitable addressable actuator may be used or an addressable circuit may be incorporated into the pumps for receiving pump-specific communication from the controller <b>120</b>, <b>236</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Fluid flow in the sampling probe <b>204</b> according to several embodiments is controlled by controlling the flow rate in the cavity <b>214</b>, the flow path <b>226</b>, or both the cavity <b>214</b> and flow path <b>226</b> such that direction of fluid flowing in the cavity and the flow path may be controlled with respect to one another as represented by the arrows within the cavity <b>214</b> that show fluid flowing between the sleeve <b>222</b> and the cavity <b>214</b>. In some cases, a flow rate may be selected for the cavity area and/or the flow path that urges at least some fluid flow from the flow path <b>226</b> to flow to the cavity <b>214</b> and on to the cavity pump <b>218</b>. In other cases, a flow rate may be selected for the cavity area and/or the flow path that urges at least some fluid flow from the cavity <b>214</b> to the flow path <b>226</b> and on to the sleeve pump <b>224</b> for testing and/or storage.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The several exemplary embodiments disclosed herein provide autonomous switchover from a clean-up process to a sampling process using the tool <b>200</b>. In operation, commands from the controller <b>236</b> may initiate the first pump <b>218</b> for a fluid clean-up process.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The autonomous switchover may be accomplished using a closed-loop sensor and actuator system. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> takes multiple measurements to estimate several fluid characteristics of the fluid entering the probe <b>204</b>. These estimates are transmitted as electrical signals to the controller <b>236</b> processor and/or to the surface controller <b>120</b> processor. In one example, the processor may be used to access information relating to characteristics of drilling fluid and/or borehole fluid, and these characteristics may be used in programs to compare fluid entering the probe to the drilling and/or borehole fluid characteristics. In another example, known formation fluid characteristics are stored in the database and used to compare the characteristics estimated using the fluid analysis device <b>240</b>. The controller may be programmed with a preset acceptable level of contamination, such as 5% acceptable contamination for example. Once the preset acceptable contamination is achieved, the controller sends an electrical signal to the addressable pump actuators <b>250</b> to automatically begin a sample acquisition process. The controller may further command the addressable controllable valve <b>210</b> to divert all or part of the fluid flowing into the probe <b>204</b> to the sample tank <b>230</b>. A pressure sensor <b>252</b> may be used to monitor fluid pressure in the sample tank <b>230</b>. A suitable overpressure for maintaining the sampled fluid in single-phase may be programmed into the controller. A signal from the pressure sensor <b>252</b> may be conveyed to the controller <b>236</b>. The controller <b>236</b> may then process the received pressure signal and command the pump <b>224</b> to stop pumping fluid into the tank <b>230</b>. Multiple tanks <b>230</b> may be used, and second or other tanks may be filled automatically simultaneously with the first tank <b>230</b> or after the first tank <b>230</b> is filled. The controller may then send a command signal to the addressable pump actuator <b>250</b> coupled to the probe extension pump <b>244</b> to retract the probe <b>204</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In the non-limiting example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the sampling probe <b>204</b> is shown mounted on the sub <b>116</b>, but any suitable mounting location may be used that allows formation fluid communication into the tool <b>200</b>. For example, a sub member extending from the tool <b>200</b> may be used as a mounting location. In one example, the fluid sampling probe <b>204</b> may be incorporated into a centralizer. Those skilled in the art will understand that a centralizer is a member, usually metal, extending in a radial direction from the sub <b>116</b> and is used to help keep the sub <b>116</b> centered within the borehole. Other configurations of downhole tools may use ribs as centralizers or no centralizer at all. In some cases, a backup shoe may be used to provide a counter force to help keep the probe pad <b>202</b> pressed against the borehole wall.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The fluid sampling probe <b>204</b> may be coupled to the sub <b>116</b> in a controllably extendable manner by using an extension device <b>242</b> as described above. In other embodiments, dual packers or straddle packers may be used as the sealing element. In another example, the fluid sampling probe <b>204</b> may be mounted in a fixed position with an extendable rib or centralizer used to move the pad <b>202</b> toward the borehole wall.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The inner sleeve-like member <b>222</b> may be of any number of sleeve types to allow fluid communication between the sleeve flow path <b>226</b> and cavity <b>214</b>. In one example, the sleeve may be a solid cylinder-shaped sleeve that extends from a rear section <b>238</b> of the fluid sampling probe <b>204</b> toward the pad port <b>208</b> and terminating in the cavity without extending all the way to the borehole wall. In this manner, fluid communication between the sleeve flow path and cavity is concentrated substantially near the sleeve terminating end within the cavity. In another non-limiting example, the sleeve-like member <b>222</b> may include several openings along the length of the sleeve or the front portion of the sleeve <b>222</b> to allow fluid communication between the sleeve flow path <b>226</b> and the cavity <b>214</b> as shown by the arrows extending from the flow path <b>226</b> to the cavity <b>214</b>. In several embodiments that include openings along the sleeve <b>222</b>, the sleeve <b>222</b> may either terminate within the cavity <b>214</b> or the sleeve may extend to the borehole wall as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a non-limiting example of a fluid analysis device <b>240</b> having several fluid test devices <b>302</b>, <b>304</b>, <b>306</b>, <b>308</b>, <b>310</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>314</b>, <b>316</b>. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may include any number of fluid test devices for estimating the several characteristics typical of fluid flowing in the tool <b>200</b>. Shown here are a fluorescence test device <b>302</b>, a reflectometer <b>304</b>, a viscometer <b>306</b>, pressure and temperature transducers <b>308</b>, sonic devices <b>310</b>, resistivity measurement devices <b>312</b>, capacitance and dielectric constant measurement devices <b>314</b>, and spectrometers <b>316</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> in several embodiments includes a fluid cell <b>318</b> that may be a continuous flow path portion of the flow lines <b>228</b> (or <b>220</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) leading to and from the fluid analysis device <b>240</b>. Each of the fluid test devices <b>302</b>, <b>304</b>, <b>306</b>, <b>308</b>, <b>310</b>, <b>312</b>, <b>314</b>, <b>316</b> is in communication with the fluid cell <b>318</b> with each test device being used for estimating a different characteristic of fluid flowing in the fluid cell <b>318</b>. Any useful characteristic of the fluid flowing in the fluid cell <b>318</b> may be estimated. Non-limiting examples are optical characteristics, electrical characteristics and physical characteristics. Depending upon the test devices used, several coupling methods may be used for coupling a particular test device to the fluid cell <b>318</b>. For example, some test devices may be in fluid contact with fluid in the fluid cell <b>318</b>, some devices may be in optical communication, some devices may be in acoustic communication, some devices may be in physical contact with fluid in the fluid cell <b>318</b>, and still others may be in pressure and/or thermal communication with the fluid in the fluid cell <b>318</b>. The representative example in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows one possible order of a particular set of test devices. Other combinations of test devices placed in various relative positions may be used to estimate characteristics of the fluid. As noted earlier, the fluid analysis device <b>240</b> is not necessarily a set of contiguously placed fluid test devices. The fluid analysis device may be functionally achieved by gathering information from several test devices placed at non-contiguous locations along a drill string and testing fluid entering the drilling tool.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the non-limiting example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, optical characteristics may be estimated using a downhole fluorescence test device <b>302</b> that includes a light source <b>320</b> emitting a light toward a window <b>322</b> in optical communication with fluid in the fluid cell <b>318</b>. A photodetector <b>324</b> may be used to detect fluorescence emitted by fluid components in the fluid within the fluid cell <b>318</b>. An output of the fluorescence test device <b>302</b> may be conveyed via a data bus <b>326</b> to a processor <b>236</b> for processing. Other optical characteristics may be estimated using a reflectometer <b>304</b> that includes a light source <b>328</b> emitting a light toward a window <b>330</b> in optical communication with fluid in the fluid cell <b>318</b>. A photodetector <b>332</b> may be used to detect light energy reflected by the fluid within the fluid cell <b>318</b>. An output of the reflectometer <b>304</b> may be conveyed via the data bus <b>326</b> to the processor <b>236</b> for processing. Other optical energy characteristics may be estimated using a spectrometer <b>316</b> to determine spectral wavelength information in the visible range near infrared range or other using other wavelengths for mass spectrometry and gas content. The spectrometer <b>316</b> may include a light source <b>352</b> emitting light toward a window <b>354</b> in the fluid cell <b>318</b>. A photodetector <b>356</b> receives light energy after the emitted light interacts with the fluid in the fluid cell. The energy received at the photodetector provides spectral energy information about the fluid in the fluid call. Optical information may be conveyed to the processor <b>236</b> via the data bus <b>326</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Physical characteristics of the fluid may be estimated using a viscometer <b>306</b> that includes a transducer <b>334</b> converting fluid viscosity characteristics to information conveyed to the processor <b>236</b> via the data bus <b>326</b>. Other physical characteristics such as pressure, temperature and fluid density may be estimated using pressure, temperature and fluid density transducers <b>308</b> that include respective sensing elements <b>336</b> for gathering pressure, temperature and fluid density information in electronic form. The gathered information may be conveyed to the processor <b>236</b> via the data bus <b>326</b>. Another physical characteristic relates to acoustic transmittance of the fluid, which may be estimated using sonic devices <b>310</b> having associated energy source <b>338</b> and receiver <b>340</b> and an electronics module <b>342</b> for converting the sonic information received to a form for transmitting.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Electrical characteristics may be estimated using resistivity measurement devices <b>312</b> that may include several contacts <b>344</b> for estimating resistivity of the fluid. Other electrical characteristics of the fluid may be estimated using capacitance and dielectric constant measurement devices <b>314</b> having associated contacts <b>346</b>, <b>448</b> and electronics module <b>350</b> for determining fluid electrical characteristics. Output signals from the sonic devices <b>310</b>, the resistivity devices <b>312</b>, the capacitance/dielectric devices <b>314</b> and any other suitable test device may be conveyed to the processor <b>236</b> via the data bus <b>326</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Other devices may be included on the tool <b>300</b> without departing from the scope of the disclosure. One or more of the devices depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> may include a chemical test device, a fluid compositional analysis device, a gas chromatograph, a pH test device, a salinity test device, a CO2 test device, an H2S test device, a device for determining wax and asphaltene components, a device for determining metal content, (mercury or other metal), and a device for determining acidity of the fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is another non-limiting embodiment of a downhole fluid sampling tool <b>400</b>. In several embodiments, the fluid sampling tool <b>400</b> may include components substantially similar to the components as described above with respect to the tool <b>200</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a sampling probe <b>404</b> has a durable rubber pad <b>402</b> at a distal end of the sampling probe <b>404</b>. The pad <b>402</b> may be mechanically pressed against the borehole wall adjacent a formation <b>206</b> hard enough to form a hydraulic seal between the wall and probe <b>404</b>. A probe extension and retraction device <b>242</b> may be used to extend and retract the sampling probe <b>404</b>. Any number of extension and retraction devices <b>242</b> may be used and remain within the scope of the disclosure. In the non-limiting example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the extension and retraction device <b>242</b> includes a hydraulic pump <b>244</b> that pumps hydraulic fluid contained in a reservoir <b>246</b> to and from a probe housing <b>448</b>. The sampling probe <b>404</b> is movably disposed in the probe housing <b>448</b>, such that hydraulic fluid pressure in the housing <b>448</b> causes the fluid sampling probe <b>404</b> to move in or out with respect to the tool <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The pad <b>402</b> includes an opening or port <b>408</b> leading to a cavity <b>414</b> formed by an inner wall <b>416</b> of the probe <b>404</b>. A pump <b>224</b> may be used to reduce pressure within the cavity <b>414</b> to urge formation fluid into the port <b>408</b> and cavity <b>414</b>. A flow line <b>228</b> may be used to convey fluid from the cavity <b>414</b> to the borehole annulus <b>110</b> via a dump line <b>234</b> or to a fluid sampling chamber <b>230</b>. The dump line <b>234</b> may be routed to any suitable location as shown, above the sampling chamber <b>230</b> or in-line with the sampling chamber <b>230</b>. A controllable valve <b>210</b> may be used to control fluid flow from the pump <b>224</b> to either the sampling chamber <b>230</b> or to the dump line <b>234</b>. A fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may be used to determine type and content of fluid flowing in the flow line <b>228</b>. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may include any number of testing devices, and is shown schematically here as a single box for simplicity. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> may be located on either side of the pump <b>224</b> or the several test devices may be located on both the inlet and outlet of the pump <b>224</b> as desired. A more detailed description of the fluid analysis device <b>240</b> is described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The pump <b>224</b> may be controlled by one or more surface controllers (see <b>120</b> <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), or by one or more downhole controllers <b>236</b> as shown and by programmed instructions that are stored in a memory within the controller <b>236</b> and executed by a processor in the controller <b>236</b>. Bi-directional communication between the surface and the tool <b>400</b> may be accomplished using a transceiver <b>112</b> in communication with the controller <b>120</b>, <b>236</b>. As mentioned above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the transceiver <b>112</b> may utilize any number of communication media, including drilling fluid pulse telemetry and wired telemetry. The tool may be disposed on a wired pipe or a wireline tool carrier may be used where a communication cable extends to the surface.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Addressable actuators <b>250</b> may be coupled to the pump <b>224</b> for receiving pump-specific communication from the controller <b>236</b>. The controller may issue control commands such as on/off commands, pump rate commands and/or pump direction commands to control fluid flow within the tool <b>400</b>. An addressable actuator <b>250</b> may be coupled to the probe extension pump <b>244</b> so that the controller <b>236</b> may be used to control probe extension as well. Any suitable addressable actuator may be used or an addressable circuit may be incorporated into the pumps for receiving pump-specific communication from the controller <b>120</b>, <b>236</b>. The controllable valve <b>210</b> may be actuated by a similar actuator <b>250</b> controlled by commands from the controller <b>236</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The several exemplary embodiments disclosed herein provide autonomous switchover from a clean-up process to a sampling process using the tool <b>400</b>. In operation, commands from the controller <b>236</b> may initiate the pump <b>224</b> for a fluid clean-up process. The fluid clean-up process is an initial sampling to generate a flow rate in the chamber and flow line <b>228</b>. Clean-up flow is through the controllable valve <b>210</b> to help remove borehole fluid that may be contaminating the fluid entering the tool from the formation <b>206</b>. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> uses several test devices for autonomous switchover from the clean-up process to the fluid sampling process. Once the fluid is relatively free of contamination by borehole fluid, the controller may actuate the controllable valve <b>210</b> to automatically switch flow from the dump line <b>234</b> to the line <b>228</b> leading to the sample chamber <b>230</b>. Multiple tanks <b>230</b> may be used for repeat sampling, and second or other tanks may be filled automatically simultaneously with the first tank <b>230</b> or after the first tank <b>230</b> is filled. Generally, sample tanks <b>230</b> may also be nitrogen buffered for keeping the sample in single phase during retrieval from down hole to the surface.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The autonomous switchover and repeat sampling may be accomplished using a closed-loop sensor and actuator system. The fluid analysis device <b>240</b> takes multiple measurements as described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> to estimate several fluid characteristics of the fluid entering the probe <b>404</b>. These estimates are transmitted as electrical signals to the controller <b>236</b> processor. In one example, the processor may be used to access information relating to characteristics of drilling fluid and/or borehole fluid, and these characteristics may be used in programs to compare fluid entering the probe to the drilling and/or borehole fluid characteristics. In another example, known formation fluid characteristics are stored in the database and used to compare the characteristics estimated using the fluid analysis device <b>240</b>. The controller may be programmed with a preset acceptable level of contamination, such as 5% acceptable contamination for example. Once the preset acceptable contamination is achieved, the controller sends an electrical signal to the addressable pump actuators <b>250</b> and/or to the controllable valve <b>210</b>. In response to the transmitted command, the pump rate the pump <b>224</b> and the valve <b>210</b> position are change to automatically begin a sample acquisition process. A pressure sensor <b>252</b> may be used to monitor fluid pressure in the sample tank <b>230</b>. A suitable overpressure for maintaining the sampled fluid in single-phase may be programmed into the controller. A signal from the pressure sensor <b>252</b> may be conveyed to the controller <b>236</b>, and the controller <b>236</b> may then process the received pressure signal and command the pump <b>224</b> to stop pumping fluid into the tank <b>230</b>. The controller may then send a command signal to the addressable pump actuator <b>250</b> coupled to the probe extension pump <b>244</b> to retract the probe <b>404</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In the non-limiting example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the sampling probe <b>404</b> is shown mounted on the sub <b>116</b>, but any suitable mounting location may be used that allows formation fluid communication into the tool <b>400</b>. For example, a sub member extending from the tool <b>400</b> may be used as a mounting location. In one example, the fluid sampling probe <b>404</b> may be incorporated into a centralizer. Those skilled in the art will understand that a centralizer is a member, usually metal, extending in a radial direction from the sub <b>116</b> and is used to help keep the sub <b>116</b> centered within the borehole. Other configurations of downhole tools may use ribs as centralizers or no centralizer at all. In some cases, a backup shoe may be used to provide a counter force to help keep the probe pad <b>402</b> pressed against the borehole wall.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The several embodiments described above and shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-4</figref> provide for a closed-loop formation fluid sampling system having autonomous switchover from a clean-up process to a fluid sampling process. The closed-loop system further provides for optimized pump rates in order to provide maximum clean-up in the shortest possible time and then to switch over, autonomously, to begin filling sampling tanks. In this manner, tasks traditionally performed by an application engineer, may be enhanced or transferred completely to the autonomous process. Real-time monitoring in conjunction with the closed-loop process further provides autonomous control of the pump-rates to help ensure fluid pressures are maintained above the fluid bubble-point or wax/asphaltene fall out pressure during draw down and sampling. The real-time comparison of sampled fluid to known drilling fluid characteristics and/or the real-time comparison of sampled fluid to known formation fluid characteristics provide determination and verification of a reachable residual contamination level that may be acceptable for useful formation fluid samples.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a method <b>500</b> for fluid sampling and acquisition that includes a clean-up process by which contaminants, usually borehole fluids, are removed from the fluid sample stream flowing into a fluid sampling tool. The exemplary method <b>500</b> includes conveying a carrier into a well borehole that traverses a subterranean formation of interest <b>502</b>. The carrier has a port and the method includes placing the port in fluid communication with the subterranean formation of interest <b>504</b>. The method includes urging a fluid into the port using a fluid control device <b>506</b>, the fluid containing a formation fluid and a contaminant. A first signal indicative of a first fluid characteristic of the fluid is generated using a first test device in communication with the fluid <b>508</b>, and a second signal indicative of a second fluid characteristic of the fluid is generated using a second test device in communication with the fluid <b>510</b>. The first signal and the second signal are processed <b>512</b> using a processing device to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid, and a control signal is generated <b>514</b> when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value, the control signal actuating <b>516</b> the fluid control device to direct fluid having a level of contamination at about or below the predetermined value to a fluid sampling chamber carried by the carrier.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In one embodiment, at least one of the first signal and the second signal is indicative of an optical characteristic of fluid in the fluid cell, and the optical characteristic comprises one or more of fluorescence, a reflectance and spectral energy. In one embodiment, at least one of the first signal and the second signal is indicative of an electrical characteristic of fluid in the fluid cell, and the electrical characteristic comprises one or more of resistivity, capacitance, and dielectric constant. In another embodiment, at least one of the first signal and the second signal is indicative of a physical characteristic of fluid in the fluid cell, and the physical characteristic comprises one or more of viscosity, pressure, temperature, fluid density, and acoustic transmittance. The method of generating the first signal and the second signal may be a combination of at least two of an optical characteristic, and electrical characteristic and a physical characteristic of fluid in the fluid cell.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In several embodiments, the method may include sending control instructions from the processing device to one or more addressable pumps and/or to one or more addressable valves for controlling fluid flow in the tool.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The present disclosure is to be taken as illustrative rather than as limiting the scope or nature of the claims below. Numerous modifications and variations will become apparent to those skilled in the art after studying the disclosure, including use of equivalent functional and/or structural substitutes for elements described herein, use of equivalent functional couplings for couplings described herein, and/or use of equivalent functional actions for actions described herein. Such insubstantial variations are to be considered within the scope of the claims below.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A downhole apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a carrier conveyable in a well borehole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump providing a variable pump rate for generating a pressure gradient across a flow path of a fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid control device that urges the fluid into a port, the fluid containing a contaminant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first test device in communication with the fluid, the first test device generating a first signal indicative of a first fluid characteristic;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second test device in communication with the fluid, the second test device generating a second signal indicative of a second fluid characteristic; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing device that receives the first signal and the second signal, the processing device processing the first signal and the second signal to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid, the processing device generating a control signal when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A method for estimating fluid contamination downhole comprising:
<claim-text>conveying a carrier in a well borehole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting a variable pump rate to reduce a contaminant disposed in a fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>urging the fluid into a port using a fluid control device, the fluid containing a contaminant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a first signal indicative of a first fluid characteristic using a first test device in communication with the fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a second signal indicative of a second fluid characteristic using a second test device in communication with the fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>processing the first signal and the second signal using a processing device to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a control signal when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A downhole apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a carrier conveyable in a well borehole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump providing a variable pump rate for generating a pressure gradient across a flow path of a fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fluid control device that urges the fluid into a port, the fluid containing a contaminant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a test device in communication with the fluid, the test device generating a signal indicative of a fluid characteristic;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing device that receives the signal, the processing device processing the signal to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid, the processing device generating a control signal when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device includes a device for estimating an optical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device comprises one or more of a fluorescence test device, a reflectometer and a spectrometer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device includes a device for estimating an electrical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the device for estimating an electrical characteristic comprises one or more of a resistivity test device, a capacitance test device, and a dielectric test device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device includes a device for estimating a physical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device comprises one or more of a viscometer, a pressure transducer, a temperature transducer, a fluid density test device, and a sonic test device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device comprises one or more of a chemical test device, a fluid compositional analysis device, a gas chromatograph, a pH test device, a salinity test device, a CO<sub>2 </sub>test device, an H<sub>2</sub>S test device, a device for determining wax and asphaltene components, a device for determining metal content, and a device for determining acidity of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the test device includes a plurality of devices for estimating a combination of at least two of an optical characteristic, an electrical characteristic, a physical characteristic and a chemical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid control device includes one or more addressable pumps that receive control instructions from the processing device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid control device includes one or more addressable valves that receive control instructions from the processing device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the apparatus comprises a fluid sampling device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the control signal actuates the fluid control device to direct fluid having a level of contamination at about or below the predetermined value to a fluid sampling chamber carried by the carrier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> further comprising at least another pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the pump rate is adjusted for a clean-up process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the pump generates a flow in a sleeve surrounding a cavity.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. An apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the pressure gradient comprises a vector of a varying direction and a varying magnitude.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. A method for estimating fluid contamination downhole comprising:
<claim-text>conveying a carrier in a well borehole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>adjusting a variable pump rate to reduce a contaminant disposed in a fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>urging the fluid into a port using a fluid control device, the fluid containing a contaminant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a signal indicative of a fluid characteristic using a test device in communication with the fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>processing the signal using a processing device to estimate a level of contamination in the fluid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a control signal when the estimated level of contamination meets a predetermined value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the signal is indicative of an optical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein the optical characteristic comprises one or more of fluorescence, a reflectance and spectral energy.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the signal is indicative of an electrical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, wherein the electrical characteristic comprises one or more of resistivity, capacitance, and dielectric constant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the signal is indicative of a physical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, wherein the physical characteristic comprises one or more of viscosity, pressure, temperature, fluid density, and acoustic transmittance.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein generating the signal includes generating one or more signals indicative of a combination of at least two of an optical characteristic, an electrical characteristic, a chemical characteristic and a physical characteristic of the fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid control device includes one or more addressable pumps, the method including sending control instructions from the processing device to the one or more addressable pumps.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein the fluid control device includes one or more addressable valves, the method including sending control instructions from the processing device to the one or more addressable valves.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref> further comprising sampling the fluid using a fluid sampling device.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref> further comprising actuating the fluid control device using the control signal; and using the fluid control device to direct fluid having a level of contamination at about or below the predetermined value to a fluid sampling chamber carried by the carrier.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. A method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref>, wherein adjusting comprises generating a pressure gradient across a flow path of the fluid. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
