<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640629-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640629</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11940962</doc-number>
<date>20071115</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2006-0114143</doc-number>
<date>20061117</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>46</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>E</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>3</main-group>
<subgroup>10</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 16367</main-classification>
<further-classification> 16277</further-classification>
<further-classification> 16224</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Mobile terminal</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6985579</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Abood et al.</name>
<date>20060100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>37943313</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2004/0121825</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ma et al.</name>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555754</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0046797</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chen</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555754</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0271733</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Abe et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 16225</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0318645</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Takamori et al.</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555754</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2009/0036179</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chiou et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4555754</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 16367</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 16 24</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 16224</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4555754</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>37943312</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>37943313</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361681</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080115326</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080522</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Sang-Hoon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Birch, Stewart, Kolasch &#x26; Birch, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>LG Electronics Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Batson</last-name>
<first-name>Victor</first-name>
<department>3677</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Sullivan</last-name>
<first-name>Matthew</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A mobile terminal including a first body, a second body having a display unit and arranged to overlap the first body in a closed state, and a hinge module connecting the second body to the first body such that the second body is rotatable around a first axis generally perpendicular to the first body. The hinge module being configured to allow a portion of the second body to be elevated so as to be slantingly arranged with respect to the first body in an open state.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="239.10mm" wi="308.19mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="164.25mm" wi="165.18mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="233.26mm" wi="73.66mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="193.72mm" wi="177.63mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="173.14mm" wi="177.88mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="226.40mm" wi="136.65mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="106.51mm" wi="149.61mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="244.60mm" wi="169.93mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="239.35mm" wi="77.22mm" file="US07640629-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Korean Application No. 10-2006-0114143, filed Nov. 17, 2006, and is herein incorporated by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates generally to a mobile terminal, and more particularly, a mobile terminal having one body with a display that is rotatable with respect to another body between opened and closed states and the body with the display is moveable to a slanting position with respect to the other body.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A related art mobile terminal is one of many portable electronic devices that allow the user to wirelessly transmit/receive information or read/process information while on the move. Recently, owing to the development of information technology, communication technology, and memory technology, the mobile terminal can directly create multimedia and transmit/receive multimedia, in addition to its basic call functions. For example, the mobile terminal can allow the user to capture an image or video, send an image or video, and/or enjoy an image or video by using a digital camera mounted therein, reproduce a multimedia file such as music, movies or games, or receive digital multimedia broadcasting (DMB) using satellite communication or terrestrial waves.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, the mechanical configuration of the related art mobile terminal has been changed to a structure that allows convenient use of the display unit. For example, although the conventional display unit is usually embodied as a vertical screen orientation, some display units are embodied in a horizontal screen orientation to allow more convenient viewing of broadcasts or video.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, the related art mobile terminal has the following problems. That is, a body portion having the display unit with a screen mounted in a vertical orientation can be rotated in a planar manner such that the screen is in a horizontal orientation to allow the user to watch images on a wider screen, but such planar rotation fails to provide a desired viewing angle for the user to watch the images more conveniently.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In addition, in order to obtain a desired viewing angle, the user needs to either use a device, such as a stand, cradle, or other support, to lean the entire mobile terminal thereon, which requires some space on which the stand should be placed and is thus cumbersome and inconvenient.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Therefore, in order to address the above matters the various features described herein have been conceived. One aspect of the exemplary embodiments is to provide a mobile terminal having a display unit that is capable of providing a desired viewing angle that is convenient for the user to watch an image in a viewing mode.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another aspect of the exemplary embodiments is to provide a mobile terminal having a display unit allowing a tilt angle to be automatically made while the display unit is rotated from a vertical orientation to a horizontal orientation, thus removing the necessity of a cradle.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to principles of this invention, a mobile terminal is provided that includes a first body, a second body having a display unit and arranged to overlap the first body in a closed state, and a hinge module connecting the second body to the first body such that the second body is rotatable around a first axis generally perpendicular to the first body. The hinge module being configured to allow a portion of the second body to be elevated so as to be slantingly arranged with respect to the first body in an open state.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to another aspect, the hinge module may be configured to allow the portion of the second body to be elevated while the second body is partially rotated around the first axis.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to a further aspect, the hinge module may include a first hinge portion formed on one of a front surface of the first body and a rear surface of the second body, the first hinge portion may include a slide face having a height that gradually increases so as to elevate the second body as the second body is rotated around the first axis from the closed state to the open state. A second hinge portion may be formed on the other of the front surface of the first body and the rear surface of the second body, where the second hinge portion is in slidably movable contact with the slide face of the first hinge portion. A supporting portion connects the first and second hinge portions.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to yet a further aspect, the slide face of the first hinge portion may include a planar portion formed to be generally parallel to the first body, and a slope portion extending from the planar portion and having the gradually increasing height.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to a different aspect, the first hinge portion may be formed to have a fan-like shape.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to still another aspect, the supporting portion may include a supporting recess formed at one portion of one of the first hinge portion and the second hinge portion, and a supporting projection formed at the other of the first hinge portion and the second hinge portion, the supporting projection being received in the supporting recess. The supporting recess may be substantially hemispherical and the supporting projection may be substantially spherical.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to another aspect, the hinge module may include a release preventing portion that prevents the first hinge portion from being released from the second hinge portion. The release preventing portion may include a release preventing rail having a groove formed at one surface of the first hinge portion, and a connecting portion mounted at one end of the second hinge portion, the connecting portion being received in the release preventing rail. The connecting portion may include a body extending from one end of the second hinge portion, and a protrusion extending from the body, the protrusion being slidably inserted into the release preventing rail.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to yet another aspect, the hinge module may include an elastic force member that provides an elastic force to assist in the rotational movement of the second hinge portion from the closed state to the open state. The elastic force member may include an elastic unit located at one surface of the second hinge portion, where the elastic unit is elastically extendable in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion, a transfer unit connected at one end of the elastic unit, where the transfer unit is linearly moveable by being connected to the first hinge portion, and a guide rail recessed in one surface of the first hinge portion, the guide rail receiving the transfer unit therein to guide the transfer unit.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to a further aspect, the elastic unit may include a fixed member extending from the one surface of the second hinge portion, a first shaft extending from one side of the fixed member in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion, a first elastic member located at one end of the first shaft to provide an elastic force to the rotation of the second hinge portion, and a first guide member covering the first elastic member and configured to guide an elastic movement of the first elastic member.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">According to a different aspect, the transfer unit may include a second shaft extending toward the first hinge portion, a second guide member connected at an end of the second shaft distal to the second hinge portion, the guide member being displaceable along an axis defined by the second shaft as the second body is elevated, and a transfer member located at one end of the second guide member, where the transfer member is at least partially received in the guide rail. The transfer unit may further include a second elastic member connected between the distal end of the second shaft and the transfer member.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The foregoing and other objects, features, aspects and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the present invention when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a portion of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principles of the invention, In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a mobile terminal according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of the mobile terminal of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded perspective view of the mobile terminal of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a hinge module according to the exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic front view showing a closed state of the mobile terminal of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a sectional view taken along line VI-VI in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic front view showing an opened state of the mobile terminal of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a sectional view taken along line VIII-VIII in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The mobile terminal according to the exemplary embodiment of the present invention will now be described with reference to the accompanying drawings. While only one exemplary embodiment is shown it is understood that the present invention may be implemented in many different mobile terminals.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the mobile terminal according to the exemplary embodiment includes a first body <b>100</b>, a second body <b>200</b>, and a hinge module <b>300</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) that connects the first and second bodies <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> such that they are rotatable with respect to each other. For inputting information such as numbers or characters or a command, the first body <b>100</b> includes input devices <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> in the form of keypads, although other input devices could be used, mounted thereon. An upper surface of the first body <b>100</b> may be divided into a region which is always exposed and a region which is opened and closed according to a rotation of the second body <b>200</b>. In this exemplary embodiment, the first input device <b>110</b> may be installed on the exposed region while the second input device <b>120</b> may be installed on the region that is opened and closed by the second body <b>200</b>. The first input device <b>110</b> is accessed by the user no matter whether the second body <b>200</b> is rotated to be opened or not, and the second input device <b>120</b> is selectively accessible when the second body <b>200</b> is opened. Through a microphone <b>130</b> disposed adjacent to the input device <b>110</b>, the user's voice can be inputted during call communication with another person.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">A display unit <b>210</b> is located at a main or front surface of the second body <b>200</b> and outputs visual information. When the second body <b>200</b> is at a closed position with respect to the first body <b>100</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), the second body <b>200</b> provides a vertical screen, and when the second body <b>200</b> is rotated by about 90&#xb0; with respect to the first body <b>100</b> to be at an opened position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), the display unit <b>210</b> provides a horizontal screen. Because the screen image outputted by the display unit <b>210</b> varies according to the position of the second body <b>200</b> with respect to the first body <b>100</b>, the user can conveniently watch the screen image. A receiver or a speaker <b>220</b> that outputs a voice of another person during a call function or sound associated with an image or video displayed by the display unit may be located at the side of the display unit <b>210</b>. A camera <b>230</b> may be disposed to be adjacent to the display unit <b>210</b> to receive an image or the like of the user. In this case, the image may be stored in the mobile terminal or may be sent to the other person for a video call or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the hinge module <b>300</b> connects the second body <b>200</b> to the first body <b>100</b> such that the second body <b>200</b> is rotatable around a first axis (A) perpendicular to the first body <b>100</b>. Also, the hinge module <b>300</b> allows the second body <b>200</b> to be elevated so as to be slantingly disposed with respect to the first body when rotated from a closed state to an open state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). For example, as the second body <b>200</b> is rotated about the first axis (A) the second body is also rotatable about a second axis (B). As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the second axis (B) rotates about the first axis (A) as the second body <b>200</b> is rotated. In particular, the second body may first rotate substantially parallel to the first body <b>100</b> and then, while continuing to rotate about the first axis (A) begin to rotate about the second axis (B). In such an opened state, the second axis (B) is substantially parallel to a lengthwise direction of the second body <b>200</b> horizontally disposed on a planar surface (P) of the first body <b>100</b>. In other words, as the second body <b>200</b> is rotated, the second axis (B) is rotated together centering around the first axis (A) on the planar surface (P). During the rotation, the second axis (B) is maintained to be substantially perpendicular to the first axis (A).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Through the hinge module <b>300</b>, the second body <b>200</b> is connected to the first body <b>100</b>, and after the second body <b>200</b> is horizontally rotated at a certain angle relatively with respect to the first body <b>100</b>, it is rotated while being stood at a tilt angle. In this manner, the second body <b>200</b> is rotated by approximately 90&#xb0; with respect to the first body <b>100</b> and when it reaches the opened position, it is slantingly stood to provide a tilt angle or a viewing angle (a) suitable for the user to watch an image through the display unit <b>210</b>. Further details of the hinge module <b>300</b> will be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The hinge module <b>300</b> includes a first hinge portion <b>310</b>, a second hinge portion <b>320</b>, and a supporting portion. The first hinge portion <b>310</b> is located on the front surface of the first body <b>100</b>. The first hinge portion <b>310</b> includes slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> where the height is gradually increased as it goes from an edge portion in the direction in which the second body <b>200</b> is rotated from the closed state to the open state. Specifically, the slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> define a planar portion formed to be substantially parallel to the front surface of the first body <b>100</b> and a slope portion extending from the slide face <b>311</b> and having a certain height increased as it goes upward, respectively. The second hinge portion <b>320</b> is located on the second body <b>200</b> and is slidably moved by contacting the slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>. The supporting portion may be formed at the first and second hinge portions <b>310</b> and <b>320</b> in order to support such that the second body <b>200</b> is relatively rotated with respect to the first body <b>100</b>. While the first hinge portion <b>310</b> and the second hinge portion <b>320</b> have been described as being located on the first body <b>100</b> and the second body <b>200</b>, respectively, it is understood that the locations of the first hinge portion <b>310</b> and the second hinge portion <b>320</b> may be switched.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The first hinge portion <b>310</b> may be formed to be recessed in a fan-like shape such that the planar portion <b>311</b> may be flush with the front surface of the first body <b>100</b>. The second hinge portion <b>320</b> may be formed to be planar with the second body <b>200</b> and rotatable by contacting the slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>. The second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated substantially horizontally with respect to the first body <b>100</b> at the planar portion <b>311</b>, and rotated to be stood at the tilt angle (&#x3b1;) with respect to the first body <b>100</b> at the slope portion <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The supporting portion includes a supporting recess <b>331</b> located at one portion of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>, and a supporting projection <b>332</b> formed at one portion of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> so as to be combined in or inserted into the supporting recess <b>331</b>. As shown in the exemplary embodiment, the supporting recess <b>331</b> may have a hemispherical shape and the supporting projection <b>332</b> may have a spherical shape. Because the supporting projection <b>332</b> is inserted in the supporting recess <b>331</b>, the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotatable such that it may be inclined while being rotated with respect to the first hinge portion <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">A release preventing portion <b>340</b> may be formed between the first and second hinge portions <b>310</b> and <b>320</b> in order to prevent the first and second hinge portions <b>310</b> and <b>320</b> from being released after being combined. In particular, the release preventing portion <b>340</b> may include a release preventing rail <b>341</b> formed as a groove at one surface of the first hinge portion <b>310</b> and a connecting portion formed at one end of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> and insertable into the release preventing rail <b>341</b>. The connecting portion may include a body <b>342</b> extending from one end of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> and a protrusion <b>343</b> extending from the body <b>342</b> to be received in the release preventing rail <b>341</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The connecting portion is combined with the release preventing rail <b>341</b> so that the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is moveable in a state that a lower surface of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> contacts with the slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>. To maintain this contact, a gap between the release preventing rail <b>341</b> and the slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> of the first hinge portion <b>310</b> is uniformly maintained and is the same as a gap between the protrusion <b>343</b> and the second hinge portion <b>320</b>. Consequently, the release preventing rail has a portion that is substantially parallel to the planar portion <b>311</b> and a portion that is substantially parallel to the slope portion <b>312</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">An elastic force member may be located at the first and second hinge portions <b>310</b> and <b>320</b> in order to provide an elastic force to assist in the rotational movement of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> and fix or maintain a state after the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The elastic force member may include an elastic unit <b>350</b> located on one surface of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> and is elastically extendable in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion <b>320</b>, a transfer unit <b>360</b> connected at one end of the elastic unit <b>350</b> and is linearly moveable by being connected to the first hinge portion <b>310</b>, and a guide rail <b>370</b> recessed in the form of a groove on one surface of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>. The guide rail <b>370</b> is configured to receive the transfer unit <b>360</b> therein and to guide the transfer unit <b>360</b> therealong.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The elastic unit <b>350</b> may include a fixed member <b>351</b> extending from one surface of the second hinge portion <b>320</b>, a first shaft <b>352</b> extending from one side of the fixed member <b>351</b> in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion <b>320</b>, a first elastic member <b>353</b> located at one end of the first shaft <b>352</b> to provide an elastic force to the rotation of the second hinge portion <b>320</b>, and a first guide member <b>354</b> coveting the first elastic member <b>353</b> and configured to guide an elastic movement of the first elastic member <b>353</b>. The first shaft <b>352</b> serves as a guide when the first elastic member <b>353</b> is elastically moved and accordingly the first guide member <b>354</b> is linearly moved in a state of covering the first elastic member <b>353</b>. The first guide member <b>354</b> is linearly moved based on the first shaft <b>352</b>, and the transfer unit <b>360</b> is mounted at one end of the first guide member <b>354</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">In particular, the first elastic member <b>353</b> operates as follows. When the fixed member <b>351</b> is rotated while tracing a circular arc according to the rotation of the second hinge portion <b>320</b>, the transfer unit <b>360</b> is linearly moved. In this case, the distance between the fixed member <b>351</b> and the transfer member <b>364</b> changes, and the first elastic member <b>353</b> acts to elastically control the change in the distance. And at this time, the second body <b>200</b> is semi-automatically opened by virtue of a restoration force at a middle position of the circular arc.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The transfer unit <b>360</b> includes a second shaft <b>361</b> extending towards the first hinge portion <b>310</b>, a second guide member <b>362</b> connected at an end of the second shaft <b>361</b> distal the second hinge portion <b>320</b>, a second elastic member <b>363</b> connected between the distal end of the second shaft <b>361</b> and a transfer member <b>364</b>, the transfer member <b>364</b> being located at one end of the second guide member <b>362</b> and is at least partially received in the guide rail <b>370</b>. The guide member is displaceable along an axis defined by the second shaft <b>361</b> as the second body <b>200</b> is elevated.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The second shaft <b>361</b> is located at the first guide member <b>354</b> of the elastic unit <b>350</b>, and when the second guide member <b>362</b> is linearly moved up and down in a state of covering the second elastic member <b>363</b>, the second shaft <b>361</b> serves as a guide.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The second guide member <b>362</b> serves to connect the second shaft <b>361</b> to the transfer member <b>364</b> such that the spacing between the second hinge <b>320</b> and the transfer member <b>364</b> is adjustable as the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is slantingly rotated along the slide faces <b>311</b> and <b>312</b> of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>. In addition, the second elastic member <b>363</b> is guided by the second guide member <b>362</b> to provide a buffering force to the rotation of the second hinge portion <b>320</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As shown in the exemplary embodiment, the transfer member <b>364</b> is formed as a sphere and is partially inserted into the guide rail <b>370</b> to allow for linear movement. The guide rail <b>370</b> includes a groove linearly on one surface of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>, to which the transfer member <b>364</b> of the transfer unit <b>360</b> is combined or inserted into. When the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated, the transfer member <b>364</b> is moved along the guide rail <b>370</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The operation of the mobile terminal constructed as described above will now be described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref>. With the mobile terminal closed (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</figref>), the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is positioned in the horizontal position on the planar portion <b>311</b> and the first and second bodies <b>100</b> and <b>200</b> are positioned to face each other (i.e., to contact each other).</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">When the second body <b>200</b> is rotated with respect to the first body <b>100</b> in order to open the mobile terminal, the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated in a state of contacting first the slide face <b>311</b> and then the slide face <b>312</b> of the first hinge portion <b>310</b>. Specifically, first, while the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated on the planar portion <b>311</b>, the second body <b>200</b> is horizontally rotated relatively with respect to the first body <b>100</b>, and while the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated on the slope portion <b>312</b>, a portion of the second body <b>200</b> is elevated (lifted) while being inclined with respect to the first body <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">When the mobile terminal is completely opened (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>), the second body <b>200</b> is in a substantially 90&#xb0; rotated state with respect to the first body <b>100</b> and positioned to be inclined forwardly, providing the viewing angle (a) at which the user can conveniently watch an image.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this manner, when the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is rotated with respect to the first hinge portion <b>310</b>, the release preventing portion <b>340</b> acts such that the protrusion <b>343</b> formed at one end of the second hinge portion <b>320</b> is inserted in the release preventing rail <b>341</b> formed at one surface of the first hinge portion <b>310</b> to thus prevent the hinge module <b>300</b> from being released.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Also, the elastic unit <b>350</b> of the elastic force member, which is compressed when the transfer unit <b>360</b> is moved along the linearly formed guide rail <b>370</b>, provides the restoration force to allow the second body <b>200</b> to be semi-automatically opened.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As so far described, the mobile terminal according to the present invention has many advantages. That is, because the body with the display unit is sloped at the tilt angle, the viewing angle at which the user can conveniently watch an image can be obtained,</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In addition, because the display unit is positioned semi-automatically at the tilt angle after being rotated to provide the horizontal screen image, no cradle is required for the mobile terminal. Thus, the portability of mobile terminal can be improved and the mobile terminal can be conveniently used.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">As the present invention may be embodied in several forms without departing from the spirit or essential characteristics thereof, it should also be understood that the above-described embodiments are not limited by any of the details of the foregoing description, unless otherwise specified, but rather should be construed broadly within its spirit and scope as defined in the appended claims, and therefore all changes and modifications that fall within the metes and bounds of the claims, or equivalents of such metes and bounds are therefore intended to be embraced by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A mobile terminal comprising:
<claim-text>a first body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second body having a display unit and arranged to overlap the first body in a closed state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hinge module connecting the second body to the first body such that the second body is rotatable around a first axis generally perpendicular to the first body, the hinge module being configured to permit a portion of the second body to be elevated so as to be slantingly arranged with respect to the first body in an open state, the hinge module being configured to allow the portion of the second body to be elevated while the second body is partially rotated around the first axis, the hinge module including:
<claim-text>a first hinge portion formed on one of a front surface of the first body and a rear surface of the second body, the first hinge portion including a slide face having a height that gradually increases so as to elevate the second body as the second body is rotated around the first axis from the closed state to the open state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second hinge portion formed on the other of the front surface of the first body and the rear surface of the second body, the second hinge portion being in slidably movable contact with the slide face of the first hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporting portion connecting the first and second hinge portions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a release preventing portion that prevents the first hinge portion from being released from the second hinge portion, the release preventing portion including:
<claim-text>a release preventing rail having a groove formed at one surface of the first hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connecting portion mounted at one end of the second hinge portion, the connecting portion being received in the release preventing rail.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the slide face of the first hinge portion comprises a planar portion formed to be generally parallel to the first body, and a slope portion extending from the planar portion and having the gradually increasing height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first hinge portion is formed to have a fan-like shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the supporting portion includes:
<claim-text>a supporting recess formed at one portion of one of the first hinge portion and the second hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a supporting projection formed at the other of the first hinge portion and the second hinge portion, the supporting projection being received in the supporting recess.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the supporting recess is substantially hemispherical and the supporting projection is substantially spherical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting portion comprises:
<claim-text>a body extending from one end of the second hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a protrusion extending from the body, the protrusion being slidably inserted into the release preventing rail.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the hinge module includes an elastic force member that provides an elastic force to assist in the rotational movement of the second hinge portion from the closed state to the open state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic force member includes:
<claim-text>an elastic unit located at one surface of the second hinge portion, the elastic unit being elastically extendable in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transfer unit connected at one end of the elastic unit, the transfer unit being linearly moveable by being connected to the first hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a guide rail recessed in one surface of the first hinge portion, the guide rail receiving the transfer unit therein to guide the transfer unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic unit includes:
<claim-text>a fixed member extending from the one surface of the second hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first shaft extending from one side of the fixed member in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first elastic member located at one end of the first shaft to provide an elastic force to the rotation of the second hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide member covering the first elastic member and configured to guide an elastic movement of the first elastic member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the transfer unit includes:
<claim-text>a second shaft extending toward the first hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second guide member connected at an end of the second shaft distal to the second hinge portion, the guide member being displaceable along an axis defined by the second shaft as the second body is elevated; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transfer member located at one end of the second guide member, the transfer member being at least partially received, in the guide rail.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the transfer unit further includes a second elastic member connected between the distal end of the second shaft and the transfer member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the hinge module includes an elastic force member that provides an elastic force to assist in the rotational movement of the second hinge portion from the closed state to the open state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic force member includes:
<claim-text>an elastic unit located at one surface of the second hinge portion, the elastic unit being elastically extendable in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transfer unit connected at one end of the elastic unit, the transfer unit being linearly moveable by being connected to the first hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a guide rail recessed in one surface of the first hinge portion, the guide rail receiving the transfer unit therein to guide the transfer unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the elastic unit includes:
<claim-text>a fixed member extending from the one surface of the second hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first shaft extending from one side of the fixed member in a lengthwise direction of the second hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first elastic member located at one end of the first shaft to provide an elastic force to the rotation of the second hinge portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first guide member covering the first elastic member and configured to guide an elastic movement of the first elastic member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the transfer unit includes:
<claim-text>a second shaft extending toward the first hinge portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second guide member connected at an end of the second shaft distal to the second hinge portion, the guide member being displaceable along an axis defined by the second shaft as the second body is elevated; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transfer member located at one end of the second guide member, the transfer member being at least partially received in the guide rail.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The mobile terminal of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the transfer unit further includes a second elastic member connected between the distal end of the second shaft and the transfer member. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
