<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07665188-20100223.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20100209" date-publ="20100223">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07665188</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100223</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11705716</doc-number>
<date>20070214</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2006 006 944</doc-number>
<date>20060214</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>394</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100223</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19113</main-classification>
<further-classification> 19114</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Apparatus on a carding machine for cotton, synthetic fibres and the like, in which at least one flat bar with a flat clothing is present</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4757575</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Varga</name>
<date>19880700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6101680</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Naf et al.</name>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 19102</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6578237</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Patelli et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 19108</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6691373</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Leder</name>
<date>20040200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 19 98</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6704970</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ebenhoh et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 19114</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7020932</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Breuer et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 19104</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7073229</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Breuer et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 19102</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0157216</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Graf</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CH</country>
<doc-number>664 165</doc-number>
<kind>A5</kind>
<date>19841100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>745 707</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19440300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 866 153</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 219 735</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>1 309 229</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19730300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2 400 863</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>2 428 049</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00016">
<othercit>German Search Report dated Aug. 22, 2006, issued in 10 2006 006 944.7.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00017">
<othercit>United Kingdom Search Report, Dated Jul. 7, 2007, Issued in GB 0 702 581.0.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>20</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19102</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19104</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19113</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19114</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070186386</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070816</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Landmesser</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Erkelenz</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Venable LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kinberg</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gozzi</last-name>
<first-name>Justine A.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tr&#xfc;tzschler GmbH &#x26; Co. KG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Moenchengladbach</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hurley</last-name>
<first-name>Shaun R</first-name>
<department>3765</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In an apparatus on a carding machine for cotton, synthetic fibers and the like, in which at least one flat bar with a flat clothing is present, in which a clothing strip having a flat clothing, preferably wire hooks, arranged in a strip-form support element, is secured to a support body of the flat bar and lies opposite the clothing of a roller, e.g. the cylinder, the spacing between a surface defined by the tips of the flat clothing and the tip circle of the cylinder clothing decreases in the direction of rotation of the cylinder. In order to be able to alter and adapt the angle (offset) in a simple manner in terms of mechanical engineering, the top face, of the clothing strip and the tip surface of the flat clothing are not aligned parallel with one another.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="97.37mm" wi="153.67mm" file="US07665188-20100223-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="230.29mm" wi="162.05mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07665188-20100223-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="118.70mm" wi="145.37mm" file="US07665188-20100223-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="227.33mm" wi="155.11mm" file="US07665188-20100223-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="195.24mm" wi="145.03mm" file="US07665188-20100223-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="229.70mm" wi="133.18mm" file="US07665188-20100223-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from German Patent Application No. 10 2006 006 944.7, dated Feb. 14, 2006, the entire disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to an apparatus on a carding machine for cotton, synthetic fibres and the like, in which at least one flat bar with a flat clothing is present.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In practice, in the case of the flat system of a flat card, the flat bar is set at an angle (what is known as the taper or offset) to the tangential cylinder plane. This has inter alia the following advantages over the central arrangement:</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">the narrowest spacing of the cylinder is at a defined adjustment edge (heel) which can be emptied out well;</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The material gradually enters a tapering gap and is opened/cleaned in an improved manner.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In certain known arrangements the flat clothing, preferably wire hooks, arranged in a strip-form support element is secured to a carrier body of the flat bar, and lies opposite the clothing of a roller, e.g. the cylinder, the spacing between the tip plane of the flat clothing and the tip circle of the cylinder clothing decreases in the direction of rotation of the cylinder, and the tip plane of the flat clothing and a notional surface&#x2014;arranged parallel to the tangent to the tip circle of the cylinder clothing at the narrowest point&#x2014;are arranged at an angle &#x3b2; to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the case of one known apparatus EP 0 866 153 A, a carrier body (profiled member) having a bottom face is present, to which a flexible clothing comprising a carrier layer (base) and hooks embedded therein is secured. The base is adhesively secured to the foot part. The flat bar is guided in its working position (in the main carding zone) such that the tips of the hooks lie in a catchment plane (tip plane) which comprises a very narrow point or very narrow carding line opposite the outer surface of the cylinder. The catchment plane forms an angle &#x3b2; with a notional surface, the notional surface being arranged parallel to the tangent that intersects the outer surface at the above-mentioned narrowest point. To produce the angle &#x3b2;, the flat bar and the carrier body respectively must be designed within an inclination at a corresponding angle, and be both manufactured and mounted at an inclination, i.e. the inclination of the carrier body in relation to the tangent to the outer surface, and hence the angle &#x3b2;, is fixed for each card flat. When the carrier layer with the clothing is exchanged due to wear, the angle &#x3b2; remains the same owing to the parallel arrangement of the top and bottom faces of the carrier layer. With this apparatus, alteration of the angle &#x3b2; or adaptation to changed technical requirements is only possible through a change in the inclination of the carrier body, which is expensive in mechanical engineering terms.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is an aim of the invention to produce an apparatus of the kind described initially, which avoids or mitigates the said disadvantages and which in particular allows alteration and adaptation of the angle (offset, taper) in a simple manner in terms of construction.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The invention provides a card flat for use on a carding machine, comprising a support body and a clothing strip, the clothing strip comprising clothing arranged in a clothing carrier layer with the clothing having tips which define a tip surface, wherein the clothing strip comprises an upper surface, and said upper surface and the tip surface defined by the clothing tips are oriented in non-parallel relationship.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The notional surface defined by the clothing tips is referred to below as the &#x201c;tip surface&#x201d; and, in preferred embodiments in which the notional surface defined by the clothing tips is a substantially planar surface, as the &#x201c;tip plane&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Because the top face and the tip surface are not aligned parallel to one another, i.e. the clothing strips other than rectangular in cross-section, as the carrier layer is being exchanged it is easy to alter the angle (taper), that is, to adjust the spacing between flat clothing and cylinder clothing. Alternatively, an exchange can also be advantageous even when the clothings are not worn, if the angle is to be changed for optimum co-ordination with the fibre material to be processed and/or with an increased production capacity. Advantageously, a clothing on a revolving flat with integrated offset is produced.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In a preferred arrangement, the tip surface is substantially planar and the upper surface of the clothing strip and the tip surface of the flat clothing are arranged at an angle to one another. The carrier element of the clothing strip may be of substantially wedge-shaped construction. As well, or instead, an intermediate layer, for example, adhesive, of the clothing strip may be of substantially wedge-shaped construction. In yet a further embodiment, a top element, for example, sheet metal strip, of the clothing strip may be of substantially wedge-shaped construction. Advantageously, the clothing strip consists of at least two layers, at least one layer being of substantially wedge-shaped construction. It may be advantageous for the angle between the tip surface of the flat clothing and a notional surface running parallel to the tangent to the tip circle of the cylinder clothing to decrease in the direction of rotation of the cylinder. Advantageously, the cylinder clothing forms a heel at the smallest spacing between the tip surface of the flat clothing and the tip circle of the cylinder clothing. Advantageously, the top layer of the clothing element consists of a sheet metal strip, for example, steel band. Advantageously, the top layer and the carrier layer of the clothing strip are joined to one another, for example, by adhesion. Advantageously, the top face of the clothing strip and the bottom face of the support body are reversibly detachably joined to one another. For example, a top face of a top element of the clothing strip and the bottom face of a magnetic element may be reversibly detachably joined to one another. Preferably, in such arrangements, at least one magnetic element is associated with the bottom face of the support body. In that manner, the clothing strip can be exchangeable and/or the clothing carrier layer is exchangeable. If desired, the clothing of the flat bar may have a curved tip surface. For example, the tip surface may be concavely curved or convexly curved. In some embodiments, the non-parallel alignment may extend over only a part of the width of the clothing and the clothing strip respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">It may be desirable in some circumstances for&#x2014;viewed in the direction of rotation of the cylinder&#x2014;a constant spacing coaxial to the mid point of the cylinder to adjoin the non-parallel alignment. If desired, the flat clothing may have regions of different clothing parameters, for example wire length, wire thickness, piercing depth, pile configurations, base thickness. In that case, the tips of the flat clothing may be divided into groups, each group having tips that are used to form a fibre zone, and the groups advantageously each forming a tip surface. In one preferred embodiment, the clothing set into the carrier layer, for example, fabric or the like, consists of wires or the like, which are bent approximately in a U-shape and are inserted so that the cross-member of the U-shaped wires or the like runs on the rear side of the carrier element. The flat bar may be part of a revolving flat. The flat bar may instead be a stationary carding element. Advantageously, a flexible clothing is present, for example, comprising a carrier and clothing tips, wires, hooks or the like. Advantageously, the clothing carrier layer is strip-form. The clothing may consist of saw tooth wire strips for example, all-steel clothing. Expediently, the clothing is mounted on the flat bar in the region of the bottom face. Advantageously, a carrier element of three clothing strips (textile material) is arranged in a recess in the bottom face. The recess may be defined by at least two lateral webs or similar on the longitudinal sides of the flat foot. In one preferred embodiment, a clothing strip is received in the recess, additionally a sheet metal plate being fixed to the clothing support layer via a compensating layer of adhesive, which sheet metal plate is brought into connection with a magnet provided on the flat bar. Thus, advantageously, a sole of a magnetic material is arranged on the rear side of the flat clothing. The sole may be a steel band, sheet metal or similar. Advantageously, laterally the sole has extensions, webs or the like bent at an angle. Preferably, the magnetic component, for example, magnetic band, magnetic strip, magnetic rod or the like, extends in the longitudinal direction of the flat bar.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Advantageously, the flat body is an extruded profile of a light metal, for example, aluminium. Preferably, the extruded profile is a hollow profile. Two end head parts (flat heads) may advantageously be associated with the flat body. In certain embodiments, the flat body consists of fibre-reinforced plastics material. In that case, a magnetic element, where present, can be integrated in the fibre-reinforced plastics material. In one preferred embodiment, at least one and preferably each of the edge regions of the carrier element adjoining the longitudinal edges is set with tips.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The invention thus provides a flat system for a flat card for cotton, synthetic fibres and the like, in which at least one flat bar with a flat clothing strip is present, in which the flat clothing, preferably wire hooks, arranged in a strip-form carrier layer is secured to a support body, in which a top face of a clothing strip comprising the carrier layer and the tip surface of the flat clothing are not aligned parallel to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The invention also provides a flexible clothing for a flat bar on a carding machine for cotton, synthetic fibres and the like, having a flat clothing strip in which the flat clothing, preferably wire hooks, is arranged in a strip-form carrier layer, in which the top face of the clothing strip and the tip surface of the flat clothing are not aligned parallel to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Furthermore, the invention provides a flat card having a revolving flat assembly for cotton, synthetic fibres and the like, in which at least one flat bar with a flat clothing strip is present, in which the flat clothing, preferably wire hooks, arranged in a strip-form carrier layer is secured to a support body and lies opposite the clothing of a roller, for example, the cylinder, and the spacing between the tip surface of the flat clothing and the tip circle of the cylinder clothing decreases in the direction of rotation of the cylinder, in which the top face of the clothing strip and the tip surface of the flat clothing are not aligned parallel to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In certain embodiments, the clothing strip has a marking, which indicates the alignment of the preferred wedge shape.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The invention also provides an apparatus on a carding machine for cotton, synthetic fibres and the like, in which at least one flat bar with a flat clothing is present, in which a clothing element having a flat clothing, preferably wire hooks, arranged in a strip-form support element, is secured to a support body of the flat bar and lies opposite the clothing of a roller, e.g. the cylinder, the spacing between the tip surface of the flat clothing and the tip circle of the cylinder clothing decreases in the direction of rotation of the cylinder, and the tip surface of the flat clothing and a notional surface&#x2014;arranged parallel to the tangent to the tip circle of the cylinder clothing at the narrowest point&#x2014;are arranged at an angle to one another, wherein the top face of the clothing strip and the tip surface of the flat clothing are not aligned parallel with one another.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is schematic side view of a carding machine in which there may be used an apparatus according to the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of a portion of a revolving card flat assembly including card flats according to a first embodiment of the invention and a fragment from the first slideway of a two-sided slideway;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>a </i>shows three flat bars, the spacing between the tip plane of the flat clothings and the cylinder clothing decreasing in the direction of rotation of the cylinder;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>b </i>shows a flat bar according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>a</i>, wherein the top face of the clothing strip and the tip plane of the flat clothing are not aligned parallel to one another, with an illustration of the angle &#x3b1; between flat surface and tip plane and of the angle &#x3b2; for the offset;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows the flat bar of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 3</figref><i>a</i>, comprising flat support body and clothing strips, in an exploded view;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5</figref><i>a</i>, <b>5</b><i>b </i>show two further embodiments, in which the clothing support part is of wedge-shaped construction in cross-section; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows yet another embodiment in which the clothing support part is of wedge-shaped construction in cross-section.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a flat card, for example, a flat card known as the TC 03 (Trade Mark), made by Tr&#xfc;tzschler GmbH &#x26; Co. KG. of M&#xf6;nchengladbach, Germany, has a feed roller <b>1</b>, feed table <b>2</b>, licker-ins <b>3</b><i>a</i>, <b>3</b><i>b</i>, <b>3</b><i>c</i>, cylinder <b>4</b>, doffer <b>5</b>, stripping roller <b>6</b>, squeezing rollers <b>7</b>, <b>8</b>, web-guide element <b>9</b>, web funnel <b>10</b>, take-off rollers <b>11</b>, <b>12</b>, revolving flat <b>13</b> with flat guide rollers <b>13</b><i>a</i>, <b>13</b><i>b </i>and flat bars <b>14</b>, can <b>18</b> and can coiler <b>19</b>. The directions of rotation of the rollers are shown by respective curved arrows. The letter M denotes the midpoint (axis) of the cylinder <b>4</b>. The reference numeral <b>4</b><i>a </i>denotes the clothing and <b>4</b><i>b </i>denotes the direction of rotation of the cylinder <b>4</b>. The letter A denotes the working direction. Arrow B denotes the carding setting of the flat bars <b>14</b> and arrow C denotes the return transport direction of the flat bars <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows one embodiment according to the invention. On each side of the card, a flexible bend <b>17</b> having several adjusting screws is secured laterally by screws to the machine frame. The flexible bend <b>17</b> has a convex outer surface <b>17</b><i>a </i>and an underside <b>17</b><i>b</i>. Above the flexible bend <b>17</b>, there is a first slideway <b>20</b>, for example, of anti-friction plastics material, which has a convex outer surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>and a concave inner surface <b>20</b><i>b</i>. The second slideway (on the other side of the machine) is not shown. The concave inner surface <b>20</b><i>b </i>lies on the convex outer surface <b>17</b><i>a</i>. Each flat bar <b>14</b> has at both ends a respective card flat head, to which two steel pins <b>15</b>*, <b>15</b>** are secured axially and slide in the direction of arrow B on the convex outer surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the slideway <b>20</b>. The flat clothing strip <b>16</b> is mounted on the undersurface of the support body <b>15</b>. The reference number <b>21</b> denotes the tip circle of the narrowest point of the flat clothings <b>16</b>. On its circumference, the cylinder <b>4</b> has a cylinder clothing <b>4</b><i>a</i>, for example, saw-tooth clothing. The reference numeral <b>22</b> denotes the tip circle of the cylinder clothing <b>4</b><i>a</i>. The distance between the tip circle <b>21</b> and the tip circle <b>22</b> is denoted by the letter a, and is, for example, 0.20 mm. The distance between the convex outer surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>and the tip circle <b>22</b> is denoted by the letter b. The radius of the convex outer surface <b>20</b><i>a </i>is denoted by r<sub>1 </sub>and the radius of the tip circle <b>22</b> is denoted by r<sub>2</sub>. The radii r<sub>1 </sub>and r<sub>2 </sub>intersect at the mid-point M (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the cylinder <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>a </i>shows (drawn exaggeratedly) the decrease in the gap between the flat clothings <b>16</b><sub>1</sub>, <b>16</b><sub>2</sub>, <b>16</b><sub>3 </sub>on the one hand and the cylinder clothing <b>4</b><i>a </i>on the other hand in the direction of rotation <b>4</b><i>b </i>of the cylinder <b>4</b>. With the spacing between the free tips of the clothing tips <b>16</b><i>b</i><sub>1</sub>, <b>16</b><i>b</i><sub>2</sub>, <b>16</b><i>b</i><sub>3 </sub>of the flat clothings <b>16</b><sub>1</sub>, <b>16</b><sub>2</sub>, <b>16</b><sub>3 </sub>and the cylinder clothing <b>4</b><i>a </i>in mind, the widest spacing is marked with c<sub>1 </sub>and the narrowest spacing is marked with c<sub>2</sub>. The spacings c<sub>1 </sub>and c<sub>2 </sub>appear in a radial direction in relation to the midpoint M (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the cylinder <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>b</i>, which shows in enlargement one of the card flats of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>a</i>, the clothing element <b>16</b> in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b </i>has a top element <b>16</b><i>c</i>, the top face <b>16</b><i>c</i><sub>1 </sub>of which is in contact with lower face <b>15</b><i>c </i>of the support body <b>15</b>, a bottom element in which clothing tips <b>16</b> are provided, and intermediate layer, of wedge-shaped configuration, between the top and bottom elements. The clothing tips <b>16</b> define a tip surface which in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b </i>is a planar tip surface referred to herein as &#x201c;tip plane&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b</i>, the top face <b>16</b><i>c</i><sub>1 </sub>of the top element <b>16</b><i>c </i>of the clothing element <b>16</b> and the tip plane <b>23</b> of the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>are not aligned parallel to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">According to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>b</i>, the tip plane <b>23</b> of the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>and a notional surface <b>19</b>&#x2033;&#x2014;arranged parallel to the tangent <b>19</b>&#x2032; to the tip circle <b>22</b> of the cylinder clothing <b>4</b><i>a </i>at the narrowest point c<sub>2</sub>&#x2014;are arranged at an angle &#x3b2; to one another (shown exaggerated in the drawing). At each flat bar <b>14</b> the tip plane <b>23</b> of the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>is consequently at an angle &#x3b2; of, for example, 0&#xb0;55&#x2032; in relation to the parallel surface <b>19</b>&#x2033;. What is known as an offset, also called a taper, is consequently formed. The gap formed by the angle &#x3b2; between the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>and the cylinder clothing <b>4</b><i>a </i>closes in the direction of rotation <b>4</b><i>b </i>of the cylinder <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Furthermore, according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>b </i>the top face <b>16</b><i>c</i><sub>1 </sub>of the clothing element <b>16</b> and the tip plane <b>23</b> of the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>are arranged at an angle &#x3b1; to another (shown exaggerated in the drawing). The wedge formation created by the angle &#x3b1; opens in the direction of rotation <b>4</b><i>b </i>of the cylinder <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the flat bar <b>14</b> consists of a card flat support body <b>15</b> and a clothing element <b>16</b>. The clothing element <b>16</b> is detachably (reversibly) secured to the card flat support body <b>15</b>. The card flat support body <b>15</b> includes a profiled card flat body <b>15</b>&#x2032;, which comprises a card flat foot <b>15</b><i>a </i>and a card flat back <b>15</b><i>b</i>. At the two ends of the elongate profiled card flat body <b>15</b>&#x2032;, for example of extruded aluminium, moulded plastics or the like, there is a respective card flat head, which&#x2014;in the embodiment according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, each comprise two card flat pins <b>15</b>* and <b>15</b>**. On the side remote from the flat bars <b>15</b><i>b</i>, two webs <b>15</b><i>h</i>, <b>15</b><i>i </i>are provided on the card flat foot <b>15</b><i>a </i>in the longitudinal direction, so that in the region of the bottom face <b>15</b><i>c </i>there is a two-tier recess <b>15</b><i>d</i>, <b>15</b><i>e</i>. The card flat support body <b>15</b> furthermore includes a magnetic element <b>15</b><i>f</i>, for example, a magnetic band, magnetic strip, magnetic rod or similar, which via its top face <b>15</b><i>f</i><sub>1 </sub>is fastened, in the upper recess <b>15</b><i>d</i>, by a layer of adhesive <b>15</b><i>g </i>to the bottom face <b>15</b><i>c</i>. The length of the card flat support body is, for example, 1 m.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In the embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the clothing element <b>16</b> comprises a clothing strip <b>16</b>&#x2032;, which consists of a strip-form clothing carrier element <b>16</b><i>a</i>, for example, of textile material, and the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b</i>. The flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>consists of clothing tips <b>19</b> (wire hooks), the wire hooks being approximately U-shaped and fixed in the carrier element <b>16</b><i>a </i>by being pushed through the face <b>16</b><i>a</i><sub>1</sub>. The regions where the wire hooks change direction project beyond the face <b>16</b><i>a</i><sub>1</sub>. The ends of the wire hooks <b>19</b>, the clothing tips, are free. The wire hooks consist of steel wire. The clothing element <b>16</b> furthermore includes a top element <b>16</b><i>c</i>, for example a steel plate strip, a steel band or similar, the bottom face <b>16</b><i>c</i><sub>2 </sub>of which is fixed by way of a connecting intermediate layer <b>16</b><i>d</i>, for example, an adhesive layer, to the top face <b>16</b><i>a</i><sub>1 </sub>of the clothing carrier element <b>16</b><i>a</i>. <b>16</b><i>d</i><sub>1 </sub>denotes the top face and <b>16</b><i>d</i><sub>2 </sub>denotes the bottom face of the intermediate layer <b>16</b><i>d</i>, the top face <b>16</b><i>d</i><sub>1 </sub>and the bottom face <b>16</b><i>d</i><sub>2 </sub>being so arranged that they are not parallel to one another, so that the cross-section of the intermediate layer <b>16</b><i>d </i>is wedge-shaped. The clothing element <b>16</b> is fixed with its components clothing strip <b>16</b>&#x2032;, intermediate layer <b>16</b><i>d </i>and top element <b>16</b><i>c </i>in the recess <b>15</b><i>e</i>, so that only the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>projects beyond the bottom face of the card flat foot <b>15</b><i>a</i>. The fixing is so effected so that the top face <b>16</b><i>c</i><sub>1 </sub>of the flat element <b>16</b><i>c </i>(steel band) is in flat abutment with the bottom face <b>15</b><i>f</i><sub>2 </sub>of the magnetic element <b>15</b><i>f </i>(assembly plane). The positive-engaging connection between flat support body <b>15</b> and clothing element <b>16</b> is stable in operation. The carding forces that act on the flat clothing <b>16</b><i>b </i>are absorbed and compensated for by the webs <b>15</b><i>h</i>, <b>15</b><i>i </i>in the flat foot <b>15</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a </i>shows a further embodiment of clothing element. The clothing carrier element <b>16</b><i>a </i>has a wedge-shaped construction in cross-section, whilst the top element <b>16</b><i>c </i>and the intermediate layer <b>16</b><i>d </i>are plane-parallel. In yet another embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>b</i>, the top element <b>16</b><i>c </i>is of wedge-shaped construction in cross-section, whilst the clothing element <b>16</b><i>a </i>and the intermediate element <b>16</b> are plane-parallel.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the clothing carrier element <b>16</b><i>a </i>consists of three layers <b>16</b>*, <b>16</b>** and <b>16</b>***, that is, layers, for example, of textile material and plastics. Whereas the upper layer <b>16</b>* and the bottom layer <b>16</b>*** are of plane-parallel construction, the middle layer <b>16</b>** is wedge-shaped in cross-section. The top face <b>16</b><i>a</i><sub>1 </sub>may, for example, be adhesively secured to the bottom face <b>15</b><i>c</i>. The carrier element <b>16</b><i>a </i>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> can also be arranged in place of the carrier element <b>16</b><i>a </i>shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Although the foregoing invention has been described in detail by way of illustration and example for purposes of understanding, it will be obvious that changes and modifications may be practised within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A card flat for use on a carding machine, comprising:
<claim-text>a support body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic element; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clothing element having an upper surface, wherein the upper surface is reversibly detachably coupled to the support body by the magnetic element, the clothing element comprising:
<claim-text>clothing having tips, wherein the tips define a tip surface, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clothing carrier layer, wherein the clothing are arranged in the clothing carrier layer and the upper surface and the tip surface are oriented in a non-parallel relationship.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tip surface is substantially planar and the upper surface of the clothing element and the tip surface are arranged at an angle to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the clothing element is of substantially wedge-shaped construction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, in which the clothing element comprises at least two layers, wherein at least one of the two layers is of substantially wedge-shaped construction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the clothing element further comprises an upper layer, said upper layer including said upper surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising an intermediate layer arranged between the clothing carrier layer and the upper layer, and at least one of said upper layer, intermediate layer and clothing carrier layer is of substantially wedge-shaped construction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the support body further comprises a bottom face, wherein the upper surface of the clothing element and the bottom face are reversibly detachably joined to one another by the magnetic element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the clothing element and/or the clothing carrier layer is exchangeable.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the clothing has a curved tip surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the non-parallel alignment extends partially over the width of the clothing element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the clothing arranged in the carrier layer comprises wires, wherein the wires are approximately U-shaped and inserted so that a cross-member of the U-shaped wires runs on a rear side of the carrier layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the support body has a base with a bottom face and the clothing element is received in a recess in the bottom face of the support body, the recess being defined by at least two lateral webs on longitudinal sides of the base of the support body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A card flat for use on a carding machine, comprising:
<claim-text>a support body, wherein the support body comprises a magnet; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clothing element having an upper surface, wherein the upper surface is reversibly detachably coupled to the support body by the magnetic, the clothing element comprising:
<claim-text>clothing having tips, wherein the tips define a tip surface,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a clothing carrier layer, wherein the clothing are arranged in the clothing carrier layer and the upper surface and the tip surface are oriented in a non-parallel relationship, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sheet metal plate and a compensating layer of adhesive, the sheet metal plate positionable to connect with the magnet.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the sheet metal plate comprises a body of magnetic material arranged on a rear side of the clothing element and extending in a longitudinal direction of the flat bar.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the support body comprises an extruded, hollow profile of a light metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the support body comprises fibre-reinforced plastics material, in which the magnetic element is integrated in the fibre-reinforced plastics material for effecting magnetic connection of the clothing element to the support body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the clothing has regions with different clothing parameters, wherein each of said regions has clothing tips that are used to form a fibre zone, each zone forming a respective tip surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the card flat is adapted for use as a part of a revolving flat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A card flat according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the card flat is adapted for use as a stationary carding element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. An apparatus on a flat card for fibres, comprising:
<claim-text>a rotatable cylinder clothing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one flat bar including:
<claim-text>a support body,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a magnetic element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a strip-form clothing element reversibly detachably secured to the support body by the magnetic element, the clothing element having a flat clothing, wherein the flat clothing comprises wire hooks defining a tip surface positioned opposite the cylinder clothing, wherein a spacing between the tip surface of the flat clothing and a tip circle of the cylinder clothing decreases in a direction of rotation of the cylinder clothing and a notional surface arranged parallel to a tangent to the tip circle of the cylinder clothing is defined at a narrowest point, wherein the tip surface of the flat clothing and the notional surface are arranged at an angle to one another, and wherein a top face of the strip-form clothing element and the tip surface of the flat clothing are aligned non-parallel with one another. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
