<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07653971-20100202.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20100119" date-publ="20100202">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07653971</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100202</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11481994</doc-number>
<date>20060706</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>658</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100202</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19 66CC</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Cotton conditioning device</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4103397</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Jackson</name>
<date>19780800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4140503</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vandergriff</name>
<date>19790200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4999881</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vandergriff et al.</name>
<date>19910300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5155886</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Schrader et al.</name>
<date>19921000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5199133</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Burton</name>
<date>19930400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5381587</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vandergriff</name>
<date>19950100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6314618</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Mehner et al.</name>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6698066</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Latham</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>36</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19 66 CC</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19 48 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19 39</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19 66 R</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19200</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 19308</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080005869</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080110</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cory</last-name>
<first-name>Mark D.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fortson</city>
<state>GA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Miller &#x26; Martin PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cherokee Fabrication Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Salem</city>
<state>AL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Patel</last-name>
<first-name>Tejash</first-name>
<department>3765</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention related generally to a device for adding moisture to fibrous material such as cotton. The conditioning device receives a continuous cotton batt from a battery condenser. The continuous cotton batt is fed between two opposing drums. Hot moist air is fed into one drum and drawn out of the perforated surface of the drum, through the batt as it is being compressed between the two drums, and into the other drum. The opposing drums are internally compartmented by a plurality of longitudinal staves, each compartment being covered by a corresponding segment of the perforated surface. Hot dry air is fed into the compartments of the drums when the corresponding segment of the surface is not carrying the cotton batt in order to dry the surface of the drum and clear the perforations of any lint that might have been retained on the surface.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="219.46mm" wi="174.07mm" file="US07653971-20100202-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="223.94mm" wi="181.78mm" file="US07653971-20100202-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="221.06mm" wi="191.09mm" file="US07653971-20100202-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="198.71mm" wi="185.67mm" file="US07653971-20100202-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="202.01mm" wi="177.63mm" file="US07653971-20100202-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates in general to processing fibrous materials, and in particular to a device for humidifying lint cotton and other fibrous materials and compressing the material to increase its density.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to a cotton conditioning device for adding moisture to lint cotton prior to the baling process. The device can be used with any existing cotton gin battery condenser. The device can be used as an attachment to receive a cotton batt from any existing battery condenser by attaching it intermediate the battery condenser and a slide configured to receive the humidified and compressed batt from the conditioning device. The device humidifies lint cotton by receiving a batt of lint cotton and compressing it at a nip point between two opposing, counter-rotating drums housed side-by-side with one drum being slightly elevated relative to the other. As the cotton lint is compressed between the two opposing drums, moist hot air is injected into one drum, through the perforated surface of the drum, through the batt being compressed and is drawn into the second drum.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Hot dry air is fed into the compartments of the drums when the corresponding segment of the surface is not carrying the cotton batt in order to keep dry the surface of the drums and clear the perforations of any lint that might have been retained on the surface.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">It is well recognized that humidifying cotton lint prior to baling aids with the baling process by reducing the forces required to compress the bale. Also, there are multiple reasons that correct moisture levels are desirable for the spinning mills that use these bales. For example, cotton fibers with too low of a moisture content become brittle and are prone to breakage. There are currently four widely-used methods to add moisture to a cotton batt prior to baling. One common method, falling out of favor for its poor results, is simply to set up an atomized mister above the slide that moves the cotton batt to the baler, spraying water directly onto the surface of the cotton. The thicker the batt, the less desirable this method becomes. The moisture does not tend to migrate through the batt evenly, resulting in alternating layers of wet and dry cotton in the finished bales. When moisture is added in this way, it is very easy to add too much water to a bale, thus making it prone to damage from rotting. This method can also be deceitful since excess water weight can easily be added to a bale (cotton being sold by weight). Even if the right amount of moisture is added per unit volume of cotton, it is only useful if it is fairly evenly distributed throughout the bale. When a spray system is used on a thick batt, the layering effect described above can potentially create micro layers of moisture-damaged cotton and good cotton throughout a bale, thus rendering the entire bale useless.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A second method is described in U.S. Pat. No. 4,103,397, entitled &#x201c;Lint Slide Grid Humidifier.&#x201d; The device of this patent registration consists of a perforated lint slide which receives a batt of cotton from a battery condenser. As the batt is moved along the slide, hot moist air is allowed to slowly rise up through the bat along most of the length of the lint slide. Although this system is effective, it is inefficient because the rate of moisturization of the device cannot keep up with current capacity requirements. The capacity of a slide grid humidifier can be increased by adding length to the slide, but it is impractical to elongate slides further due to factory building height limitations. Furthermore, current batts are thicker than batts produced in the past and it is difficult to pass humid air through them uniformly by applying only a positive pressure on one side, resulting in an uneven distribution of moisture throughout the batt.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Another common method of humidifying lint cotton is shown in a variety of patents by A. L. Vandergriff. U.S. Pat. No.(s) 4,140,503, 4,999,881 and 5,381,587 are different versions of a cotton lint humidifying device having a drum with separated segments. U.S. Pat. No. 4,140,503 teaches a device which raises the moisture level of the cotton lint by passing it between sealing rollers. Moist or humid air is then supplied to the condenser chambers, raising the cotton lint to the desired moisture level.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Similarly, U.S. Pat. No. 4,999,881 uses a system of air chambers and conduits which transport dry heated air to certain metal surfaces within the condenser unit, increasing the temperature of surfaces and avoiding moisture build up as a means of condensate control.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">U.S. Pat. No. 5,381,587 teaches a cotton gin lint condenser which rotates the batt through different segments of the housing. The housing has a lint inlet segment, a segment for adding moisture to the batt by passing it through warm humid air, a segment for doffing the batt from the drum, and a segment for removing moisture from the drum by rotating it through dry air. The warm dry air also warms the lint slide surface.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Another way to add moisture to cotton lint is taught in U.S. Pat. No. 6,314,618 entitled &#x201c;Moisture Conditioner for Lint Cotton.&#x201d; This device is different from prior devices because the steam roller is not a part of the cotton gin battery condenser but rather an add-on the device. The steam roller device may be incorporated at the top of the slide after the battery condenser. A continuous batt of cotton is passed between a stationary screen and a rotatable cylinder having a perforated surface. Hot humidified air is passed through the screen and batt, and is drawn into the cylinder.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It is an object of the present invention to provide a cotton conditioning device for adding moisture to lint cotton during the baling process.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another object of the present invention is to provide a cotton conditioning device that further compresses the continuous cotton batt received from a battery condenser.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A further object of the present invention is to provide a cotton conditioning device which can be used with any existing cotton gin battery condenser.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Another object of the present invention is to provide a device which effectively and efficiently adds moisture to lint cotton during the baling process.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Another object of the present invention is to provide a cotton conditioning device which can be manufactured and sold at a reasonable price and added to existing cotton processing lines.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Accordingly, a presently preferred embodiment of the present invention provides a cotton gin conditioning device for adding moisture to lint cotton prior to the baling process. The conditioning device receives a continuous cotton batt from a cotton gin battery condenser that is fed between two opposing, counter-rotating drums. Hot moist air is drawn from a source into one drum and forced or drawn out of the perforated surface of the drum, through the batt as it is being compressed between the two drums, and into the other drum. The opposing drums are internally compartmented by a plurality of longitudinal staves, each compartment being covered by a corresponding segment of the perforated surface. Hot dry air is fed or drawn into the compartments of the drums when the corresponding segment of the surface is not carrying the cotton batt in order to dry the surface of the drum and clear the perforations of any lint that might have been retained on the surface.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The particular features and advantages of the invention as well as other objects will become apparent from the following description taken in connection with the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side schematic view of the cotton conditioning device of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side schematic view of the cotton conditioning device of the present invention showing the airflow routes.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top longitudinal cross section view of a stationary unit of the present invention wherein the cross section is shown through the center plane of the rotatable lower drum.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial side exterior view of a side of the housing of the suspended unit of the present invention without any ducting attached to the anterior passage or posterior passage.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As illustrated in a schematic side view in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, this invention teaches a cotton conditioning device <b>10</b> for adding moisture to cotton lint prior to the baling process. The cotton conditioning device <b>10</b> of the present invention consists of a stationary unit <b>30</b> and a suspended unit <b>60</b> positioned in mating contact with the stationary unit <b>30</b> along mating surfaces <b>28</b> and <b>29</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the stationary unit <b>30</b> comprises a housing <b>22</b> containing a cylindrical, rotatable lower drum <b>31</b> on an axial shaft <b>44</b> running through a first side <b>24</b> of the housing <b>22</b> and a first opposing end of the drum <b>31</b>, to a second opposing end of the drum <b>31</b> and an opposing second side <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b>. The opposing ends of the drum <b>31</b> are substantially covered or capped by the solid, non-permeable first and second sides <b>24</b>, <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b> which remain stationary as the drum <b>31</b> rotates. Each first and second side <b>24</b>, <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b> further comprise a mating surface <b>28</b> shaped to correspond to the mating surfaces <b>29</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Returning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the housing <b>22</b> generally defines an enclosure for the lower drum <b>31</b> that is substantially open between the mating surfaces <b>28</b> and further defines an opening <b>13</b> for receiving a continuous batt <b>11</b>. The opening in the housing <b>22</b> between the mating surfaces <b>28</b> and the opening for receiving a continuous batt <b>11</b> may be the same or separate openings.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Preferably, the stationary unit <b>30</b> is attached adjacent to the batt output opening <b>13</b> of a battery condenser <b>17</b> such that the continuous batt <b>11</b> is fed from the battery condenser <b>17</b> onto the lower drum <b>31</b> or the upper drum <b>61</b> proximate to the nip point or gap <b>14</b> between the lower drum <b>31</b> and the adjacent upper drum <b>61</b>. Again, as best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the stationary unit <b>30</b> further comprises an output opening <b>75</b> between the first and second sides <b>24</b>, <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b> through which the compressed and humidified batt <b>11</b> advances after conditioning. Preferably, the output opening <b>75</b> is directly connected to the top of the lint slide <b>76</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) over which it will travel to the baler.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the suspended unit <b>60</b> comprises a housing <b>23</b> containing a cylindrical, rotatable upper drum <b>61</b> on an axial shaft <b>45</b> running through a first side <b>26</b> of the housing <b>23</b> and a first opposing end of the drum <b>61</b>, to a second opposing end of the drum <b>61</b> and an opposing second side <b>27</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the housing <b>23</b>. The opposing ends of the drum <b>61</b> are substantially covered or capped by the solid, non-permeable first and second sides <b>26</b>, <b>27</b> of the housing <b>23</b> which remain stationary as the drum <b>31</b> rotates. Each first <b>26</b> and second side <b>27</b> of the housing <b>23</b> also have a mating surface <b>29</b> shaped to correspond to the mating surfaces <b>28</b> of the stationary unit <b>30</b>. The housing <b>23</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> is generally shaped like a boot, with a rounded heel portion <b>81</b>, a toe portion <b>82</b> and a leg portion <b>80</b>, but is open between the mating surfaces <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The upper drum <b>61</b> is located within the heel portion <b>81</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> and, as shown, the curvature of mating surfaces <b>29</b> substantially follows the curvature of the exterior surface <b>63</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The toe portion <b>82</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> houses a powered, rotatable doffing roller <b>83</b> on a shaft <b>78</b> running from the first and second sides <b>26</b>, <b>27</b> of housing <b>23</b> that is substantially parallel to shaft <b>45</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>. Shaft <b>78</b> is adjustibly positionable on the first and second sides <b>26</b>, <b>27</b> of the housing <b>23</b> such that the distance between the doffing roller <b>83</b> and the upper drum <b>61</b> may be varied by the user. The doffing roller <b>83</b> functions to remove any lint that accumulates on the perforated stainless steel exterior surface <b>63</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>. A plurality of replaceable flashings <b>85</b> extend from the exterior <b>84</b> of the doffing roller <b>83</b> along its longitudinal axis. The doffing roller <b>83</b> is rotated in the same direction as the upper drum <b>61</b> so that the flashings <b>85</b> of the doffing roller <b>83</b> sweep against the exterior surface <b>63</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>, thereby removing any lint that may have accumulated on the upper drum <b>61</b>. As the flashings <b>85</b> are worn away from friction with the perforated surface <b>63</b> of the drum <b>61</b>, the doffing roller <b>83</b> can be positioned nearer to the upper drum <b>61</b> so as to remain effective until the flashings <b>85</b> must be replaced. Preferably, the doffing roller <b>83</b> runs at a perimeter speed (or surface speed) slightly faster than the upper drum <b>61</b> such that in the event any excess lint is carried around on the surface <b>63</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b> after the batt would normally have been expected to have separated from the drum <b>61</b>, the excess lint would be brushed off and thrown down to the lint slide <b>76</b> by the doffing roller <b>83</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The suspended unit <b>60</b> is suspended from a laterally transverse shaft <b>79</b> located toward the top of leg portion <b>80</b> of the housing <b>23</b>. The shaft <b>79</b> is axially aligned with the upper drum <b>61</b>. When suspended from shaft <b>79</b>, the mating surfaces <b>29</b> of the suspended unit <b>61</b> contact or rest upon the mating surfaces <b>28</b> of the stationary unit <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The lower drum <b>31</b> and the upper drum <b>61</b> are positioned within their respective housings <b>22</b>, <b>23</b> to form a nip point <b>14</b> between the exterior surface <b>33</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> and the exterior surface <b>63</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>. At the nip point <b>14</b>, when the mating surfaces <b>28</b>, <b>29</b> of the housings <b>22</b>, <b>23</b> are in mated position, the surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b> of the upper and lower drums <b>61</b>, <b>31</b> face each other across a gap that is preferably about one quarter inch (0.63 cm) apart, but not more than about one inch (2.54 cm) apart, to facilitate the intake of the batt <b>11</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the upper drum <b>61</b> is positioned slightly above the lower drum <b>31</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in order to maintain the directional path of the batt <b>11</b> that existed prior to its introduction into the conditioning device <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">As a continuous batt <b>11</b> is fed into the nip point <b>14</b>, the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> rotate in opposite directions away from the battery condenser <b>17</b>. Friction of the batt <b>11</b> with the texturized, perforated exterior surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b> of the rotating drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> at and about the nip point <b>14</b> serves to continually advance the batt <b>11</b> through the conditioning device <b>10</b>. A continuous batt <b>11</b> exiting a battery condenser <b>17</b> is typically four to fifteen inches thick and is compressed as it traverses the nip point <b>14</b>. The perimeter speed (or surface speed) of drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> are set at approximately the same perimeter speed of the battery condenser drum (not shown) to prevent breakage of the batt.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The shaft <b>79</b> acts as a pivot point for the suspended unit <b>60</b> and upper drum <b>61</b>, allowing the suspended unit <b>60</b> and upper drum <b>61</b> to be pushed away from the stationary unit <b>30</b> and lower drum <b>31</b> as a batt <b>11</b> passes between the lower drum <b>31</b> and the upper drum <b>61</b>. Even though it is pivotedly engaged against the stationary unit <b>30</b>, the weight of the suspended unit <b>60</b> will generally provide sufficient compressive force to the batt <b>11</b> at the nip point <b>14</b> so that the suspended unit <b>60</b> does not pivot, or pivots only nominally (generally less than 6 to 8 inches) during the ordinary course of operation. In order to ensure that the proper amount of compression is achieved, one or more pneumatic pistons (not shown) may be attached to the toe portion of the housing <b>23</b>, thereby providing a means for controlling movement of the suspended unit <b>60</b> and its drum <b>61</b> relative to the stationary unit <b>30</b> and its drum <b>31</b>. In order to facilitate cleaning of the conditioning device <b>10</b>, it has been found that it is preferable to provide a leverage point above the suspended unit <b>60</b>, such as arm <b>19</b> and eyelet <b>20</b>. Using the leverage point and a hook or loop <b>21</b> on the toe portion of the housing <b>23</b>, a cable or chain (not shown) can be connected to winch the suspended unit <b>60</b> away from the stationary unit <b>30</b> for easy access, such as for cleaning.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the internal configuration, placement and connection of the lower drum <b>31</b> within the housing <b>22</b> of the stationary unit <b>30</b>. However, except for differences in the shape of the housing <b>23</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b>, the internal configuration and attachment of the upper drum <b>61</b> within the housing <b>23</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> substantially mirror that of the lower drum <b>61</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The lower drum <b>31</b> comprises an axial central core <b>32</b> through which the drum shaft <b>44</b> runs. The core <b>32</b> is connected to the shaft <b>44</b> by collars <b>93</b>, <b>94</b> towards either opposing end <b>91</b>, <b>92</b> of the drum <b>31</b> The shaft <b>44</b> extends through the first side <b>24</b> and second side <b>25</b> of the housing. The shaft <b>44</b> is operationally connected, such as through a gear box (not shown) to a motor means (shown schematically as <b>97</b>) for powering and controlling the rotational speed of the drum <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The exterior surface <b>33</b> of drum <b>31</b> comprises a perforated surface having a multiplicity of perforations, preferably distributed uniformly about the entire surface <b>33</b>, which is preferably stainless steel. The exterior surface <b>63</b> of upper drum <b>61</b> is similarly perforated. Preferably the exterior surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b> are not smooth, but rather has a slight texture to assist in carrying the cotton lint batt <b>11</b> along with the rotation of the drum <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>. Finally, in one embodiment, the exterior perforated surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b> of the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> comprise a removable perforated stainless steel sheath attached to the staves <b>36</b>, <b>66</b> so that it can be removed for cleaning or replacement.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the exterior surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b> of both drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> are separated from their respective cores <b>32</b>, <b>62</b> by a plurality of radial staves <b>36</b>, <b>66</b>, preferably twelve staves, extending from the cores <b>32</b>, <b>62</b> to the exterior surface <b>33</b>, <b>63</b>. Staves <b>36</b>, <b>66</b> are substantially the same length as the cores <b>32</b>, <b>62</b> and divide the interior of the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> into a plurality of open-ended radial compartments <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> running along the longitudinal axis of the drum <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>. Compartments <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> are bounded interiorly by a segment of the core <b>32</b>, <b>62</b>, on either side by staves <b>36</b>, <b>66</b> and exteriorly by a segment of the perforated surface <b>33</b>, <b>63</b>. As explained in more detail below, the compartments <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> function in separating air flow inside the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the opposing ends <b>91</b>, <b>92</b> of drum <b>31</b> have a plurality of replaceable gaskets <b>98</b>, <b>99</b> to provide a seal against the inner faces <b>101</b>, <b>102</b> of the first and second sides <b>24</b>, <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b>. Specifically, replaceable gaskets <b>98</b> or <b>99</b> are attached to the opposing ends of the core <b>32</b>, the opposing ends of the external surface <b>33</b> and each of the plurality of staves <b>36</b>. Upper drum <b>61</b> is gasketed in an identical manner.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">At least one of, but preferably both the first and second sides <b>24</b>, <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b> are pierced by an anterior passage <b>37</b> and a posterior passage <b>41</b>. The anterior passage <b>37</b> is shaped to open into the lower drum <b>31</b> between the core <b>32</b> and the exterior surface <b>33</b> about and before the nip point <b>14</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), i.e., on the anterior side of the drum <b>31</b>. In other words, the anterior passage <b>37</b> is positioned to open into compartments <b>35</b> of the drum that are in close proximity to the nip point <b>14</b>, preferably with more of the anterior passage <b>37</b> located proximate to the nip point <b>14</b> on the leading side of the nip point <b>14</b>, i.e., the side where the batt <b>11</b> will traverse prior to being compressed by the nip point <b>14</b>. The posterior passage <b>41</b> is shaped to open into the drum <b>31</b> between the core <b>32</b> and the exterior surface <b>33</b> on the opposite side of the drum <b>31</b> from the nip point <b>14</b>, i.e., the posterior side of the drum <b>31</b>. An anterior duct <b>42</b> connects to the anterior passage <b>37</b>, and a posterior duct <b>43</b> connects to the posterior passage <b>41</b>. Though not illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, and illustrated only schematically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, portions of the ducts <b>42</b> and <b>43</b> are preferably incorporated into the housing <b>22</b>, but this is not necessary to the proper functioning of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Similarly, but illustrated only schematically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, at least one of, but preferably both the first side <b>26</b> and the second side <b>27</b> (not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the housing <b>23</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> are pierced by an anterior passage <b>67</b> and a posterior passage <b>69</b>. The anterior passage <b>67</b> is shaped to open into the upper drum <b>61</b> between the core <b>62</b> and the exterior surface <b>63</b> about and before the nip point <b>14</b>, i.e., the anterior side of drum <b>61</b>. The posterior passage <b>69</b> is shaped to open into the drum <b>61</b> between the core <b>62</b> and the exterior surface <b>63</b> on the opposite side of the drum <b>61</b> from the nip point <b>14</b>, i.e., the posterior side of drum <b>61</b>. An anterior duct <b>72</b> connects to the anterior passage <b>67</b>, and a posterior duct <b>70</b> connects to the posterior passage <b>69</b>. As illustrated, in a preferred embodiment portions of the ducts <b>72</b> and <b>70</b> are incorporated into the housing <b>23</b>, such as by ducting <b>73</b> and <b>71</b> which lead from ducts <b>72</b> and <b>70</b>, respectively, to passages <b>67</b> and <b>69</b>. Alternate configurations of ducting are within the contemplation of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In a preferred embodiment of the present invention, it has been found advantageous to provide a means for varying the size of the anterior and posterior passages <b>37</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>69</b> of both the lower and upper drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>. Varying the size of the passages <b>37</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>69</b> allows for the airflow to be more precisely directed into the compartments <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> of the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> as well as increasing and decreasing the rate of the airflow. For example, by directing the flow of air primarily into the compartments <b>35</b>, <b>36</b> as they rotate towards the nip point <b>14</b>, the flow of hot moist air can be directed primarily through the batt <b>11</b> before it is compressed by the nip point <b>11</b>, thereby increasing the efficiency of the dispersion of moisture throughout the width of the batt <b>11</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a partial side exterior view of a first side <b>26</b> of the housing <b>23</b> of the suspended unit <b>60</b> without any ducting (not shown) attached to the anterior passage <b>67</b> or posterior passage <b>69</b>. The exterior surface <b>63</b>, core <b>62</b> and staves <b>66</b> of drum <b>61</b> are illustrated by dashed lines indicating they are behind the side <b>26</b> of the housing <b>23</b>, except for a visible portion <b>112</b> of several of the staves <b>66</b> that are passing the anterior and posterior passages <b>67</b>, <b>69</b>. One means for varying the size of the anterior and posterior passages <b>37</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>69</b> is to associate one or more slidable baffles <b>114</b> with each passage <b>37</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>69</b> that may be positioned over all or a portion of the associated passage <b>37</b>, <b>41</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>69</b>. Baffles <b>114</b> may be attached on the inside or outside of the housing <b>23</b>, or, in one preferred embodiment, may be incorporated internally within a cavity (not shown) inside the side <b>26</b> of the housing <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Returning, then, to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the stationary unit <b>30</b> further comprises opposing upper and lower sets of a plurality of rows of replaceable flashing <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> extending from the housing <b>22</b> to engage and form a seal with the exterior surface <b>33</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b>. Flashing <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> runs from the first side <b>24</b> to the second side <b>25</b> of the housing <b>22</b>, engaging the exterior surface <b>33</b> of the drum <b>31</b> substantially along its entire length. The upper set of flashing <b>38</b> engages the exterior surface <b>33</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> as the surface <b>33</b> rotates from the posterior passage <b>41</b> towards the anterior passage <b>37</b>. The lower set of flashing <b>39</b> engages the exterior surface <b>33</b> of drum <b>31</b> as the surface <b>33</b> rotates from the anterior passage <b>37</b> towards the posterior passage <b>41</b>. Thus it can be seen that the opposing sets of flashing <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> serve to create and separate an anterior air chamber <b>107</b> and a posterior air chamber <b>108</b> on the anterior and posterior sides of the drum <b>31</b>. The opposing sets of flashing <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> function as a means to substantially prevent air from migrating from the anterior air chamber <b>107</b> to the posterior air chamber <b>108</b> or vice versa. Because the drum <b>31</b> is rotating when in operation, a certain amount of air contained within the compartments <b>35</b> of the drum <b>31</b> may be carried from the anterior air chamber <b>107</b> to the posterior air chamber <b>108</b> and vice versa, but this nominal migration of air is not sufficient to interrupt the directions of the airflows in each chamber <b>107</b>, <b>108</b> that are created as described below in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The preferred number of flashings <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> used in each set and their positioning relative to each other depend upon several variables such as the radius of the drum <b>31</b>, the number of staves <b>36</b>, length of flashings <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> and the anticipated rotational velocity of the drum <b>31</b>. The number and positioning of rows of flashings <b>38</b>, <b>39</b> within each set should be varied as necessary in order to minimize or prevent altogether the instances where a continuous channel from one air chamber <b>107</b> to the other <b>108</b> is created as the drum <b>31</b> rotates.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The housing <b>22</b> further comprises an exit passage <b>56</b> through the housing <b>22</b> into the posterior air chamber <b>108</b>. Ducting <b>54</b> may be connected to the exit passage <b>56</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a side schematic view of the drum rotation and airflow routes through the cotton conditioning device <b>10</b> is shown. When the suspended unit <b>60</b> is put into position, its mating surface <b>29</b> substantially mates with the mating surface <b>28</b> of the stationary unit, thus forming the complete conditioning device <b>10</b>. One or more motors (not shown) rotate the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> and the doffing roller <b>83</b> at the desired speeds. The lower drum <b>31</b> rotates in the direction indicated by arrow A, opposite the rotation of the upper drum <b>63</b>, the direction of which is indicated by arrow B. Doffing roller <b>83</b> also rotates in the same direction as the upper drum <b>62</b> as indicated by arrow C.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">When the complete conditioning device <b>10</b> is formed, the three airflow channels illustrated schematically by arrows X, Y and Z in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> are formed. Any manner and configuration of ducting and fans may be utilized to create an air pressure gradient through each of the channels that will cause properly conditioned air to flow in the desired direction through the three airflow channels of the conditioning device <b>10</b>. Similarly, any of the known methods of conditioning the air (i.e., heating, adding moisture, etc.) that will travel through the three airflow channels of the conditioning device <b>10</b> may be utilized in connection with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A primary conditioning channel (illustrated by arrows X<b>1</b>-X<b>6</b>) is formed to direct hot, moist air through the batt <b>11</b> as it passes about the nip point <b>14</b> between the counter-rotating lower drum <b>31</b> and upper drum <b>61</b>. Specifically, air flowing through the primary conditioning channel is blown or drawn, or both, but preferably at least drawn, from a hot, moist air source (not shown) through ducting <b>50</b>, <b>51</b>, <b>42</b> (arrows X<b>1</b> and X<b>2</b>), through anterior passage <b>37</b> (arrows X<b>3</b>) into one or more of compartments <b>35</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> as said compartments rotate past anterior passage <b>37</b>, through the perforated surface <b>33</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> (arrows X<b>4</b>) through the perforated surface <b>63</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>, into one or more of compartments <b>65</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b> as said compartments rotate past anterior passage <b>67</b>, through anterior passage <b>67</b> (arrow X<b>5</b>) and on through ducting <b>73</b>, <b>72</b> (arrow X<b>6</b>), eventually to a bank of cyclones (not shown) to remove particulate matter from the air, and eventually to an exhaust (not shown). Preferably, the negative air pressure generated by one or more pull fans at the exhaust end of the primary conditioning channel is greater than the positive air pressure generated by any pushing fans that push or inject air into the primary conditioning channel to ensure the proper draw or pressure gradient of hot, moist air across the batt <b>11</b> through the primary conditioning channel.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Due to the rotation of the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>, each open-ended compartment <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> only periodically comprises a portion of the primary conditioning channel as it rotates past (or adjacent to) the anterior passage <b>37</b>, <b>67</b>. When a portion of an compartment <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> is beside an anterior passage <b>37</b>, <b>67</b>, a continuous channel is opened allowing the flow of air described above. When a portion of a compartment <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> is not beside an anterior passage <b>37</b>, <b>67</b>, there is no draw of air through the compartment <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> unless the compartment <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> is beside the posterior passage <b>41</b>, <b>69</b> of that respective drum <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>, at which point the compartment <b>35</b>, <b>65</b> forms a portion of one of the other two airflow channels of the conditioning device <b>10</b> as described below.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Thus it can be seen that due to the positioning of the anterior passages <b>37</b>, <b>67</b> about, and preferably tending towards the side of the nip point <b>14</b> where the batt <b>11</b> is approaching the nip point <b>14</b> before being compressed, when a batt <b>11</b> is moving towards and through the nip point <b>14</b> between counter-rotating drums <b>31</b> and <b>61</b>, the hot, moist air is drawn through the batt <b>11</b> from the compartments <b>35</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> and into the compartments <b>65</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>, thereby adding moisture in a substantially uniform manner to the entire width and breadth of the batt <b>11</b>. The draw of air through the anterior passage <b>67</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b> must be of sufficient strength to create a draw through the anterior passage <b>37</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> despite the potential leakage of some air into the anterior air chamber <b>107</b>. To the extent that hot, moist air might flow into the anterior air chamber <b>107</b> from the compartments <b>35</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> prior to being drawn through the batt <b>11</b> and into the compartments <b>65</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b>, the anterior air chamber <b>107</b> may be considered a portion of the primary conditioning channel.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Using the cotton conditioning device <b>10</b> of the present invention, one is able to control the moisture content of the batt <b>11</b> by adjusting the amount of moisture in the flow of hot, moist air at its source, or by adjusting the speed at which the batt <b>11</b> transverses the conditioning device <b>10</b>, or by adjusting the pressure gradient or speed at which the hot moist air moves through the primary conditioning channel. For example, the moisture content of the hot moist air may need to be adjusted to account for the amount of moisture already existing in the air of that particular locality and/or the amount of moisture desired in the batt <b>11</b>. One or more conventional sensing devices can be added to detect the moisture content of the lint cotton either before or after passing through the conditioning device <b>10</b> and alert the user to make necessary adjustments. This adjustment could also be made automatically with electronic controls connected to the sensing devices.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In a preferred embodiment, it has been found useful to utilize the hot, moist air traveling to the anterior passage <b>37</b> to heat the underside of slide <b>76</b> before drawing it through ducting <b>50</b>, <b>51</b> and <b>42</b> to anterior passage <b>37</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Because of the moisture being pulled through the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b> as part of the primary conditioning channel, in order to avoid the accumulation of condensation and lint on the exterior perforated surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b>, cores <b>32</b>, <b>62</b> and staves <b>36</b>, <b>66</b> of the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>, it is desirable to dry these surfaces during operation. The other two airflow channels (illustrated by arrows Y and Z) carry hot, dry air through the conditioning device <b>10</b> to dry the exterior perforated surfaces <b>33</b>, <b>63</b>, cores <b>32</b>, <b>62</b> and staves <b>36</b>, <b>66</b> of the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">A first drying channel (illustrated by arrows Y<b>1</b>-Y<b>4</b>) is formed to direct hot, dry air along a pressure gradient through the posterior side of drum <b>31</b>. Specifically, air flowing through the first drying channel is blown or drawn, or both, but preferably at least drawn, from a hot, dry air source (not shown) through posterior duct <b>43</b> (arrow Y<b>1</b>), through posterior passage <b>41</b> (arrows Y<b>2</b>) into one or more of compartments <b>35</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> as said compartments rotate past posterior passage <b>41</b>, through the perforated surface <b>33</b> of the lower drum <b>31</b> into posterior air chamber <b>108</b> (arrows Y<b>3</b>) and on through exit duct <b>56</b> (arrow Y<b>4</b>) and any associated ducting <b>54</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Due to the rotation of the drum <b>31</b>, each compartment <b>35</b> only periodically comprises a portion of the first drying channel as it rotates past the posterior passage <b>41</b>. When a portion of a compartment <b>35</b> is beside the posterior passage <b>41</b>, a continuous channel is opened allowing the flow of air described above.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Though it is possible that the direction of the air flow through the first drying channel might be reversed from the flow just described, this is less preferable because the action of air blowing in through the perforated surface <b>33</b> would tend to carry lent into the compartments <b>35</b> of the drum <b>31</b> where it might accumulate, resulting in an accelerated need to clean the conditioning device <b>10</b>. Conversely, by using the preferred airflow through the first drying channel, air blowing from inside the compartments <b>35</b> out through the perforated surface <b>33</b> assists in keeping the perforations from becoming clogged with lint.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">A second drying channel (illustrated by arrows Z<b>1</b>-Z<b>4</b>) is formed to direct hot, dry through the posterior side of drum <b>61</b> in order to dry the exterior perforated surface <b>63</b>, core <b>62</b>, and staves <b>66</b> of drum <b>61</b>. Specifically, air flowing through the second drying channel is blown or drawn, or both, but preferably at least blown, from a hot, dry air source (not shown) through posterior duct <b>70</b> (arrow Z<b>1</b>), through ducting <b>71</b> (arrow Z<b>2</b>), then through posterior passage <b>69</b> (arrow Z<b>3</b>) of upper drum <b>61</b> into one or more of compartments <b>65</b> of the upper drum <b>61</b> as said compartments <b>65</b> rotate past posterior passage <b>69</b>, through and away from the perforated surface <b>63</b> of drum <b>61</b>. In the illustrated preferred embodiment, the posterior side of upper drum <b>61</b> comprises an unsealed compartment that is open to the atmosphere, allowing the hot, dry air to be pushed away out of any available opening, such as along the lines illustrated as arrows Z<b>4</b>. If desired, additional exhaust ducting or hooding (not shown) could be added to carry the air away from the second drying channel after it exits the perforated surface <b>63</b> of drum <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Due to the rotation of the drum <b>61</b>, each open-ended compartment <b>65</b> only periodically comprises a portion of the second drying channel as it rotates past the posterior passage <b>69</b>. When a portion of a compartment <b>65</b> is beside the posterior passage <b>69</b>, a continuous channel is opened, allowing the flow of air described above.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Where each of the first drying channel and second drying channel ultimately exits or is vented to the atmosphere, it may also be desirable to employ any of the known means to control condensation that may form on surfaces as the hot, dry air carries moisture away from the drums <b>31</b>, <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">Numerous alterations of the structure herein disclosed will suggest themselves to those skilled in the art. However, it is to be understood that the present disclosure relates to the preferred embodiment of the invention which is for purposes of illustration only and not to be construed as a limitation of the invention. All such modifications which do not depart from the spirit of the invention are intended to be included within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>Having thus set forth the nature of the invention, I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A device for humidifying and compressing a batt of fibrous material comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a rotating first drum adjacent a counter-rotating second drum, the first drum and the second drum forming a nip point for compressing and passing the batt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) the first drum having opposing ends, a perforated exterior surface and being internally divided into a plurality of open-ended compartments, the first drum being enclosed on both ends by a plurality of solid sides, at least one of said solid sides enclosing the first drum having an anterior passage positioned about the nip point for allowing the flow of air through the solid side into the compartments of the first drum as said compartments of the first drum rotate adjacent said anterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) the second drum having opposing ends, a perforated exterior surface and being internally divided into a plurality of open-ended compartments, the second drum being enclosed on both ends by a plurality of solid sides, at least one of said solid sides enclosing the second drum having an anterior passage positioned about the nip point for allowing the flow of air from inside the compartments of the second drum through the solid side enclosing said second drum as said compartments of the second drum rotate adjacent said anterior passage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) at least one fan for creating a flow of moist air through the anterior passage of said solid side enclosing the first drum into the compartments of the first drum as the compartments of the first drum rotate adjacent the anterior passage of said solid side enclosing the first drum, out of the compartments of the first drum through the perforated surface of the first drum across the nip point and through the perforated surface of the second drum into the compartments of the second drum as the compartments of the second drum rotate adjacent the anterior passage of said solid side enclosing the second drum and out of the compartments of the second drum through the anterior passage of said solid side enclosing the second drum thereby humidifying a batt as it traverses in the proximity of the nip point.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a housing defining an enclosure for the first drum and the second drum, said housing having an opening for receiving said batt and an output opening through which the ball advances after conditioning.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein said housing further comprises:
<claim-text>(a) a stationary unit defining an enclosure for the first drum, said stationary unit comprising the solid sides enclosing the first drum, each of said solid sides enclosing the first drum further comprising a mating surface, said stationary unit being substantially open between the mating surfaces of said solid sides enclosing the first drum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a suspended unit defining an enclosure for the second drum, said suspended unit comprising the solid sides enclosing the second drum, each of said solid sides enclosing the second drum further comprising a mating surface shaped to correspond to a mating surface of the stationary unit, said suspended unit being substantially open between the mating surfaces of said solid stationary sides enclosing the second drum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) wherein the mating surfaces of the suspended unit are engaged against the corresponding mating surfaces of the stationary unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein one of said first and second counter-rotating drums is slightly elevated relative to the other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>(a) at least one of said solid sides enclosing the first drum having a posterior passage opening into the compartments of said first drum on the opposite side of said first drum from the nip point; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one fan connected to the posterior passage for creating a flow of hot dry air through the solid side enclosing the first drum into the compartments of the first drum as the compartments of the first drum rotate adjacent the posterior passage and out of the compartments of the first drum through the perforated surface of the first drum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>(a) at least one of the solid sides enclosing the second drum having a posterior passage opening into the compartments of the second drum on the opposite side of the second drum from the nip point; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one fan connected to the posterior passage for creating a flow of hot dry air through the solid side enclosing the second drum into the compartments of the second drum as the compartments of the second drum rotate adjacent the posterior passage and out of the compartments of the second drum through the perforated surface of the second drum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the stationary unit further comprises a posterior air chamber defined by a portion of the housing, an upper plurality of rows of replaceable flashing extending from the housing to engage and form a substantially lengthwise seal with the perforated exterior surface of the first drum, and a lower plurality of rows of replaceable flashing extending from the housing to engage and form a substantially lengthwise seal with the perforated exterior surface of the first drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref> further comprising
<claim-text>(a) at least one of the solid stationary sides enclosing the first drum having a posterior passage opening into the compartments of the first drum on the opposite side of the first drum from the nip point,</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) the housing having an exit passage opening into the posterior air chamber, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) at least one fan connected to the posterior passage for creating a flow of hot dry air through the solid side enclosing the first drum into the compartments of the first drum as the compartments of the first drum rotate adjacent the posterior passage, out of the compartments of the first drum through the perforated surface of the first drum into the posterior air chamber and through the exit passage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the corresponding mating surfaces of the stationary unit and of the suspended unit have a curvature substantially following the curvature of the perforated exterior surface of the second drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising a rotatable doffing roller adjustably positionable adjacent one or more of said drums.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> further comprising a laterally transverse shaft axially aligned with the second drum from which the suspended unit is pivotably suspended.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> further comprising one or more pistons attached to the suspended unit for controlling the movement of the suspended unit relative to the stationary unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein each of said drums further comprise a core connected to a shaft, the perforated exterior surface being connected to the core by connection to a plurality of radial staves extending from the core, said staves having substantially the same length as the core, said shaft extending at least to the solid sides of the housing and being operationally connected to a motor for powering and controlling the rotational speed of the drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the core, staves and perforated exterior surface at both ends of each drum have a plurality of replaceable gaskets to provide a seal against the solid sides of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein the perforated exterior surface of said first drum is releasably connected to the staves of said first drum, and wherein the perforated exterior surface of said second drum is releasably connected to the staves of said second drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of the anterior passage of the solid side enclosing the first drum and means for varying the size of the anterior passage of the solid side enclosing the second drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said posterior passage opening into the compartments of said first drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said posterior passage opening into the compartments of said second drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A device for humidifying a batt of fibrous material comprising a primary conditioning channel for carrying moist air along a pressure gradient, said primary conditioning channel comprising:
<claim-text>(a) an anterior passage through at least one of a pair of opposing sides of a housing positioned to enclose both ends of a first rotatable drum, said first rotatable drum having a plurality of open-ended internal longitudinal compartments and a perforated exterior surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one compartment of said first rotatable drum as said compartment rotates adjacent said anterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a plurality of perforations in a segment of the exterior surface of the first rotatable drum over the compartment as it rotates adjacent said anterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a gap of between about one quarter inch to about one inch between the exterior surface of the first rotatable drum and a perforated exterior surface of a second rotatable drum aligned with the first rotatable drum, said second rotatable drum having a plurality of open-ended internal longitudinal compartments;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) a plurality of perforations in a segment of the exterior surface of the second rotatable drum over a compartment of the second rotatable drum as the compartment rotates adjacent a second-drum anterior passage through at least one of a pair of opposing sides of a housing positioned to enclose both ends of the second rotatable drum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) at least, one compartment of the second rotatable drum as it rotates adjacent the second-drum anterior passage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) the second-drum anterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) wherein the batt is advanced through the gap between the first and second rotatable drums as said drums rotate in opposite directions and the pressure gradient through the primary conditioning channel is created by means of one or more fans connected to said primary conditioning channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> further comprising a first drying channel for carrying hot dry air along a pressure gradient, said first drying channel comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a posterior passage through at least one of the pair of opposing sides of the housing enclosing the first rotatable drum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one compartment of said first rotatable drum as said compartment rotates adjacent said posterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a plurality of perforations in a segment of the exterior surface of said first rotatable drum over the compartment as it rotates adjacent said posterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a posterior air chamber defined by a portion of the housing, an upper plurality of rows of replaceable flashing extending from the housing to engage and form a substantially lengthwise seal with the perforated exterior surface of the first rotatable drum, and a lower plurality of rows of replaceable flashing extending from the housing to engage and form a substantially lengthwise seal with the perforated exterior surface of the first rotatable drum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) an exit passage through said housing into the posterior air chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) wherein the pressure gradient through the first drying channel is created by means of one or more fans connected to said first drying channel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> further comprising a second drying channel for carrying hot dry air along a pressure gradient, said second drying channel comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a posterior passage through at least one of the pair of opposing sides of the housing enclosing the second rotatable drum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one compartment of said second rotatable drum as said compartment rotates adjacent said posterior passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a plurality of perforations in a segment of the exterior surface of said second rotatable drum over the compartment as it rotates adjacent said posterior passage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) an output opening through said housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) wherein the pressure gradient through the second drying channel is created by means of one or more fans connected to said second drying channel <b>19</b>.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of one or more of said anterior passages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">claim 20</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said posterior passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said posterior passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. A device for humidifying and compressing a batt of fibrous material comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a housing having an opening for receiving said batt and an output opening for outputting said batt after humidification and compression;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) said housing further comprising:
<claim-text>(i) a stationary unit having at least first and second opposing sides, each of said first and second opposing sides further comprising a mating surface, said mating surfaces of said first and second opposing sides defining an opening in the stationary unit between said first and second opposing sides;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a suspended unit having at least first and second opposing sides, each of said first and second opposing sides further comprising a mating surface shaped to engage with the corresponding mating surface of the stationary unit, said mating surfaces of said first and second opposing sides defining an opening in the suspended unit between said first and second opposing sides; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iii) a shaft from which the suspended unit is suspended to pivotably engage with the stationary unit;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a cylindrical, rotatable first drum on an axial shaft, said shaft running from the first opposing side of the stationary unit, through a first opposing end of said first drum, to a second opposing end of said first drum, to the opposing second side of the stationary unit, said first drum having a perforated exterior surface and being internally divided into a plurality of open-ended compartments by a plurality of radial staves extending from the shaft to the perforated exterior surface, said staves running axially along the shaft from about the first opposing end of said first drum to about the second opposing end of said first drum, and wherein the first opposing end of the first drum is substantially covered by the first side of the stationary unit and the second opposing end of the first drum is substantially covered by the second side of the stationary unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a cylindrical, rotatable second drum on an axial shaft, said shaft running from the first opposing side of the suspended unit, through a first opposing end of said second drum, to a second opposing end of said second drum, to the opposing second side of the suspended unit, said second drum having a perforated exterior surface and being internally divided into a plurality of open-ended compartments by a plurality of radial staves extending from the shaft to the perforated exterior surface, said staves running axially along the shaft from about the first opposing end of said second drum to about the second opposing end of said second drum, and wherein the first opposing end of the second drum is substantially covered by the first side of the suspended unit and the second opposing end of the second drum is substantially covered by the second side of the suspended unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) said first and second drums forming a nip point for compressing and passing the batt when the suspended unit is engaged with the stationary unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(f) one or more motors operatively connected to rotate said first and second drums in opposite directions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(g) at least one anterior passage in one or more of the opposing sides of the stationary unit, said anterior passage positioned to open into one or more of the opposing ends of the first drum about the nip point;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(h) at least one second-drum anterior passage in one or more of the opposing sides of the suspended unit, said second-drum anterior passage positioned to open into one or more of the opposing ends of the second drum about the nip point; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(i) at least one fan connected to either of said anterior passages for creating a flow of moist air through a primary conditioning channel, said primary conditioning channel comprising: (i) said anterior passage of the stationary unit, (ii) at least one of the compartments of the first drum as said compartment of the first drum rotate adjacent the anterior passage of the stationary unit, (iii) a plurality of perforations in a segment of the exterior surface of the first drum over said compartment of the first drum, (iv) the nip point, (v) a plurality of perforations in a segment of the exterior surface of the second drum, said segment covering at least one of the compartments of the second drum as said compartment of the second drum rotates adjacent said second-drum anterior passage of the suspended unit, (vi) at least one of the compartments of the second drum as said compartment of the second drum rotates adjacent said second-drum anterior passage of the suspended unit, and (vii) said second-drum anterior passage of the suspended unit.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>(a) at least one posterior passage in one or more of the opposing sides of the stationary unit, said posterior passage positioned to open into one or more of the opposing ends of the first drum opposite the anterior passage of said first drum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one fan connected to said posterior passage for creating a flow of hot dry air through the posterior passage, into the compartments of the first drum as the compartments of the first drum rotate adjacent said posterior passage and out of the compartments of the first drum through the perforated surface of the first drum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref> further comprising a posterior air chamber defined by a portion of the stationary unit, an upper plurality of rows of replaceable flashing extending from the stationary unit to engage and form a substantially lengthwise seal with the perforated exterior surface of the first drum, and a lower plurality of rows of replaceable flashing extending from the housing to engage and form a substantially lengthwise seal with the perforated exterior surface of the first drum, said posterior air chamber further comprising an exit passage through said portion of the stationary unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>(a) at least one posterior passage in one or more of the opposing sides of the suspended unit, said posterior passage positioned to open into one or more of the opposing ends of the second drum opposite the anterior passage of said second drum; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) at least one fan connected to said posterior passage for creating a flow of hot dry air through the posterior passage, into the compartments of the second drum as the compartments of the second drum rotate adjacent said posterior passage and out of the compartments of the second drum through the perforated surface of the second drum.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> wherein said first drum further comprises a core attached about the shaft of said first drum, and wherein the radial staves of said first drum extend from said core to the perforated exterior surface of said first drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> wherein said second drum further comprises a core attached about the shaft of said second drum, and wherein the radial staves of said second drum extend from said core to the perforated exterior surface of said second drum.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> wherein one of said first and second drums is slightly elevated relative to the other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> further comprising a rotatable doffing roller adjustably positionable adjacent one or more of said drums.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> further comprising one or more pistons attached to the suspended unit for controlling the movement of the suspended unit relative to the stationary unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said anterior passages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text>35. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00026">claim 26</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said posterior passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036" num="00036">
<claim-text>36. The device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00028">claim 28</claim-ref> further comprising means for varying the size of said posterior passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
