<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07654118-20100202.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20100119" date-publ="20100202">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07654118</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100202</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11515423</doc-number>
<date>20060905</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2005-0082322</doc-number>
<date>20050905</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>554</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100202</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 68 1204</main-classification>
<further-classification> 68 1202</further-classification>
<further-classification> 68 1205</further-classification>
<further-classification> 68 1206</further-classification>
<further-classification>  8158</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for washing machine</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0048549</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Matsukura et al.</name>
<date>20060300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 68 1206</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00002">
<othercit>Michelle Clifford et al.; &#x201c;Measuring Tilt with Low-g Accelerometers&#x201d;; Freescale Semiconductor, Inc. 2005; Application Note, Sensor Products, Tempe, AZ, Rev 0. May 2005; pp. 1-8.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00003">
<othercit>Kimberly Tuck; &#x201c;Tilt Sensing Using Linear Accelerometers&#x201d;; Freescale Semiconductor, Inc. 2007; Application Note, Accelerometer Systems and Applications Engineering, Tempe, AZ, Rev 2. May 2007; pp. 1-8.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>7</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 68 1204</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 68 1206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 68 24</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 68 25</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070050916</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070308</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Soo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Dong-Won</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-Do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>McKenna Long &#x26; Aldridge LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>LG Electronics Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Barr</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<department>1792</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Cormier</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention discloses a laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for a washing machine. The laundry amount sensing apparatus for the washing machine in which a tub is inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state includes a control unit that senses an inclination of the tub, determines a laundry amount corresponding to the sensed inclination of the tub, and controls a spin-drying speed according to the selected laundry amount.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="90.51mm" wi="96.77mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="115.23mm" wi="123.61mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="104.39mm" wi="134.28mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="117.35mm" wi="103.72mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="96.35mm" wi="144.78mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="174.33mm" wi="115.06mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="120.06mm" wi="90.09mm" file="US07654118-20100202-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2005-0082322, filed on Sep. 5, 2005, which is hereby incorporated by reference for all purposes as if fully set forth herein.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to a washing machine, and more particularly, to a laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for a washing machine which can precisely detect a laundry amount by using a correlation between an inclination of a wash tub and a laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Background Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In general, a washing machine applies a mechanical operation such as friction or vibration to the laundry put into a washing solution, thereby separating contaminants from the laundry.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The washing machine performs a washing step that applies a mechanical force to the laundry mixed with the washing solution, a rinsing step that separates the washing solution containing contaminants from the laundry, and a spin-drying step that removes rinse water from the laundry.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">When the laundry is not evenly distributed in the washing machine, namely, when the laundry is unbalanced, serious vibration and noise occur in the spin-drying operation.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Therefore, the washing machine needs a laundry leveling function that detects unbalanced laundry and evenly distributes the laundry according to the detected unbalance.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a structure of a conventional drum type washing machine.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the conventional drum type washing machine includes: a housing <b>11</b> that provides the shape of a main body; a suspension device <b>12</b> including a spring and a damper in the housing <b>11</b>; an outer water tub <b>13</b> supported by the suspension device <b>12</b>; a drum type inner rotating tub <b>14</b> positioned in the outer water tub <b>13</b>, for washing the laundry; a driving unit <b>15</b> for rotating the inner rotating tub <b>14</b>; and a rotation shaft <b>16</b> for transferring a driving force of the driving unit <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In the washing and rinsing operations of the drum type washing machine, water is supplied to the inner rotating tub <b>14</b>. When the water level in the inner rotating tub <b>14</b> reaches an appropriate water level, the supply of water is stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The inner rotating tub <b>14</b> is repeatedly rotated in the forward or backward direction by the driving force generated by the driving unit <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In the spin-drying operation, water supplied to the inner rotating tub <b>14</b> is drained off. The inner rotating tub <b>14</b> is first rotated at a low speed in the forward or backward direction by the driving force of the driving unit <b>15</b> for performing the laundry leveling function and then is accelerated to a spin-drying speed for performing the spin-drying operation.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The spin-drying operation needs precise sensing of the amount of laundry in the inner rotating tub <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a conventional laundry amount sensing method for a drum type washing machine calculates a sum of PWM duties required to reach a specific RPM, and a sum of RPM errors generated in a specific period maintaining the specific RPM.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The difference between the sum of the PWM duties required to reach the RPM and the sum of the RPM errors is determined as a laundry amount data.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">However, the conventional laundry amount sensing method for the drum type washing machine drives the motor of the washing machine to sense the laundry amount, which increases power consumption.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In addition, the conventional laundry amount sensing method for the drum type washing machine cannot precisely sense the laundry amount according to the laundry quality.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Furthermore, the conventional laundry amount sensing method for the drum type washing machine does not sense the laundry amount by a single load, thereby causing an unbalance sensing error.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Therefore, an object of the present invention is to provide a laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for a washing machine which can precisely detect a current laundry amount of the washing machine by using a correlation between an inclination of a tub and laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">To achieve these and other advantages and in accordance with the purpose of the present invention, as embodied and broadly described herein, there is provided a laundry amount sensing apparatus for the washing machine in which a tub is inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state includes a control unit that senses an inclination of the tub, determines a laundry amount corresponding to the sensed inclination of the tub, and controls a spin-drying speed according to the selected laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a laundry amount sensing apparatus for a washing machine in which a tub is inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state, the apparatus including: a storing unit that stores laundry amount corresponding to each inclination of the tub in advance; a sensing unit that senses the inclination of the tub; and a control unit that selects the laundry amount corresponding to the inclination sensed by the inclination sensing unit from the storing unit, and controlling a spin-drying speed according to the selected laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">According to yet another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a laundry amount sensing method for a drum type washing machine inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state including a step for sensing an inclination of a tub, and sensing a laundry amount corresponding to the sensed inclination of the tub.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">According to yet another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a laundry amount sensing method for a drum type washing machine inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state, the method including the steps of: storing laundry amount corresponding to each inclination of a tub; sensing the inclination of the tub; and selecting the laundry amount corresponding to the sensed inclination of the tub among the previously-stored laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">According to yet another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a laundry amount sensing method for a drum type washing machine inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state including: determining a formula describing a correlation between an inclination of a tub and a laundry amount; and sensing the inclination of the tub, and determining the laundry amount based upon the sensed inclination of the tub and the formula.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The foregoing and other objects, features, aspects and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the present invention when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The accompanying drawings, which are included to provide a further understanding of the invention and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and together with the description serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a structure of a conventional drum type washing machine;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a graph showing a process of determining a laundry amount data by using RPM in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a state wherein a gravity center of a tub of the washing machine moves forward due to increase of a laundry amount;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a structure of a laundry amount sensing apparatus for a washing machine in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a state wherein an inclination sensing unit is adhered to a tub in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart showing a laundry amount sensing method for a washing machine in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Reference will now be made in detail to the preferred embodiments of the present invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">A laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for a washing machine which can reduce power consumption of the washing machine and shorten a spin-drying operation time and a washing operation time by precisely detecting a current laundry amount in the washing machine by using a correlation between an inclination of a tub and a laundry amount will now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The laundry amount sensing apparatus for the washing machine grew out of the fact that a center of gravity moves to a front surface of a tub due to increase of a laundry amount and changes the inclination of the tub as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram illustrating the structure of the laundry amount sensing apparatus for the washing machine in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the laundry amount sensing apparatus for the washing machine includes a tub <b>100</b>, an inclination sensing unit <b>200</b>, a storing unit <b>500</b>, a control unit <b>300</b>, a display unit <b>400</b> and a driving unit <b>600</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The tub <b>100</b> is inclined at a predetermined angle in a non-load state. The center of gravity of the tub <b>100</b> moves forward as the laundry amount increases.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The inclination sensing unit <b>200</b> for sensing an inclination of the tub <b>100</b> is placed in an optimum position for sensing the inclination of the tub <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">As depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the inclination sensing unit <b>200</b> is placed on the top surface of the tub <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">An acceleration sensor, a mercury sensor or a transmission-type photo sensor may be employed as the inclination sensing unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Preferably, the acceleration sensor for sensing acceleration on two or more axes is used as the inclination sensing unit <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The storing unit <b>500</b> stores inclinations corresponding to variations of the laundry amount in advance by experiment.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The storing unit <b>500</b> may be a ROM table for storing the inclinations corresponding to the laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The control unit <b>300</b> controls the whole operation of the washing machine.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The control unit <b>300</b> selects the laundry amount corresponding to the inclination sensed by the inclination sensing unit <b>200</b> from the storing unit <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In addition, the control unit <b>300</b> performs spin-drying related control on the basis of the sensed laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The display unit <b>400</b> displays the current washing operation state and the remaining time.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The driving unit <b>600</b> drives the tub <b>100</b> at a predetermined speed under the control of the control unit <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The laundry amount sensing method for the washing machine in accordance with the present invention will now be described in more detail with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The storing unit <b>300</b> stores data representing the correlation between the inclination of the tub <b>100</b> and the laundry amount in advance by experiment.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The inclination of the tub <b>100</b> decreases as the laundry amount in the tub <b>100</b> increases.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">That is, the laundry put into the tub <b>100</b> is increased by a predetermined amount, and the change in inclination is detected verses the changes in the laundry amount and is stored in the storing unit <b>500</b> in the form of database.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In order to detect the laundry amount during the washing operation, the inclination sensing unit <b>200</b> senses the inclination of the tub <b>100</b> and applies the sensed inclination to the control unit <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">In accordance with one embodiment of the present invention, the control unit <b>300</b> selects the laundry amount corresponding to the inclination sensed by the inclination sensing unit <b>200</b> from the storing unit <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In accordance with another embodiment of the present invention, the control unit <b>300</b> detects the current laundry amount by using a formula obtained by the correlation between the inclination and the laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">That is, the control unit <b>300</b> makes a graph of the laundry amount corresponding to the inclinations detected by experiment, and converts the graph into a formula.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The control unit <b>300</b> controls the spin-drying operation according to the laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">That is, the control unit <b>300</b> controls the revolution speed of the tub <b>100</b> to be an appropriate speed according to the laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In accordance with the present invention, the laundry amount is detected by sensing the inclination of the tub of the washing machine. Differently from the conventional art, the operation of driving the motor of the washing machine is not required to sense the laundry amount. Also, the time of detecting the laundry amount after the washing operation is reduced to thereby shorten the spin-drying time.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As discussed earlier, the laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for the washing machine can precisely detect the current laundry amount of the washing machine by using the correlation between the inclination of the tub and the laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">As a result, the laundry amount sensing apparatus and method for the washing machine may reduce power consumption of the washing machine and shorten the spin-drying time and the washing time by precisely detecting the current laundry amount of the washing machine by using the correlation between the inclination of the tub and the laundry amount.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">As the present invention may be embodied in several forms without departing from the spirit or essential characteristics thereof, it should also be understood that the above-described embodiments are not limited by any of the details of the foregoing description, unless otherwise specified, but rather should be construed broadly within its spirit and scope as defined in the appended claims, and therefore all changes and modifications that fall within the metes and bounds of the claims, or equivalence of such metes and bounds are therefore intended to be embraced by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A laundry amount sensing apparatus for a washing machine in which a tub is inclined with respect to vertical in a non-load state, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a storing unit that stores a laundry amount corresponding to each inclination of the tub in advance;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sensing unit that senses the inclination of the tub; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit that selects the laundry amount corresponding to the inclination sensed by the inclination sensing unit from the storing unit, and controlling a dehydrating speed according to the selected laundry amount.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The laundry amount sensing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inclination sensing unit is an acceleration sensor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The laundry amount sensing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inclination sensing unit is attached to the tub.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The laundry amount sensing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the storing unit is a ROM table that stores the inclination corresponding to variations of the laundry amounts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The laundry amount sensing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the storing unit stores the laundry amount corresponding to the inclinations in an inverse proportional relation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The laundry amount sensing apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the control unit detects the laundry amount corresponding to the current inclination by using a formula describing the correlation between the inclination and the laundry amount.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A laundry amount sensing method for a drum type washing machine, in which a tub is inclined with respect to vertical in a non-load state, comprising: storing data representing laundry amount versus inclination of a tub; sensing the inclination of the tub; and selecting the laundry amount corresponding to the sensed inclination of the tub among the previously-stored laundry amount.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The laundry amount sensing method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein storing the laundry amount includes storing the inclinations corresponding to variations of the laundry amount in an inverse proportional relation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A laundry amount sensing method for a drum type washing machine, in which a tub is inclined with respect to vertical in a non-load state, comprising: determining a formula describing a correlation between an inclination of a tub and a laundry amount; and sensing the inclination of the tub; and determining the laundry amount based upon the sensed inclination of the tub and the formula.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The laundry amount sensing method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein determining the formula including making a graph of the laundry amount corresponding to the inclinations of the tub detected by experiment, and obtaining the formula by using the graph. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
