<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07654422-20100202.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20100119" date-publ="20100202">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07654422</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100202</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12009265</doc-number>
<date>20080117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-008388</doc-number>
<date>20070117</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>142</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>87</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100202</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>87</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100202</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>223 99</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Needle threader</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2567408</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Soderberg</name>
<date>19510900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3006518</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lillard</name>
<date>19611000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3404707</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Feld</name>
<date>19681000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>139  1 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3893602</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ivy</name>
<date>19750700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4008836</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Herzstein</name>
<date>19770200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4422564</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Koenig et al.</name>
<date>19831200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5165582</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Andrews</name>
<date>19921100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5311889</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ringle et al.</name>
<date>19940500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>132321</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5988463</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>DiCarlo et al.</name>
<date>19991100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>223 99</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>8-4948</doc-number>
<date>19960200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>223 99</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>112224</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>112225</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080169320</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080717</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fujiwara</last-name>
<first-name>Yasuhiro</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hamre, Schumann, Mueller &#x26; Larson, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Clover Mfg. Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Izaguirre</last-name>
<first-name>Ismael</first-name>
<department>3765</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A needle threader includes a flat handle portion and a thread-introducing loop portion extending from the handle portion. The thread-introducing loop portion includes a folded insertion edge at a tip for insertion into an eye of a needle. The thread-introducing loop portion includes a plate member having a first end, a second end, and a narrow band portion integrally connecting between the first and second ends. The narrow band portion has the folded insertion edge at a lengthwise center. The first end and the second end of the plate member are laid one on another and held in the handle portion. The narrow band portion is exposed from the handle portion to form the thread-introducing loop portion.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="79.33mm" wi="154.35mm" file="US07654422-20100202-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="212.09mm" wi="165.69mm" file="US07654422-20100202-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.24mm" wi="102.70mm" file="US07654422-20100202-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a needle threader for use in threading a sewing needle or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the field of handicraft such as embroidery and sewing, a needle threader is known which is a tool for facilitating threading of an embroidery needle or the like. Typically, a needle threader includes a thread-introducing loop portion that can be passed through the eye of a needle, and a handle portion attached to the thread-introducing loop portion. The handle portion is formed of a thin metal plate for example, and is adapted to be pinched with the fingers. The thread-introducing loop portion has a thin wire of a circular cross-section formed into an approximately diamond-shaped loop, for example, so that the loop can be inserted into the needle eye by utilizing a pointed tip.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">There is also known a needle threader which has a thread-introducing loop portion formed of a flat metal wire (see Japanese Utility Model Publication No. 8-004948 for example). In the needle threader disclosed in this publication, the flat-shaped (or plate-shaped) metal wire is folded into an approximately diamond-shaped loop so that the metal wire has a flat cross section having a long axis orthogonal to a plane constituting the diamond-shaped loop. According to such a structure, when the thread-introducing loop portion is passed through the needle eye, the tip end of the thread-introducing loop portion is inserted into the needle eye in the state where the long axis of the cross section of the metal wire extends in the longitudinal direction of the needle eye. The thread-introducing loop portion is pulled back through the needle eye after a thread is passed through the thread-introducing loop portion. At this time, the thread is placed in the folded loop portion located at the end of the thread-introducing loop portion, along the long axis of the cross section of the metal wire. Thus, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</figref> in the above-described publication, the portions of the thread passed through the needle eye are placed at a distance from each other in the longitudinal direction of the needle eye. As such, according to the needle threader disclosed in the above publication, even if the thread is relatively thick, it is possible to pull out the thread-introducing portion, while the thread is being held thereby, without causing the thread and the thread-introducing loop portion to get stuck at the needle eye.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Meanwhile, the thread-introducing loop portion has its end portion attached to the handle portion made of a thin metal plate. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> in the above publication, the metal wire has a cross section whose long axis is orthogonal to a flat axis of the handle portion. Thus, in order to attach the end portion of the thread-introducing loop portion to the handle portion, the handle portion is applied with a cut, for example, and the end portion of the thread-introducing loop portion is inserted into the cut and, then, the cut portion is pressed for so-called caulking. With this configuration, however, when the thread-introducing loop portion repeatedly receives a pulling force toward its end, it may be torn off at its portion attached to the handle portion. Furthermore, an impact applied to the attaching portion may cause undesirable deformation of the end of the thread-introducing loop portion and/or the handle portion.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a needle threader which ensures that a thread-introducing loop portion passed through a needle eye for threading can be pulled out smoothly without causing the thread and the thread-introducing loop portion to get stuck at the needle eye, and which appropriately maintains an attached state of the thread-introducing loop portion to a handle portion.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A needle threader according to the present invention comprises a flat handle portion and a thread-introducing loop portion extending from the handle portion. The thread-introducing loop portion includes a folded insertion edge at a tip for insertion into an eye of a needle. The thread-introducing loop portion comprises a plate member having a first end, a second end, and a narrow band portion integrally connecting between the first and second ends. The narrow band portion has said folded insertion edge at a lengthwise center. The first end and the second end of the plate member are laid one on another and held in the handle portion. The narrow band portion is exposed from the handle portion to form said thread-introducing loop portion.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Preferably, the folded insertion edge of the thread-introducing loop portion is elongated in a direction in which the needle eye is elongated.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In a preferred embodiment, the first end has a greater size than the second end, and the first end has an ornamental pattern formed by etching a portion not laid on the second end. Further, the handle portion is formed of a transparent resin.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, each of the first end and the second end has an engagement hole, and the engagement hole of the first end is aligned with the engagement hole of the second end. Further, the handle portion has an engagement projection inserted through the engagement holes of the first and second ends.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, the narrow band portion has an intermediate portion between the insertion edge and the first end and another intermediate portion between the insertion edge and the second end, and the intermediate portions is curved moderately such that a distance between the intermediate portions increases as a position in the intermediate portions approaches a lengthwise center of the intermediate portions.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The other features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description of the present invention when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view showing an example of a needle threader according to the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along the line II-II in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are perspective views showing how to use the needle threader according to the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A preferred embodiment of the present invention will now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a needle threader A according to an embodiment of the present embodiment includes a plate member <b>1</b> and a handle portion <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The plate member <b>1</b> includes a first end <b>11</b>, a second end <b>12</b>, and a narrow band portion <b>13</b> connecting these ends. The plate member <b>1</b> is formed in one piece by subjecting a thin metal plate such as a stainless steel spring member to stamping or etching for example. The plate member <b>1</b> has a thickness of, e.g., about 0.1 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The narrow band plate portion <b>13</b> extends in a straight line with a constant width. The narrow band plate portion <b>13</b> is folded at a lengthwise intermediate position to provide a folded insertion edge <b>13</b><i>a</i>. A portion <b>13</b><i>b </i>of the plate <b>13</b> located between the folded insertion edge <b>13</b><i>a </i>and the first end <b>11</b> as well as another portion <b>13</b><i>c </i>of the plate <b>13</b> located between the folded portion <b>13</b><i>a </i>and the other end <b>12</b> is curved moderately in a manner that these curved portions come farther apart from each other as they each approach its lengthwise center. The insertion edge <b>13</b><i>a </i>and the curved portions <b>13</b>B and <b>13</b>C may be formed by subjecting the narrow band portion <b>13</b> to presswork, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The first and second ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are wider than the narrow band portion <b>13</b>, and they are laid one on another while being held within the handle portion <b>2</b>. Each of the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> is provided with a plurality of (e.g., three) engagement holes <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>a</i>, respectively, penetrating in the thickness direction. Each engagement hole <b>11</b><i>a </i>of the first end <b>11</b> is aligned with a corresponding engagement hole <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the second end <b>12</b> when the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are laid one on the other. The first end <b>11</b> has a greater size than the second end <b>12</b>. The first end <b>11</b> has an ornamental pattern <b>11</b><i>b </i>provided as perforations in a region not overlapping the second end <b>12</b>. The ornamental pattern <b>11</b><i>b </i>may be formed by subjecting the first end <b>11</b> to etching for material removal.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The handle portion <b>2</b> is formed of a transparent synthetic resin, which may be AS resin for example. The handle portion <b>2</b> has a flat shape as a whole to be conveniently nipped between the thumb and the pointing finger. The handle portion <b>2</b> also serves to hold the overlapping ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> of the plate member <b>1</b> therein. More specifically, the handle portion <b>2</b> includes first and second members <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b </i>which are welded together into one piece with the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> sandwiched between these two members. Such welding of the two members <b>2</b><i>a</i>, <b>2</b><i>b </i>may be performed by ultrasonic bonding or high frequency welding. The first member <b>2</b><i>a </i>of the handle portion <b>2</b> has integral engagement projections <b>2</b><i>c </i>which are inserted through the engagement holes <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>a </i>of the plate member <b>1</b> into complementary recesses <b>2</b><i>c</i>. In the needle threader A, while the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> of the plate member <b>1</b> are housed and secured in the handle portion <b>2</b>, the narrow band portion <b>13</b> is exposed from the handle portion <b>2</b> to form a thread-introducing loop portion that can be passed through the eye of a needle.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In use of the needle threader A of the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the insertion edge <b>13</b><i>a </i>of the narrow band portion <b>13</b> is passed through the eye <b>4</b><i>a </i>of a needle <b>4</b> in such a manner that the width direction of the narrow band portion <b>13</b> coincides with the longitudinal direction of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>, and a thread <b>5</b> is passed through the narrow band portion <b>13</b> that has been inserted into the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>. Then, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the narrow band portion <b>13</b> is pulled out of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a </i>with the thread <b>5</b> being left passed therethrough. In this manner, threading of the thread <b>5</b> through the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a </i>is finished.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As described above, in the needle threader A of the present embodiment, when inserting the narrow band portion <b>13</b> into the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>, the width direction of the narrow band plate portion <b>13</b> is aligned with the longitudinal direction of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>. Accordingly, when pulling the narrow band plate portion <b>13</b> out of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>, the thread <b>5</b> that has been passed through the narrow band portion <b>13</b> extends in the width direction of the narrow band plate portion <b>13</b>, and thus, the plane including the thread <b>5</b> is oriented in the longitudinal direction of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>. This ensures that the portions of the thread <b>5</b> being passed through the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a </i>are apart from each other in the longitudinal direction of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a</i>, so that the thread <b>5</b> and the narrow band portion <b>13</b> can be pulled out smoothly without getting stuck at the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a </i>(see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). Furthermore, the narrow band portion <b>13</b> is formed into a loop shape with the moderately curved portions <b>13</b><i>b</i>, <b>13</b><i>c </i>thereof. Such a structure is advantageous in that it is possible to reduce the resistance due to elastic deformation of the narrow band portion <b>13</b> when pulling it out of the needle eye <b>4</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In the needle threader A of the present embodiment, the plate member <b>1</b> formed in one piece is secured in the handle portion <b>2</b> in the state where its ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> are laid one on the other. Accordingly, even if a pulling force is repeatedly applied to the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> during a threading operation, the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> would not come off the handle portion <b>2</b>. Furthermore, the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> covered with the handle portion <b>2</b> well withstand the impact. As such, it is possible to maintain the state where the narrow band portion <b>13</b> (the thread-introducing loop portion) is appropriately secured to the handle portion <b>2</b>, which prolongs the service life of the needle threader. In the needle threader A, the engagement projection <b>2</b><i>c </i>of the handle portion <b>2</b> is inserted through the engagement holes <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>a </i>formed at the respective ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> of the plate member <b>1</b>, which ensures appropriate positioning of the ends <b>11</b>, <b>12</b> with respect to the handle portion <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Furthermore, the handle portion <b>2</b> is formed of a transparent resin, and its interior can be seen therethrough. This allows the ornamental pattern <b>11</b><i>b </i>formed at the first end <b>11</b> of the plate member <b>1</b> housed and secured in the handle portion <b>2</b> to be viewed from the outside, consequently providing an attractive appearance.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">While the specific embodiment of the present invention has been explained above, the present invention is not limited thereto, and various modifications are possible within the range not departing from the concept of the invention. For instance, the specific shapes and materials of the respective portions of the needle threader of the present invention are not limited to those of the above embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Furthermore, the needle threader of the present invention may be configured such that the narrow band portion exposed from the handle portion is covered with a resin cap when not in use, to prevent undesirable contact of the narrow band portion with a foreign article.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A needle threader comprising a flat handle portion and a thread-introducing loop portion extending from the handle portion, the thread-introducing loop portion including a folded insertion edge at a tip for insertion into an eye of a needle;
<claim-text>wherein the thread-introducing loop portion comprises a plate member having a first end, a second end, and a narrow band portion integrally connecting between the first and second ends, the narrow band portion having said folded insertion edge at a lengthwise center;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first end and the second end of the plate member are laid one on another and held in the handle portion, the narrow band portion being exposed from the handle portion to form said thread-introducing loop portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first end has a greater size than the second end, the first end has an ornamental pattern formed at a portion not laid on the second end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the handle portion is formed of a transparent resin.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The needle threader according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the gripping portion has a flat axis that extends in an in-plane direction of the first end or the second end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The needle threader according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the ornamental pattern includes perforations formed in the first end.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The needle threader according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>each of the first end and the second end has an engagement hole, the engagement hole of the first end being aligned with the engagement hole of the second end, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the handle portion has an engagement projection inserted through the engagement holes of the first and second ends.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The needle threader according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the narrow band portion has an intermediate portion between the insertion edge and the first end and another intermediate portion between the insertion edge and the second end, the intermediate portions being curved moderately such that a distance between the intermediate portions increases as a position in the intermediate portions approaches a lengthwise center of the intermediate portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A needle threader comprising a flat handle portion and a thread-introducing loop portion extending from the handle portion, the thread-introducing loop portion including a folded insertion edge at a tip for insertion into an eye of a needle;
<claim-text>wherein the thread-introducing loop portion comprises a plate member having a first end, a second end, and a narrow band portion integrally connecting between the first and second ends, the narrow band portion having said folded insertion edge at a lengthwise center;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first end and the second end of the plate member are laid one on another and held in the handle portion, the narrow band portion being exposed from the handle portion to form said thread-introducing loop portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one of the first end and the second end is enlarged to have a greater width than the band portion for providing an ornamental pattern within the handle portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the handle portion is formed of a transparent resin. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
