<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07647877-20100119.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20100104" date-publ="20100119">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07647877</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100119</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12116194</doc-number>
<date>20080506</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>49</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100119</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>D</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>49</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100119</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>112241</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Thread take-up lever for a sewing machine</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2550628</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Webster</name>
<date>19510400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112241</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3310015</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gegauf, Jr.</name>
<date>19670300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112245</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3545392</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fresard</name>
<date>19701200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112241</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4070976</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Taketomi</name>
<date>19780100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112241</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4263859</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Johnson</name>
<date>19810400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112184</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4341171</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Johnson</name>
<date>19820700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112250</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5069150</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ogawa</name>
<date>19911200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112241</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5441003</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hashiride</name>
<date>19950800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>112259</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>112241</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090277367</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20091112</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tseng</last-name>
<first-name>Hsien-Chang</first-name>
<address>
<street>1F, No. 11, Lane 125, Sec. 1, Kuo Kuang Road</street>
<city>Ta-Li City, Taichung Hsien</city>
<postcode>412</postcode>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shia</last-name>
<first-name>Banger</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Izaguirre</last-name>
<first-name>Ismael</first-name>
<department>3765</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A thread take-up lever for a sewing machine is mounted on the sewing machine and can prevent a thread from disengaging from a thread-receiving portion. The thread take-up lever is disposed with a C-shaped thread-receiving portion having an open recess. Adjacent to the open recess is provided at least one positioning portion for fixing a thread-stopping member. One end of the thread-stopping member is fixed to the positioning portion, and an elastic stopping portion extends from the other end of the thread-stopping member. The stopping portion is formed with a free end abutted against an inner periphery of the open recess. The free end can be pushed away by the thread, and then the free end will automatically return to its original position immediately to abut against the open recess again, thus forming a structure to prevent the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="130.47mm" wi="137.75mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="138.68mm" wi="134.11mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07647877-20100119-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="174.67mm" wi="116.25mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="187.96mm" wi="94.32mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="175.18mm" wi="123.87mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="147.91mm" wi="92.20mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="134.45mm" wi="106.76mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="148.51mm" wi="101.68mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="160.95mm" wi="91.52mm" file="US07647877-20100119-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a thread take-up lever for a sewing machine, and more particularly to a thread take-up lever which can really prevent a thread from disengaging from a thread-receiving portion. An open recess of the thread-receiving portion of the thread take-up lever is disposed with an elastic thread-stopping member, so that the thread can indeed enter the thread-receiving portion in one direction and is prevented from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion in the other direction.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">At present, the thread take-up lever for a sewing machine has various forms and structures, and a structure of which for preventing a thread is prevented from disengaging from a thread-receiving portion is the main structure that needs to be improved. Currently, the relevant invention has also been disclosed in TW patent application M 2499621 &#x201c;a thread take-up lever for a sewing machine for preventing a thread from disengaging from a thread-receiving portion&#x201d;. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, a thread take-up lever is folded and formed as one piece, and a thread guide end <b>91</b> is folded on the upper thread take-up lever to form a long and narrow thread-receiving portion <b>92</b> with respect to the body of the thread take-up lever <b>90</b> for preventing the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b>. On an upper side of the thread guide end <b>91</b> is defined a concave surface <b>910</b> for reception of a clip <b>93</b> to form a blocking end <b>930</b>, the blocking end <b>930</b> is defined with a concave portion <b>931</b> for preventing the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b>, one end of the concave portion <b>931</b> is closed while the other end is open. In order to prevent the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b>, the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b> is designed to form a long and narrow passage. However, since said long and narrow passage is made of metal and produced by press forming, it is hard to trim the rough edge <b>920</b> formed in the passage due to a limitation of such long and narrow space. Thus the thread is unable to enter the passage, and the thread will be cut down and scratched easily due to such rough edge <b>920</b>. After the thread is scratched, the thread is likely to be broken by the thread take-up lever, and the sewing machine must be threaded again, so that not only the time will be wasted, but also the quality of the product will be affected.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The thread take-up lever is additionally defined with a clip, and the blocking end of the clip is located at one side of the thread guide. A large interspace is formed between the blocking end and the thread guide, so the thread is likely to fall off the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In addition, the conventional technology cited in the abovementioned invention is such that the thread guide end is folded, the structure can not prevent the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b>, so an elastic linear member is defined on one side of the thread guide end for preventing the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion <b>92</b>. However, the unnecessary interspace will be formed in such a structure so that the thread will disengage therefrom easily.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The present invention has arisen to mitigate and/or obviate the afore-described disadvantages.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The primary objective of the present invention is to provide a thread take-up lever for a sewing machine, an open thread-receiving portion is disposed at a front end of the thread take-up and is adjacent to an open recess. A thread-stopping member extends from an outside to an inside of the open recess, and one end of the thread-stopping member is fixed at one end of the open recess. An elastic stopping portion is formed with a free end extending towards the other end of the open recess, and the free end is abutted against an inner periphery of the open recess, so that the open recess of the thread-receiving portion is closed by the elastic stopping portion to prevent the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention is characterized in that: due to its elastic property, the elastic free end of the thread-stopping member is deformable when subjected to a pressure, so that a user can pull a thread tight and directly push the elastic free end downward with the tight thread, making the elastic free end of the stopping portion deform and move away from the inner periphery of the open recess of the thread-receiving portion, and thus the open recess of the thread-receiving portion is opened and naturally, the thread is pushed into it, and then, the elastic free end of the stopping portion recovers and closes the open recess of the thread-receiving portion so as to prevent disengagement of the thread out of the thread-receiving portion, in other words, with only one pushing movement of the user, the thread is moved into the open recess of the thread-receiving portion and restricted therein.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a sewing machine in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view showing that the sewing machine is provided with a thread take-up lever in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of the thread take-up lever in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view showing that a thread-stopping member is assembled on a thread take-up lever in accordance with the first embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is an exploded view of the sewing machine in accordance with a second embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a view showing that the thread-stopping member is assembled on the thread take-up lever in accordance with a third embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a three-dimensional exploded view of the sewing machine in accordance with the third embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a three-dimensional view of the sewing machine in accordance with the conventional invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The present invention will be clearer from the following description when viewed together with the accompanying drawings, which show, for purpose of illustrations only, the preferred embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>, a sewing machine <b>10</b> in accordance with a first embodiment of the present invention comprises a machine bed <b>11</b> and a horizontal arm <b>12</b>. The horizontal arm <b>12</b> is provided with a thread take-up lever <b>20</b> on whose front end is disposed a thread-receiving portion <b>21</b> having a laterally open recess <b>210</b>. Adjacent to the open recess <b>210</b> is provided at least one positioning portion <b>22</b>, the positioning portion <b>22</b> is cylinder-shaped, as shown in figure for fixing one end of a thread-stopping member <b>30</b>, and the other end of the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> is folded to close a top side of the open recess <b>210</b> and abutted against an inner periphery of open recess <b>210</b> of the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b>, so that the open recess of the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b> is closed in one direction.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The thread-stopping member <b>30</b> comprises a fixing end <b>31</b> which is abutted against one side of the thread take-up lever <b>20</b>, and the fixing end <b>31</b> is provided with a fixing portion <b>310</b> in the form of a through hole for insertion of the poisoning portion <b>22</b>, so that the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> can be fixed to the thread take-up lever <b>20</b>. A number of the positioning portion <b>22</b> is the same as a number of the fixing portion <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A stopping portion <b>32</b> extends from the fixing end <b>31</b> of the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> to close the top side of the open recess <b>210</b>, the stopping portion <b>32</b> extends from the outside to the inside of the open recess <b>210</b>, one end of the stopping portion <b>32</b> is formed with an elastic free end <b>320</b> abutted against an inner periphery of the open recess <b>210</b> so that the free end <b>320</b> is only allowed to move into the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b> without moving out of the open recess <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, when a thread <b>40</b> enters the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b> from the outside of the open recess <b>210</b> of the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b>, the thread <b>40</b> can push away the free end <b>320</b> to enter the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b>, and then the free end <b>320</b> will automatically return to its original position immediately to abut against the open recess <b>210</b> again, so that the stopping portion <b>32</b> of the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> can indeed close the open recess <b>210</b>, and the thread <b>40</b> is not allowed to slide off the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">A second embodiment of the sewing machine can also be as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the abovementioned positioning portion <b>22</b> can be replaced with a rivet <b>23</b> and a through hole <b>24</b>, and the same function can be achieved. A third embodiment of the sewing machine is as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, adjacent to a front edge of the positioning portion <b>22</b> of the thread take-up lever <b>20</b> is provided a groove <b>25</b>, and the fixing end <b>31</b> of the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> is folded to form a stopping portion <b>32</b> which is inserted into the groove <b>25</b> for fixing the thread-stopping member <b>30</b>. In addition, a fourth embodiment of the sewing machine is as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> can be a folded linear elastic member, and the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> is roughly U-shaped and has an inverse L-shaped side. The two fixing ends <b>31</b> are different in length, one is long and the other is short, respectively, and folded to form a positioning portion <b>311</b>. A free end <b>321</b> of the stopping portion <b>32</b> of the thread-stopping member <b>30</b> is in the form of a horizontal arm to abut against an inner periphery of the open recess <b>210</b> of the thread-receiving portion <b>21</b>, and through holes <b>24</b> are defined in the thread take-up lever <b>20</b> for insertion of the positioning portion <b>311</b> of the thread-stopping member <b>30</b>, respectively. Thus, a support point and resistance point are formed in the thread take-up lever <b>20</b>, respectively. The free end <b>321</b> of the stopping portion <b>32</b> is abutted to an inner periphery of the open recess <b>210</b>, so that the open recess <b>210</b> is closed completely.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">While we have shown and described various embodiments in accordance with the present invention, it is clear to those skilled in the art that further embodiments may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A thread take-up lever for a sewing machine, comprising:
<claim-text>a thread-receiving portion being disposed on a front end of a thread take-up lever for receiving a thread, the thread-receiving portion having an open recess, an elastic thread-stopping member being disposed at the open recess; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the thread-stopping member being provided with a stopping portion extending from a fixing end of the thread-stopping member to close a top side of the open recess, the stopping portion extending from an outside to an inside of the open recess;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein one end of the stopping portion of the thread-stopping member is formed with an elastic free end which abuts against an inner periphery of the open recess of the thread-receiving portion, so that the free end is only allowed to move into the thread-receiving portion without moving out of the open recess in such a manner that when a thread enters the thread-receiving portion from the outside of the open recess of the thread-receiving portion, the thread can push away the free end to enter the thread-receiving portion, and then the free end will automatically return to its original position immediately to abut against the open recess again, so that the stopping portion of the thread-stopping member can indeed close the open recess, and the thread is not allowed to slide off the thread-receiving portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The thread take-up lever as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thread take-up lever is disposed with a positioning portion, and the thread-stopping member is disposed with a fixing portion, the positioning portion is inserted into the fixing portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The thread take-up lever as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning portion is a protruding post, and the fixing portion is a through hole for insertion of the protruding post.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The thread take-up lever as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning portion is cylinder-shaped, and the fixing portion is a through hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The thread take-up lever as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning portion of the thread take-up lever is in the form of a rivet and a through hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The thread take-up lever as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein a groove is defined adjacent to an edge of the positioning portion of the thread take-up lever, and a fixing end of the thread-stopping member is folded to form the stopping portion which is inserted into the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The thread take-up lever as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the thread-stopping member is a folded linear elastic member, the thread-stopping member comprises a fixing end which is fixed to the thread take-up lever, one end of the fixing end is provided with the fixing portion, the stopping portion extends from the other end of the fixing end, one end of the stopping portion is formed with a free end being adjacent to the open recess, the thread take-up lever is provided with a positioning portion for fixing the fixing portion of the thread-stopping member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A thread take-up lever for a sewing machine, comprising:
<claim-text>a thread-receiving portion being disposed on a front end of a thread take-up lever for receiving a thread, the thread-receiving portion having an open recess, an elastic thread-stopping member being disposed at the open recess; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the thread-stopping member being provided with a stopping portion to close the open recess of the thread-receiving portion so as to prevent the thread from disengaging from the thread-receiving portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the thread take-up lever is disposed with a positioning portion, and the thread-stopping member is disposed with a fixing portion, the positioning portion is inserted into the fixing portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a groove is defined adjacent to an edge of the positioning portion of the thread take-up lever, and a fixing end of the thread-stopping member is folded to form the stopping portion which is inserted into the groove. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
