<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640924-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640924</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11516332</doc-number>
<date>20060906</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>RU</country>
<doc-number>2006102830</doc-number>
<date>20060131</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>333</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>124 511</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Mechanism for feeding ball bullets from a bin to a holder</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>307275</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Edmondson</name>
<date>18841000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198659</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1413694</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vollmer</name>
<date>19220400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89 3317</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2628376</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Scribner</name>
<date>19530200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 15  314</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2951422</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bobkowski</name>
<date>19600900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89 331</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4872547</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Helland</name>
<date>19891000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198659</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>4-18237</doc-number>
<date>19920100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>6-74691</doc-number>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00008">
<othercit>Computer-Generated English Translation and Patent Abstracts of Japan of JP 6-74691 dated Mar. 18, 1994.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00009">
<othercit>Patent Abstracts of Japan of JP 4-18237 dated Jan. 22, 1992.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>5</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>124 511</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>124 52</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070175464</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070802</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cherepanov</last-name>
<first-name>Valery Leonidovich</first-name>
<address>
<city>Izhevsk</city>
<country>RU</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>RU</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ladas and Parry LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Federalnoe Gosudarstvennoe Unitarnoe Predpriyatie &#x201c;Izhevsky Mekhanichesky Zavod&#x201d;</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Izhevsk</city>
<country>RU</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ricci</last-name>
<first-name>John</first-name>
<department>3711</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A feeding mechanism for ball bullets from a bin to a holder. The mechanism contains a bin <b>1</b> and additional reservoir <b>2</b> which in a lower part communicate. A vibrator <b>3</b> is placed in the lower part of the bin <b>1</b> and the additional reservoir <b>2</b>. The vibrator <b>3</b> is formed of two plates <b>4</b> and <b>5</b> of L-shape that oscillate on the axis <b>6</b> due to spring <b>7</b> and cam <b>8</b>, which is rotated by the electric drive <b>9</b>. A feeding screw mechanism is disposed in the lower part of the bin <b>1</b> and the additional reservoir <b>2</b>, the mechanism comprising a screw <b>10</b> with a helical spring. The base <b>12</b> is connected to cam <b>8</b> through a friction coupling <b>13</b>. The cam <b>8</b> gains rotation from the electric drive <b>9</b> through the gearing <b>14</b>. The bin <b>1</b> with additional reservoir <b>2</b> communicates with the holder <b>16</b> through the channel <b>15. </b></p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="242.06mm" wi="191.85mm" file="US07640924-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="244.94mm" wi="191.85mm" file="US07640924-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="149.01mm" wi="184.40mm" file="US07640924-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a pneumatic weapon, in particular, to mechanisms for feeding ball bullets from the bin to a holder.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">An automatic gun, for shooting plastic balls is known according to the Japanese patent No. 4-18237, F41C 3/06. The gun comprises a holder magazine, a bin, a feeding mechanism, and a drive operated manually by the user. When the user manually pulls an actuator element, the feeding mechanism rotates, and balls placed between teeth of toothed feeding mechanism pass through a channel of the holder magazine to an output opening.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A drawback of the device is that manual feeding of the holder magazine reduces performance of the gun. The rigid walls of the bin contribute to formation of congestion of the bullets, which prevents feeding of the bullets to the barrel of the gun. The rigid feeding system can result in blocking the mechanism, that is also a drawback of the known device.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A ball feeding mechanism for toy guns is known according to Japanese patent No. 06074691, application 04227495, cl. F41B 11/02. The feeding mechanism comprises a bin and a screw feeder (worm) with an electric motor below the bin. The screw feeds balls from the bin through a lead-in section to a forcing section. The balls are then fed by means of compressed air to a flexible tube (holder) to the gun. Compressed air maintains balls in the flexible tube and escapes through openings in the tube.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The rigidity of the bin walls and absence of additional devices to eliminate congestion of ball bullets at the bin outlet can result in a shut-down of the gun operation and reduce its reliability. The gun has an air source (additional propellant) that feeds ball bullets to the gun and complicates the gun structure. This is a drawback.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is an object of the present invention to create an article with increased operation reliability with simultaneous simplification of its structure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">This object is achieved by means of a feeding mechanism for ball bullets from the bin to the holder comprising a screw with electric drive, a bin and a holder. The screw comprises a helical compression spring.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Preferably, the screw comprises a cylindrical base, and a compression spring is fixed on it at an end distal to the holder.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The bin can be formed with a first and an additional reservoir, with both reservoirs being provided with a common vibrator.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It is preferable that both reservoirs of the bin interconnect.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A gap between spring turns should range from 1.2-1.5 of the ball diameter.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The vibrator can be configured for operation with the feeding mechanism drive.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The vibrator movement is preferably operated from the drive through a cam.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably the vibrator is disposed in the lower part of the bin, and is formed of two plates, joined together to form an L-shape fixed to the axis and elastically pressed against the cam.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The feeding mechanism comprising the compression spring provides constant urging of the ball bullets to an indent opposite the channel so as to ensure stable initial speed of the ball bullet when the gun is shot. This feeding mechanism makes it possible to increase operation reliability since a vibrator is disposed in the lower parts of both reservoirs of the bin, thereby preventing congestion at the inlet of the holding part of the magazine.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The additional reservoir in the bin assists in also preventing ball congestion by directing ball bullets accumulated at the holder entry to the additional reservoir of the bin by operation of the electric drive.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The invention is illustrated by drawing as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a general view of the device,</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a cross-section A-A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a cross-section B-B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The ball bullets feeding mechanism comprises a bin <b>1</b> and an additional reservoir <b>2</b> which, in a lower part, communicate with each other therebetween. Vibrator <b>3</b> and additional reservoir <b>2</b> are disposed in the lower part of the bin <b>1</b>. The vibrator <b>3</b> comprises two plates <b>4</b> and <b>5</b> formed in L-shape and oscillating on axis <b>6</b> by spring <b>7</b> and cam <b>8</b>, which is rotated by the electric drive <b>9</b>. A feeding screw mechanism is provided in the lower part of bin <b>1</b> and additional reservoir <b>2</b>, the screw mechanism comprising a screw <b>10</b> having a helical compression spring which is connected to a cylindrical base <b>12</b> by bent end <b>11</b> distal to the holder. Thus the base <b>12</b> is connected to a cam <b>8</b> through a friction coupling <b>13</b>. The cam <b>8</b> is rotationally driven from the electric drive <b>9</b> through a gearing <b>14</b>. The bin <b>1</b> with the additional reservoir <b>2</b> communicates with a holder <b>16</b> through channel <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The ball bullets feeding mechanism from the bin to the holder operates as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Ball bullets <b>17</b> are fed in the bin <b>1</b> and the electric drive <b>9</b> is actuated. The electric drive <b>9</b> rotates cam <b>8</b> through the gearing <b>14</b>. It also rotates the screw <b>10</b> through the friction coupling <b>13</b> and the base <b>12</b>. The ball bullets <b>17</b>, under action of gravity, descend from the bin <b>1</b> to the base <b>12</b> of the feeding screw mechanism and are urged by the screw spiral of the screw <b>10</b>, through the channel <b>15</b>, to the holder <b>16</b>. The rotating cam <b>8</b> activates the vibrator <b>3</b> elastically pressed to the cam <b>8</b> by spring <b>7</b>. The plates <b>4</b> and <b>5</b> swinging around an axis <b>6</b>, stirs ball bullets <b>17</b> preventing congestion.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">When holder <b>16</b> is filled by the ball bullets <b>17</b>, the screw <b>10</b>&#x2014;comprising a compression spring with a gap between turns equal to 1.2-1.5 diameters of the ball diameter&#x2014;is compressed to provide elastic compression of ball bullets <b>17</b> in the holder and the first ball to the indent <b>18</b>. The friction coupling <b>13</b> defines the predetermined compression force.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">When the holder <b>15</b> is filled, rotation of the screw <b>10</b> ceases. The gun is ready to shoot.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Pressing a trigger (not shown in the drawing) causes ejection of the ball bullets <b>17</b> under action of compressed gas from the barrel of the gun. At the same time, the electric drive <b>9</b> fills the holder <b>16</b> with balls. The electric drive may be controlled by an electronic device.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A feeding mechanism for ball bullets comprising:
<claim-text>a screw mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a drive of the screw mechanism with a friction coupling;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bin;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a holder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vibrator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said screw mechanism comprising a cylindrical base, a spiral compression spring comprising first and second ends, said compression spring being attached to said cylindrical base by the second spring end which is distal from the holder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said drive of the screw mechanism being connected to the cylindrical base through said friction coupling;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said bin having an additional container for balls, the bin and the additional container being interconnected;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said bin and said additional container for balls are provided with said vibrator.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the spring has turns with a gap between the turns of the spring being in the range from 1.2 to 1.5 of a diameter of the balls.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a cam attached to said drive of the screw mechanism with the friction coupling, said cam being configured to activate the vibrator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The mechanism according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said vibrator is formed of two plates joined in an L-shaped combination rotatable around an axis and pressed against the cam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An apparatus for feeding balls to a gun comprising:
<claim-text>(1) a bin for the balls comprising a first reservoir and an additional reservoir, the first and additional reservoirs communicating with each other at a lower part of the bin;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(2) vibrator means disposed in the lower part of the bin for shaking the balls in the lower part of the bin to inhibit congestion of the balls in the lower part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(3) a screw mechanism for urging balls from the lower part to a holder for the balls from which the balls may be discharged to the gun, said mechanism comprising a cylindrical base and a spiral compression spring attached to the cylindrical base at a first end of the spring that is distal from the holder; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(4) a drive for the screw mechanism comprising a friction coupling.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the spring has turns with a gap between the turns of the spring being in the range from 1.2 to 1.5 of a diameter of the balls.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a cam attached to said drive of the screw mechanism with the friction coupling, said cam being configured to activate the vibrator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein said vibrator is formed of two plates joined in an L-shaped combination rotatable around an axis and pressed against the cam.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The apparatus as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a plurality of balls, said holder being dimensioned such that the balls pass through the holder in single file. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
