<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640745-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640745</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11623153</doc-number>
<date>20070115</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>309</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>44</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 606051</main-classification>
<further-classification> 60612</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">High-pressure fluid compression system utilizing cascading effluent energy recovery</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5142866</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Yanagihara et al.</name>
<date>19920900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 606052</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5384051</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McGinness</name>
<date>19950100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5405533</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hazlebeck et al.</name>
<date>19950400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5471834</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kapich</name>
<date>19951200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5591415</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dassel et al.</name>
<date>19970100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6112523</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kamo et al.</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60612</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6255529</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Nagase et al.</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6279550</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Bryant</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6324846</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Clarke</name>
<date>20011200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 606052</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6462230</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Nagase et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6470683</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Childs et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6519926</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hazlebeck</name>
<date>20030200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6557345</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Moeckel</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60599</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6571552</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ban et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6808179</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Bhattacharyya et al.</name>
<date>20041000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00016">
<othercit>N. Watson, M.S. Janota, &#x201c;Turbocharging the Internal Combustion Engine,&#x201d; Wiley-Interscience Publication, John Wiley &#x26; Sons, 1982, pp. 392-397.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>43</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 606051</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60612</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080169246</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080717</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Japikse</last-name>
<first-name>David</first-name>
<address>
<city>Woolwich</city>
<state>ME</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Downs Rachlin Martin PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Concepts ETI, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>White River Junction</city>
<state>VT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Hoang M</first-name>
<department>3748</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A high-pressure system and method utilizing an input fluid. The system includes a reactor treating a material to produce an effluent having an energy content, a plurality of stages compressing the input fluid in a stepwise manner providing a high-pressure reactor input stream to the reactor, and a cascading effluent energy recovery system mechanically communicating with the plurality of stages. The cascading effluent energy recovery system imparts a portion of the energy content of the effluent into each of the plurality of stages powering that stage. The method includes receiving an input fluid, compressing the input fluid over a plurality of stages producing the high-pressure stream, providing the high-pressure stream to the reactor, recovering a portion of the energy content of the effluent at each of the plurality of stages, and using each the portion of the energy in compressing the input fluid at a corresponding respective stage.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="142.07mm" wi="148.42mm" file="US07640745-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="166.20mm" wi="162.39mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640745-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="159.26mm" wi="142.75mm" file="US07640745-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure generally relates to the field of pressurizing systems for use in thermo-chemical processes. In particular, the present disclosure is directed to a high-pressure compression system utilizing cascading effluent energy recovery.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">High-pressure air and steam are used in various industrial applications. For example, extremely high-pressure air may be used on submarines for clearing main ballast tanks. High-pressure water vapor (commonly referring to water molecules with or without air or other gas molecules present) can also be used to create a very effective high-pressure chemical reaction with a purpose of reducing various components of the reaction down to their fundamental constituents of water and carbon dioxide. For example, this technique is used in the process of supercritical water oxidation (SCWO), wherein diverse waste streams, including sewage, commercial waste, old munitions, and the like, are converted to basic oxidized constituents with minimal harmful waste effluent from the process.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conventional forms of compression for such high-pressure applications have been accomplished with positive displacement compressors originally designed for submarines and that provide pressures in the order of 5,000 psi. Such conventional compressors limit the possibilities of efficient recapture of waste energy and reinsertion of the energy back into the cycle.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Various processes for treating a feedstock require process materials to be maintained at elevated pressures. Additionally, conventional processes may require the feedstock to be at an elevated temperature. In such treatment processes, obtaining a high-pressure rise with minimum energy consumption presents a continuing problem. One of the efforts to recover waste energy in current systems involves the use of conventional turbines to expand the high-pressure gas effluent stream once the reaction is complete. The energy recaptured is then delivered to an electric generator. The electric power created in the generator is either used to drive the high-pressure positive displacement compressors or is returned to the grid.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Inefficient use of waste energy has been particularly acute in the hydrothermal treatment of organic waste products using SCWO techniques. In a typical SCWO process, the materials in a reaction chamber are preferably maintained at a pressure of over 200 bar and a temperature of over 700&#xb0; Celsius. Processes may have a preferred reaction pressure of 1000 bar. Conventional positive displacement compressors, as described above, are used to help achieve such high-pressures in the reaction chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In SCWO processes, oxidation of waste organics can be achieved by pumping an oxidizer, such as air, into the reaction chamber for mixing with other constituents of the reaction, such as supercritical water, raw wastes, and additives such as a fuel to assist in maintaining suitable temperatures. Such processes are described in U.S. Pat. No. 4,338,199 issued to Model on Jul. 6, 1982, U.S. Pat. No. 5,106,513 issued to Hong on Apr. 21, 1992, and U.S. Pat. No. 6,519,926 issued to Hazlebeck on Feb. 18, 2003, which are all hereby incorporated by reference in their entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Multiple stage turboccharging of internal combustion engines is a technique well known in the art. For examples, such multiple stage turbocharging of internal combustion engines may be found in U.S. Pat. No. 7,000,393 issued to Wood et al. Additionally, multiple stage turbocharging of internal combustion engines is also provided in <i>Turbocharging the Internal Combustion Engine, </i>by N. Watson and M. S. Janota, at sections 11.5 and 11.6, published by Wiley-Interscience Division, John Wiley &#x26; Sons, Inc., New York (1982). However, the recovery of energy in such conventional systems has generally been inefficient.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In one embodiment of the present disclosure, a system utilizing an input fluid is disclosed. The system includes a continuous reaction reactor for converting an input material using the input fluid so as to produce an effluent having an energy content of a first energy type. A plurality of compression stages are located in series with one another for compressing the input fluid in a stepwise manner so as to provide a pressurized reactor input stream to the continuous reaction reactor. A cascading effluent energy recovery system mechanically communicates with each of the plurality of compression stages. The cascading effluent energy recovery system imparts a portion of the energy content of the effluent into each of the plurality of compression stages so as to power that one of the plurality of compression stages.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In another embodiment of the present disclosure, a system utilizing an input fluid is provided. The system comprises a reactor for converting a material using the input fluid so as to produce an effluent having an energy content of a first energy type. The system also comprises a first early compression stage that includes a first early stage compressor for compressing the input fluid and a first early stage expansion turbine for recovering a portion of the energy content of the effluent. The first expansion turbine is mechanically linked to the first early stage compressor for at least partially driving the first compressor. A first motor/generator is mechanically linked to each of the first early stage compressor and the first early stage expansion turbine. The first motor/generator selectively powers the first early stage compressor during periods of insufficient power from the first early stage expansion turbine and converting an excess of the energy content into electricity during periods of excess power from the first early stage expansion turbine. A latter compression stage is located downstream from the first early compression stage and upstream from the reactor. The latter compression stage comprises a latter stage compressor for further compressing the input fluid and a latter stage expansion turbine for recovering a second portion of the energy content of the effluent. The latter stage expansion turbine is mechanically linked to the latter stage compressor for driving the latter stage compressor.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In yet another embodiment of the present disclosure, a method of providing a pressurized stream of an input fluid to a continuous reaction reactor so as to produce a non-pulsed effluent having an energy content is disclosed. The method includes the steps of receiving an input fluid and compressing the input fluid over a plurality of compression stages so as to produce the pressurized stream. The pressurized stream is provided to the continuous reaction reactor. A portion of the energy content of the effluent is recovered at each of the plurality of compression stages. Each portion of the energy content is used in compressing the input fluid at a corresponding respective one of the plurality of compression stages.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In a further embodiment, a method of providing a pressurized stream of al input fluid to a reactor so as to produce a non-pulsed effluent having an energy content is disclosed. The method includes the steps of receiving an input fluid and compressing the input fluid over a plurality of compression stages so as to produce the pressurized stream. The pressurized stream is provided to the reactor. A portion of the energy content of the effluent is recovered at each of the plurality of compression stages. The portion of the energy content at at least one of the plurality of compression stages is supplemented with additional energy to supplement the compressing of the input fluid.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">For the purpose of illustrating the disclosure, the drawings show aspects of one or more embodiments of the disclosure. However, it should be understood that the present disclosure is not limited to the precise arrangements and instrumentalities shown in the drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of the components of a high-pressure system in accordance with the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of a later compression stage of a high-pressure system in accordance with the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an efficient high-pressure system <b>100</b>. At a high level, system <b>100</b> includes a pressurized chemical reaction system <b>110</b> and a cascading energy recovery system <b>112</b>. As can be readily seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, cascading energy recovery system <b>112</b> interacts with pressurized system <b>110</b> to recover at least a portion of the initial energy content from effluent <b>114</b> and uses this energy to produce, or aid in producing, a high-pressure stream <b>118</b>, e.g., air and/or steam, that is input into pressurized system <b>110</b> as part of the reaction process.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">High-pressure system <b>100</b> includes a series of compression and expansion stages, here stages <b>124</b>, <b>126</b>, and <b>128</b>, for compressing an input fluid <b>122</b>, e.g., vapor and/or gas, through the series of stages to produce high-pressure stream <b>118</b> for reactor <b>116</b> on a compression side and for expanding effluent <b>116</b> through the series of stages to produce power for each associated stage on an expansion side. It is noted that while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows three compression and expansion stages <b>124</b>, <b>126</b>, and <b>128</b>, the present disclosure contemplates a lower or greater number of stages while keeping within the scope and spirit of the present disclosure. The number of compression and expansion stages utilized may depend upon the actual pressure requirements for high-pressure stream <b>118</b> and upon the actual energy content available from reactor effluent <b>114</b>. Generally, three or more stages will typically be required to achieve necessary levels of pressure on the input side of pressurized chemical reaction system <b>110</b> and to successfully recapture high amounts of waste energy on the output side, as will be described below.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the illustrative embodiment shown, pressurized chemical reaction system <b>110</b> includes a reactor <b>116</b> that may perform a continuous self-sustaining process for converting an uninterrupted continuous feed of input materials, as discussed further below, into effluent <b>114</b> with an initial energy content. The self-sustaining process of reactor <b>116</b> provides a thermally self-sustaining continuous flow of energy to system <b>100</b>, wherein the reactor includes but is not limited to a supercritical water oxidation (SCWO) reactor, or other type of continuous chemical process reactor. In these cases, reactor <b>116</b> may be referred to as a &#x201c;continuous reaction reactor.&#x201d; It is noted that the present disclosure also contemplates that reactor <b>116</b> may be of a &#x201c;pulsed reaction&#x201d; type in which the on going process involves a series of intermittent reactions, e.g., combustions. Examples of such pulsed reaction reactors include reciprocating type internal combustion engines, e.g., spark-ignition engines or diesel engines, among others. Input materials may include any of a variety of materials which may be treated and/or converted to usable end products, as will be discussed below.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates reactor <b>116</b> as an SCWO reactor in which SCWO reactions occur under high-pressure and high-temperature conditions. (Again, although the illustrated embodiment is directed to SCWO, those skilled in the art will readily appreciate that the scope of this disclosure covers systems beyond SCWO.) Reactor <b>116</b> may process a mixture of a feedstock <b>130</b>, an additive <b>132</b>, and high-pressure stream <b>118</b>. Reactor <b>116</b> generally gasifiers the mixture of water and organics under hydrothermal treatment conditions to produce effluent <b>114</b> with the initial energy content. Effluent <b>114</b> may include a high-temperature and high-pressure gaseous mixture of steam and combustible gases containing particulates, salts and corrosive species, among other things. Moreover, effluent <b>114</b> may include compounds resulting from the broken chemical bonds of organics during the reaction in reactor <b>116</b>. Additionally, reactor <b>116</b> may include mechanical systems and/or purging systems (not shown) for helping transport materials through the reactor.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Feedstock <b>130</b> generally includes organic wastes. Additive <b>132</b> may include one or more waste materials or fuel, including but not limited to, an oil-based hydrocarbon or diesel. Additive <b>132</b> may also include, but is not limited to, neutralizing agents to neutralize acids formed in reactor <b>116</b>, inert solids to aid in salt transport, salt-forming agents, corrosion inhibitors, minerals, and combustible material for use as an auxiliary fuel. Generally, burning additive <b>132</b> helps maintain appropriate elevated temperatures in reactor <b>116</b> for the desired reactions. For example, elevated temperatures may generally be in the range of 350&#xb0; Celsius to 800&#xb0; Celsius, but are not limited to this range. High-pressure stream <b>118</b> generally includes pressurized steam and air for use in reactor <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As shown, the compression side of first stage <b>124</b> may include a first compressor <b>134</b> having a moderate pressure ratio, such as a pressurization in the range of but not limited to 2 to 9, for compressing input fluid <b>122</b>. First compressor <b>134</b> may be mechanically linked with a first expansion turbine <b>136</b> of energy recovery system <b>112</b>, e.g., via a first shaft <b>138</b> on the expansion side of first compression and expansion stage <b>124</b>. First expansion turbine <b>136</b> generally powers first compressor <b>134</b> as effluent <b>114</b> expands through the turbine. The input:output pressure ratios for both first compressor <b>134</b> and first expansion turbine <b>136</b> are preferably chosen so as to balance the thrust to a reasonable first order, with residual thrust being handled by bearings or a thrust collar (not shown). Additionally, first compression and expansion stage <b>124</b> may also include a first motor/generator <b>140</b> coupled to first shaft <b>138</b> so as to selectively drive first compressor <b>134</b>, either alone or in combination with first expansion turbine <b>136</b>, during periods of insufficient power from the first expansion turbine or to generate electricity when the amount of energy needed to drive the first compressor is less than the energy recovered by the first expansion turbine.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The compression side of second compression and expansion stage <b>126</b> may include a second compressor <b>142</b> for further compressing/pressurizing input fluid <b>122</b>, which may be received as a cooled second-stage input <b>166</b> as described below. Second compressor <b>142</b> is mechanically linked with a second expansion turbine <b>144</b>, via a second shaft <b>146</b>. Second expansion turbine <b>144</b> generally powers second compressor <b>142</b> as effluent <b>114</b> expands through the second turbine. Additionally, second compression and expansion stage <b>126</b> may also include a second motor/generator <b>148</b> coupled to second shaft <b>146</b> so as to selectively drive second compressor <b>142</b>, either alone or in combination with second expansion turbine <b>144</b>, during periods of insufficient power from the second expansion turbine or to generate electricity when the amount of energy needed to drive the second compressor is less than the energy recovered by the second expansion turbine.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Third compression and expansion stage <b>128</b> may include a third compressor <b>150</b> oil the compression side for yet further compressing input fluid <b>122</b> so as to produce high-pressure stream <b>118</b> that enters reactor <b>116</b>. Third compressor <b>150</b> may be driven by a third expansion turbine <b>152</b> via a third shaft <b>154</b>. In the present example, each compression and expansion stage <b>124</b>, <b>126</b>, <b>128</b> achieves a gain of approximately, but not limited to, 6 to 7 times in pressure exiting that stage relative to the input of that stage.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Since third turbine <b>152</b> of third compression and expansion stage <b>128</b> is the first of three expansion turbines <b>136</b>, <b>144</b>, and <b>152</b> to expand effluent <b>114</b>, the third turbine will typically output sufficient power to drive third compressor <b>150</b> without the need of an associated motor/generator in the stage, as in first and second stages <b>124</b>, <b>126</b>. Moreover, typical optimal speeds of operation of the later compression stage(s), i.e., stage(s) closest to reactor <b>116</b>, are so high that it is often problematic, at least under contemporary technology, to employ a motor rotating at such high speeds.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">For startup of one or more later compression stages, i.e., the stage(s) closest to reactor <b>116</b>, and/or where additional motive force in steady-state is needed, a motive system without additional rotating parts may be provided, e.g., in the form of a bootstrap, or bypass <b>156</b>, that bypasses reactor <b>116</b> and utilizes pressurized flow from one or more lower stages, here, compression and expansion stages <b>124</b>, <b>126</b>. The bootstrap driving of third compression and expansion stage <b>128</b> by bypass <b>156</b> utilizes a portion of input fluid <b>122</b> after compression/pressurization by second compression and expansion stage <b>126</b>. In other embodiments, e.g., one or more bootstrap drives similar to bypass <b>156</b> may replace the motor/generators of two or more stages after first compression and expansion stage <b>124</b> or other early compression stages.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Pressurized system <b>110</b> may also include one or more intercoolers, or heat exchangers, e.g., heat exchangers <b>158</b>, <b>160</b>, that may serve one or more purposes. For example, in some processes, inter-stage cooling of compressed input fluid <b>122</b> may be required to satisfy temperature requirements for a cycle. Inter-stage cooling helps achieve improved downstream stage compressor performance and thermodynamic efficiency. Additionally, lower temperatures allow compressors, such as compressors <b>134</b>, <b>142</b>, and <b>150</b>, and related components to be constructed from less expensive materials and/or surface-coated with materials having lower temperature limits that provide less stringent design constraints. Alternatively, the material characteristics of the particular compressors and related components selected may require inter-stage cooling. Inter-stage cooling may be accomplished by providing heat exchangers <b>158</b>, <b>160</b> between corresponding respective successive compression and expansion stages. For example, first heat exchanger <b>158</b> may be fluidly located between first compression and expansion stage <b>124</b> and second compression and expansion stage <b>126</b>, and second heat exchanger <b>160</b> may be fluidly located between the second compression and expansion stage and third compression and expansion stage <b>128</b>. Heat exchangers (intercoolers) <b>158</b> and <b>160</b> capture and remove heat and energy from the input fluid following compression at the corresponding respective compression and expansion stages. The removed heat and energy may be used within high-pressure system <b>100</b> as described below or elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">During operation of high-pressure system <b>100</b>, input fluid <b>122</b> enters first compressor <b>134</b> at first compression and expansion stage <b>124</b>. First compressor <b>134</b> imparts energy to input fluid <b>122</b> by raising tie pressure and temperature of the input fluid to produce a first-stage output <b>162</b> for introduction into second compressor <b>142</b> of second compression and expansion stage <b>126</b>. As discussed below in more detail, first compressor <b>134</b> is powered by either first expansion turbine <b>136</b>, first motor/generator <b>140</b>, or both, depending upon the particular operating characteristics and state of operation of high-pressure system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">When first heat exchanger <b>158</b> is present, first-stage output <b>162</b> enters the first heat exchanger, wherein heat and energy is removed from the first-stage output, e.g., using a coolant <b>164</b>. First heat exchanger <b>158</b> provides a cooled second-stage input <b>166</b> to second compressor <b>142</b>. The heat and energy removed from first-stage output <b>162</b> may be utilized, e.g.,.to assist in pre-heating feedstock <b>130</b> and/or additive <b>132</b> for receipt by reactor <b>116</b>, or for another purpose.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Cooled second-stage input <b>166</b> (or first-stage output <b>162</b> if first heat exchanger <b>158</b> is not present) enters second compressor <b>142</b> for additional compression so as to output a second-stage output <b>168</b> with a higher pressure and temperature than the cooled second-stage input. For example, if the output:input pressure ratio for first compressor <b>134</b> is slightly greater than 7, and the output:input pressure ratio for second compressor <b>142</b> is also slightly greater than 7, then an output:input pressure ratio of approximately 50 or more for the two stages together may be achieved. As discussed below in more detail, second compressor <b>142</b> is powered by either second expansion turbine <b>144</b>, second motor/generator <b>148</b>, or both, depending upon the particular operating characteristics of high-pressure system <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">When second heat exchanger <b>160</b> is present, second-stage output <b>168</b> enters the second heat exchanger, wherein heat and energy is removed from the second-stage output, e.g., using a coolant <b>170</b>. Second heat exchanger <b>160</b> provides a cooled third-stage input <b>172</b> to third compressor <b>150</b>. The heat and energy removed from second-stage output <b>168</b> may be transferred to and utilized in another part of system <b>100</b> or used elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Cooled third-stage input <b>172</b> (or second-stage output <b>168</b> if second heat exchanger <b>160</b> is not present) enters third compressor <b>150</b> for additional compression so as to output high-pressure stream <b>118</b>. Which has a higher pressure and temperature than the cooled third-stage input. In one example, the output:input pressure ratio for first compressor <b>134</b> may be slightly greater than 7, the Output:input pressure ratio for second compressor <b>142</b> may be slightly greater than 7, and the output: input pressure ratio for third compressor <b>150</b> may be approximately 5, resulting in a combined output:input pressure ratio for the three stages of approximately 250, which if input fluid <b>122</b> has an initial pressure of about 14 psi results in high-pressure stream <b>118</b> having a pressure of about 3,500 psi.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">It is noted that high-pressure system <b>100</b> may not include a heat exchanger (intercooler) downstream of third compressor <b>150</b>. This is so because it may be desirable to retain the full temperature of high-pressure stream <b>118</b> exiting third compressor <b>150</b> (or other final stage(s) in other embodiments) in order to keep heat (enthalpy) in the system to promote the reaction in reactor <b>116</b>. In any case, the materials from which the later stage compressor(s) are typically constructed must be able to operate for long periods of time at highly elevated temperatures. It is also noted that first, second, and third compressors, <b>134</b>, <b>142</b>, <b>150</b> are illustrated with progressively smaller impellers <b>180</b>, <b>182</b>, <b>184</b> respectively, to indicate that smaller physical dimensions of these machines may be needed due to higher gas density and to keep up with the peripheral speed of the respective compressor's rotating elements within the tolerances of the materials available for their construction.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Turning to the expansion side of cascading energy recovery system <b>112</b>, in this illustrative embodiment third expansion turbine <b>152</b> expands effluent <b>114</b> to provide sufficient power to drive third compressor <b>150</b> generally without the need for additional power from an associated motor. (While this is true for this embodiment, it is to be understood that other embodiments may indeed include a motor/generator if needed or desired.) As mentioned above, during startup of high-pressure system <b>100</b>, bypass <b>156</b> from downstream of second compressor <b>142</b> may be used to help drive third expansion turbine <b>152</b> along with effluent <b>114</b>. Bypass <b>156</b> may be closed and/or the flow therein may be adjusted via a valve <b>174</b>, e.g., a balancing valve or similar device, that may work in conjunction with one or more other devices (not shown), e.g., a timer, pressure sensor in the bypass, and/or a speed sensor associated with third expansion turbine <b>152</b> or third shaft <b>154</b>, among others. Valve <b>174</b> may work to reduce bootstrap driving of third expansion turbine <b>152</b> as is appropriate as effluent <b>114</b> gains sufficient energy to drive the third expansion turbine.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Effluent <b>114</b> expands and cools through third expansion turbine <b>152</b>. If effluent <b>114</b> contains a vapor, upon cooling some of the vapor may condense, resulting in a third-stage liquid output <b>176</b> and a third-stage vapor output <b>178</b> from third expansion turbine <b>152</b>. In the context of SCWO, third-stage liquid output <b>176</b> will typically be principally water, entrained salts, and precipitants. Third-stage liquid output <b>176</b> may be removed via a liquid removal collector and channel (not shown). In the SCWO context, third-stage vapor output <b>178</b> typically includes simpler compounds produced in reactor <b>116</b> from feedstock <b>130</b>. Due to the expansion through third expansion turbine <b>152</b>, the removed compounds are at a reduced temperature and reduced pressure relative to effluent <b>114</b>. Generally, third-stage vapor output <b>178</b> retains large amounts of energy in the form of elevated temperature and pressure, even with the temperature and pressure drop across third expansion turbine <b>152</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Third-stage vapor output <b>178</b> cascades into second expansion turbine <b>144</b> of second compression and expansion stage <b>126</b>, where it expands and helps drive second compressor <b>142</b>. If the power needed to drive second compressor <b>142</b> is greater than the power provided by second expansion turbine <b>144</b>, second motor/generator <b>148</b> will act as a motor to help drive the second compressor. If, on the other hand, the power needed to drive second compressor <b>142</b> is less than the power provided by second expansion turbine <b>144</b>, second motor/generator <b>148</b> may act as a generator to produce electricity. If the power requirement of second compression <b>142</b> and the power output by second expansion turbine <b>144</b> balance, second motor/generator <b>148</b> may not operate in either a motor or generator capacity. Third-stage vapor output <b>178</b> expands and cools in second expansion turbine <b>144</b> to produce a second-stage vapor output <b>186</b> and, typically, a second-stage liquid output <b>188</b>, which may be removed via a liquid removal collector and channel (not shown). In the SCWO context, second-stage liquid output <b>188</b> may include simpler compounds produced from third-stage vapor output <b>178</b> in second expansion turbine <b>144</b>. By virtue of the expansion through second expansion turbine <b>144</b>, the removed compounds are at a reduced temperature and reduced pressure relative to third-stage vapor output <b>178</b>. Second-stage output vapor <b>180</b> retains large amounts of energy in the form of elevated temperature and pressure, even with the temperature and pressure drop across second expansion turbine <b>144</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Second-stage vapor output <b>186</b> cascades into first expansion turbine <b>136</b> of first compression and expansion stage <b>124</b>, where it expands and helps drive first compressor <b>134</b>. If the power needed to drive first compressor <b>134</b> is greater than the power provided by first expansion turbine <b>136</b>, first motor/generator <b>140</b> will act as a motor to help drive the first compressor. It on the other hand, the power needed to drive first compressor <b>134</b> is less than the power provided by first expansion turbine <b>136</b>, first motor/generator <b>140</b> may act as a generator to produce electricity. If the power required by first compression <b>134</b> and the power output by first expansion turbine <b>136</b> balance, first motor/generator <b>140</b> may not operate in either a motor or generator capacity. First expansion turbine <b>136</b> expands and cools second-stage vapor output <b>186</b> to produce a first-stage output <b>190</b>, which may include vapors and liquid of lower temperature and pressure and suitable for final energy extraction with a heat exchanger (not shown) or for inputting to a separator (not shown) that isolates the components of the effluent for disposal or other use, such as fuel for reactor <b>116</b> or elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an alternative embodiment of a latter compression and expansion stage <b>200</b>, generally a stage located directly upstream or closest to a reactor <b>218</b>, of the present disclosure. Generally, latter compression and expansion stage <b>200</b>, e.g., third compression and expansion stage <b>128</b> in the illustrative embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, may include a latter stage compressor <b>202</b> and an additional compressor <b>204</b> mounted on, e.g., a common shaft <b>206</b> that may also be shared with a respective latter stage expansion turbine <b>208</b>. Additional compressor <b>204</b> may provide additional compression of an input <b>272</b> from a previous stage to stage <b>200</b>, e.g., cooled third-stage input <b>172</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, when required by process requirements. Latter stage expansion turbine <b>208</b> may receive a bootstrap bypass drive stream <b>210</b> from latter stage compressor <b>202</b>. A valve <b>212</b> may be provided for controlling the flow of bypass drive stream <b>210</b> into latter stage expansion turbine <b>208</b>. A heat exchanger <b>214</b> may be included to reduce the temperature of a portion of bypass drive stream <b>210</b> to provide a cooled drive stream <b>216</b> to drive additional compressor <b>204</b>. The heat and energy recovered by heat exchanger <b>214</b> may be used, e.g., to preheat materials supplied to a reactor <b>218</b> or for other purposes in the corresponding system (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As will be appreciated, ally stage of a high-pressure system made in accordance with the present disclosure, such as any one of first, second, and third compression and expansion stages <b>124</b>, <b>126</b>, <b>128</b> of high-pressure system <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, may include multiple compressors in the manner illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, while keeping within the scope and spirit of the present disclosure. Multiple compressors in a stage of such a system may improve that stage's efficiency and reduce mechanical stress on each compressor.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Moreover, it will be appreciated that the use of a multiplicity of turbocharger-type stages to provide a pre-reaction compression process may be desirable for use with other reaction systems that utilize supercritical water oxidation. In any such system the compression arrangement of the present disclosure achieves various beneficial results, such as reduced size of motor/generators needed, elimination of positive displacement equipment, the availability of design methodologies for radial flow compressors and turbines, minimal interfacing with an external electric grid, reduction in size of the compression and energy recovery systems, and simplification of maintenance.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Exemplary embodiments have been disclosed above and illustrated in the accompanying drawings. It will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes, omissions and additions may be made to that which is specifically disclosed herein without departing from the spirit and scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system utilizing an input fluid, comprising:
<claim-text>a continuous reaction reactor for converting an input material using the input fluid so as to produce an effluent having an energy content of a first energy type; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of compression stages, located in series with one another, for compressing the input fluid in a stepwise manner so as to provide a pressurized reactor input stream to said continuous reaction reactor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cascading effluent energy recovery system mechanically communicating with each of said plurality of compression stages, said cascading effluent energy recovery system for imparting a first portion of said energy content of said effluent into each of said plurality of compression stages so as to power that one of said plurality of compression stages; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bootstrap bypass extending from said plurality of compression stages to said cascading effluent energy recovery system so as to bypass said continuous reaction reactor and provide a compressed version of said input fluid directly to said cascading effluent energy recovery system.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of fewer than all of said plurality of compression stages includes an energy converting device for selectively powering that one of said plurality of compression stages during periods of insufficient power from said cascading effluent energy recovery system or converting an excess of said portion of said energy content into a second energy type different from said first energy type during periods of excess power from said cascading effluent energy recovery system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein said energy converting device directly selectively powers said one of said plurality of compression stages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said energy converting device comprises a motor/generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said plurality of compression stages includes a corresponding respective plurality of compressors and said cascading effluent energy recovery system includes a plurality of expansion turbines for respectively driving said plurality of compressors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of fewer than all of said plurality of compression stages includes an energy converting device for selectively powering the corresponding one of said plurality of compressors during periods of insufficient power from the corresponding one of said plurality of expansion turbines or converting an excess of said portion of said energy content into a second energy type different from said first energy type during periods of excess power from the corresponding one of said plurality of expansion turbines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said energy converting device comprises a motor/generator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said plurality of compression stages includes at least three compression stages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a heat exchanger fluidly located between successive ones of said plurality of compression stages, said heat exchanger for removing heat from the input fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said bootstrap bypass includes a valve for controlling flow of said compressed version of said input fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said plurality of compression stages includes a latter stage upstream of said continuous reaction reactor, said latter stage having a latter stage compressor and said cascading effluent energy recovery system having a latter stage expansion turbine for driving said latter stage compressor, said bootstrap bypass extending from a bypass tap in said plurality of compression stages prior to said latter stage to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising a heat exchanger located between said bypass tap and said latter stage compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said plurality of compression stages includes a latter stage immediately upstream of said continuous reaction reactor, said latter stage having first and second latter stage compressors in series with one another, and said cascading effluent energy recovery system having a latter stage expansion turbine for driving said first and second latter stage compressors, said bootstrap bypass extending from a bypass tap in said first latter stage compressor to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further including a valve located in said bootstrap bypass for controlling flow of the input fluid to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said bootstrap bypass includes a heat exchanger having a heat-exchanger input from said first latter stage compressor, said heat exchanger for removing heat from said heat-exchanger input so as to produce a cooled output.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising a secondary line for providing at least a portion of said cooled output to said second latter stage compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said continuous reaction reactor comprises a supercritical water oxidation reactor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A system utilizing an input fluid, comprising:
<claim-text>a reactor for converting a material using the input fluid so as to produce an effluent having an energy content of a first energy type;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first early compression stage comprising:
<claim-text>a first early stage compressor for compressing the input fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first early stage expansion turbine for recovering a first portion of said energy content of said effluent, said first early stage expansion turbine mechanically linked to said first early stage compressor for at least partially driving said first compressor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first motor/generator mechanically linked to each of said first early stage compressor and said first early stage expansion turbine, said first motor/generator selectively powering said first early stage compressor during periods of insufficient power from said first early stage expansion turbine and converting an excess of said energy content into electricity during periods of excess power from said first early stage expansion turbine;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latter compression stage located downstream from said first early compression stage and upstream from said reactor, said latter compression stage comprising:
<claim-text>a latter stage compressor for further compressing the input fluid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latter stage expansion turbine for recovering a second portion of said energy content of said effluent, said latter stage expansion turbine mechanically linked to said latter stage compressor for driving said latter stage compressor; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bootstrap bypass extending from a bypass tap located upstream from said latter stage compressor to said latter stage expansion turbine for providing at least a portion of the input fluid to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein said reactor comprises a continuous self-sustaining chemical process reactor for converting a continuous feed of said input material in a continuous reaction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein said continuous reaction reactor comprises a supercritical water oxidation reactor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein said reactor comprises a pulsed reactor for converting an intermittent feed of the input material in a pulse reaction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein said reactor comprises an internal combustion engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein said reactor comprises a diesel engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further including a second early compression stage located downstream of said first early compression stage and upstream of said latter compression stage, said second early compression stage comprising:
<claim-text>a second early stage compressor for further compressing the input fluid relative to said first compressor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second early stage expansion turbine for recovering a third portion of said energy content of said effluent, said second early stage expansion turbine mechanically linked to said second early stage compressor for at least partially driving said second early stage compressor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second motor/generator mechanically linked to each of said second early stage compressor and said second early stage expansion turbine, said second motor/generator selectively powering said second early stage compressor during periods of insufficient power from said second early stage expansion turbine or converting an excess of said energy content into electricity during periods of excess power from said second early stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further comprising at least one heat exchanger located downstream from said first early stage compressor and upstream from said latter stage compressor, said at least one heat exchanger for removing heat from the input fluid following compression of the input fluid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein said bootstrap bypass including a balancing valve for controlling flow of the input fluid from said bypass tap to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further comprising a heat exchanger located downstream from said bypass tap and upstream from said latter stage compressor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein said latter stage includes an additional compressor in series with said latter stage compressor, said latter stage expansion turbine driving said latter stage compressor and said additional compressor and said bootstrap bypass extending from said bypass tap in said additional compressor to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further including a balancing valve located in said bootstrap bypass upstream from said latter stage expansion turbine for controlling flow of the input fluid to said latter stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. A method of providing a pressurized stream of an input fluid to a continuous reaction reactor so as to produce a non-pulsed effluent having an energy content, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an input fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>compressing said input fluid over a plurality of compression stages so as to produce the pressurized stream;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing the pressurized stream to the continuous reaction reactor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recovering a portion of the energy content of the effluent at each of said plurality of compression stages; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>using each said portion of the energy content in compressing said input fluid at a corresponding respective one of said plurality of compression stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said series of compression stages comprises a latter stage that includes a latter stage expansion turbine for driving a latter stage compressor, the method further comprising bootstrap bypassing at least a portion of said input fluid past said reactor to said latter stage expansion turbine so as to at least partially drive said latter stage compressor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00030">claim 30</claim-ref>, wherein the step of recovering a portion of the energy content of the effluent at each of said plurality of compression stages includes passing at least a portion of the effluent through an expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00031">claim 31</claim-ref>, wherein the step of compressing said input fluid over a plurality of compression stages includes passing said input fluid through a series of compressors, said expansion turbine at each of said plurality of compression stages at least partially driving a corresponding one of said series of compressors.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00030">claim 30</claim-ref>, further comprising a step of supplementing said portion of the energy content of the effluent at each of fewer than all of said plurality of compression stages with additional power for compressing said input fluid or converting an excess of said portion of the energy content into another form of energy.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00033">claim 33</claim-ref>, wherein the step of supplementing or recovering includes, respectively, externally powering an electric motor/generator and driving said motor/generator with said excess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text>35. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00033">claim 33</claim-ref>, wherein the step of recovering a portion of the energy content of the effluent at each of said plurality of compression stages includes passing at least a portion of the effluent through an expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036" num="00036">
<claim-text>36. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00030">claim 30</claim-ref>, further comprising a step of removing heat from said input fluid after one or more of said plurality of compression stages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037" num="00037">
<claim-text>37. A method of providing a pressurized stream of an input fluid to a reactor so as to produce an effluent having an energy content, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving an input fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>compressing said input fluid over a plurality of compression stages so as to produce the pressurized stream;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a first portion of the pressurized stream to a reactor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>bootstrap bypassing the reactor with a second portion of the pressurized stream;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recovering a portion of the energy content of the effluent at each of said plurality of compression stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>using each said portion of the energy content in compressing said input fluid at a corresponding respective one of said plurality of compression stages; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>supplementing said portion of the energy content at at least one of said plurality of compression stages with additional energy to supplement the compressing of said input fluid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said supplementing includes allowing the second portion of the pressurized stream in a latter-stage expansion turbine to expand so as to supplement the compressing of said input fluid in a latter-stage compressor of said plurality of compression stages that is mechanically linked to said latter-stage expansion turbine.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038" num="00038">
<claim-text>38. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein the step of supplementing said portion of the energy content includes using an electric motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039" num="00039">
<claim-text>39. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein the step of providing the pressurized stream to a reactor comprises providing the pressurized stream to a continuous reaction reactor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00040" num="00040">
<claim-text>40. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00039">claim 39</claim-ref>, wherein the step of providing the pressurized stream to a reactor comprises providing the pressurized stream to a supercritical water oxidation reactor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00041" num="00041">
<claim-text>41. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00037">claim 37</claim-ref>, wherein the step of providing the pressurized stream to a reactor comprises providing the pressurized stream to a pulse reaction reactor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00042" num="00042">
<claim-text>42. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00041">claim 41</claim-ref>, wherein the step of providing the pressurized stream to a reactor comprises providing the pressurized stream to an internal combustion engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00043" num="00043">
<claim-text>43. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00042">claim 42</claim-ref>, wherein the step of providing the pressurized stream to a reactor comprises providing the pressurized stream to a diesel engine. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
