<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640736-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640736</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11772251</doc-number>
<date>20070702</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>400</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60473</main-classification>
<further-classification> 60415</further-classification>
<further-classification> 60476</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Self-contained hydraulic actuator system</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3902318</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Becker et al.</name>
<date>19750900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60388</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5144801</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Scanderbeg et al.</name>
<date>19920900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60475</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5181380</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Favre et al.</name>
<date>19930100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60405</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6494039</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Pratt et al.</name>
<date>20021200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60368</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6519939</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Duff</name>
<date>20030200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60473</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60473</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60475</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60415</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60476</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60464</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60478</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60393</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60434</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11186946</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20050722</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7249458</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11772251</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080010984</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080117</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Arbel</last-name>
<first-name>Aviram</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hod Hasharon</city>
<country>IL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>IL</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cohn</last-name>
<first-name>Alexandru</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kiryat Ono</city>
<country>IL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>IL</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Friedman</last-name>
<first-name>Mark M.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ashradan Holdings Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tel Aviv</city>
<country>IL</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kershteyn</last-name>
<first-name>Igor</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The hydraulic linear actuator system of the present invention includes a pump that is configured to rotate in a single direction at a substantially constant velocity. Both the direction and flow rate of fluid through the system is controlled by adjusting the positional relationship between the stator and the rotor of the pump. This positional relationship is adjustable between a forward flow state, a non-flow state and a reverse flow state. The hydraulic linear actuator is responsive to the flow of fluid through the system so as to be displaced in a first direction by the forward flow state of the pump and in a second direction by the reverse flow state of the pump.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="225.81mm" wi="171.28mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="225.72mm" wi="170.43mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="233.00mm" wi="150.71mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="237.15mm" wi="148.59mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="247.73mm" wi="160.61mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="191.52mm" wi="131.15mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="237.74mm" wi="163.41mm" file="US07640736-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="186.52mm" wi="168.74mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640736-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="196.51mm" wi="170.52mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640736-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="240.03mm" wi="167.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640736-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a Continuation-In-Part of, and therefore claims priority from, application Ser. No. 11/186,946 filed 22 Jul. 2005.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD AND BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to self-contained actuator systems and, in particular, it concerns a self-contained hydraulic linear actuator system having a pump, the pumping assembly of which is adjustable so as to control the speed and direction of the fluid flow through the system and a linear actuator responsive to the fluid flow.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Self-contained hydraulic actuator systems having closed hydraulic systems incorporating bi-directional pumps are known in the art. Heretofore, these systems required bi-directional motors to drive the pump. Therefore, the speed and direction of pump rotation, and thus fluid flow through the system, is the direct result of the movement of the motor driving the pump. The motors best suited for this purpose are electrical servomotors, which provide the ability to change speed and direction quickly as required. This is particularly relevant in the field of motion simulation.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">There are a number of drawbacks associated with the use of servomotors to drive bi-directional pumps. One major drawback is that bi-directional servomotors are expensive since they must be built to perform, and withstand the rigors of, substantially instantaneous changes of speed and/or direction numerous times during the performance of a task.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">There is therefore a need for a self-contained hydraulic linear actuator system having a pump, the pumping assembly of which is adjustable so as to control the speed and direction of the fluid flow through the system and a linear actuator responsive to the fluid flow. It would be advantageous if the system included a closed hydraulic system.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention is a self-contained hydraulic linear actuator system having a pump, the pumping assembly of which is adjustable so as to control the speed and direction of the fluid flow through the system and a linear actuator responsive to the fluid flow.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to a further teaching of the present invention, a self-contained hydraulic actuator system comprising; a) a drive motor configured to rotate at a substantially constant velocity; b) a hydraulic pump driven by the drive motor; c) a hydraulic linear actuator in fluid communication with the hydraulic pump so as to be actuated in a first direction by a forward flow state and in a second direction by a reverse flow state; d) a control system associated with the hydraulic pump, the control system configured to control adjustment of the hydraulic pump between the forward flow state, a non-flow state and the reverse flow state, and the control system includes a bi-directional motor such that a speed and direction of the adjustment is affected by the bi-directional motor; and e) a positioning system configures to provide positional information regarding the hydraulic linear actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the hydraulic pump includes a controllably variable pumping assembly such that the adjustments includes a variation of the controllably variable pumping assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the hydraulic pump includes a stator and a rotor deployed within the stator and the variation of the controllably variable pumping assembly includes adjusting the positional relationship between the stator and the rotor.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the hydraulic pump is a vane pump.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the positioning system includes a position feedback system configured to provide position information regarding the hydraulic linear actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the position feedback system includes at least one of an optical encoder and a linear potentiometer associated with the actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the fluid communication between the hydraulic pump and the actuator is via a closed hydraulic system.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">According to a further teaching of the present invention, there is also provided: a) a fluid expansion reservoir; and b) a valve configuration configured so as to maintain fluid communication between the fluid expansion reservoir and a downstream port of the hydraulic pump.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the hydraulic pump is configured with first and second ports, and the first and second ports alternately act as upstream and downstream ports such that when the first port acts as the upstream port the second port acts as the downstream port, and when the first port acts as the downstream port the second port acts as the upstream port, therefore, the valve configuration maintains the fluid communication between the fluid expansion reservoir and one of the first and second ports, dependent on which of the first and second ports is acting as the downstream port.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to a further teaching of the present invention, the fluid expansion reservoir is not vented.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The invention is herein described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side elevation of a preferred embodiment of a self-contained hydraulic linear actuator system constructed and operative according to the teachings of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a top elevation of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken along line A-A, showing the stator adjusted toward the left side of the pump housing;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken along line B-B, showing the stator adjusted toward the left side of the pump housing;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken along line B-B, showing the stator adjusted toward the right side of the pump housing;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is cross-sectional view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> taken along line B-B, showing the stator adjusted to the neutral position;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic of a preferred hydraulic circuit constructed and operative according to the teachings of the present invention, showing the shuttle valve deployed in a fluid supply state;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic of a preferred hydraulic circuit constructed and operative according to the teachings of the present invention, showing the shuttle valve deployed in a fluid reception state; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a block diagram of a preferred embodiment of a control system for the linear actuator constructed and operative according to the teachings of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The present invention is a self-contained hydraulic linear actuator system having a pump, the pumping assembly of which is adjustable so as to control the speed and direction of the fluid flow through the system and a linear actuator responsive to the fluid flow.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The principles and operation of a self-contained hydraulic linear actuator system according to the present invention may be better understood with reference to the drawings and the accompanying description.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">By way of introduction, the hydraulic linear actuator system of the present invention includes a pump that is configured to rotate in a single direction at a substantially constant velocity. Therefore, the drive motor that drives the pump can be a single direction constant velocity motor such as is known in the art, rather than a bi-directional variable speed servomotor. This gives the hydraulic linear actuator system of the present invention a substantial cost advantage over systems that employ a more expensive bi-directional variable speed servomotor.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Both the direction and flow rate of fluid through the system is controlled by adjusting the configuration of the pump, which is adjustable between a forward flow state, a neutral non-flow state and a reverse flow state. The hydraulic linear actuator is responsive to the flow of fluid through the system so as to be displaced in a first direction by the forward flow state of the pump and in a second direction by the reverse flow state of the pump.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">It should be noted that the use of the terms &#x201c;clockwise,&#x201d; &#x201c;counter-clockwise,&#x201d; &#x201c;left&#x201d; and &#x201c;right&#x201d;, are used herein with reference to direction as seen in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring now to the drawings, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> illustrate side and top elevations, respectively, of the exterior of a preferred embodiment of the hydraulic linear actuator system <b>2</b> of the present invention. Seen here are the drive motor <b>4</b>, the stepper motor housing <b>6</b> that houses the stepper motor that affects adjustment of the configuration of the pump, as will be discussed below, the linear actuator <b>8</b>, and the pump <b>20</b>. Attached to the pump <b>20</b> is the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b>, which will be discussed below.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The drive motor is preferably an AC electric motor. However, it should be noted that substantially any drive device such as, but not limited to, DC electric motors, and internal combustion engines, may be used to drive the pump.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The linear actuator <b>8</b> may be a hydraulic cylinder and piston actuator, as is illustrated herein, in which the actuator cylinder <b>10</b> is rigidly attached to the pump <b>20</b> via the actuator attachment extension <b>12</b> of the pump <b>20</b> that is configured with fluid passageways which provide fluid communication between the pump <b>20</b> and the actuator cylinder <b>10</b>. It will be appreciated that the actuator <b>8</b> need not be attached to the pump <b>20</b> and that fluid communication may be provided by substantially any method known in the art such as, but not limited to, hoses, tubes, pipes, and any other suitable fluid conduit. It will also be appreciated that substantially any hydraulically driven device may be associated with the pump <b>20</b> of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In a preferred embodiment described herein, the pump <b>20</b> illustrated is a rotary vane pump configured with a controllably variable pumping assembly. It should be noted, however, that the principles of the present invention may be applied to equal advantage to piston pumps as well. As seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-6</figref> the variable pumping assembly, which is deployed within the pump housing <b>22</b>, includes a displaceable stator <b>24</b> and a rotor <b>26</b> with a plurality of vanes <b>28</b> deployed within the stator <b>24</b>. The stator <b>24</b> is configured so as to pivot about the pivot shaft <b>30</b>, while the rotor <b>26</b> rotates in a static position. Therefore, the positional relationship between the stator <b>24</b> and the rotor <b>26</b> may be adjusted. As the positional relationship between the stator <b>24</b> and the rotor <b>26</b> is adjusted, the position of the working pump volume <b>32</b> within the stator <b>24</b> is varied, as is illustrated clearly in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-6</figref>. This also varies the positional relationship of the working pump volume <b>32</b> to the inlet/outlet ports <b>34</b> and <b>36</b>. The ports <b>34</b> and <b>36</b> are referred to herein as inlet/outlet ports because their role changes with the direction of fluid flow through the pump. With regard to the discussion herein, the rotor is considered to be rotating in a clockwise direction (see arrow <b>38</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the stator <b>24</b> is displaced to the far left and the majority of the working pump volume <b>32</b> is to the left of the rotor <b>26</b>. Therefore, fluid is drawn into the working pump volume <b>32</b> during an expansion stroke, through inlet/outlet port <b>36</b>, which is now acting as the inlet port. As pump comes to an exhaust stroke the fluid is forced out of the working pump volume <b>32</b> through inlet/outlet port <b>34</b>, which is now acting as the outlet port.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the stator <b>24</b> is substantially centrally deployed and the working pump volume <b>32</b> is substantially evenly distributed around the rotor <b>26</b>. Therefore, there are neither expansion nor exhaust strokes and substantially no fluid is drawn in, or forced out, of the working pump volume <b>32</b> through either of the inlet/outlet ports <b>34</b> and <b>36</b>. In this &#x201c;neutral&#x201d; position, a non-flow state is achieved within the hydraulic system.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the stator <b>24</b> is displaced to the far right and the majority of the working pump volume <b>32</b> is to the right of the rotor <b>26</b>. Therefore, fluid is drawn into the working pump volume <b>32</b> during an expansion stroke, through inlet/outlet port <b>34</b>, which is now acting as the inlet port. As pump comes to an exhaust stroke the fluid is forced out of the working pump volume <b>32</b> through inlet/outlet port <b>36</b>, which is now acting as the outlet port.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Thusly configured, the speed and direction of fluid flow through the pump <b>20</b>, and therefore through the system, is controlled by adjusting the positional relationship between the stator <b>24</b> and the rotor <b>26</b>. Due to the location of the inlet/outlet ports, when the stator <b>24</b> is positioned in a central, &#x201c;neutral&#x201d; position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), a non-flow state is achieved within the hydraulic system. As the stator <b>24</b> is displaced away from the neutral position in a first direction, for example to the left (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>), a forward flow state is achieved. As the stator <b>24</b> is displaced away from the neutral position in a second direction, for example to the right (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>), a reverse flow state is achieved. It will be appreciated that the further away from the neutral position the stator is displaced, the more fluid will be moved though the pump <b>20</b>. The amount of fluid moving through the pump affects the speed and distance of actuator displacement. It will be understood that direction of rotor rotation, and which direction of fluid flow is considered to forward and reverse flow states are considered to be design considerations, and examples used herein are not to be considered as limitations.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Adjustment of the position of stator <b>24</b> is affected by a bi-directional stepper motor (not shown here) that is housed within the stepper motor housing <b>6</b> and controlled by a control system that includes the position controller <b>64</b>. The stepper motor drives spur <b>60</b>, which interacts with spur gear section <b>62</b> that extends from the stator <b>24</b>. Configured thus, speed and direction of rotation of the stepper motor affects the speed and direction of stator <b>24</b> displacement. As illustrated herein, rotation of the stepper motor in a clockwise direction will displace the stator <b>24</b> to the left and counter-clockwise rotation will displace the stator <b>24</b> to the right. It will be appreciated that while the preferred embodiment of the present invention described herein refers to the use of a stepper motor to adjust the position of stator <b>24</b>, this is not intended as a limitation to the scope of the present invention. Therefore, variant embodiments in which adjustment of the position of stator <b>24</b> is directly affected by another drive device such as, but not limited to, a bi-directional motor, or a unidirectional motor in conjunction with a direction changeable gear train.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The speed and rotational direction of the stepper motor is controlled by the position controller <b>64</b> as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>. In this embodiment of the present invention, when the position controller receives a command to bring the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b> to a desired position, the current position of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b> is determined based on feedback from the feedback system that includes the optical encoder <b>70</b>, which is associated with the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>. It should be noted that feedback regarding the position of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b> may be supplied by a linear potentiometer in instead of, or in addition to, the optical encoder. Based on the current position of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b> and the speed at which the change of position is to be affected, the rotational direction and number of steps the stepper motor <b>66</b> must take, and the rate at which the step must be taken is determined. The pulse generator included in the stepper motor driver <b>68</b> then delivers the appropriate pulses, at the appropriate rate, thereby causing the stepper motor <b>66</b> to turn the necessary amount in order to bring the stator <b>24</b> to the required position to affect the desired position of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>. It will be appreciated that in embodiments of the present invention which have remote actuators, that is, actuators that are not directly attached to the pump <b>20</b>, the control system may be configured with COM ports to provide external connection access to the control system.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It is noteworthy that, unlike systems of prior art that utilize stepper motors and track position bases on the number and direction of step taken, the present invention uses the features of the stepper motor <b>66</b> solely for the purpose of controlling the direction and amount of stator <b>24</b> displacement and the speed at which the displacement occurs. The position of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b> is monitored by a positioning system that includes the encoder <b>66</b> which provides position feedback to the position controller <b>64</b>. This provides a more accurate indication of the true position of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>, since the rotation of the stepper motor <b>66</b> is not directly related to the displacement of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>. Rather, rotation of the stepper motor <b>66</b> is directly related to the position of the stator <b>24</b> which in turn affect displacement of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">It will be appreciated that the use of a hydraulic cylinder and piston actuator in a closed hydraulic system present the problem of the volume differential between the two sides of the piston since the one side includes the actuator rod <b>14</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>). One way to solve this problem is the inclusion of a fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b> and a valve <b>42</b> to control the flow of fluid into and out of the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b>. Another solution could include configuring the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b> with two actuator rods <b>14</b>, one extending to each side of the piston, thereby effectively eliminating the volume differential between the two sides.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As described above, the direction of fluid flow through the hydraulic pump of the present invention is controlled by displacement of the stator <b>24</b>. Therefore, as illustrated in the schematic views of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>, the inlet and outlet ports of the pump <b>20</b> alternately act as upstream and downstream ports such that when the first port <b>44</b> acts as the upstream port the second port <b>46</b> acts as the downstream port, and when the first port <b>44</b> acts as the downstream port the second port <b>46</b> acts as the upstream port. Therefore, the valve <b>42</b>, preferably a shuttle valve as illustrated herein, maintains fluid communication between the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b> and which ever of the first <b>44</b> and second <b>46</b> ports is acting as the downstream port at the time. That is, the valve <b>42</b> is configured to respond to a pressure differential within the hydraulic system and maintains fluid communication between the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b> and the low-pressure side of the pump <b>20</b>. It should be noted the while the valve <b>42</b> is preferably a shuttle valve, the use of any suitable valve configuration is within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates the fluid flow during an expansion stroke of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>. As mentioned above, the amount of fluid displaced from the cylinder on this side of the piston is insufficient to fill the hydraulic volume of the cylinder on the other side of the piston. Therefore, the shuttle valve <b>42</b> is positioned to allow fluid to flow from the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b> into the main flow stream <b>48</b> of the hydraulic circuit, on the downstream side of the pump <b>20</b>. In this case, port <b>44</b> is acting as the downstream port.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates the fluid flow during a retraction stroke of the hydraulic linear actuator <b>8</b>. Here, the amount of fluid displaced from the cylinder is more than is required to fill the hydraulic volume of the cylinder on the other side of the piston. Therefore, the shuttle valve <b>42</b> is positioned to allow fluid to flow from the main flow stream <b>48</b> of the hydraulic circuit into the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b>, on the downstream side of the pump <b>20</b>. In this case, port <b>46</b> is acting as the downstream port.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">It will be appreciated that in a preferred embodiment of the present invention, the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b> is closed, that is, not vented, thereby maintaining the hydraulic system as a closed system. Optionally, the fluid expansion reservoir <b>40</b> may be pressurized, preferably to a pressure of 2 atmospheres.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Another optional feature of the present invention is the deployment of a flywheel <b>80</b> associated with the drive motor <b>4</b> as is known in the art when using a device that rotates in a single direction at a substantially constant velocity. This provides the system of the present invention a distinct energy usage advantage over systems using bi-directional drive motors in which a flywheel would be counter productive.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">It will be appreciated that the above descriptions are intended only to serve as examples and that many other embodiments are possible within the spirit and the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A self-contained hydraulic actuator system comprising;
<claim-text>(a) a drive motor configured to rotate at a substantially constant velocity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a hydraulic pump driven by said drive motor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) a hydraulic linear actuator in fluid communication with said hydraulic pump so as to be actuated in a first direction by a forward flow state and in a second direction by a reverse flow state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a control system associated with said hydraulic pump, said control system configured to control adjustment of said hydraulic pump between said forward flow state, a non-flow state and said reverse flow state, and said control system includes a bi-directional motor such that a speed and direction of said adjustment is affected by said bi-directional motor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(e) a positioning system configures to provide positional information regarding said hydraulic linear actuator.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said hydraulic pump includes a controllably variable pumping assembly such that said adjustments includes a variation of said controllably variable pumping assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said hydraulic pump includes a stator and a rotor deployed within said stator and said variation of said controllably variable pumping assembly includes adjusting a positional relationship between said stator and said rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said hydraulic pump is a vane pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said positioning system includes a position feedback system configured to provide position information regarding said hydraulic linear actuator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said position feedback system includes at least one of an optical encoder and a linear potentiometer associated with said actuator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said fluid communication between said hydraulic pump and said actuator is via a closed hydraulic system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The self-contained hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further including:
<claim-text>(a) a fluid expansion reservoir; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a valve configuration configured so as to maintain fluid communication between said fluid expansion reservoir and a downstream port of said hydraulic pump.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said hydraulic pump is configured with first and second ports, and said first and second ports alternately act as upstream and downstream ports such that when said first port acts as said upstream port said second port acts as said downstream port, and when said first port acts as said downstream port said second port acts as said upstream port, therefore, said valve configuration maintains said fluid communication between said fluid expansion reservoir and one of said first and second ports, dependent on which of said first and second ports is acting as said downstream port.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The hydraulic actuator system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said fluid expansion reservoir is not vented.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
