<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640923-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640923</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12327086</doc-number>
<date>20081203</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>11</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>124 32</main-classification>
<further-classification>124 73</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Hidden sensor structure for paintball gun</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6966313</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Yokota et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>124 32</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7461646</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Jones</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>124 77</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0221684</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rice</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>124 71</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0107938</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Rice</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>124 73</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0209650</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Jones</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>124 73</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0078370</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kaakkola et al.</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>124 73</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>124 32</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Yi-Tsong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tainan</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>WPAT, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>King</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yeh</last-name>
<first-name>Hsin-Cheng</first-name>
<role>05</role>
<address>
<city>Tainan Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chambers</last-name>
<first-name>Troy</first-name>
<department>3641</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Tillman, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Reginald</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun is to secure a loader unit on a hopper of a barrel. A loader is used to hold against the loader unit. The loader unit has arcuate slots to receive resilient stoppers therein, with studs protruding from the resilient stoppers to extend into the hopper. A sensor has an emission end, a receiving end, and a socket. The sensor is coupled to the loader unit from the bottom of the barrel, with the emission end and the receiving end inserting into two troughs formed on two sides of the load unit and the socket engaging with a fixture of the loader unit.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="170.35mm" wi="169.25mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="230.97mm" wi="174.58mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="183.64mm" wi="181.53mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="199.31mm" wi="143.26mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="265.51mm" wi="101.94mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="184.07mm" wi="174.58mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="215.39mm" wi="176.02mm" file="US07640923-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, and more particularly to a sensor hidden in a paintball gun to have a unity appearance.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In recent years, a paintball gun has becoming a very popular leisure game to youngsters. In order to save the high pressurized air and stop the paintballs left in a loader from wasting, a sensor and a stopper are adapted, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. A barrel A has a pair of troughs A<b>1</b> at two sides thereof, an insertion hole A<b>2</b> and a receiving hole A<b>3</b> thereat. The insertion hole A<b>2</b> is adapted for a sensor B to be inserted therein. The receiving hole A<b>3</b> is adapted to receive a nut A<b>4</b>, a ball A<b>5</b> and a spring A<b>6</b> therein in sequence and sealed with a cap C into the trough A<b>1</b>. The cap C is secured through a bolt C<b>1</b> to the barrel A. The sensor B is covered by the cap C and is urged by the spring A<b>6</b>. The nut A<b>4</b> restraints the ball A<b>5</b> in the receiving hole A<b>3</b>. The inner diameter of the receiving hole A<b>3</b> is smaller than the outer diameter of the ball A<b>5</b> so that the ball A<b>5</b> is urged by the spring A<b>6</b> to move within the receiving hole A<b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, the above-mentioned structure has a number of shortcomings.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">1. The sensor is preset in the barrel and inserted into the insertion hole by means of the bolt to secure the cap. This design is not convenient to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">2. The trough for the cap to be secured remains a gap which may gather dust therein.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">3. The trough on the barrel affects the unity appearance of the gun.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention is to provide a hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun. In particular, a sensor is installed in a barrel to make the gun in a unity design.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to the present invention, there is provided a hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, comprising a sensor, a loader unit, and a barrel, said barrel being adapted for said loader unit and a loader to seat therein; said sensor comprising an emission end, a corresponding receiving end, and a socket, said socket having an insertion hole at a central portion thereof; said loader unit comprising a pair of troughs at two sides thereof for receiving said emission end and said receiving end therein, a first through hole for said emission end and said receiving end to communicate with each other, and a fixture protruding from a lower end thereof for said socket of said sensor to seat thereon, said fixture having a threaded hole at a central portion thereof; said barrel having a hopper at an upper end thereof for said loader unit to seat thereon and recesses formed on an inner wall thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Preferably, said loader unit is a hollow cylinder corresponding to said hopper of said barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, said loader unit further has a pair of arcuate slots above said troughs.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, one end of each said arcuate slot is formed with a second through hole.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Preferably, said loader unit further comprises a pair of resilient stoppers to be inserted into said arcuate slots.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Preferably, each said resilient stopper has a stud protruding from an inner side thereof, said stud extending through said second through hole into said hopper of said barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Preferably, the barrel has the hopper on top of the barrel for the loader unit and the loader to be seated thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Preferably, the recesses formed on the inner wall of the barrel correspond in position to the resilient stoppers of the loader unit, and are adapted for the studs to be inserted therein.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The present invention has the following advantages.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0019">1. The sensor is coupled to the load unit from the bottom of the barrel such that the sensor is hidden in the barrel to form a unity appearance.</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0020">2. The loader unit is sealed in the barrel without necessary of another lid to cover.</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0021">3. There is no lid or threaded fasteners on the barrel, preventing dust from entering.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded view of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side cross-sectional view of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view taken along line A-A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a top cross-sectional view showing a loader unit of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the present invention in conjunction with a loader and a gun handle; and</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an exploded view of the prior art.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun of the present invention comprises a sensor <b>1</b>, a loader unit <b>2</b>, and a barrel <b>3</b>. The barrel <b>3</b> has a hopper <b>31</b> for the loader unit <b>2</b> along with a loader <b>4</b> to seat thereon. The loader <b>4</b> engages with the loader unit <b>2</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0029">The sensor <b>1</b> comprises an emission end <b>11</b>, a receiving end <b>12</b> corresponding to the emission end <b>11</b>, and a socket <b>13</b>. The socket <b>13</b> has an insertion hole <b>14</b> at a central portion thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0030">The loader unit <b>2</b> is a hollow cylinder corresponding to the hopper <b>31</b> of the barrel <b>3</b>. The loader unit <b>2</b> has a pair of troughs <b>21</b> formed on two sides thereof to receive the emission end <b>11</b> and the receiving end <b>12</b> therein, a first through hole <b>211</b> for the emission end <b>11</b> and the receiving end <b>12</b> to communicate with each other, and a fixture <b>22</b> protruding from the bottom of the loader unit <b>2</b> for the socket <b>13</b> to seat and secure thereat. The fixture <b>22</b> has a threaded hole <b>221</b> at a central portion for locking. The loader unit <b>2</b> further has a pair of arcuate slots <b>23</b> above the pair of troughs <b>21</b> to receive a pair of resilient stoppers <b>24</b> therein. One end of the arcuate slot <b>23</b> is formed with a second through hole <b>231</b> for a stud <b>241</b> protruding from an inner side of the resilient stopper <b>24</b> to extend therethrough into the hopper <b>31</b> of the barrel <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0031">The hopper <b>31</b> is formed at the top of the barrel <b>3</b> for the loader unit <b>2</b> and the loader <b>4</b> to seat and secure thereat. A pair of recesses <b>32</b> are formed on an inner wall of the hoper <b>31</b>, corresponding in position to the studs <b>241</b> of the resilient stoppers <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0032">To assemble the present invention, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>3</b>, and <b>4</b>, the resilient stoppers <b>24</b> are inserted into the arcuate slots <b>23</b> of the loader unit <b>2</b> with the studs <b>241</b> extending into the second through holes <b>231</b>. The loader unit <b>2</b> is placed in the hopper <b>31</b> of the barrel <b>3</b>. The resilient stoppers <b>24</b> are confined to the inner wall of the barrel <b>3</b>. The loader <b>4</b> is placed on top of the loader unit <b>2</b> for providing a pressure against the loader unit <b>2</b> to prevent the loader unit <b>2</b> from disengagement, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The studs <b>241</b> are extended into the hollow cylinder of the loader unit <b>2</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, for stopping paintballs. The sensor <b>1</b> is coupled to the loader unit <b>2</b> from the bottom of the barrel <b>3</b>, with the emission end <b>11</b> and the receiving end <b>12</b> inserting into the troughs <b>21</b> and the socket <b>13</b> engaging with the fixture <b>22</b>. Thus the sensor <b>1</b> is hidden in the barrel <b>3</b> securely without a fastener.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0033">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the present invention is in conjunction with the loader <b>4</b> and a gun handle <b>5</b>. The loader <b>4</b> is disposed on top of the loader unit <b>2</b>. A fastener <b>51</b> is inserted into the threaded hole <b>221</b> of the fixture <b>22</b> such that the loader unit <b>2</b> is secured to the handle <b>5</b> and the handle <b>5</b> is located immediately underneath the barrel <b>3</b>.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, comprising a sensor, a loader unit, and a barrel, said barrel being adapted for said loader unit and a loader to seat therein;
<claim-text>said sensor comprising an emission end, a corresponding receiving end, and a socket, said socket having an insertion hole at a central portion thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said loader unit comprising a pair of troughs at two sides thereof for receiving said emission end and said receiving end therein, a first through hole for said emission end and said receiving end to communicate with each other, and a fixture protruding from a lower end thereof for said socket of said sensor to seat thereon, said fixture having a threaded hole at a central portion thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said barrel having a hopper at an upper end thereof for said loader unit to seat thereon and recesses formed on an inner wall thereof.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said loader unit is a hollow cylinder corresponding to said hopper of said barrel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said loader unit further has a pair of arcuate slots above said troughs.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein one end of each said arcuate slot is formed with a second through hole.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said loader unit further comprises a pair of resilient stoppers to be inserted into said arcuate slots.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The hidden sensor structure for a paintball gun, as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein each said resilient stopper has a stud protruding from an inner side thereof, said stud extending through said second through hole into said hopper of said barrel. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
