<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640946-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640946</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10544708</doc-number>
<date>20040206</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>10</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-029895</doc-number>
<date>20030206</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>422</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>17</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137571</main-classification>
<further-classification>414217</further-classification>
<further-classification>141  8</further-classification>
<further-classification>141 65</further-classification>
<further-classification>141 98</further-classification>
<further-classification>118715</further-classification>
<further-classification>438758</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Vacuum treating device with lidded treatment container</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4268275</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chittick</name>
<date>19810500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 48111</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5791830</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fort et al.</name>
<date>19980800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>406151</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6009667</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Mizukami</name>
<date>20000100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6048782</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Moslehi</name>
<date>20000400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438565</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6565662</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Amano et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>61-138238</doc-number>
<date>19860800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-299900</doc-number>
<date>19981100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>11-101345</doc-number>
<date>19990400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-317296</doc-number>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-185534</doc-number>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-335941</doc-number>
<date>20011200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-134383</doc-number>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-100697</doc-number>
<date>20030400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-197613</doc-number>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>414217</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>141  8</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>141 65</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>141 98</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438758</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137571</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>118715</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060099053</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060511</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Saito</last-name>
<first-name>Tetsuya</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yamanashi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oblon, Spivak, McClelland, Maier &#x26; Neustadt, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tokyo Electron Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lowe</last-name>
<first-name>Michael S</first-name>
<department>3652</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2004/001253</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20040206</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20050805</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2004/070814</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20040819</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A vacuum treating device, comprising a treatment container having a container body (<b>111</b>) and a lid (<b>112</b>) and allowing an internal pressure to be reduced and a lid support mechanism (<b>130</b>), wherein an upper opening (<b>111</b><i>a</i>) formed in the container body can be closed airtight by the lid (<b>112</b>). The lid support mechanism (<b>130</b>) opens and closes the upper opening (<b>111</b><i>a</i>) of the container body by moving the lid (<b>112</b>) so as to be translatingly moved in the vertical direction and, when the lid (<b>112</b>) is moved upward from the container body (<b>111</b>), supports the lid (<b>112</b>) so as to be rotated around a vertical axis disposed around the lid.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="176.70mm" wi="156.04mm" file="US07640946-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="205.74mm" wi="156.63mm" file="US07640946-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="233.43mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US07640946-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="217.42mm" wi="87.97mm" file="US07640946-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="190.16mm" wi="152.57mm" file="US07640946-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a vacuum processing apparatus having a lid-attached processing vessel for use in a film forming process of, e.g., semiconductor substrate.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Conventionally, a vacuum processing apparatus has been used for performing on a semiconductor substrate, an LCD substrate or the like, various processes such as film forming process, etching, ashing, heat treatment and the like, under a depressurized atmosphere. In such an apparatus, a processing vessel for performing vacuum processing includes a vessel main body having an upper opening, and a lid attached to the vessel main body to be opened or closed. Further, as for this kind of apparatus, it has been known that a lid is rotatably attached to the vessel main body around the horizontal axis line through a hinge or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">For example, an opening/closing lid hinge mechanism of a vacuum processor has been known, wherein a gear mechanism is configured to open or close a lid around a horizontal axis line along a longitudinally elongated elliptic path (for example, see Japanese Patent Laid-open application No. H11-101345 (particularly, FIG. 2)). By this mechanism, the lid can be opened or closed without being overhung at the outside of the vessel main body.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Further, a vacuum processor including a slide mechanism for horizontally sliding a lid and a rotation mechanism for rotating the lid around the horizontal axis line has been known (for example, see Japanese Patent Laid-open Application No. 2001-185534 (particularly FIG. 6)). By using this mechanism, maintenance becomes easier, and at the same time, attaching or detaching a heavy object to or from the lid can be readily carried out.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, in the former technology, a complicated mechanism needs to be provided to track the longitudinally elongated elliptic path during the opening or closing operation. Further, multiple or large-scale mechanism(s) need to be disposed around the lid to perform the sliding or rotational operation. Accordingly, the processor becomes expensive and large sized.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Still further, in these technologies, since the lid is rotated around the horizontal axis line to fully open the vessel main body, such a configuration cannot be adopted that a part of the processor (e.g., source material supply system) is disposed above the lid. As a result, not only is the foot print of the processor increased, the capability to maintain it is also undermined.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Still further, recently, there is a demand for a vacuum processing apparatus, wherein a source gas is produced by vaporizing a liquid source material or sublimating a solid source material, and is then supplied into a processing vessel. In this kind of apparatus, the conductance of a line provided between the source material vessel and the processing vessel has to be increased to ensure a supply amount of source gas, or to smoothly supply the source gas into the processing vessel. For this, the line provided between the source material vessel and the processing vessel must have a large diameter and short in length. However, in the configuration of the conventional apparatus, the line provided between the source material vessel and the processing vessel could not be made short.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, in the aforementioned technologies, since the lid is rotated around the horizontal axis line, if the source material vessel is fixed on the lid, the source material vessel will be tilted and thus, the source material accommodated therein is also tilted and cause other changes on the source material. Accordingly, a proper supply amount of source material cannot be achieved.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">It is, therefore, an object of the present invention to provide a vacuum processing apparatus of simple configuration that can be configured at low cost, wherein other component part, such as source material supply system and the like, may be disposed above the lid.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Further, it is an object of the present invention to provide a vacuum processing apparatus capable of having a short pipeline distance between a source material vessel and a processing vessel.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Still further, it is an object of the present invention to provide a vacuum processing apparatus capable of realizing such a configuration where the state of source material is not changed by opening or closing of the lid.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention for achieving the aforementioned objects, there is provided a vacuum processing apparatus including: a processing vessel whose inside can be depressurized, the processing vessel including a vessel main body having an upper opening and a lid for airtightly closing the upper opening of the vessel main body; and a lid support mechanism for opening or closing the upper opening of the vessel main body by moving the lid, wherein the lid support mechanism allows the lid to be translated in a vertical direction, and to be rotated around a vertical axis line disposed at a peripheral position of the lid when the lid is elevated from the vessel main body.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In this way, the lid is translated upward and then rotated around the vertical axis line, to thereby be dislocated from the vessel main body. Therefore, the upper opening of the vessel main body can be opened. Here, since the lid is translated upward and then rotated around the vertical axis line, other component part may be disposed at a position above the lid, which was dead space conventionally. Further, the lid support mechanism may be formed of supporting structure, which is installed coaxially on the vertical axis line, so that the configuration thereof need not be complicated and large sized. Still further, since the processing vessel can be opened while maintaining the lid's orientation at horizontal position, the source material therein may not be affected when the processing vessel is opened, even in case where the source material vessel is fixed on the lid.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Meanwhile, same as in the conventional art, if the lid is opened around the horizontal axis line, it is largely rotated upward, and thus, it being tilted or reversed. For the same reason, it is impossible to dispose a part of the processor above the lid, or to fix the source material vessel on the lid.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Further, it can be configured such that if the lid is not elevated at a predetermined height, it is not allowed to rotate. By doing this, the vessel main body or the lid can be prevented from being damaged due to erroneous manipulation.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In the present invention, the lid support mechanism may be configured to maintain the lid at a predetermined height while the lid is rotated. By doing this, a height-maintaining operation of the lid becomes unnecessary during the rotation thereof, so that it is possible to carry out the rotating operation safely and more readily.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the present invention, the lid support mechanism may have a supporting member for supporting the lid directly or indirectly, wherein the supporting member is extended substantially horizontally above the lid from the vicinity of the vertical axis line. Therefore, it is possible to maintain the pose or position of the lid with high accuracy.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">In the present invention, a lifting unit for upwardly lifting the lid may be further included. By using this, in case of elevating the lid, it is possible to carry out such an elevating operation with small force, and thus, more easily.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In the present invention, a source material vessel, disposed above the lid, for accommodating therein a source material supplied into the processing vessel may be further included. In this way, the pipeline distance between the source material vessel and the processing vessel can be short, and at the same time, the diameter of line can be large without increasing the foot print. Thus, the conductance of line between the source material vessel and the processing vessel can be large. For the same reason, in case where the source gas obtained by vaporizing the liquid source material or sublimating the solid source material is supplied into the processing vessel, the amount of source gas to be supplied can be ensured sufficiently. Further, the source gas can be prevented from being changed while supplying it, so that high quality processing can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In the present invention, it is preferred that the source material vessel is immovably disposed with respect to the lid. By doing this, for example, the supply line between the source material vessel and the lid can be configured to be fixed, and therefore, the apparatus may have more simple configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Further, a source material supply line for supplying a source material from an upper portion of the lid into the processing vessel through the lid may be included. By using this, the lid is maintained at the horizontal position during the opening or closing operation thereof, so that the source material supply line may be connected to the lid without causing any problems. Hence, the source material supply line may be fixed to the lid, and further, the position thereof is not changed.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In this case, a gas supply line extended through the lid to the upper portion thereof and connected to the source material supply line may be further included.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Further, the vacuum processing apparatus may include any apparatus, which performs any processings at the state where the processing vessel is depressurized. For example, film forming apparatus such as CVD, etching apparatus such as dry etching, ashing apparatus such as plasma asher, heat treating device such as annealing furnace, etc., may be enumerated.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> offers a schematic view showing a preferred embodiment of a vacuum processing apparatus in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> provides a plane perspective view of the apparatus described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross sectional view showing main parts of an opening/closing supporting unit in the apparatus described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> presents a perspective view schematically showing line configuration of the apparatus described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A Preferred embodiment of a vacuum processing apparatus in accordance with the present invention will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view showing an overall configuration of a vacuum processing apparatus <b>100</b> in accordance with the present embodiment. The vacuum processing apparatus <b>100</b> includes a processing vessel <b>110</b>, a source material supply system <b>120</b>, a lid support mechanism <b>130</b> and a gas exhaust system <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The processing vessel <b>110</b> contains a vessel main body <b>111</b> having an upper opening <b>111</b><i>a, </i>and a lid <b>112</b> for hermetically closing the upper opening <b>111</b><i>a </i>of the vessel main body <b>111</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Further, in the vessel main body <b>111</b>, a processing table <b>113</b> for supporting thereon an object to be processed, such as semiconductor wafer or the like (not shown), is disposed. A source material discharging head (shower head) for discharging a source material (source gas) into the processing vessel <b>110</b> is installed at a bottom surface of the lid <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The source material supply system <b>120</b> is disposed above the lid <b>112</b>. The source material supply system <b>120</b> includes a source material supply box <b>121</b> having a source material vessel <b>122</b> accommodating therein a source material (liquid or solid in the present embodiment) and a source material supply line <b>123</b> for supplying a source material (source gas in the present embodiment), which is connected to the source material vessel <b>122</b>. Further, a control unit <b>120</b>A for controlling the source material supply status may be installed in the source material supply system <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The source material supply line <b>123</b> is connected to a discharging head <b>112</b>A through the lid <b>112</b>. A source material replacement valve <b>123</b><i>a </i>and a source material supply valve <b>123</b><i>b </i>are provided in the source material supply line <b>123</b>. Further, a gas discharge line <b>124</b> is connected to the source material supply line <b>123</b>. A discharge valve <b>124</b><i>a </i>is installed in the gas discharge line <b>124</b>. The gas discharge line <b>124</b> penetrates the lid <b>112</b> and the vessel main body <b>111</b> to communicate with the outside of the vessel main body <b>111</b>. Further, one or more gas supply line(s) <b>125</b> is (are) connected to the source material supply line <b>123</b>. A gas supply valve <b>125</b><i>a </i>is installed in the gas supply line <b>125</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The gas supply line <b>125</b> involves supplying carrier gas or cleaning gas for cleaning each line or processing vessel. As schematically shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the gas supply line <b>125</b> is introduced from the outside into the vessel main body <b>111</b>, and penetrates the lid <b>112</b> to be introduced into the source material supply box <b>121</b>, to thereby be connected to the source material supply line <b>123</b>. Further, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the lid support mechanism <b>130</b> and others as well as valves of respective lines are properly omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Returning again to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a lid support member <b>131</b> is disposed above the lid <b>112</b>. The lid support member <b>131</b> supports the lid <b>112</b> directly or indirectly. The lid support member <b>131</b> is connected to a driving member <b>132</b>, which is rotatably supported with respect to a shaft <b>133</b> inserted therein. More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a bearing <b>132</b><i>a, </i>e.g., cross roller bearing or the like, is interposed between the driving member <b>132</b> and the shaft <b>133</b>, and the driving member <b>132</b> is configured to be fixed along the direction of axis line while it is to be rotated around the axis line, with respect to the shaft <b>133</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The axis line (vertical axis line) of the shaft <b>133</b> is disposed at a peripheral position of the lid <b>112</b> (position other than the center), e.g., right outside the lid <b>112</b> in the present embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The shaft <b>133</b> is elevatably supported with respect to a fixed member <b>134</b> fixed on the vessel main body <b>111</b>. To be more specific, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the fixed member <b>134</b> has a guide unit <b>134</b><i>a, </i>e.g., ball spline or the like, for fixing the shaft <b>133</b> so that it can be moved along the direction of the axis line but cannot be rotated around the axis line.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As mentioned above, the lid support mechanism <b>130</b> allows the lid <b>112</b> to be translated in the normal direction to the vessel main body <b>111</b>, and be rotated around the vertical axis line disposed at the peripheral position of the lid <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">At a lower portion of the fixed member <b>134</b>, a lifting unit <b>135</b> for upwardly moving the shaft <b>133</b> is installed. As described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the lifting unit <b>135</b> applies lifting force to the shaft <b>133</b> by using a resilient member <b>135</b><i>a, </i>e.g., constant force spring or the like. Further, the lid <b>112</b> is configured to be readily elevated by the lifting unit <b>135</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In the present embodiment, the source material supply box <b>121</b> is upwardly supported by the lid support member <b>131</b>. Further, the lid <b>112</b> is supported by brackets <b>138</b> attached to the source material supply box <b>121</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates such a state in detail. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a top view of the vacuum processing apparatus <b>100</b>, and at the same time, perspective views of the source material supply box <b>121</b> and the lid <b>112</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> basically shows a state where the vessel main body <b>111</b> is closed by the lid <b>112</b>; and at the same time, it shows as a dashed double-dotted line a state where the lid <b>112</b> is opened (rotated state).</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Here, plural (three in the drawing) brackets <b>138</b> are provided to support the lid <b>112</b>, which is suspended from the source material supply box <b>121</b>. As mentioned above, in this embodiment, the lid support member <b>131</b> indirectly supports the lid <b>112</b> through the source material supply box <b>121</b> and the brackets <b>138</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">At the lid support member <b>131</b>, plural horizontal position adjusting mechanisms <b>139</b> formed of positioning screws, dial gauge and the like are installed. By these horizontal position adjusting mechanisms <b>139</b>, the lid <b>112</b> supported indirectly by the lid support member <b>131</b> as described above can be positioned in the horizontal direction. To be more specific, position or direction of the lid <b>112</b> on a the horizontal plane can be adjusted by the plural horizontal position adjusting mechanisms, which carry out positioning at various positions in the horizontal direction (in the drawing, two horizontal position adjusting mechanisms (<b>139</b>,<b>139</b>), which perform positioning in different directions normal to each other).</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Further, at the lid support member <b>131</b>, plural vertical position adjusting mechanisms <b>131</b><i>a </i>for adjusting the vertical position of the lid <b>112</b> are installed. The height of the lid <b>112</b> may be adjusted by these vertical position adjusting mechanisms <b>131</b><i>a. </i>Moreover, the height of the lid <b>112</b> is adjusted by using the plural vertical position adjusting mechanisms <b>131</b><i>a, </i>which are separated from each other in the horizontal direction, so that the inclination level of the lid <b>112</b> is adjusted.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">To be more specific, each of the vertical position adjusting mechanisms <b>131</b><i>a </i>attached to the lid support member <b>131</b> is configured to adjust the height of the source material supply box <b>121</b> with respect to the lid support member <b>131</b>, and thus, adjusting the height of the lid <b>112</b> indirectly.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">At the lid support mechanism <b>130</b>, a rotation lock unit (plunger) <b>132</b><i>c </i>for fixing the rotation of the lid <b>112</b> is installed. The rotation lock unit (plunger) <b>132</b><i>c </i>fixes the driving member <b>132</b> and the shaft <b>133</b> in the rotation direction all the time, and such locked state is released by performing a predetermined operation (e.g., unloading operation).</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Further, there is installed a raised position keeping unit for keeping the lid <b>112</b> at a raised position of predetermined height when the lid <b>112</b> is elevated from the vessel main body <b>111</b>. As described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the raised position keeping unit includes a supported material <b>137</b> (in the drawing, corresponding to a rotatably supported roller), which is attached to the driving member <b>132</b> through a fitting member <b>136</b>; and a supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b </i>(a top surface of the fixing member <b>134</b>) for upwardly supporting the supported material <b>137</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As shown by the solid line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in the state where the lid <b>112</b> is disposed on the vessel main body <b>111</b> (the upper opening <b>111</b><i>a </i>of the vessel main body <b>111</b> is closed or it is disposed at a raised position right above the vessel main body <b>111</b>), the supported member <b>137</b> is not supported by the supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b </i>in the side of the fixing member <b>134</b>. Contrary to this, if the lid <b>112</b> disposed at the raised position is rotated by a predetermined angle in the horizontal direction, the supported member <b>137</b> reaches to the supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b </i>of the fixing member <b>134</b>. In such a state, if the lid <b>112</b> is further rotated in the horizontal direction, the supported member <b>137</b> moves on the supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b </i>(while rotating, in case of a roller).</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">As mentioned above, since the supported member <b>137</b> is supported on the supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b, </i>the lid <b>112</b> is supported at a predetermined height during the rotation thereof. Further, a stepped portion <b>134</b><i>c </i>is formed in the supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b </i>to confine the rotation range of the lid <b>112</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Here, if the lid <b>112</b> tends to rotate when it is not elevated at a predetermined height, the supported material <b>137</b> will contact the side of the fixing member <b>134</b>. Accordingly, even though the rotation lock unit <b>132</b><i>c </i>is not provided or the rotation lock unit <b>132</b><i>c </i>is released, it is possible to control the lid <b>112</b> not to rotate if it does not reach a predetermined height.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the aforementioned gas exhaust line <b>124</b> and the gas supply line <b>125</b> are respectively opened around the upper opening <b>111</b><i>a </i>on the top surface of the vessel main body <b>111</b>. The gas exhaust line <b>124</b> is connected to the gas exhaust system <b>140</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. Further, in the gas exhaust system <b>140</b>, a gas exhaust unit such as a turbo molecular pump <b>143</b>, a dry pump <b>144</b> or the like is installed. Still further, a bypass line <b>142</b> or valve <b>141</b><i>a </i>or <b>142</b><i>a </i>may be disposed, if necessary. Still further, the gas supply line <b>125</b> is to introduce from the processing vessel <b>110</b> into the source material supply box <b>121</b> through the lid <b>112</b> various gases, which have been supplied into the processing vessel <b>110</b> from the outside.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the following, operation and effect of the vacuum processing apparatus <b>100</b> as configured above will be explained.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">When the processing vessel <b>110</b> is opened in the vacuum processing apparatus <b>100</b>, first, the lid <b>112</b> is elevated from the vessel main body <b>111</b> manually or by using any driving source (electric motor, fluid pressure cylinder, etc.). At this time, the rotation of the lid <b>112</b> is controlled by control structure such as the rotation lock unit <b>132</b><i>c, </i>the supported material <b>137</b> or the like, until the lid <b>112</b> is disposed at a predetermined height. Accordingly, it is possible to carry out safe and easy manipulation in case of performing, e.g., manual operation. Further, at this time, the lid <b>112</b> can be elevated, i.e., translated upward while being supported and basically maintaining its orientation (at horizontal position).</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">If the lid <b>112</b> is elevated to a predetermined height, it is rotated around the shaft <b>133</b> (vertical axis line), and thus, being dislocated from the vessel main body <b>111</b> in the horizontal direction as described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. At this time, since the supported member <b>137</b> is placed and supported on the supporting surface <b>134</b><i>b </i>of the fixing member <b>134</b>, the height of rotating lid <b>112</b> is kept during the rotation thereof even though it is not supported.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows as a dashed double-dotted line a state where the lid <b>112</b> is fully opened. In such a state, the lid <b>112</b> and the source material supply box <b>121</b> are not disposed above the vessel main body <b>111</b>, so that maintenance (cleaning or repair of equipment) of the processing vessel <b>110</b> can be performed very easily.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In the vacuum processing apparatus <b>100</b> of the present embodiment, the source material supply system <b>120</b> is disposed at a position right above the lid <b>112</b>, which was dead space conventionally. Therefore, the overall apparatus can be made compact. Further, it is possible to directly supply the source material into the processing vessel <b>110</b> from the upper portion, to thereby shorten the source material supply line while increasing the line's conductance. Hence, the amount of source material to be supplied can be maintained steadily, and at the same time, the source material can be prevented from being changed while supplying it. Accordingly, the processing can be performed by using various source materials smoothly.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">To be more specific, in case where the source gas is discharged from the source material vessel <b>122</b> by vacuum-exhaustion of the processing vessel <b>110</b> by the gas exhaust system <b>140</b>, if conductance of the source material supply line <b>123</b> is low, the amount of source gas to be supplied cannot be kept or the source gas may be changed in the supply line. However, in the present embodiment, it is possible to avoid such a problem by increasing conductance of the source material supply line <b>123</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Particularly, in the present embodiment, since the source material supply system <b>120</b> is fixed on the lid <b>112</b>, the lid <b>112</b> and the source material supply system <b>120</b> can be rigidly coupled to each other. Accordingly, the configuration can be simplified, and at the same time, the source gas can be prevented from being contaminated. Further, in the present embodiment, in case of performing vacuum-exhaustion of source material vessel <b>122</b> or various lines, vacuum level may be increased.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">For example, if the source material is solid, it is sublimated to produce source gas, which is supplied into the processing vessel <b>110</b>. In this case, it may be difficult to maintain the amount of source gas to be supplied, depending on the characteristics of the source material. However, in the present embodiment, the length of source material supply line <b>123</b> can be reduced, and the diameter of line can be large without interfering with surrounding structures. For the same reason, the amount of source gas to be supplied can be ensured, and thus, the processing can be performed smoothly.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Further, when vaporizing liquid source material other than organic metal and supplying it from the supply line <b>123</b> into the processing vessel <b>110</b>, if the conductance of supply line <b>123</b> is small, the source material may be liquefied or decomposed in the line. If the liquefied or decomposed product is supplied into the processing vessel, the processing quality may be degraded. However, in the present embodiment, since the conductance of supply line is increased, the source material supply condition can be improved and high quality processing can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">In the present embodiment, since the position of the lid <b>112</b> is not changed during the opening or closing thereof, the source material vessel <b>122</b> can be disposed above the lid <b>112</b> without causing any problem. Further, even though the lid <b>112</b> and the source material vessel <b>122</b> are fixed to each other, the status of source material accommodated in the source material vessel <b>122</b> is not changed, i.e., the source material is not tilted in the source material vessel <b>122</b>, since the position of the source material vessel <b>122</b> is not changed. Therefore, the supply amount of source material and the supply status may be stabilized.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In the present embodiment, the length of the source material supply line <b>123</b> may be set in the range of 30&#x2dc;100 cm, and practically, about 70&#x2dc;80 cm. Further, the line diameter may be configured in the range of 20&#x2dc;80 mm, and preferably, large diameter of 30&#x2dc;50 mm may be employed.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In the present embodiment, the vacuum processing apparatus has a depressurized processing vessel, in which any processings may be carried out. As for the vacuum processing apparatus, film forming apparatus such as CVD, etching apparatus such as dry etching, ashing apparatus such as plasma asher, heat treating device such as annealing furnace or the like, may be enumerated.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A vacuum processing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a processing vessel having an inside that can be depressurized, the processing vessel including a vessel main body having an upper opening and a lid for airtightly closing the upper opening of the vessel main body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lid support mechanism for opening or closing the upper opening of the vessel main body by moving the lid; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a source material vessel system disposed above the lid and having a source material vessel which accommodates therein a source material, the source material vessel system supplying a source gas generated from the source material into the processing vessel,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the source material vessel system further includes a source gas supply line, extending from the source material vessel to an upper portion of the lid, for supplying the source gas into the processing vessel through the lid,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the vacuum processing apparatus further comprises an additional gas supply line for supplying a carrier gas or a cleaning gas, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the additional gas supply line is introduced into the vessel main body from outside of the vessel main body, and wherein the additional gas supply line extends through the vessel main body, and then extends through the lid and is connected to the source gas supply line, and wherein the carrier gas or the cleaning gas is introduced into the inside of the processing vessel by first passing through the additional gas supply line, then through the source gas supply line, and then into the inside of the processing vessel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lid support mechanism allows the lid to be translated in a vertical direction, and to be rotated around a vertical axis line disposed at a peripheral position of the lid when the lid is elevated from the vessel main body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the lid support mechanism is configured to maintain the lid at a predetermined height while the lid is rotated.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the lid support mechanism has a supporting member for supporting the lid directly or indirectly, and wherein the supporting member extends substantially horizontally above the lid from the vicinity of the vertical axis line.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising a lifting unit for upwardly lifting the lid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the source material vessel is immovably disposed with respect to the lid, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein during movement of the lid, a relative position between the lid and the source material vessel is not changed so that the source material accommodated therein is not tilted.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the source gas supply line is immovably disposed with respect to the lid, and
<claim-text>wherein a relative position between the lid and the source gas supply line is not changed.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the source material vessel is immovably disposed with respect to the lid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the source gas supply line is immovably disposed with respect to the lid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the source gas supply line is immovably disposed with respect to the lid.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the apparatus includes a pump to reduce pressure in said processing vessel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the source material vessel includes the source material in a non-gaseous state, and wherein the source material is supplied to the processing vessel in a gaseous state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the source material vessel includes the source material in a non-gaseous state, and wherein the source material is supplied to the processing vessel in a gaseous state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The vacuum processing apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the vessel main body has a top surface at which the upper opening is formed, and the additional gas supply line is connected to the source gas supply line via the top surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
