<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640821-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640821</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11619570</doc-number>
<date>20070103</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>354</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>H</subclass>
<main-group>55</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7442486</main-classification>
<further-classification> 7442487</further-classification>
<further-classification> 7442482</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Circulating member for a ball screw</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2618166</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Douglas</name>
<date>19521100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442487</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3667311</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wysong</name>
<date>19720600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442475</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4226137</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sharp</name>
<date>19801000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442486</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5937700</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brown et al.</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442486</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5988007</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nishimura</name>
<date>19991100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442487</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6813969</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Huang</name>
<date>20041100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442483</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0076733</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yamamoto et al.</name>
<date>20050400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442487</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0196291</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Yoshioka et al.</name>
<date>20060900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 7442487</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7442482</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7442486</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 7442487</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080156131</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080703</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Yu-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lin</last-name>
<first-name>Kenny</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shia</last-name>
<first-name>Banger</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hiwin Technologies Corp.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hannon</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas R</first-name>
<department>3656</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Krause</last-name>
<first-name>Justin</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A circulating member for a ball screw is disposed on a nut, the nut is formed with Gothic type threads, and the circulating member of the ball screw is formed with return path for enabling the balls to circulate. The connecting ports at both ends of the return path for connecting the threads of the nut are shaped in Gothic style, thus eliminating the level difference and consequently preventing the balls from being struck and jammed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="93.64mm" wi="112.78mm" file="US07640821-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="246.30mm" wi="167.22mm" file="US07640821-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="190.84mm" wi="162.48mm" file="US07640821-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="181.36mm" wi="165.86mm" file="US07640821-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="258.74mm" wi="161.21mm" file="US07640821-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="189.57mm" wi="156.46mm" file="US07640821-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="207.18mm" wi="167.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640821-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a component for a ball screw, and more particularly to a circulating member for a ball screw, which can eliminate the conjunction level difference and prevent the balls from being struck.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Nowadays, ball screw is used more and more widely in modern industries. As a linear transmission means, the ball screw not only has high precision but also has the advantages of low frictional loss, high energy conversion ratio, low noise and high rigidity. Hence, it is self-evident that the ball screw is very important to various industrial mechanisms.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In order for the balls between the screw and the nut to circulate smoothly and for eliminating the circulating impact force caused therebetween, the nut is usually provided at both ends thereof with a circulating member (for example, circulating cap). And the circulating member is a key member for enabling the balls circulation from the screw and the nut. Therefore, how to develop an improved and competitive circulating cap is the common goal that the manufactures are striving for.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The conventional circulating members are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> show an ordinary conventional circulating structure, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a circulating member disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 2,618,166, wherein the conventional ball screw comprises: a nut <b>10</b>, a screw <b>11</b>, a plurality of balls <b>12</b>, and a circulating member <b>13</b> installed radially from outside into inside of the ball screw. The circulating member <b>13</b> is inserted in the nut <b>10</b> via the hole <b>101</b> and serves to cooperate with the Gothic type (Gothic type or Gothic shape is a pointed arch) thread <b>102</b> to guide the balls <b>12</b>. The balls <b>12</b> climb over the ridge of the threads of the screw <b>11</b> and move from one thread <b>102</b> to the other neighboring thread <b>102</b> through the return path <b>131</b> of the circulating member <b>13</b> connected between two neighboring threads <b>102</b>. The two neighboring inner threads <b>102</b> of the nut <b>10</b> are connected with the return path <b>131</b> of the circulating member <b>13</b> to form an enclosed circulating path for enabling the balls to circulate endlessly. The structures shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> are the same in design, therefore, they are designated with the same reference numbers. These conventional circulating structures have the disadvantages as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">When the balls <b>12</b> move into the return path <b>131</b> of the circulating member <b>13</b>, since the inner threads <b>102</b> of the nut <b>10</b> are of Gothic type, but the return path <b>131</b> of the circulating member <b>13</b> is a circular arc-shaped passage. Inevitably, at the conjunction between the return path <b>131</b> of the circulating member <b>13</b> and the inner threads <b>102</b> of the nut <b>10</b> appears a non-continuous level difference X and consequently the balls <b>12</b> are likely to be struck or jammed by the level difference X when moving in and out of the circulating member <b>13</b>, and consequently, the balls <b>12</b> can't move smoothly.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The aforementioned circulating member <b>13</b> generally refers to a cap piece, an engaging piece, or the like, used to connect the thread for enabling the balls to circulate. The circulating path <b>131</b> is circular arc-shaped and constant in cross section. Since the circulating path <b>131</b> can't flushly abut the inner threads <b>102</b> of the nut <b>10</b>, inevitably, there will exist a level difference X, and consequently, the balls will strike the level difference X.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present invention has arisen to mitigate and/or obviate the afore-described disadvantages.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The primary objective of the present invention is to provide a circulating member for a ball screw which won't have a severe conjunction level difference.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">To obtain the abovementioned objective, the circulating member for a ball screw in accordance with the present invention is disposed on a nut with Gothic type threads and is formed with a return path to be connected to the threads of the nut for enabling balls to circulate. At either end of the return path of the circulating member is formed a connecting port for connecting the threads of the nut, and the connecting port is shaped in Gothic style.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">By such arrangements, level difference at the conjunction between the circulating member and the nut disappears, thus preventing the balls from being struck and jammed, reducing the operation noise.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross sectional view of a circulating member for a ball screw disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 2,618,166;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross sectional view of a conventional circulating member for a ball screw;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective cross sectional view of showing the interior structure of a conventional circulating member for a ball screw;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an assembly view in accordance with the present invention of showing a circulating cap is being assembled on a ball screw;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective cross sectional view in accordance with the present invention of showing a part of the circulating cap and the nut;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an illustrative view of a circulating member in accordance with a second embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view of the circulating member in accordance with the second embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows the data comparison between the drive torque of a ball screw with the conventional arc-shaped connecting port and the drive torque of a ball screw with the Gothic connecting port of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The present invention will be more clear from the following description when viewed together with the accompanying drawings, which show, for purpose of illustrations only, the preferred embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, an embodiment of the circulating member for ball screw in accordance with the present invention is a circulating cap <b>20</b>, but the present invention is not limited to the circulating cap, all circulating members installed in the nut of the ball screw are considered to be within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The circulating cap <b>20</b> is radially disposed in a through hole <b>41</b> of a nut <b>40</b>, in the nut <b>40</b> are formed Gothic type threads <b>42</b> through which the nut <b>40</b> is threaded to a screw <b>30</b>. The circulating cap <b>20</b> is formed with a return path <b>21</b> for connecting the threads <b>42</b> of the nut <b>40</b>. The structural improvements of the present invention are described as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">At either end of the return path <b>21</b> of the circulating cap <b>20</b> are formed a connecting port <b>211</b> for connecting the threads <b>42</b> of the nut <b>40</b>, and the connecting ports <b>211</b> are shaped in Gothic style for cooperating with the Gothic type threads <b>42</b> of the nut <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">By such arrangements, level difference at the conjunction between the circulating member and the nut disappears, thus preventing the balls from being struck and jammed, and reducing the operation noise.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">It is to be noted that, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, the return path <b>21</b> of the circulating member in accordance with the present invention is circular arc-shaped and inconstant in cross section (gradually changed in cross section), between the two connecting ports <b>211</b> is a circular arc-shaped path <b>212</b> that is gradually changed toward both sides to form the Gothic type connecting port <b>211</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Therefore, the aforementioned connecting port is Gothic type and is constant in cross section, and the part <b>221</b> of the circulating path where the balls move upward (as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) is gradually changed into a circular arc-shaped path <b>212</b> with an inconstant cross section, and then is turned into a circular arc-shaped path <b>212</b> with a constant cross section when passing through the thread ridge. Such an embodiment enables the balls to roll more smoothly.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Finally, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows the data comparison between the drive torque of a ball screw with the conventional circular arc-shaped connecting port and the drive torque of a ball screw with the Gothic connecting port of the present invention. As far as the circular arc-shaped connecting port is concerned, the drive torque of the ball screw is unstable, and its average drive torque is relatively large as compared with the Gothic type connecting port. These test data show that the structural design of the circulating path of the present invention can prevent the balls from being struck and jammed.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">To summarize, the present invention is disposed on a nut, the nut is formed with Gothic type threads, and the circulating member of the ball screw is formed with return path for enabling the balls to circulate. The connecting ports at both ends of the return path for connecting the threads of the nut are shaped in Gothic style, thus eliminating the level difference and consequently preventing the balls from being struck and jammed.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">While we have shown and described various embodiments in accordance with the present invention, it is clear to those skilled in the art that further embodiments may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A circulating member for a ball screw being disposed on a nut which is provided with gothic arch threads, the circulating member is formed with a return path which is connected to the threads of the nut for enabling balls to circulate, characterized in that:
<claim-text>a connecting port for connecting the threads of the nut is formed at each end of the return path of the circulating member, and the connecting port is shaped in the form of a pointed arch;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the return path is inconstant in cross section, a middle portion of the return path is circular arch-shaped in cross section and both ends of the return path is pointed arch-shaped in cross section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a part of the return path where the connecting port is located is gothic arch-shaped, and a part of the circulating path is circular arc-shaped in cross section, and a part of the return path where the balls pass through a thread ridge of a thread of the screw shaft is circular arc-shaped in cross section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The circulating member for a ball screw as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a through hole is formed in the nut for accommodation of the circulating member of the ball screw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The circulating member for a ball screw as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the circulating member is a circulating cap positioned in the nut.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
