<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640735-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640735</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11533121</doc-number>
<date>20060919</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>287</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60468</main-classification>
<further-classification> 60488</further-classification>
<further-classification>13761417</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Auxiliary pump for hydrostatic transmission</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2588527</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Holmes</name>
<date>19520300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>137529</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2761389</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Turner</name>
<date>19560900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>13761414</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4570849</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Klaucke et al.</name>
<date>19860200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 91452</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5555727</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hauser et al.</name>
<date>19960900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60488</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>9</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60468</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60488</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>13761414</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>13761417</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>13761418</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60718464</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20050919</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070062186</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070322</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wuthrich</last-name>
<first-name>Jerome B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Moundridge</city>
<state>KS</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Dong</last-name>
<first-name>Xingen</first-name>
<address>
<city>Greeneville</city>
<state>TN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Renner, Otto, Boisselle &#x26; Sklar, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Parker-Hannifin Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Cleveland</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lopez</last-name>
<first-name>F. Daniel</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An auxiliary pump assembly for a hydrostatic transmission that operates at a reduced pressure when the auxiliary circuit is not in use, and operates at an increased pressure when the auxiliary circuit is in use, thereby reducing the heat generated by the auxiliary pump. The auxiliary pump assembly can be used to supply low pressure makeup flow to a closed loop of a hydrostatic transmission. A combination valve including a bypass valve and a relief valve is also provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="254.85mm" wi="349.76mm" file="US07640735-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="232.49mm" wi="160.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640735-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="213.44mm" wi="147.15mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640735-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="208.11mm" wi="162.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640735-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="206.42mm" wi="154.43mm" file="US07640735-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="183.64mm" wi="156.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640735-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="247.90mm" wi="132.76mm" file="US07640735-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="232.07mm" wi="142.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640735-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="142.32mm" wi="132.59mm" file="US07640735-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application hereby incorporates by reference and claims the benefit of U.S. Provisional Application No. 60/718,464 filed Sep. 19, 2005.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to hydrostatic transmissions. More particularly, the invention relates to hydrostatic transmissions for use in vehicles, such as mowing machines.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Hydrostatic transmissions have many uses, including the propelling of vehicles, such as mowing machines, and offer a stepless control of the machine's speed. A typical hydrostatic transmission system includes a variable displacement main hydraulic pump connected in a closed hydraulic circuit with a fixed displacement hydraulic motor. The closed hydraulic circuit includes a first conduit connecting the main pump outlet with the motor inlet and a second conduit connecting the motor outlet with a pump inlet. Either of these conduits may be the high pressure line depending upon the direction of pump displacement from neutral. For most applications, the pump is driven by a prime mover, such as an internal combustion engine or an electrical motor, at a certain speed in a certain direction. Many hydrostatic transmissions also include a charge pump for providing makeup flow to the closed circuit to replace fluid lost due to internal leakage. Charge pumps are typically positive displacement pumps (e.g., a gear pump) driven by the same input as the main hydraulic pump and provide fluid to the closed circuit via one or more check valves. Changing the displacement of the main pump will change its output flow rate, which controls the speed of the motor. Pump outflow can be reversed, thus reversing the direction of the motor. In a vehicle, the motor is typically connected through suitable gearing to the vehicle's wheels or tracks.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In many applications, fluid from the hydrostatic transmission is used to operate one or more auxiliary hydraulic circuits, for example, to raise and/or lower an implement such as a mower deck. Such auxiliary circuits, though used relatively seldom, often require relatively high pressure to operate properly. Thus, a readily available high pressure fluid source is needed to power the auxiliary circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One solution has been to provide a hydrostatic transmission with an auxiliary pump capable of providing sufficient pressurized fluid to operate the auxiliary circuit. In some applications, the auxiliary pump is provided in place of a charge pump and is used to supply fluid not only to the auxiliary circuit, but also to provide makeup flow to the closed loop of the hydrostatic transmission. Due to the high pressure required by the auxiliary circuit and the infrequent use of the same, such an arrangement generates significant heat as the auxiliary pump continuously pressurizes fluid. Accordingly, such systems often require an additional fluid cooler for dissipating the generated heat.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention provides an auxiliary pump assembly for a hydrostatic transmission that operates at a reduced pressure when the auxiliary circuit is not in use, and operates at an increased pressure when the auxiliary circuit is in use, thereby reducing the heat generated by the auxiliary pump. The auxiliary pump assembly can be used to supply low pressure makeup flow to a closed loop of a hydrostatic transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Accordingly, the invention provides an auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly for a hydrostatic transmission system for a vehicle comprising an auxiliary hydraulic pump having an inlet and an outlet, a pump discharge line connectable to an actuator for supplying fluid from the outlet of the pump to the actuator, and a low pressure relief valve connected in series with a selectively actuated flow control device between the outlet of the pump and the inlet of the pump, the low pressure relief valve allowing fluid to pass therethrough that is at a pressure exceeding a first pressure level. The flow control device, in a first mode of operation, permits flow from the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a second pressure level greater than the first pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the first level such that pressurized fluid at the outlet of the auxiliary pump can be supplied to the pump discharge line up to the second pressure level. In a second mode the flow control device connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet of the auxiliary pump, whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In an exemplary embodiment, the flow control device comprises a high pressure relief valve and a bypass valve connected in parallel between the outlet of the pump and the low pressure relief valve, whereby when the bypass valve is closed the flow control device permits flow from the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve when pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a second pressure level greater than the first pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the second level, whereby pressurized fluid at the outlet of the auxiliary pump can be supplied to the pump discharge line up to the second level, and when the bypass valve is open the flow control device connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve. The low pressure relief valve can be connectable to a charge line for providing makeup flow to a hydrostatic transmission. The flow control device can be a relief valve that can be selectively opened whereby when the relief valve is selectively opened fluid can flow from the outlet of the pump to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure. The flow control device can be adjacent the auxiliary pump, integral with the auxiliary pump, or located within the confines of an auxiliary pump housing.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to another aspect of the invention, a hydrostatic transmission system for a vehicle comprises a pump, a motor, supply and return lines connecting the pump and motor in a closed circuit, and the auxiliary pump assembly as set forth above, wherein an outlet of the flow control device of the auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly is connected to a charge line of the hydrostatic transmission for providing makeup flow to the closed circuit. The flow control device can be located within the confines of a housing of the hydrostatic transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to another aspect of the invention, a valve for use as the flow control device in an auxiliary hydraulic circuit of a hydrostatic transmission comprises a valve body having an inlet and an outlet connected by an interior passage, a bypass valve member supported in the valve body for axial movement between open and closed positions respectively permitting and blocking flow of a fluid through the interior bore, and a relief valve member for permitting flow between the inlet and outlet via a relief passage in response to fluid pressure at the inlet exceeding a prescribed amount. In an exemplary embodiment, the relief valve member is supported by and forms a part of the bypass valve member and a flow passageway including an orifice is provided for connecting the inlet to the outlet for permitting a minimum flow between the inlet and the outlet regardless of the position of the bypass valve member or relief valve member. The orifice can be formed integrally with at least one of the bypass vale member and relief valve member.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to yet another aspect of the invention, a method of operating an auxiliary pump assembly for controlling an auxiliary component of a vehicle comprises the steps of switching a flow control device to operate in a first mode that permits flow from a pump outlet to a low pressure relief valve when pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a prescribed pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the prescribed level, whereby pressurized fluid at the outlet of the pump can be supplied to a pump discharge line up to the prescribed level, and switching the flow control device to operate in a second mode that connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet of the auxiliary pump, whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further features of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description when considered in conjunction with the drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a portion of a prior art hydraulic transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating an auxiliary hydraulic circuit having an auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly in accordance with the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating a hydrostatic transmission including an auxiliary hydraulic circuit having an auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly in accordance with the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating another hydrostatic transmission including an auxiliary hydraulic circuit having an auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly in accordance with the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a a schematic diagram of yet another hydrostatic transmission including an auxiliary hydraulic circuit having an auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly in accordance with the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a combination bypass and pressure relief valve including a bypass orifice in accordance with the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the valve of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> in a bypass open configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the valve of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> in a bypass closed configuration with the pressure relief valve closed.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the valve of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> in a bypass closed configuration with the pressure relief valve open.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is an enlarged portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrating a restricting orifice.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring now to the drawings in detail, and initially to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a schematic diagram is shown illustrating a portion of a fluid circuit <b>10</b> of a known hydrostatic transmission. The fluid circuit <b>10</b> includes a main pump <b>12</b> and an auxiliary pump <b>14</b>. The main pump <b>12</b> is connected by line <b>16</b> to port A and by line <b>18</b> to port B for supplying and returning hydraulic fluid to a hydraulic motor (not shown). The auxiliary pump <b>14</b> includes an outlet <b>20</b> connected to discharge line <b>22</b> for supplying fluid from the outlet of the auxiliary pump <b>14</b> to an auxiliary actuator (not shown) to which the discharge line <b>22</b> is connectable. A return line <b>24</b> returns fluid from the auxiliary actuator. The return line <b>24</b> includes a filter <b>25</b> and is connected via charge line <b>26</b> to check valves <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> for supplying makeup flow to lines <b>16</b> and <b>18</b> in a conventional manner. A pressure relief valve <b>31</b> is provided for relieving pressure from the closed loop. Return line <b>24</b> is also connected to a charge relief valve <b>32</b> which in turn is connected to an auxiliary pump input line <b>34</b> for returning fluid to auxiliary pump <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The outlet <b>20</b> of the auxiliary pump <b>14</b>, in addition to being connected to discharge line <b>22</b>, is connected to a high pressure auxiliary circuit relief valve <b>36</b> that allows fluid to bypass the auxiliary actuator when the pressure in discharge line <b>22</b> exceeds a certain amount, such as 650 psi. Fluid that flows through the high pressure auxiliary relief valve <b>36</b> flows via line <b>38</b> to the auxiliary return line <b>24</b> and subsequently through check valves <b>28</b> and/or <b>30</b> into lines <b>16</b> and <b>18</b> or via charge relief valve <b>32</b> back to the auxiliary pump inlet line <b>34</b>. A flow restricting orifice <b>40</b> connects line <b>38</b> to sump <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In operation, main pump <b>12</b> and auxiliary pump <b>14</b> are driven together, typically by the same input shaft (not shown). Depending on the direction of operation of the main pump <b>12</b>, fluid is supplied via line <b>16</b> or line <b>18</b> to port A or port B, respectively, and returned via the opposite port and line. Accordingly, main pump <b>12</b> lines <b>16</b> and <b>18</b> and the motor (not shown) define a closed loop hydraulic circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The auxiliary pump <b>14</b> supplies fluid to the auxiliary discharge line <b>22</b> via the outlet <b>20</b> of the pump <b>14</b>. Accordingly, when the auxiliary actuator is not in operation and, therefore, fluid is not flowing from the discharge line <b>22</b> to the return line <b>24</b>, fluid pressure builds in discharge line <b>22</b> to a maximum of 650 psi at which point the auxiliary relief valve <b>36</b> opens thereby allowing fluid to flow into line <b>38</b> and subsequently through check valves <b>28</b> and/or <b>30</b> as makeup flow, through charge relief valve <b>32</b> back to the auxiliary pump inlet line <b>34</b>, and/or through restricting orifice <b>40</b> to sump <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">When the auxiliary actuator is activated fluid flows through discharge line <b>22</b> and returns via auxiliary return line <b>24</b>. The auxiliary relief valve <b>36</b> will typically remain closed during operation of the auxiliary actuator unless the pressure in the pump discharge line <b>22</b> exceeds a prescribed level. Fluid returning via line <b>24</b> is then subsequently routed through check valves <b>28</b> and/or <b>30</b> as makeup flow, charge relief valve <b>32</b>, and/or restricting orifice <b>40</b> to the sump <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The illustrated auxiliary pump <b>14</b>, therefore, provides fluid to the auxiliary actuator when in operation and provides makeup flow to lines <b>16</b> or <b>18</b> via fluid that travels from discharge line <b>22</b> through the auxiliary actuator and returns via line <b>24</b>, or in the case when the auxiliary actuator is not is use, the auxiliary pump <b>14</b> provides makeup flow to lines <b>16</b> and <b>18</b> via the high pressure auxiliary relief valve <b>36</b>. Because the auxiliary actuator is typically used intermittently, during a substantial portion of the operation the auxiliary pump <b>14</b> the fluid is pressurized to 650 psi even though such high pressure is not necessary. As indicated above, this will heat the fluid and may require the use of a cooler to cool the fluid.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Turning now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a schematic diagram is shown illustrating an auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly <b>50</b> for a hydrostatic transmission in accordance with the invention. The assembly <b>50</b> includes an auxiliary pump <b>52</b>, a discharge line <b>54</b> connectable to an actuator (now shown) for supplying fluid from an outlet <b>56</b> of the pump <b>52</b> to the actuator. A low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> is connected in series with a selectively actuated flow control device <b>60</b> between the outlet <b>56</b> of the pump <b>52</b> and an inlet line <b>62</b>. The low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> allows fluid to pass therethrough that is at a pressure exceeding a first pressure, for example 100 psi. The flow control device <b>60</b>, which in the illustrated embodiment is a high pressure relief valve <b>64</b> connected in parallel with a bypass valve <b>66</b> between the outlet <b>56</b> and the low pressure relieve valve <b>58</b>, operates in two modes of operation. In a first mode of operation, the flow control device <b>60</b> permits flow from the pump outlet <b>56</b> to the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> when pressure of the fluid at the outlet <b>56</b> exceeds a second pressure level that is greater than the first pressure level. Thus, pressurized fluid at the outlet <b>56</b> of the auxiliary pump <b>52</b> can be supplied to the pump discharge line up to the second level of pressure. In a second mode, the flow control device <b>60</b> connects the pump outlet <b>56</b> to the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet <b>56</b> of the auxiliary pump <b>52</b>. Thus, the pressure at the outlet <b>56</b> of the pump <b>52</b> will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device <b>60</b> and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line <b>54</b> to flow through the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">It will be appreciated that a makeup flow supply line <b>68</b>, connected at a point between the flow control device <b>60</b> and the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b>, can be connected to a charge line of a hydrostatic transmission for providing makeup flow to a closed circuit of the same. By way of example, the makeup flow supply line <b>68</b> could be connected to charge line <b>26</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. To ensure adequate makeup flow is available, an optional bypass line <b>70</b> and a restricting orifice <b>72</b> can be provided for connecting the outlet of the pump <b>52</b> to the makeup flow supply line <b>68</b>. Although illustrated as part of the flow control device <b>60</b>, bypass line <b>70</b> and orifice <b>72</b> can be provided separate from the flow control device <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In operation, the auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> can be used to supply fluid to an auxiliary actuator via discharge line <b>54</b> and also supply makeup flow via makeup flow supply line <b>68</b> to a closed loop of a hydrostatic transmission. Accordingly, auxiliary pump <b>52</b> is configured to move fluid into discharge line <b>54</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, discharge line <b>54</b> is connectable to an auxiliary actuator as a two-way line providing for both flow and return of fluid from an auxiliary actuator. When the auxiliary actuator is operated fluid flows to the actuator via discharge line <b>54</b> while the flow control device <b>60</b> typically remains in the first mode of operation thereby permitting flow through the flow control device <b>60</b> only when pressure in discharge line <b>54</b> and/or of the outlet <b>56</b> of the pump <b>52</b> exceeds the second higher pressure. In this manner, flow control device <b>60</b> acts as safety relief valve to prevent overload of the auxiliary circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">When the actuator is not in use, the flow control device <b>60</b> operates in the second mode of operation thereby connecting the pump outlet <b>56</b> to the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet <b>56</b> or in the discharge line <b>54</b>. This second mode of operation is achieved by opening bypass valve <b>66</b> such that fluid can flow from the outlet <b>56</b> around the high pressure relief valve <b>64</b> to the low pressure valve <b>58</b> and/or the makeup flow supply line <b>58</b> for supplying makeup flow to the closed loop of hydrostatic transmission. It will be appreciated that during operation of the pump <b>54</b>, a minimum amount of the fluid flowing from the outlet <b>56</b> of the pump <b>54</b> flows through bypass line <b>70</b> and restricting orifice <b>72</b> to makeup flow supply line <b>68</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The configuration of the auxiliary hydraulic assembly <b>50</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> facilitates low pressure operation of the auxiliary pump <b>52</b> when the auxiliary actuator is not in use. Unlike prior art systems that typically maintained high pressure in the auxiliary circuit lines during all times, the auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> reduces heat generation in the auxiliary circuit by maintaining a lower operating pressure when the auxiliary actuator is not in use.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-5</figref>, three different hydrostatic transmissions are illustrated including the auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the hydrostatic transmission <b>100</b> includes a main pump <b>102</b> and auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> as part of a pump unit <b>106</b>. Both the main pump <b>102</b> and auxiliary pump <b>106</b> are driven by a common input <b>107</b>. The main pump <b>102</b> is connected to a motor <b>108</b> via lines A and B thereby forming a closed loop. The auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b>, which is identical to the auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> described in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, is connected to the closed loop for supplying makeup flow thereto in the manner previously described. Pump discharge line <b>54</b> can be connected to an auxiliary actuator, as mentioned.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, hydrostatic transmission <b>100</b> includes a pump unit <b>106</b> having two closed loops, each closed loop having a pump <b>102</b> connected to a motor <b>108</b> via lines A<b>1</b>, B<b>1</b> and A<b>2</b>, B<b>2</b> as shown. The auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> is connected to each closed loop for supplying makeup flow thereto in the same manner as described in connection with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Pump discharge line <b>54</b> can be connected to an auxiliary actuator, as mentioned.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the hydrostatic transmission <b>100</b> is an integrated hydrostatic transmission. The hydrostatic transmission <b>100</b> includes a pump <b>102</b> connected to a motor <b>108</b> via lines A and B in a closed loop configuration. The auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> is connected in the manner previously described to the closed loop for providing makeup flow thereto and the discharge line <b>54</b> is provided for connection to an auxiliary actuator.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">It will be appreciated that the auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> described herein can be used in a wide variety of hydrostatic transmission configurations for both providing makeup flow to a closed loop of the hydrostatic transmission and for providing fluid to an auxiliary circuit. Although in the illustrated embodiments, a single action actuator is used, it will be appreciated that the discharge line <b>54</b> of the auxiliary pump assembly <b>50</b> can be connected to a wide variety of actuators and, in some cases, a return line from the actuator can return flow to the auxiliary pump assembly at a suitable point, such as line <b>68</b> for supplying makeup flow to the closed loop system and/or returning fluid to the intake line <b>62</b> of the auxiliary pump <b>52</b> via low pressure relief valve <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6-10</figref>, and initially to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, a combination valve <b>150</b> in accordance with the invention is illustrated. The illustrated valve <b>150</b> is a solenoid actuated valve, but any suitable actuating mechanism can be used. As will be described, the valve <b>150</b> includes a bypass valve, a relief valve, and a bypass orifice for allowing an amount of fluid to flow through the valve regardless of the state of the valve. It will be appreciated that the valve <b>150</b> can be used in the above-described auxiliary hydraulic pump assemblies as the flow control device, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The valve <b>150</b> includes a valve body <b>152</b>, a magnetic plunger <b>154</b>, and a valve stem <b>156</b>. It will be appreciated that the valve body <b>152</b> is configured to be received within a coil <b>155</b> thereby forming a solenoid. When the coil <b>155</b> is energized, the plunger <b>154</b> is forced downward thereby moving the valve stem <b>156</b> to open or close the bypass valve. In the illustrated embodiment, the valve body <b>152</b> includes a radial passageway (port) <b>158</b> connected internally via a chamber <b>160</b> to an axial passageway (port) <b>162</b>. A bypass valve including a bypass valve member <b>164</b> and bypass valve seat <b>166</b> is configured to prevent flow in the internal chamber <b>160</b> when the coil <b>155</b> is energized, as will be described. The bypass valve member <b>164</b> is biased open by spring <b>167</b> thereby allowing fluid to flow from the radial port <b>158</b> (inlet) to the axial port <b>162</b> (outlet). A relief valve is provided including a relief valve member <b>168</b>, which in the illustrated embodiment is supported within a relief flow passage <b>199</b> in the bypass valve member <b>164</b>, and a relief valve seat portion <b>170</b> formed by a portion of the bypass valve member <b>164</b> against which the relief valve member <b>168</b> is configured to seal. Relief valve spring <b>172</b> biases the relief valve member <b>168</b> into sealing engagement with the relief valve seat portion <b>170</b> as long as the pressure of the fluid in the radial port <b>158</b> is below a prescribed amount. An orifice <b>174</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>) is provided connecting the radial port <b>158</b> to axial port <b>162</b> regardless of the states of the bypass valve <b>164</b> and relief valve <b>168</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Accordingly, when the valve stem <b>156</b> is in an open position and, consequently, the bypass valve is open (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>), fluid can enter the valve <b>150</b> through the radial passageway <b>152</b> and exit through axial passageway <b>162</b>. When the valve stem <b>156</b> is in a closed position (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-10</figref>), the bypass valve member <b>164</b> is closed thereby restricting fluid from flowing from the radial port <b>158</b> to the axial port <b>162</b> as long as the pressure of the fluid entering the radial port is less than the prescribed pressure required to open the relief valve member <b>168</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Turning to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the bypass valve member <b>164</b> is shown in the closed position. In this configuration, if the pressure of the fluid at the radial passageway <b>152</b> is greater than the prescribed pressure required to actuate the relief valve, the relief valve will open as shown thereby permitting fluid to flow from the radial passageway <b>158</b> to the axial passageway <b>162</b> via the relief passage <b>169</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">It will be appreciated that, regardless of the positions of the bypass valve member <b>164</b> and/or relief valve member <b>168</b>, fluid can flow from the radial passageway <b>158</b> to the axial passageway via the orifice <b>174</b>. Accordingly, in the case of the valve <b>150</b> being installed in an auxiliary pump circuit between an outlet of a pump and a makeup flow supply line as described above with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, the orifice <b>174</b> permits a minimum amount of fluid to be supplied to the makeup flow supply line. In some applications, supplying a constant minimum amount of fluid to a closed loop can be important for preventing cavitation of a pump in the closed circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">It will further be appreciated that the above-described valve <b>150</b>, when used in an auxiliary pump assembly as described above, for example, can function as the flow control device. Thus, when the valve <b>150</b> is open (See <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>), the valve <b>150</b> functions in accordance with the second mode of operation of the flow control device <b>60</b> connecting the pump outlet <b>54</b> to the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet <b>56</b> of the auxiliary pump <b>52</b>. Thus, the pressure at the outlet <b>56</b> of the pump <b>52</b> will be limited by the low pressure relief valve. When the valve <b>150</b> is closed (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8-10</figref>), the valve functions in accordance with the first mode of operation of the flow control device <b>60</b> and permits flow from the pump outlet <b>56</b> to the low pressure relief valve <b>58</b> when pressure of the fluid at the outlet <b>56</b> exceeds a second pressure level that is greater than the first pressure level. Thus, pressurized fluid at the outlet <b>56</b> of the auxiliary pump <b>52</b> can be supplied to the pump discharge line up to the second level of pressure. Finally, the orifice <b>174</b> of the valve <b>150</b> functions as the orifice <b>72</b> to allow a minimum amount of fluid to flow from the pump outlet to the makeup flow supply line <b>68</b> regardless of the state of the valve <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Although the invention has been shown and described with respect to a certain preferred embodiment or embodiments, it is obvious that equivalent alterations and modifications will occur to others skilled in the art upon the reading and understanding of this specification and the annexed drawings. In particular regard to the various functions performed by the above described elements (components, assemblies, devices, compositions, etc.), the terms (including a reference to a &#x201c;means&#x201d;) used to describe such elements are intended to correspond, unless otherwise indicated, to any element which performs the specified function of the described element (i.e., that is functionally equivalent), even though not structurally equivalent to the disclosed structure which performs the function in the herein illustrated exemplary embodiment or embodiments of the invention. In addition, while a particular feature of the invention may have been described above with respect to only one or more of several illustrated embodiments, such feature may be combined with one or more other features of the other embodiments, as may be desired and advantageous for any given or particular application.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly for a hydrostatic transmission system for a vehicle comprising:
<claim-text>an auxiliary hydraulic pump having an inlet and an outlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump discharge line connectable to an actuator for supplying fluid from the outlet of the pump to the actuator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a low pressure relief valve connected in series with a selectively actuated flow control device between the outlet of the pump and the inlet of the pump, the low pressure relief valve allowing fluid to pass therethrough that is at a pressure exceeding a first pressure level;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the flow control device in a first mode of operation for when high pressure fluid is to be supplied to the actuator permits flow from the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve when pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a second pressure level greater than the first pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the second level, whereby pressurized fluid at the outlet of the auxiliary pump can be supplied to the pump discharge line up to the second level, and in a second mode of operation for when high pressure fluid is not to be supplied to the actuator connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet of the auxiliary pump, whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the flow control device is a relief valve that is selectively openable whereby when the relief valve is selectively opened fluid can flow from the outlet of the to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flow control device comprises a high pressure relief valve and a bypass valve connected in parallel, whereby when the bypass valve is closed the flow control device permits flow from the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve when pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a second pressure level greater than the first pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the second level, whereby pressurized fluid at the outlet of the auxiliary pump can be supplied to the pump discharge line up to the second level, and when the bypass valve is open the flow control device connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an outlet of the flow control device is connectable to a charge line for providing make-up flow to the hydrostatic transmission.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flow control device is adjacent the pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flow control device is integral with the pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pump includes a pump housing, and the flow control device is located within the confines of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A hydrostatic transmission including a pump, a motor, supply and return lines connecting the pump and motor in a closed circuit, and the auxiliary pump assembly as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein of the flow control device of the auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly is connected to a charge line of the hydrostatic transmission for providing makeup flow to the closed circuit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A hydrostatic transmission as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the hydrostatic transmission includes a housing, and the auxiliary pump and flow control device are located within the confines of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. An auxiliary hydraulic pump assembly for a hydrostatic transmission system for a vehicle comprising:
<claim-text>an auxiliary hydraulic pump having an inlet and an outlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump discharge line connectable to an actuator for supplying fluid from the outlet of the pump to the actuator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a low pressure relief valve connected in series with a selectively actuated flow control device between the outlet of the pump and the inlet of the pump, the low pressure relief valve allowing fluid to pass therethrough that is at a pressure exceeding a first pressure level;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the flow control device in a first mode of operation for when high pressure fluid is to be supplied to the actuator permits flow from the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve when pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a second pressure level greater than the first pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the second level, whereby pressurized fluid at the outlet of the auxiliary pump can be supplied to the pump discharged line up to the second level, and in a second mode of operation for when high pressure fluid is not to be supplied to the actuator connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet of the auxiliary pump, whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve, and a bypass restricting orifice for bypassing the flow control device and allowing a minimum amount of fluid to flow from the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A valve for use in an auxiliary hydraulic circuit of a hydrostatic transmission comprising:
<claim-text>a valve body having an inlet and an outlet connected by an interior chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bypass valve member supported in the valve body for axial movement between open and closed positions respectively permitting and restricting flow of a fluid from the inlet to the outlet; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a relief valve member for permitting flow between the inlet and outlet via a relief passage in response to fluid pressure at the inlet exceeding a prescribed level when the bypass valve member is in the closed position.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A valve as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the relief valve member forms a portion of the bypass valve member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A valve as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, further comprising a flow restricting orifice connecting the inlet to the outlet for permitting a minimum flow between the inlet and the outlet regardless of the position of the bypass valve member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A valve as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the flow restricting orifice is formed integrally with at least one of the bypass valve member and the relief valve member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. An auxiliary hydraulic circuit including a pump, an actuator, and a valve as set forth in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref> connected between an outlet of the pump and an inlet of the pump.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method of operating an auxiliary pump assembly for controlling an auxiliary component of a vehicle, comprising the steps of switching a flow control device to operate in a first mode for supplying high pressure fluid to the auxiliary component that permits flow from a pump outlet to a low pressure relief valve when pressure of the fluid at the outlet exceeds a prescribed pressure level and blocks flow when the pressure of the fluid at the outlet is no greater than the prescribed pressure level, whereby pressurized fluid at the outlet of the pump can be supplied to a pump discharge line up to the prescribed pressure level, and switching the flow control device to operate in a second mode when high pressure fluid is not to be supplied to the auxiliary component that connects the pump outlet to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure at the outlet of the auxiliary pump, whereby pressure at the outlet of the pump will be limited by the low pressure relief valve in such second mode of the flow control device and allow higher pressure fluid in the pump discharge line to flow through the low pressure relief valve; wherein the flow control device is a relief valve that is selectively openable whereby when the relief valve is selectively opened fluid can flow from the outlet of the pump to the low pressure relief valve regardless of fluid pressure.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
