<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640920-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640920</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12237680</doc-number>
<date>20080925</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-277477</doc-number>
<date>20071025</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>N</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123520</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Fuel vapor processing apparatus</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5056494</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kayanuma</name>
<date>19911000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123519</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5143041</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Franzke</name>
<date>19920900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123520</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5564398</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Maeda et al.</name>
<date>19961000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123520</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5592922</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Denz</name>
<date>19970100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123520</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5632252</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hyodo et al.</name>
<date>19970500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123520</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>48756</doc-number>
<date>19920100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>674107</doc-number>
<date>19940300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001165010</doc-number>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002004956</doc-number>
<date>20020100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004263652</doc-number>
<date>20040900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>18</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123520</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123519</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123518</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123516</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123198 D</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137587</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137588</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137589</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137 43</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>137493</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090107472</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090430</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Makino</last-name>
<first-name>Katsuhiko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Aichi-ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dennison, Schultz &#x26; MacDonald</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Aisan Kogyo Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Obi-Shi, Aichi-Ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Gimie</last-name>
<first-name>Mahmoud</first-name>
<department>3747</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention includes a first canister disposed within an intake air passage. The first canister communicates with a fuel tank via a second canister, so that a fuel vapor produced within the fuel tank can be purged by the second canister and further by the first canister. The second canister communicates with the intake air passage via a purge passage. The negative pressure within the intake air passage may be applied to the first and second canisters via the purge passage, so that the fuel vapor adsorbed by the first and second canisters can be desorbed or purged and can then be returned into the intake air passage.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="122.26mm" wi="138.94mm" file="US07640920-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="253.07mm" wi="164.76mm" file="US07640920-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="251.04mm" wi="153.42mm" file="US07640920-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="130.39mm" wi="149.61mm" file="US07640920-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="178.99mm" wi="136.65mm" file="US07640920-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to Japanese patent application serial number 2007-277477, the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to fuel vapor processing apparatus for processing fuel vapor that may be produced within a fuel tank.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A known fuel vapor processing apparatus is disclosed, for example, in Japanese Laid-Open Patent Publication No. 6-74107. The fuel vapor processing apparatus of this known publication is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> and includes a main canister <b>101</b> and a sub canister <b>103</b> connected in series with each other via a throttle <b>102</b>. The main canister <b>101</b> communicates with an upper chamber of a fuel tank T via a fuel vapor passage <b>105</b> on one hand, and communicates with an intake air passage <b>108</b> of an engine E via a purge passage <b>106</b> and a control valve <b>107</b> on the other hand. The sub canister <b>103</b> is open into the atmosphere via an atmospheric port <b>103</b><i>p. </i></p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">When the engine E is not started and is stopped, the control valve <b>107</b> is closed, and fuel vapor produced within the fuel tank T is introduced into the main canister <b>101</b> via the fuel vapor passage <b>105</b> so as to be adsorbed by an adsorption material K contained within the main canister <b>101</b>. A part of the fuel vapor that has not been adsorbed within the main canister <b>101</b> is introduced into the sub canister <b>103</b> via the throttle <b>102</b> so as to be adsorbed by an adsorption material K contained within the sub canister <b>103</b>. Therefore, the fuel vapor is prevented from dissipating into the atmosphere.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">On the other hand, during the operation of the engine E, the control valve <b>107</b> is opened, so that a negative pressure within the intake air passage <b>108</b> is applied to the sub canister <b>103</b> via the main canister <b>101</b>. Therefore, external air may enter the sub canister <b>103</b> via the atmospheric port <b>103</b><i>p</i>, so that the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption material K within the sub canister <b>103</b> can be purged. In addition, the air that may flow into the main canister <b>101</b> via the throttle <b>102</b> can purge the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption material K within the main canister <b>101</b>. With the air flowing into the main canister <b>101</b>, the purged fuel vapor is introduced into the intake air passage <b>108</b> via the purge passage <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to the known fuel vapor processing apparatus, the fuel vapor adsorbed within the sub canister <b>103</b> is purged by the air that enters the sub canister <b>103</b> via the atmospheric port <b>103</b><i>p </i>and subsequently flows through the main canister <b>101</b> and the control valve <b>107</b>. Therefore, if the control valve <b>107</b> is operated in a closing direction, for example, due to the control of the air-fuel ratio, during the operation of the engine E, the flow rate of the air entering the sub canister <b>103</b> via the atmospheric port <b>103</b><i>p </i>may be decreased. Hence, there is a possibility that the purging of the fuel vapor from within the sub canister <b>103</b> may not be effectively performed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">If the amount of the fuel vapor remaining within the sub canister <b>103</b> increases, there is a possibility that the fuel vapor is dissipated to the atmosphere via the atmospheric port <b>103</b><i>p </i>of the sub canister <b>103</b> when the engine E has stopped.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Therefore, there is a need in the art for fuel vapor processing apparatus that can prevent or minimize dissipation of fuel vapor into the atmosphere.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">One aspect according to the present invention includes a first canister disposed within an intake air passage. The first canister communicates with a fuel tank via a second canister, so that a fuel vapor produced within the fuel tank can be adsorbed by the second canister and further by the first canister. The second canister communicates with the intake air passage via a purge passage. The negative pressure within the intake air passage may be applied to the first and second canisters via the purge passage, so that the fuel vapor adsorbed by the first and second canisters can be desorbed or purged and can then be returned into the intake air passage.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1(A)</figref> is a schematic view of a fuel vapor processing apparatus according to a first embodiment of the present invention and showing the flow of fuel vapor during stopping of an engine;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1(B)</figref> is a schematic view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1(A)</figref> but showing the flow of intake air during driving of an engine;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic view of a fuel vapor processing apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view of a fuel vapor processing apparatus according to a third embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic view of a fuel vapor processing apparatus according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic view of a known fuel vapor processing apparatus.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Each of the additional features and teachings disclosed above and below may be utilized separately or in conjunction with other features and teachings to provide improved fuel vapor processing apparatus and a system incorporating the fuel vapor processing apparatus. Representative examples of the present invention, which examples utilize many of these additional features and teachings both separately and in conjunction with one another, will now be described in detail with reference to the attached drawings. This detailed description is merely intended to teach a person of skill in the art further details for practicing preferred aspects of the present teachings and is not intended to limit the scope of the invention. Only the claims define the scope of the claimed invention. Therefore, combinations of features and steps disclosed in the following detailed description may not be necessary to practice the invention in the broadest sense, and are instead taught merely to particularly describe representative examples of the invention. Moreover, various features of the representative examples and the dependent claims may be combined in ways that are not specifically enumerated in order to provide additional useful embodiments of the present teachings.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In one embodiment, a fuel vapor processing apparatus includes a main canister, a sub canister, a communication passage communicating between the main canister and the sub canister, and a purge passage communicating between the main canister and an intake air passage of an engine. The main canister can adsorb a fuel vapor that may be produced within a fuel tank. The sub canister can adsorb a part of the fuel vapor that has passed through the main canister. The sub canister is disposed within the intake air passage. During the operation of the engine, an intake air flowing through the intake air passage can (a) purge the fuel vapor adsorbed by the sub canister, (b) flow into the main canister via the communication passage, (c) purge the fuel vapor adsorbed by the main canister; and (d) return to the intake air passage via the purge passage.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">With this arrangement, for example, the fuel vapor produced within the fuel tank during the stop of the engine can be first adsorbed by the main canister. A part of the fuel vapor that has passed through the main canister can be introduced into the sub canister via the communication passage, so that the fuel vapor can be adsorbed further by the sub canister.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">During the operation of the engine, the intake air flowing through the intake air passage can first purge the fuel vapor adsorbed within the sub canister. After passing through the sub canister, the intake air is introduced into the main canister via the communication passage, so that the intake air can further purge the fuel vapor adsorbed within the main canister. The intake air containing the purged fuel vapor may return into the intake air passage via the purge passage.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In this way, even in the event that it is necessary to restrain the purging amount of the fuel vapor of the main canister, for example, for the reason of necessary air-fuel ratio control, it is possible to purge the fuel vapor of the sub canister by a large amount by using the flow of the intake air. Therefore, it is possible to minimize the amount of the fuel vapor remaining within the sub canister.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In another embodiment, an area of the sub canister through which the intake air flows is set to be larger than a cross sectional area of the communication passage. Therefore, it is possible to purge a large amount of the fuel vapor from the sub canister in comparison with the main canister.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In a further embodiment, a part of the intake air passage is divided into a first passage portion and a second passage portion by a partition wall extending substantially along the direction of flow of the intake air. The sub canister is disposed within the first passage portion. The communication passage may be in communication with the first passage portion. A flow control device is disposed within the first passage portion for controlling the flow of the intake air that flows out of the first passage portion and merges with the intake air flowing out of the second passage portion.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">With this arrangement, by controlling the flow of the intake air flowing through the first passage portion by means of the flow control device, it is possible to adjust the flow rate of the intake air that flows through the sub canister. Therefore, it is possible to control the amount of the fuel vapor that is desorbed from the sub canister.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">In a further embodiment, the first passage portion and the second passage portion receive the supply of the intake air independently of each other. With this embodiment, even in the event that an amount of the fuel vapor exceeding the capacity of the sub canister has been supplied to the sub canister and a part of the fuel vapor has been dissipated from the sub canister, it is possible to prevent the fuel vapor from flowing into the intake air passage by blocking or closing the first passage portion. Hence, it is possible to avoid such a situation that the engine is difficult to be started.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In a still further embodiment, the sub canister is configured such that the loss of pressure of the intake air flowing through the sub canister is smaller than the loss of pressure of the intake air flowing through the main canister. With this embodiment, it is possible to reduce or minimize the loss of pressure of the intake air that may be cause by the sub canister.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In a still further embodiment, a system includes a fuel tank constructed to store a fuel, an intake air passage communicating with an engine and constructed to supply an intake air to the engine, and a first canister and a second canister each configured to be able to adsorb a fuel vapor. The first canister is disposed within the intake air passage. The second canister is disposed outside of the intake air passage. A first communication passage communicates between the first canister and the second canister. A second communication passage communicates between the second canister and the intake air passage.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">A fuel vapor processing apparatus according to a first embodiment of the present invention will now be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1(A) and 1(B)</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The fuel vapor processing apparatus of this embodiment is adapted to be installed on a vehicle, such as an automobile.</p>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">&#x3c;General Construction of Fuel Vapor Processing Apparatus&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a fuel vapor processing apparatus <b>10</b> generally includes a main canister <b>20</b>, a sub canister <b>30</b>, a communication passage <b>12</b>, a purge passage <b>14</b> and a fuel vapor passage <b>16</b>. The sub canister <b>30</b> is disposed within an intake air passage <b>4</b> of a vehicle engine E. The communication passage <b>12</b> communicates between the main canister <b>20</b> and the intake air passage <b>4</b>. The fuel vapor passage <b>16</b> communicates between the main canister <b>20</b> and an upper gas chamber Ta of a fuel tank T. A control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is disposed within the purge passage <b>14</b>. The control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is remote-controlled by an ECU of the engine E. More specifically, the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is closed during the stop of the engine E, while the degree of opening of the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is controlled to suitably adjust the air-fuel ratio of the engine E during the operation of the engine E.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">&#x3c;Main Canister <b>20</b>&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the main canister <b>20</b> is configured as a substantially sealed container having an inner space. More specifically, the inner space of the main canister <b>20</b> is divided into an upper chamber and a lower chamber by a lower horizontal wall <b>23</b><i>z </i>made of filtration material. The lower chamber serves as a dissipation chamber <b>26</b>. The upper chamber is divided further into an auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> and a main chamber <b>25</b> positioned on the left side and the right side as viewed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, respectively. An adsorption material C is filled into each of the auxiliary camber <b>24</b> and the main chamber <b>25</b>. The adsorption material C may be made, for example, of activated carbon, and can adsorb the fuel vapor. Purging with air can desorb the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption material C.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">With the adsorption material C filled into each of the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> and the main chamber <b>25</b>, an upper horizontal wall <b>23</b><i>u </i>is attached to cover the upper side of the adsorption materials C. A space is defined on the upper side of the upper horizontal wall <b>23</b> within the main canister <b>20</b>. The main canister <b>20</b> has an atmospheric port <b>24</b><i>a</i>, a purge port <b>25</b><i>p </i>and a tank port <b>25</b><i>t</i>. The atmospheric port <b>2</b><i>a </i>communicates with the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> via the upper space of the upper horizontal wall <b>23</b> and through the upper horizontal wall <b>23</b>. Each of the purge port <b>25</b><i>p </i>and the tank port <b>25</b><i>t </i>communicates with the main chamber <b>25</b> via the upper space of the upper horizontal wall <b>23</b> and through the upper horizontal wall <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The tank port <b>25</b><i>t </i>communicates with the upper gas chamber Ta of the fuel tank T via the fuel vapor passage <b>16</b>. The purge port <b>25</b><i>p </i>communicates with the intake air passage <b>4</b> via the purge passage <b>14</b> at a position on the downstream side of the throttle valve <b>6</b>. The atmospheric port <b>24</b><i>a </i>communicates with the sub canister <b>30</b> via the communication passage <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">&#x3c;Sub Canister <b>30</b>&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the sub canister <b>30</b> is disposed within the intake air passage <b>4</b> to extend across the intake air passage <b>4</b> at a position on the upstream side of the throttle valve <b>6</b>. The sub canister <b>30</b> has a container formed of an air permeable thin plate. The inner space of the container is divided into a plurality of chambers by air permeable thin plates similar to the thin plate of the container. In this embodiment, the inner space of the container is divided into three chambers, i.e., a central chamber <b>32</b>, an upstream-side chamber <b>33</b> and a downstream-side chamber <b>34</b>. The upstream-side chamber <b>33</b> and the downstream-side chamber <b>34</b> are positioned on the upstream side and the downstream side of the central chamber <b>32</b>, respectively. An adsorption material D is filled into each of the upstream-side chamber <b>33</b> and the downstream-side chamber <b>34</b>. The adsorption material D may be made of activated carbon and may be the same as the adsorption material C of the main canister <b>20</b>. However, preferably, the activated carbon of the adsorption material D may be molded to have tubular or honeycomb configurations and may be oriented in the direction of flow of the intake air in order to minimize the loss of pressure of the intake air flowing though the intake air passage <b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The sub canister <b>30</b> is positioned within the intake air passage <b>4</b> such that the central chamber <b>32</b> communicates with a branch port <b>4</b><i>p </i>of the intake air passage <b>4</b>. The branch port <b>4</b><i>p </i>is connected to the communication passage <b>12</b>. Therefore, the central chamber <b>32</b> communicates with the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> of the main canister <b>20</b> via the branch port <b>4</b><i>p </i>of the intake air passage <b>4</b> and the communication passage <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">&#x3c;Operation of Fuel Vapor Processing Apparatus&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The operations of the fuel vapor processing apparatus <b>10</b> will be first described with regard to the operation during the stop of the engine E.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As indicated by arrows in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1(A)</figref>, the fuel vapor produced within the fuel tank T is introduced into the fuel vapor passage <b>16</b> and further into the main chamber <b>25</b> of the main canister <b>20</b> via the tank port <b>25</b><i>t</i>, so that the fuel vapor may be adsorbed by the adsorption material C filled within the main chamber <b>25</b>. An amount of the fuel vapor that has not been adsorbed by the adsorption material C of the main chamber <b>25</b> may be introduced into the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> via the dissipation chamber <b>26</b>. The control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is closed during the stop of the engine E, so that no fuel vapor flows into the intake air passage <b>4</b> via the purge passage <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The adsorption material C of the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> can adsorb the fuel vapor that is introduced into the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b>. An amount of the fuel vapor that has still not been adsorbed by the adsorption material C of the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> may be introduced into the central chamber <b>32</b> of the sub canister <b>30</b> via the atmospheric port <b>24</b><i>a</i>, the communication passage <b>12</b> and the branch port <b>4</b><i>p</i>, so that the fuel vapor may be adsorbed by the adsorption materials D filled within the upstream-side chamber <b>33</b> and the downstream-side chamber <b>34</b>. Therefore, it is possible to prevent the fuel vapor from dissipation into the atmosphere.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The operation of the fuel vapor processing apparatus <b>10</b> during the operation of the engine E will now be described. During the operation of the engine E, intake air enters into the intake air passage <b>4</b> via an air filter <b>2</b> and is then supplied to the engine E as indicated by arrows in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1(B)</figref>. As the intake air flows through the sub canister <b>30</b> disposed within the intake air passage <b>4</b>, the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption materials D of the sub canister <b>30</b> may be purged with the intake air. In addition, during the operation of the engine E, the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is opened, so that the negative pressure produced by the flow of the intake air within the intake air passage <b>4</b> may be applied to the central chamber <b>32</b> of the sub canister <b>30</b> via the purge passage <b>14</b>, the main chamber <b>25</b> and the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> of the main canister <b>20</b>, and the communication passage <b>12</b>. Therefore, the intake air may flow through the upstream-side chamber <b>33</b> and the downstream-side chamber <b>34</b> of the sub canister <b>30</b>. The intake air containing the purged vapor fuel may then flow into the communication passage <b>12</b> via the central chamber <b>32</b> and may thereafter flow through the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> and the main chamber <b>25</b> of the main canister <b>20</b>. Hence, the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption materials C of the main canister <b>20</b> may be purged with the intake air containing the fuel vapor and may be introduced into the intake air passage <b>4</b> via the purge passage <b>14</b> at a position on the downstream side of the throttle valve <b>6</b>. During this operation, the degree of opening of the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>is controlled based on the control signal from the ECU such that the air-fuel ratio of the engine E is suitably set.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">&#x3c;Advantages of Fuel Vapor Processing Apparatus <b>10</b>&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">According to the fuel vapor processing apparatus <b>10</b> of this embodiment, during the operation of the engine E, the intake air flowing through the intake air passage <b>4</b> can purge the fuel vapor adsorbed within the sub canister <b>30</b>. After purging the fuel vapor of the sub canister <b>30</b>, the intake air is introduced into the main canister <b>20</b> via the communication passage <b>12</b> to purge the fuel vapor within the main canister <b>20</b>. Thereafter, the intake air containing the purged fuel vapor returns to the intake air passage <b>4</b> via the purge passage <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In this way, because the sub canister <b>30</b> is disposed within the intake air passage <b>4</b> of the engine E, it is possible to purge the fuel vapor contained within the sub canister <b>30</b> by a large amount separately from the main canister <b>20</b>. In other words, even in the case that it is necessary to restrain the amount of purging the fuel vapor contained within the main canister <b>20</b> due to the relationship with the air-fuel ratio control, it is possible to purge the fuel vapor contained within the sub canister <b>30</b> by a large amount. Hence, the remaining amount of the fuel vapor within the sub canister <b>30</b> can be reduced, and therefore, it is possible to inhibit dissipation of the fuel vapor into the atmosphere.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In addition, because the sub canister <b>30</b> extends across the intake air passage <b>4</b>, the flow area of the sub canister <b>30</b> through which the intake air flows can be set to be larger than the cross sectional area of the communication passage <b>12</b>. Therefore, it is possible to ensure that the fuel vapor within the sub canister <b>30</b> is purged by a larger amount in comparison with the main canister <b>20</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">A second embodiment will now be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The second embodiment is a modification of the first embodiment. Therefore, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, like members are given the same reference numerals as the first embodiment, and the description of these members will not be repeated. In the first embodiment, the sub canister <b>30</b> extends over the entire cross sectional area of the intake air passage <b>4</b> in the first embodiment. However, in the second embodiment, the sub canister <b>30</b> extends along a part of the cross sectional area of the intake air passage <b>4</b> in the second embodiment. More specifically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a portion of the intake air passage <b>4</b> on the upstream side of the throttle valve <b>6</b> is divided into a main intake air passage <b>4</b><i>m </i>and an auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>by a partition wall <b>5</b>. The partition wall <b>5</b> extends in parallel to the lengthwise direction of the intake air passage <b>4</b> along a part of the length thereof. The sub canister <b>30</b> is positioned within the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>to extend across the same. Therefore, the sub canister <b>30</b> does not extend over the entire cross sectional area of the intake air passage <b>4</b>. With this arrangement, it is possible to reduce the loss of pressure within the intake air passage <b>4</b> in comparison with the arrangement of the first embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">Third Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">A third embodiment will now be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The third embodiment is a modification of the second embodiment and is different from the second embodiment in the construction of the sub canister <b>30</b> and the connecting point of the communication passage <b>12</b> (i.e., the position of the branch port <b>4</b><i>p</i>). In addition, the third embodiment is different from the second embodiment in the incorporation of a flow control valve <b>40</b> disposed at the downstream-side end of the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s. </i></p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">More specifically, according to a fuel vapor processing apparatus <b>50</b> of this embodiment, a sub canister <b>60</b> does not include the central chamber <b>32</b> that is provided in the canister <b>30</b> of the previously described embodiments. Instead, an adsorption material D is filled within a container having a single chamber. The sub canister <b>60</b> is positioned within the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>to extend across the same. The branch port <b>4</b><i>p </i>opens into the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>at a position on the downstream side of the sub canister <b>60</b> and communicates with the communication passage <b>12</b>. The flow control valve <b>40</b> is disposed on the downstream side of the branch port <b>4</b><i>p </i>and serves to control the flow rate of the intake air that flows through the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s</i>. The flow control valve <b>40</b> operates based on a control signal from the ECU so that the flow control valve <b>40</b> is fully closed during the stop of the engine E, and that the degree of opening of the flow control valve <b>40</b> changes to suitably set the air-fuel ratio is suitably set during the operation of the engine E.</p>
<p id="h-0013" num="0000">&#x3c;Operation of Fuel Vapor Processing Apparatus&#x3e;</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The operation of the fuel vapor processing apparatus <b>50</b> according to the third embodiment will now be described. During the stop of the engine E, the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>of the purge passage <b>14</b> and the flow control valve <b>40</b> of the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>are both fully closed. In this state, fuel vapor produced within the fuel tank T may be introduced into the main chamber <b>25</b> and the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> of the main canister <b>20</b>, so that the adsorption materials C filled within the main chamber <b>25</b> and the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> may adsorb the fuel vapor. An amount of the fuel vapor that has not been adsorbed by the adsorption materials C of the main chamber <b>25</b> and the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> is introduced into the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>via the communication passage <b>12</b> and the branch port <b>4</b><i>p</i>, so that the fuel vapor is adsorbed by the adsorption material D of the sub canister <b>60</b>. Therefore, it is possible to prevent the fuel vapor from dissipating into the atmosphere.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">During the operation of the engine E, the degree of opening of each of the flow control valve <b>40</b> of the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>and the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>of the purge passage <b>14</b> is adjusted based on the control signal from the ECU. Therefore, a part of the intake air flowing into the intake air passage <b>4</b> from the air filter <b>2</b> for supplying to the engine E may flow through the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>in which the sub canister <b>60</b> is disposed. Thus, the intake air flows through the sub canister <b>60</b> to purge the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption material D of the sub canister <b>60</b>. After flowing through the sub canister <b>60</b>, the intake air containing the purged fuel vapor may leave the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>via the flow control valve <b>40</b>. The degree of opening of the control valve <b>40</b> may be controlled based on the control signal from the ECU, so that the air-fuel ratio of the engine E can be suitably set.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In addition, during the operation of the engine E, the negative pressure within the intake air passage <b>4</b> is applied to the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>via the purge passage <b>14</b>, the main chamber <b>25</b> and the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> of the main canister <b>20</b>, and the communication passage <b>12</b>. Therefore, the intake air containing the fuel vapor that has passed through the sub canister <b>60</b> may enter the communication passage <b>12</b> and may flow further through the auxiliary chamber <b>24</b> and the main chamber <b>25</b> of the main canister <b>20</b>. Hence, the fuel vapor adsorbed by the adsorption materials C of the main canister <b>20</b> may be purged and may then be introduced into the intake air passage <b>4</b> via the purge passage <b>14</b>. During this operation, the control valve <b>14</b><i>v </i>may be controlled based on the control signal from the ECU, so that the air-fuel ratio of the engine E can be suitably set. Thus, the control valves <b>40</b> and <b>14</b><i>v </i>are controlled by the ECU to achieve a suitable air-fuel ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">In this way, according to the fuel vapor processing apparatus of this embodiment, the flow control valve <b>40</b> serves to control the flow of the intake air flowing through the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s</i>, which merges with the main intake air passage <b>4</b><i>m</i>. Therefore, it is possible to control the flow rate of the intake air flowing through the sub canister <b>60</b>. Hence, it is possible to control the amount of the fuel vapor that is purged or desorbed from the sub canister <b>60</b>.</p>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">Fourth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">A fourth embodiment will now be described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The fourth embodiment is a modification of the third embodiment and is different from the third embodiment in that an auxiliary air filter <b>2</b><i>s </i>is connected to the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>for the supply of the intake air into the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s</i>, while the air filter <b>2</b> supplies the intake air into the main intake air passage <b>4</b><i>m</i>. In other words, the main intake air passage <b>4</b><i>m </i>and the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>receive the supply of the intake air independently of each other.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">If an amount of the fuel vapor that exceeds the adsorption capacity of the sub canister <b>60</b> is supplied to the sub canister <b>60</b>, a part of the fuel vapor that may not be adsorbed by the sub canister <b>60</b> and may flow through the sub canister <b>60</b> without being adsorbed. However, during the stop of the engine E, the flow control valve <b>40</b> is closed, and therefore, the fuel vapor may not flow from the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s </i>into a portion of the intake air passage <b>4</b> on the downstream side of the auxiliary intake air passage <b>4</b><i>s</i>. Therefore, the fuel vapor may cause a problem that the engine E is difficult to be started.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>This invention claims:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A fuel vapor processing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a main canister constructed to adsorb a fuel vapor produced within a fuel tank;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sub canister constructed to adsorb a part of the fuel vapor that has passed through the main canister,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a communication passage communicating between the main canister and the sub canister; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a purge passage communicating between the main canister and an intake air passage of an engine; wherein:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sub canister is disposed within the intake air passage, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>during the operation of the engine, an intake air flowing through the intake air passage can (a) purge the fuel vapor adsorbed by the sub canister, (b) flow into the main canister via the communication passage, (c) purge the fuel vapor adsorbed by the main canister, and (d) return to the intake air passage via the purge passage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The fuel vapor processing apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an area of the sub canister through which the intake air flows is set to be larger than a cross sectional area of the communication passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The fuel vapor processing apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>a part of the intake air passage is divided into a first passage portion and a second passage portion by a partition wall extending substantially along the direction of flow of the intake air; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sub canister is disposed within the first passage portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The fuel vapor processing apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the communication passage is in communication with the first passage portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fuel vapor processing apparatus further comprises a flow control device disposed within the first passage portion and constructed to control the flow of the intake air that flows out of the first passage portion and merges with the intake air flowing out of the second passage portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The fuel vapor processing apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first passage portion and the second passage portion receive the supply of the intake air independently of each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The fuel vapor processing apparatus as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the sub canister is configured such that the loss of pressure of the intake air flowing through the sub canister is smaller than the loss of pressure of the intake air flowing through the main canister.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a fuel tank constructed to store a fuel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an intake air passage communicating with an engine and constructed to supply an intake air to the engine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first canister and a second canister each configured to be able to adsorb a fuel vapor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first canister is disposed within the intake air passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second canister is disposed outside of the intake air passage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first communication passage communicating between the first canister and the second canister; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second communication passage communicating between the second canister and the intake air passage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising a throttle valve disposed within the intake air passage, so that the intake air flows through the intake air passage from an upstream side of the throttle valve toward a downstream side of the throttle valve; wherein:
<claim-text>the first canister is disposed on the upstream side of the throttle valve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second communication passage communicates with the intake air passage at a position on the downstream side of the throttle valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a first control valve disposed within the second communication passage, wherein the first control valve is controlled in response to change of condition of the engine.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>a portion of the intake air passage on the upstream side of the throttle valve is divided into a first passage portion and a second passage portion by a partition extending substantially along the direction of flow of the intake air; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first canister is disposed within the first passage portion.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the first communication passage communicates with the first passage portion of the intake air passage at a first position on the downstream side of the first canister.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, further comprising a second control valve disposed within the first passage portion at a second position on the downstream side of the first position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the first passage portion and the second passage portion are configured to receive the supply of the intake air independently of each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A system comprising:
<claim-text>a fuel tank constructed to store a fuel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an intake air passage communicating with an engine and constructed to supply an intake air to the engine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a throttle valve disposed within the intake air passage, so that the intake air flows from an upstream side of the throttle valve toward a downstream side of the throttle valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first canister configured to be able to adsorb a fuel vapor and disposed within the intake air passage at a first position on the upstream side of the throttle valve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first communication passage communicating between the first canister and the fuel tank; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second communication passage communicating between the first canister and the intake air passage at a second position on the downstream side of the throttle valve.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising a second canister constructed to be able to adsorb the fuel vapor, wherein:
<claim-text>the second canister is disposed within the first communication passage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second communication passage includes a passage portion connecting between the second canister and the intake air passage.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the first canister comprises:
<claim-text>a central chamber; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upstream side chamber and a downstream side chamber disposed on an upstream side and a downstream side of the central chamber, respectively, and each containing a fuel vapor adsorption material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first communication passage communicates with the central chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the first canister extends across the intake air passage over the entire cross sectional area of the intake air passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The system as in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, wherein the first canister extends across a part of the cross sectional area of the intake air passage. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
