<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640971-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640971</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11761691</doc-number>
<date>20070612</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>219</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>28</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>165149</main-classification>
<further-classification> 29890052</further-classification>
<further-classification>165906</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Heat exchanger manifold sealing system</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4331201</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hesse</name>
<date>19820500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4351390</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Argyle et al.</name>
<date>19820900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165149</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4378174</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hesse</name>
<date>19830300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4544029</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cadars</name>
<date>19851000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165149</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4546822</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tamura</name>
<date>19851000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4649628</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Allemandou</name>
<date>19870300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165148</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4917182</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Beamer</name>
<date>19900400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165173</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4997035</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Beatenbough et al.</name>
<date>19910300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165173</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5195582</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Haase</name>
<date>19930300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5201368</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kroetsch</name>
<date>19930400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165173</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6082446</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ahaus et al.</name>
<date>20000700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165173</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0029874</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Boisselle et al.</name>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0144805</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kim et al.</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0039894</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Brost et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165149</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0133208</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Powers et al.</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165149</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0137866</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hernandez et al.</name>
<date>20060600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>165149</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>54815</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19820600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00018">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0406774</doc-number>
<date>19910100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00019">
<document-id>
<country>GB</country>
<doc-number>1433023</doc-number>
<date>19760400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-exemplary-claim>8</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>165149</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080308263</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081218</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kolb</last-name>
<first-name>John A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Old Lyme</city>
<state>CT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>DeLio &#x26; Peterson, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Peterson</last-name>
<first-name>Peter W.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Centrum Equitites Acquisition</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Nashville</city>
<state>TN</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Flanigan</last-name>
<first-name>Allen J</first-name>
<department>3744</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A heat exchanger manifold with improved sealing between the tank and header. The manifold includes a plastic heat exchanger tank having an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening. The lip has an outer surface and an upper surface extending outward of the tank opening, and a ridge extending upward from a portion of the upper surface extending substantially around the tank. The manifold further includes an aluminum heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core. The header has a groove around the periphery thereof receiving the tank lip and a plurality of plastically deformable tabs extending from an edge of the groove. The tabs are bent inward and contact the ridge on the tank lip to secure the tank to the header.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="161.80mm" wi="148.93mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="162.39mm" wi="167.64mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="122.00mm" wi="163.24mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="170.18mm" wi="146.73mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="142.41mm" wi="165.44mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="160.61mm" wi="148.93mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="176.95mm" wi="152.82mm" file="US07640971-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to heat exchangers and, in particular, to radiators employed with internal combustion engines used in motor vehicles.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">It has become common practice to use plastic tanks, usually made of glass-reinforced nylon 6/6 material, on heat exchangers with headered cores of brazed aluminum construction. Such heat exchangers include engine-cooling radiators, heaters and some intercoolers, primarily for automobile use. This plastic tank/aluminum (PTA) heat exchanger construction technique is also being used in some heavy-duty truck radiator applications. The problem with typical PTA construction is that it has always been considered inferior to more robust construction methods, such as tanks with gasketed, bolted tank-to-header joints, or soldered or welded tank-to-header joints. Such a judgment stems from the fact that the foot of a plastic tank is typically secured to a shallow groove in the aluminum header by means of bending tabs, which are part of the header, over the tank foot, with a rubber gasket seal between the tank foot and the bottom of the groove. When pressure is applied to the inside of the tank during operation, the tank foot tends to move upwards in a direction that tends to unbend the tabs. With repeated cycles of pressure, the tabs weaken, the compression on the gasket is relieved, and leakage of coolant to the outside occurs.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Other weaknesses of typical PTA construction include flexing of the plastic tank under cyclic pressure and temperature conditions, contributing to movement of the tank foot within the header groove, resulting in leakage. In addition, the header tab material is rendered soft by the core brazing process, making it prone to unbending during operation, leading to reduced pressure on the gasket and, ultimately, leaking. The gasket material chosen for PTA construction is not always of high quality sufficient to resist aging and stiffening under high temperatures. This is often the cause of leaking in PTA radiators. Such leaking problems are the reason for the poor reputation of PTA heat exchanger construction compared to more traditional construction methods. However, PTA construction readily lends itself to high volume, low cost production. If means could be found to overcome the shortcomings of PTA construction, it would be a welcome improvement.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Bearing in mind the problems and deficiencies of the prior art, it is therefore an object of the present invention to provide an improved heat exchanger manifold.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">It is a further object of the present invention to provide an improved heat exchanger manifold sealing system and method that is particularly useful in plastic tank and aluminum header applications.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">It is another object of the present invention to provide an improved heat exchanger manifold sealing system and method that reduces the tendency to unbend tabs used to secure the tank foot during operation and use of the heat exchanger.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">It is yet another object of the present invention to provide a heat exchanger manifold sealing system that reduces the tendency of the tank foot to rotate in the header groove during operation.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A further object of the invention is to provide an improved gasket seal and sealing method in a heat exchanger manifold.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Still other objects and advantages of the invention will in part be obvious and will in part be apparent from the specification.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The above and other objects, which will be apparent to those skilled in the art, are achieved in the present invention which is directed to a heat exchanger manifold comprising a heat exchanger tank having an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening. The lip has an outer surface and an upper surface extending outward of the tank opening, and a ridge extending upward from a portion of the upper surface extending substantially around the tank. The manifold further includes a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core. The header has a groove around the periphery thereof receiving the tank lip and at least one plastically deformable tab extending from an edge of the groove. The at least one plastically deformable tab is bent inward and contacting the ridge on the tank lip to secure the tank to the header.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Preferably, the at least one plastically deformable header tab is metal, and the metal tab is work hardened near the contact with the ridge on the tank lip. The plastically deformable header tab is preferably free of contact with the lip upper surface inward of the ridge. The tank and tank lip are preferably plastic, and the tank has a semi-circular cross-section opposite the opening. The tank lip has a height and a width, and preferably has a lip depth to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1. The groove has a depth and a width, and preferably has a groove depth to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1. The tank lip width is preferably substantially equal to the groove width to create a sliding fit between the tank lip and the groove walls. More preferably, the tank lip penetrates into the groove at least about 2.05 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">More preferably, the manifold further includes an elastomeric gasket in the header groove contacting the tank lip lower surface. The gasket has an elliptical cross section in an undeformed state with a major diameter in the width direction of the groove and a minor diameter in the depth direction of the groove. The gasket is deformed by contact with the tank lip to fill essentially the entire region between the groove and the tank lip lower surface, thereby sealing the tank lip and tank opening to the header.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In another aspect, the present invention is directed to a heat exchanger manifold comprising a heat exchanger tank having an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening. The lip has an outer surface and an inner surface and a lip width therebetween. The manifold also includes a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core. The header has a groove formed by opposite walls extending around the periphery thereof, with the groove receiving the tank lip. The groove has a depth and a width between the opposite groove walls, with a depth to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Preferably, the tank lip has an upper surface extending outward of the tank opening and a ridge extending upward from a portion of the upper surface extending substantially around the tank lip, and the header groove has at least one tab extending from an edge of the groove, with the at least one tab being bent inward and contacting the ridge on the tank lip to secure the tank to the header. Preferably the tank lip is plastic and the tank lip width is substantially equal to the header groove width to create a sliding fit between the tank lip and the groove walls.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In a further aspect, the present invention is directed to a method of assembling a heat exchanger manifold comprising providing a heat exchanger tank having an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening, the lip having an outer surface and an upper surface extending outward of the tank opening, and a ridge extending upward from a portion of the upper surface extending substantially around the tank. The method also provides a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core, the header having a groove around the periphery thereof for receiving the tank lip and at least one tab extending from an edge of the groove. The method then includes mating the tank to the header so that the tank lip is received in the header groove, and bending an upper portion of the at least one tab inward to contact the ridge on the tank lip to secure the tank to the header.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The method preferably includes using a plurality of header tabs made of metal, and bending the metal tabs using the ridge as a fulcrum to plastically deform the metal tab.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Prior to mating the tank to the header, the method preferably includes placing in the header groove an elastomeric gasket, the gasket having an elliptical cross section in an undeformed state with a major diameter in the width direction of the groove and a minor diameter in the depth direction of the groove. Subsequent to mating the tank to the header, the method preferably includes deforming the gasket by contact with the tank lip to fill essentially the entire region between the groove and the tank lip lower surface and seal the tank opening to the header, thereby sealing the tank lip and tank opening to the header.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Preferably, the tank lip is plastic and the groove is formed by opposite walls extending around the periphery of the header, and the tank lip width is substantially equal to width of the header groove to create a sliding fit between the tank lip and the groove walls.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In yet another aspect, the present invention provides a heat exchanger manifold comprising a heat exchanger tank having an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening, the tank lip having a lower surface, and a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core, the header having a groove formed by opposite walls extending around the periphery thereof, the groove having a depth and a width between the opposite walls, the groove receiving the tank lip. The manifold further includes an elastomeric gasket in a region of the header groove below the tank lip lower surface. The gasket has an elliptical cross section in an undeformed state with a major diameter in the width direction of the groove and a minor diameter in the height direction of the groove. The gasket is deformed by contact with the tank lip to fill essentially the entire region between the groove and the tank lip lower surface, thereby sealing the tank lip and tank opening to the header.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In a related aspect, the present invention provides a method of assembling a heat exchanger manifold comprising providing a heat exchanger tank having an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening, the tank lip having a lower surface, and providing a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core, the header having a groove formed by opposite walls extending around the periphery thereof, the groove having a depth and a width between the opposite walls, the groove adapted to receive the tank lip. The method includes placing in the header groove an elastomeric gasket, the gasket having an elliptical cross section in an undeformed state with a major diameter in the width direction of the groove and a minor diameter in the depth direction of the groove. The method then includes mating the tank to the header so that the tank lip is received in the header groove and the tank lip lower surface contacts the elastomeric gasket, and deforming the gasket by contact with the tank lip to fill essentially the entire region between the groove and the tank lip lower surface and seal the tank opening to the header, thereby sealing the tank lip and tank opening to the header.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The features of the invention believed to be novel and the elements characteristic of the invention are set forth with particularity in the appended claims. The figures are for illustration purposes only and are not drawn to scale. The invention itself, however, both as to organization and method of operation, may best be understood by reference to the detailed description which follows taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross sectional elevational view of a preferred tank of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a top plan view of the tank of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> mated with a header made in accordance with the present invention, prior to crimping of the tabs.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross sectional elevational view of a portion of the preferred header of the present invention prior to assembly with the tank.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side elevational view of a portion of the header of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> showing the ribs on the undeformed tabs.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top plan view of an end portion of the header of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross sectional elevational view of the tank of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> mated and sealed to the header of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> in accordance with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In describing the preferred embodiments of the present invention, reference will be made herein to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-6</figref> of the drawings in which like numerals refer to like features of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As used herein, a heat exchanger manifold consists of an inlet or outlet tank for the heat exchanger coolant, a header for attachment to the tubes of a heat exchanger core, and a seal between the tank and header joint. Preferably, the tank is made of an otherwise conventional molded plastic such as glass-reinforced nylon 6/6 material, and the header is made of a metal such as aluminum. Other types of tank and header materials may also be employed. The heat exchanger manifold of the present invention may be used in heavy-duty truck or other motor vehicle heat exchangers, such as in automobile radiators of superior durability, or in other heat exchanger applications where strength, vibration resistance and long life are required.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, tank <b>22</b> is elongated such that its length (horizontally in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) is greater than its width (vertically in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). Preferably for truck or other heavy-duty motor vehicle radiator applications, the upper surface has a semicircular configuration as seen in a cross-section normal to the tank length (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and has a wall thickness typically of about 0.155 in. (3.9 mm) for good stiffness to minimize tank flexing. The preferred tank of the present invention achieves sufficient strength and stiffness without the necessity for ribs in the tank upper walls. The tank has an opening <b>21</b> on a lower side thereof for mating with the header, and a foot or lip <b>24</b> extending outward from the tank opening around substantially the entire periphery of the opening. The foot or lip <b>24</b> has opposite inner <b>26</b> and outer <b>27</b> surfaces, and opposite upper <b>25</b> and lower <b>28</b> surfaces. The width of the foot or lip <b>24</b> is shown as W<sub>F</sub>. Along the outer portion of upper surface <b>25</b>, near the outer surface <b>27</b>, is disposed an upwardly extending ridge <b>23</b> that is essentially continuous around the periphery of the tank. Ridge <b>23</b> covers only a portion of upper surface <b>25</b>, <b>50</b> that the portion of upper surface <b>25</b> adjacent the tank <b>22</b> wall is lower than the maximum height of the ridge. The preferred tank foot as shown has a vertical height H<sub>F </sub>between upper surface <b>25</b> and lower surface <b>28</b> that is greater than the foot width W<sub>F</sub>, and may be at least 1.5 or 2 times the foot width.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The preferred heat exchanger header of the present invention is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-5</figref>. Header <b>40</b> includes openings <b>41</b> for receiving the ends of tubes <b>62</b> of an otherwise conventional heat exchanger core <b>60</b>. Fins <b>64</b> are secured to the tubes to dissipate heat from coolant flowing through the tubes. Although the connection between header <b>40</b> and tubes <b>62</b> may be any type known in the prior art, the present invention is especially useful where the core tubes <b>62</b> are brazed to the header openings <b>41</b>. A groove extends around the periphery of header <b>40</b> for mating with the foot or lip <b>24</b> of the tank <b>22</b>. The groove is formed by inner vertical wall <b>42</b>, outer vertical wall <b>44</b>, and lower wall <b>46</b> connecting the vertical walls. Outer wall <b>44</b> has a plurality of upper portions terminating in end edge <b>45</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the upper portion of wall <b>44</b> comprises a plurality of spaced tabs <b>43</b> that will be bent along phantom line <b>47</b>&#x2032; inward in the direction of arrow <b>60</b> after mating with the tank, as will be explained in more detail below. Each tab <b>43</b> is spaced from an adjacent tab by a slot extending below phantom bend line <b>47</b>&#x2032;, and the tabs extend substantially around the periphery of the header groove. To provide for further tab strength against tab unbending, the preferred heat exchanger header incorporates at last one stiffening rib <b>50</b> having an upper portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>extending into each tab <b>43</b>, substantially normal or perpendicular to the direction of bend line <b>47</b>&#x2032;. The rib may be formed by embossing or otherwise plastically deforming the groove outer wall <b>44</b>. Ribs may be included on all or fewer than all of the tabs.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The width of the groove is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> as dimension W<sub>G</sub>, the distance between inner and outer walls <b>42</b> and <b>44</b>, respectively. The depth of the groove is shown as dimension D<sub>G</sub>, the dimension between the top of the header plate <b>40</b> and the top of the groove lower surface <b>46</b>. The header groove is narrow in relation to its depth, preferably being as narrow as possible relative to its depth as manufacturing standards would allow. More preferably, the ratio of depth to width is at least about 1.5:1. In a typical truck or heavy-duty automobile radiator application of the present invention, the groove depth is about 0.300 in. (7.6 mm) and the width is about 0.205 in (5.2 mm).</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Disposed in the bottom of the header grove is a continuous ring-type elastomeric gasket <b>70</b>. To eliminate gasket deterioration under high coolant operating temperatures, the tank-to-header gasket <b>70</b> used in the heat exchanger manifold is made of EPDM rubber, preferably in an elliptical cross section. The major diameter M of the gasket elliptical cross-section is disposed in the direction of the width of the groove, and the minor diameter m of the gasket elliptical cross-section is disposed in the direction of the depth of the groove. Because of the general incompressibility of rubber, the seal is designed with an elliptical cross section to insure that the void between the tank foot and the header groove becomes completely filled by the rubber when the gasket is deformed between the tank foot and the groove side and bottom walls during assembly, as will be discussed further below.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The mated and assembled heat exchanger manifold <b>20</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. After placing elliptical elastomeric gasket <b>70</b> in the bottom of the header groove, tank foot or lip <b>24</b> is received over the gasket so that the lower surface <b>28</b> of the foot contacts the upper surface of gasket <b>70</b>. The width W<sub>F </sub>of the foot (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) is substantially equal to the width W<sub>G </sub>of the header groove (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), so that a sliding contact is created between the inner and outer surfaces <b>26</b>, <b>27</b> of the tank foot and the respective inner and outer walls <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of the header groove. In a typical heavy-duty motor vehicle application, the tank foot preferably has a penetration P (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) along the groove inner wall, below the entry radius, of at least about 2.05&#xb1;0.02 mm. The depth of penetration is sufficient to prevent rotational flexing of the foot within the groove when the tank is under pressure. The narrow header groove accommodates the tank foot, which substantially reduces any tendency of rotation of the tank foot within the header groove.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">To secure the header to the tank, the tabs <b>43</b> are bent inwards along bend line <b>47</b>&#x2032; (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>) so that they contact ridge <b>23</b> along the outer portion of foot top surface <b>25</b>. Ridge <b>23</b> provides a fulcrum for the bending of the retaining header tabs <b>43</b> during manifold assembly. When tabs <b>43</b> are bent, the metal becomes work-hardened in the area <b>47</b> of the bend. In operation of the finished heat exchanger manifold, the ridge or fulcrum becomes the point at which unbending stresses are applied to the work-hardened tabs at the very point where they are strongest. Rib portion <b>50</b><i>a </i>also bends and work hardens, and provides extra strength to the finished structure. In contrast to typical prior tab/tank foot designs, the tabs <b>43</b> of the present invention do not have to contact the upper surface <b>25</b> of the tank foot except at ridge <b>23</b>, where the tabs are hardened. The end <b>45</b> of the tab inward of ridge <b>23</b> sees no deformation or work hardening, and is preferably spaced from and free of contact with the foot upper surface.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As the tabs <b>43</b> are crimped over the tank foot, the foot lower surface <b>28</b> is forced down against the top of elliptical gasket <b>70</b> toward the groove bottom surface <b>46</b>. These forces cause the elliptical gasket to be deformed so that the gasket fills essentially the entire region between the groove walls <b>42</b>, <b>44</b>, <b>46</b> and the tank foot lower surface <b>28</b>. Minor spaces <b>71</b> may still be present around corner areas of the gasket after deformation. Sealing stress is created as the rubber pushes out radially against the constraining surfaces of the foot and the header groove. The gasket loading together with the close sliding fit of the tank foot creates a hydraulic lock with the header groove. The gasket material and elliptical shape, together with the close fitting piston-like tank foot that penetrates deep inside the gasket groove, load the incompressible elastomeric gasket material in such a way that minimizes the long term effects of gasket relaxation, squeeze-out, permanent deformation and chemical effects. These have been found to be significant factors that play a major role in the reliability of plastic tank-to-header sealing.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The present invention takes advantage of the work hardening of the metal retaining tabs during bending by directing the unbending stresses, which result from pressurizing the tank, to that portion of the retaining tabs which have been work hardened. This is accomplished by means of ridge <b>23</b> on the tank foot upper surface <b>25</b>. The balance of the upper surface of the tank foot is lower than the ridge in that region of the tabs which may be still soft from the brazing operation used to secure the core tubes to the header openings. This feature, combined with tab stiffening ribs, high-quality EPDM rubber elliptical gasket, deep header grooves, long tank foot and thicker, semi-circular tank cross-section, will result in a PTA heat exchanger construction which will provide a long, leak-free, useful life to rival traditional prior art construction techniques. To provide some measure of useful life, pressure cycle tests have shown that the heat exchanger manifold of the present invention will survive 250,000 cycles of the standard pressure cycle test that is normally applied to typical PTA production radiators. By comparison, the typical requirement for automobile original equipment PTA construction radiators is 150,000 cycles, the typical requirement for large, heavy-duty original equipment bolt-up radiators is 65,000 cycles, and the typical requirement for soldered aftermarket automobile radiators is only 15,000 cycles.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">While the present invention has been particularly described, in conjunction with a specific preferred embodiment, it is evident that many alternatives, modifications and variations will be apparent to those skilled in the art in light of the foregoing description. It is therefore contemplated that the appended claims will embrace any such alternatives, modifications and variations as falling within the true scope and spirit of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>Thus, having described the invention, what is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A heat exchanger manifold comprising:
<claim-text>a heat exchanger tank having an inner wall, an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening, the lip having an inner surface extending straight from the tank inner wall, an outer surface and an upper surface extending outward of the tank opening, and a ridge extending upward from a portion of the upper surface extending substantially around the tank, the tank lip having a height and a width, and a lip height to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core, the header having a groove around the periphery thereof receiving the tank lip, the groove having a depth and a width between opposite groove walls, and a groove depth to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1, the header groove width being substantially equal to the tank lip width to create a sliding fit between the tank lip and the groove walls, and at least one plastically deformable tab extending from an edge of the groove, the at least one plastically deformable tab being bent inward and contacting the ridge on the tank lip to secure the tank to the header, the at least one plastically deformable header tab being free of contact with the lip upper surface inward of the ridge.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The heat exchanger manifold of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the at least one plastically deformable header tab is metal, and wherein the metal tab is work hardened near the contact with the ridge on the tank lip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The heat exchanger manifold of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tank lip has a lower surface, and further including an elastomeric gasket in the header groove contacting the tank lip lower surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The heat exchanger manifold of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tank lip penetrates into the groove at least about 2.05 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The heat exchanger manifold of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tank lip has a flat lower surface, and further including an EPDM rubber gasket in a region of the header groove below the tank lip lower surface, the gasket having an elliptical cross section in an undeformed state with a major diameter in the width direction of the groove and a minor diameter in the depth direction of the groove, the gasket being deformed by contact with the tank lip to fill essentially the entire region between the groove and the tank lip flat lower surface, thereby sealing the tank lip and tank opening to the header.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The heat exchanger manifold of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tank lip has a width and the groove has a depth and a width, and wherein the tank lip width is substantially equal to the groove width.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The heat exchanger manifold of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the tank is plastic and has a semi-circular cross-section opposite the opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method of assembling a heat exchanger manifold comprising:
<claim-text>providing a heat exchanger tank having an inner wall, an opening for mating with a header and a lip extending substantially around a periphery of the opening, the lip having an inner surface extending straight from the tank inner wall, an outer surface and an upper surface extending outward of the tank opening, and a ridge extending upward from a portion of the upper surface extending substantially around the tank, the tank lip having a height and a width, and a lip height to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing a heat exchanger header adapted to connect to a heat exchanger core, the header having a groove around the periphery thereof for receiving the tank lip, the groove having a depth and a width between opposite groove walls, and a groove depth to width ratio of at least about 1.5:1, the header groove width being substantially equal to the tank up width, and at least one tab extending from an edge of the groove;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mating the tank to the header so that the tank lip is received in the header groove to create a sliding fit between the tank lip and the groove walls; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>bending an upper portion of the at least one tab inward to contact the ridge on the tank lip to secure the tank to the header, the tab being free of contact with the lip upper surface inward of the ridge.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> including a plurality of header tabs made of metal, and bending the metal tabs using the ridge as a fulcrum to plastically deform the metal tab.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the tank lip has a flat lower surface and further including, prior to mating the tank to the header,
<claim-text>placing in the header groove an EPDM rubber gasket, the gasket having an elliptical cross section in an undeformed state with a major diameter in the width direction of the groove and a minor diameter in the depth direction of the groove; and, subsequent to mating the tank to the header,</claim-text>
<claim-text>deforming the gasket by contact with the tank lip to fill essentially the entire region between the groove and the tank lip flat lower surface and seal the tank opening to the header, thereby sealing the tank lip and tank opening to the header. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
