<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640839-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640839</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11073507</doc-number>
<date>20050307</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>668</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 89  111</main-classification>
<further-classification> 89  134</further-classification>
<further-classification>361232</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Method and apparatus for improving the effectiveness of electrical discharge weapons</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5654867</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Murray</name>
<date>19970800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5786546</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Simson</name>
<date>19980700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>102438</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5936183</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McNulty, Sr.</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89  111</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6575073</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>McNulty et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89  111</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6729222</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>McNulty, Jr.</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89  134</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7075770</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Smith</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361232</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0170418</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>McNulty, Jr. et al.</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89  111</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0010184</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>McNulty, Jr.</name>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 89  134</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0187610</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Su</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361232</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>2</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 89  111</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 89  134</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361232</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation-in-part>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10719131</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20031121</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11073507</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation-in-part>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20050262994</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20051201</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>McNulty, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>James F.</first-name>
<address>
<street>1290 Third St.</street>
<city>Calimesa</city>
<state>CA</state>
<postcode>92320</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Ishman Law Firm P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chambers</last-name>
<first-name>Troy</first-name>
<department>3641</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cartridge for propelling a pair of wire-tethered contact darts for disabling a remote target with an electrical discharge. The cartridge comprises two bores each having one wire-tethered dart in front of an electrically activated pyrotechnic. A cartridge contains two separated straight bores, which each launch a single dart assemblage with a single primer of standard manufacture. A single 200 large rifle primer can launch a single dart assemblage reasonably accurately to 30 feet from the cartridge. Each assemblage is deflected to a predicted angle of flight when it collides with a center hinged cover as it exits the cartridge. This arrangement allows for longer flight distances and tighter, but still effective, dart spreads throughout the travel.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="125.14mm" wi="179.41mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="192.53mm" wi="109.64mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="213.87mm" wi="114.55mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="218.19mm" wi="100.92mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="206.16mm" wi="119.13mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="191.01mm" wi="111.00mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="209.13mm" wi="182.20mm" file="US07640839-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present application is a continuation-in-part of application Ser. No. 10/719,131 filed on Nov. 21, 2003 now abandoned.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates generally to the field of electrical discharge weapons and specifically to a method and apparatus for improving their effectiveness.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Background Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Stun pistols are weapons that connect a shocking power supply to a remote human target. Peace officers routinely use stun pistols to incapacitate violent suspects when lethal force is not justified. Stun pistols have a lower lethality than conventional side arms.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A stun pistol fires a pair of electrically opposed darts toward a target. Each dart has a trailing conductor, which remains connected to an alternate pole of a shocking supply. When both of the paired darts contact the target, a shock is passed between the darts through the target.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Both darts and tethered conductors are contained within the single Y shaped bore of an ammunition cartridge prior to firing. A variation of such a cartridge is described in U.S. Pat. No. 5,654,867 to Murray (April, 1997). Looking at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> therein, the dart assemblages <b>69</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>62</b> and <b>71</b>, <b>77</b>, <b>64</b> are each seated in the bore in front of a single metal cased propelling primer <b>78</b> at the bore exits along with a portion of their tethered conductor (not shown). Each conductor then feeds from the back of its dart assemblage and out through the bore to one of two wire storage chambers (not shown) in the cartridge and, then, alternatively, to either supply contact <b>83</b> or supply contact <b>78</b>, which is also the propelling primer. Desirably, the lower or angle launched dart assembly <b>71</b>, <b>77</b>, <b>64</b> is connected to supply contact <b>83</b> to avoid arcing shorts between the alternate <b>69</b>, <b>67</b>, <b>62</b> assemblage and the <b>83</b> contact when attempting to pass a shock through a remote target.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">When the stun pistol's power supply is energized, the sparking current passes through the tethered conductor from <b>83</b> to <b>64</b>, arcs between <b>64</b> and <b>62</b>, passes through the remaining tethered conductor from <b>62</b> to <b>82</b> and, then, sparks from <b>82</b> to <b>78</b> and ignites the detonating powder (typically a mixture comprising lead styphnate and glass frit, which aids percussion ignition) contained therein. The dart assemblages are propelled forward and the circuit opens until it again completes through a remote human target. A Berdan type 200 large rifle primer, with its anvil removed for electrical ignition, can launch both darts to a distance of up to 15 feet from the pistol without a projectile drop significant enough to effect aiming accuracy. The bore is not rifled to spin the darts, so with wire drag and gravitation forces, the flight of the darts follows a standard downward trajectory arc, which is mitigated by dart velocity, which, among other things, reduces the time of flight to the target as the dart will remain in flight only for the time it would take for the dart to drop most directly from the launcher horizontally to ground. Depending on the transformer orientation, the current might also follow a reverse path from 78 to 83 to ignite the propellant charge.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Stun pistol cartridges are small, compact, easily transportable rounds, which are suitable for loading into a small handheld firearm. Depending upon the ammunition manufacturer, the nearest perimeter of each bore exit is between &#x215b;<sup>th </sup>inch to 6/8<sup>th </sup>inch distant from the other. However, when contacting a target, the darts must be at least 7 inches distant from each other for the stun pistol shocks to pass through enough musculature to incapacitate an assailant. Stun pistols incapacitate by rigidly fixating joints. Each shock causes the muscle in its path to contract. Stun pistol pulses are repeated at a rate where the muscle cannot fully return to a relaxed state between shocks. The muscle remains in a temporarily shortened or taunt state while the train of pulses passes through it. Thereby, joints may become fixated, and if enough of the musculoskeletal system is involved, the target is incapacitated. Accordingly, manufacturers angle one or both of the cartridge bores from horizontal, so the darts will become more distant from each other in flight from the bore exits to the target. Depending upon ammunition manufacturer, launching angles are between 7&#xb0; and 11&#xb0;. This means that the darts may not be sufficiently distant from each other to pass an incapacitating shock train during the first 3 feet to 4 feet of flight and are likely too distant to both land in a target to complete a shocking circuit after 15 feet of flight. The best effective stun pistol range is from 8 feet to 12 feet. Depending on the manufacturer, a stun pistol's high tension pulse train occurs at a frequency of 10 to 25 pulses per second and a power of between 2.5 and 25 watts.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It is quite risky for a peace officer, armed with a stun pistol, to be within 15 feet, even 21 feet, of a violent suspect. Should the officer miss the suspect when firing or the stun pistol fail to incapacitate the suspect for another reason, the suspect might easily reach and attempt to overpower the officer before he or she could draw their side arm or other weapon. In the ensuing scuffle, the officer might lose his or her side arm and be killed or injured with it.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Of course, there are additional obstacles to improving stun pistol range. As stated, the cartridge launches its darts by explosion of a primer without any other propellant charge in much the same way that the original Louis Flobert (1819-1894) rim fire cartridge, using only a modified percussion cap, launched its projectile or BB pellett. As stated, a single 200 large rifle primer will launch both cartridge darts reasonably accurately to 15 feet from a cartridge's Y bore. However, to launch both darts with reasonable accuracy to 21 feet from a cartridge's Y bore, the primer cup must have the full propellant charge from both a 200 large rifle primer and a 400 small rifle primer. To launch both darts with reasonable accuracy to 30 feet from a cartridges Y bore, the primer cup must have the full propellant charge from two 200 large rifle primers. Moreover, even when launched with propellant from both a 200 large rifle primer and a 400 small rifle primer, the darts may not have sufficient force to impale into a target that is 21 feet distant from the cartridge. While the muzzle velocity of the darts is about 200 feet/second, the impact velocity after a 21 foot flight is only about 50 feet/second.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As observed, primers are intended to detonate a propellant powder by convection or, in other words, flash ignition. Primer ignition is not normally, itself, intended to propel projectiles. The routine inconsistency of the mixture of detonating powder in the primers causes bullet velocity spreads of from 15 fps to 100 fps. While this variation is normally not problematic where bullets are also propelled by the primer detonated propellant powder to typical muzzle velocities of over 1000 fps, the variation is a problem when projectiles are propelled by the detonating charge alone.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Optimally, the primer gases envelop a propellant powder's grains with enough thermal energy, conductivity and depth, so the surfaces of the grains are kept above their kindling point from primer flash until each grain completely ignites. The energy available to flash ignite the propellant powder is the energy supplied by the discharging primer less the energy used to heat the other normally highly heat conductive components of the system, like the cartridge's metal case and bullet and the metal firearm receiver. The gases enveloping the powder grains are typically heating to 5300&#xb0; F.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Of course, if the detonating charge in the primer is increased, heating within a cartridge case will increase. Such increases are problematic for stun pistol cartridges. As the primer flash enlarges, it can even melt wiring that is distant from the primer within the cartridge. The wire tethered at the dart assembly is 36 AWG copperweld insulated with a 0.005 to 0.075 wall of Tefzel. The melt point of copper is just 1981&#xb0; F. If the wire melts away and detaches from the assemblage, the dart will launch to a remote human target without its tethered conductor, and the shocking circuit will, of course, not complete through the target. This is a minor risk even when the stun pistol darts are launched by a single 200 large rifle primer, which contains its standard charge of detonating powder. Some manufacturer's primers burn &#x201c;hotter&#x201d; than others. In ascending order of &#x201c;hotness&#x201d; are Remington, CCI/Speer and Winchester primers. CCI/Speer primers are typically specified for stun pistol ammunition. Using, even, CCI/Speer 200 &#x201c;magnum&#x201d; rifle primers, which burn hotter than the standard 200 primer, results in a statistically significant number of wire tethers melting, as certainly does adding propellant from a 400 small rifle primer or doubling the charge in a 200 large rifle primer. Doubling the charge will also melt portions of the necessarily insulative plastic cartridge cases, which are shot from high impact D305 ABS plastic.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The inventive cartridge overcomes these prior art problems to improve stun pistol range and accuracy. A cartridge contains two separated straight bores, which each launch a single dart assemblage with a single primer of standard manufacture. A single 200 large rifle primer can launch a single dart assemblage reasonably accurately to 30 feet from the cartridge. Each assemblage is deflected to a predicted angle of flight when it collides with a center hinged cover as it exits the cartridge. This arrangement allows for longer flight distances and tighter, but still effective, dart spreads throughout the travel.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The aforementioned objects and advantages of the present invention as well as additional objects and advantages thereof, will be more fully understood hereinafter as a result of a detailed description of a preferred embodiment when taken in conjunction with the following drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a three-dimensional view of an embodiment of the present invention comprising a hand-held stun gun that has been combined with a cartridge containing a pair of wire-tethered darts for disabling a remote target;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a partial side view of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the cartridge of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a front view of the cartridge of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic illustration of a prior art electrical layout of a two-dart cartridge;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic illustration of a first embodiment of an improved electrical layout for increasing effectiveness of a two-dart cartridge;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic illustration of a second embodiment of an improved electrical layout for increasing effectiveness of a two-dart cartridge.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> but showing a center hinged cover for deflecting the darts to separate in flight; and</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> but showing the hinged cover of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF A PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring to the accompanying drawings and initially <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>, it will be seen that a combined stun gun and cartridge <b>10</b> comprises a stun gun <b>12</b> and a cartridge <b>14</b>, the latter being releasibly attached to the former to add a remote target immobilization capability to the near target capability of the stun gun. The stun gun <b>12</b> comprises an activation switch <b>16</b>, proximity contacts <b>18</b> and <b>20</b> and arcing contacts <b>22</b> and <b>24</b>. Arcing contact <b>22</b> is preferably larger in diameter than arcing contact <b>24</b> so that cartridge <b>14</b> cannot be connected to stun gun <b>12</b> while facing in the wrong direction which could otherwise cause injury to the user.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Cartridge <b>14</b> comprises a flat rectangular housing <b>15</b> having a pair of connectors <b>26</b> and <b>28</b> designed to mate mechanically with contacts <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> of stun gun <b>12</b> and electrically with contacts <b>18</b> and <b>20</b> of stun gun <b>12</b>. Darts <b>30</b> and <b>32</b> reside in respective cylindrical bores <b>31</b> and <b>33</b> ready to be propelled toward a remote target by respective pyrotechnics <b>34</b> and <b>36</b> which sit immediately behind the darts within the bores. Each dart <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> is tethered by a long thin insulated wire <b>38</b>, <b>40</b> which respectively resides in chambers <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> of housing <b>15</b>. When switch <b>16</b> of stun gun <b>12</b> is depressed, high voltage is applied to pyrotechnics <b>34</b> and <b>36</b> through connectors <b>18</b> and <b>20</b> and ignites the pyrotechnics to release expanding gas to propel wire-tethered darts <b>30</b> and <b>32</b> toward a remote target out of bores <b>31</b> and <b>33</b>. The voltage is then applied through wires <b>38</b> and <b>40</b> to the darts which apply the voltage across impact locations on the remote target.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates conventional prior art layout of electrical interface between high voltage poles (+) and (&#x2212;), pyrotechnics and wire tethered darts. Upon application of the high voltage (depression of switch <b>16</b>), pyrotechnic <b>36</b> ignites and a current arcs across remaining gaps to the respective wires <b>38</b> and <b>40</b> and darts <b>30</b> and <b>32</b> (which will have already exited their respective bores). This reliance on arcing across gaps left by pyrotechnic <b>36</b> causes the aforementioned disadvantages.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The schematic circuits of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref> illustrate two alternatives to the prior art layout of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> which avoid the gap arcing problem. In the layouts of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>, the wiring of the pyrotechnics is designed to ignite them and then cease current flow through them so that there is no reliance on arcing over the gap left by the pyrotechnics in order to deliver current through the darts and the target. The circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> effectively connects the pyrotechnics in series with one another, but in parallel with the darts and the target. The circuit of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> effectively connects each of the pyrotechnics separately in parallel with the darts and the target. Nevertheless, the pyrotechnics remain physically adjacent their respective darts to effect propulsion of the darts upon their ignition.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, it will be seen that 6 mm bores are positioned without angling them at (0&#xb0;) about three (3) inches apart on parallel sides of an ammunition cartridge, that is about the size and shape of a 3&#xbd; inch computer floppy disk, but thicker. A cartridge of this size can still be conveniently transported and loaded into a hand gun. Each dart assemblage and a portion of its tethered conductor is fed into a different bore in front of a single CCI/Speer 200 rifle primer. The face of the cartridge containing the muzzles is covered by an adhering surface that both covers the muzzles and extends between a projection of the muzzles along the face of the cartridge and that can bend at this extending surface. The cover might be fashioned of a lightly adhering tape like the Easy Mask&#xae; Painting Tape manufactured by Loparex, Inc. of Willowbrook, Ill. or from a length of cardboard or plastic, adhered heavily to the cartridge face between the muzzle projections and lightly tacked with adhesive to the cartridge face at each end of the cover length's axis which extends through both muzzle projections. Now, when the primer ignites, the explosive force and/or each dart assemblage collides with an opposite end of the cover, causing each end of the cover to detach from the cartridge face and to travel toward each other in an arc while the midsection of the cover remains, at least momentarily, adhered to the cartridge face. Each dart is deflected to a predicted angle from the collision or later collision.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">These inventive cartridge, with cover fashioned of Easy Mask&#xae; Painting Tape, have been manufactured and sold by Tu Corporation of Calimesa, Calif. since Apr. 16, 2004. During the entire history of manufacture, not one dart is reported to have exited a cartridge while detached by melting from its trailing conductor. Moreover, the cartridge's paired darts are generally spread about 7 inches distant from each other when impacting a target that is four (4) feet distant from the stun pistol, one foot distant from each other when impacting a target that is 15 feet distant from the stun pistol and spread about two (2) feet from each other when 30 feet distant from the target. These tight firing patters allow the cartridges darts to both impact into the average person's trunk over the entire improved range of the stun pistol. Moreover, spreads are still near as wide for close range impacts as with prior art stun pistols as the darts leave the cartridge already three (3) inches distant from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Having thus disclosed a number of illustrative embodiments of the invention herein, it will now by apparent that the illustrated electrical layouts avoid the disadvantages of the prior art. Moreover, it will be understood that variations from the disclosed embodiments may be readily perceived based upon the teaching herein. Accordingly, the scope hereof is to be limited only by the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A cartridge for use in a stun gun, the cartridge having a pair of wire-tethered contact darts adjacent respective electrically activated pyrotechnics for propelling the darts toward a remote target for disabling the target; the cartridge comprising:
<claim-text>a pair of elongated bores that are space apart from one another,</claim-text>
<claim-text>one of said contact darts positioned in each of said bores,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said elongated bores being substantially; parallel to one another; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hinged cover affixed to an exterior surface of said cartridge between said bores, unaffixed portions of said cover extending over said bores for being deflected therefrom by said contact darts upon their exiting from said bores.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The cartridge as recited in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said exiting darts are deflected apart by said unaffixed portions of said cover. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
