<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640902-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640902</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11447608</doc-number>
<date>20060605</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2005 026 553</doc-number>
<date>20050608</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>302</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>1</main-group>
<subgroup>34</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9017</main-classification>
<further-classification>123 9015</further-classification>
<further-classification>464160</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Rotor for vane-type motor with reduced leakage</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5794578</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Strauss et al.</name>
<date>19980800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 9017</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6330870</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Inoue et al.</name>
<date>20011200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 9017</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6363897</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Scheidt et al.</name>
<date>20020400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6412462</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lichti et al.</name>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6439183</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Iwasaki et al.</name>
<date>20020800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6669567</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Scheidt et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6945205</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Heintzen et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 9017</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0139334</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kinugawa</name>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0034693</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Heintzen et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10211607</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20031000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 008 729</doc-number>
<date>20000600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>15</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9015</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9016</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9017</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>123 9018</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>464  1</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>464  2</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>464160</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>11</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060278189</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20061214</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Knecht</last-name>
<first-name>Andreas</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kusterdingen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Pohl</last-name>
<first-name>Dirk</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tuebingen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Eimert</last-name>
<first-name>Jan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Esslingen</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Lipsitz &#x26; McAllister LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hydraulik-Ring GmbH</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Marktheidenfeld</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Ching</first-name>
<department>3748</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A camshaft adjuster which operates according to the vane-type motor principle, which means being able to move to and fro within a certain angle, generally comprises a stator and a rotor. The rotor itself is provided as a composite system of at least two components. One of the components is a cover. A further component of the composite system may be denoted as the rotor core. The cover is placed on the rotor.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="110.66mm" wi="259.42mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="161.80mm" wi="149.18mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="171.62mm" wi="156.04mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="187.71mm" wi="141.65mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="171.20mm" wi="157.65mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="167.72mm" wi="148.93mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="166.96mm" wi="168.99mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="153.75mm" wi="152.74mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="174.50mm" wi="135.47mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="147.91mm" wi="131.66mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="164.51mm" wi="132.59mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="190.58mm" wi="147.91mm" file="US07640902-20100105-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to the subject matter disclosed in German application DE 10 2005 026 553.7 of Jun. 8, 2005, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety for all purposes.</p>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a camshaft adjuster which, in a hydraulically adjustable manner and according to a vane-type motor principle, may adjust the camshafts of an internal combustion engine relative to a further shaft, such as for example the crankshaft.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">There are many different types of camshaft adjusters. The most frequently used type of adjuster, at the date of filing of the present application, is that which works according to the vane-type motor principle. Two wheels which are movable relative to one another, a stator and a rotor, which are positioned coaxially, together form hydraulic chambers of which at least two chambers are contra-rotating. With the increase of the one chamber, the camshaft attached to the rotor by a central screw (other types of fastening being also known) is moved in the advanced direction, for an advanced opening time of the gas exchange valves, whilst with the increase of the other contra-rotating hydraulic chamber the camshaft is moved in the retarded direction relative to the other shaft, for a retarded opening time of the gas exchange valve. The regions denoted as hydraulic chambers may also be denoted more simply as hydraulic regions. The hydraulic medium is displaced into the various hydraulic regions via channels. In this regard, for example, channel guides are known to the applicant, in which individual channel portions are firstly guided along the camshaft itself and are transferred to the camshaft adjuster in a region of a camshaft passage of the camshaft adjuster. The channels then lead to the individual hydraulic regions, partially located within the rotor and completely surrounded by the same rotor material.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Rotor-driven hydraulic channel portions are known from U.S. Pat. No. 6,439,183 (Denso Corporation), which issued from an application filed on Oct. 1, 2001. As shown primarily in FIGS. 3, 5 and 6 of U.S. Pat. No. 6,439,183 the hydraulic channel portions allow connections to the hydraulic regions which all extend on the rotor surface and are covered by the stator inner wall. It is apparent that rotors of camshaft adjusters which have a similar appearance to those disclosed in U.S. Pat. No. 6,439,183, come from an extruded profile by cutting off along the planar faces of the retarded rotor, the channels being inserted into the planar faces of the rotor by milling. Tests on camshaft adjusters produced in this manner led to high amounts of leakage of the hydraulic medium, such as for example engine oil, primarily in the full load range. Thus unnecessary energy of the internal combustion engine is used to pump the engine oil which has escaped into the oil sump back into the hydraulic chambers. In tests, leakage rates of one liter have been shown at an operating pressure of 3 bar. In particular, during hot idling such an adjuster is shown to be the main point of oil leakage.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In addition, the patent family with the members U.S. Pat. No. 6,363,897 B (INA W&#xc4;LZLAGER SCHAEFFLER OHG), which issued from an application filed on Dec. 22, 2000, and DE 19962981 A (INA W&#xc4;LZLAGER SCHAEFFLER OHG), filed Dec. 24, 1999, discloses in its second embodiment a circular sealing washer to seal the inner chamber within the stator. The seals are located in the outer walls of the adjuster. The openings in the outer walls of the camshaft adjuster are sealed relative to the rotating parts by the leakage seals present in the walls.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Camshaft adjusters with rotors, whose channels extend completely within the rotor, are frequently provided with round drilled elongate channels. The round cross-sectional shape of the channel requires a larger drilled diameter at the same decrease in pressure as the aforementioned channel shape. The shape of the channel may produce a greater decrease in pressure which is undesirable, as decreases in the channel pressure also have a negative effect on the degree of hydraulic efficiency.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Knowing the drawbacks of one or other type of rotor, the inventor sought to provide a camshaft adjuster of an internal combustion engine which reduces the drawbacks of the two known camshaft adjusters. In this connection, numerous designs of channel were tested. Amongst others, individual channel sections of a channel were considered in order to allow optimization, section by section. In this connection, the channel section is also understood to be regions of a channel which may also encompass all the individual channel lengths of a channel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The acknowledged difficulties are at least partially overcome by a camshaft adjuster according to the present invention. In addition, a suitable manufacturing possibility may be derived from the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A camshaft adjuster which operates according to the vane-type motor principle, which means being able to move to and fro within a certain angle, generally comprises a stator and a rotor. The motion of the vane-type motor-like camshaft adjuster may thus be denoted as angular motion. The stator is the outer sleeve which may consist of a plurality of parts. Within the stator there is at least one protrusion facing toward the center of the stator. A vane may move radially toward the protrusion and away from the protrusion. Most of the known camshaft adjusters have numerous protrusions, such as for example 5 protrusions, which are distributed, usually evenly distributed, over the periphery of the substantially circular stator and which all face toward the center of the camshaft adjuster, between which a number, generally the same number, of rotor vanes move with a reciprocating motion. The camshaft adjuster is like a planar disk of which there are two planar faces. Accordingly, the rotor is also of similar design, also having two planar faces. Between the vanes of the rotor and the corresponding protrusions and/or the stator, opposing hydraulic regions are formed into which the hydraulic medium may enter via channels. At least one of the channels is partially formed by the rotor. The rotor itself is produced as a composite system of at least two components. One of the components is a cover. A further component of the composite system may be denoted as a rotor core. The cover is placed on the rotor. The rotor core and cover may be considered as being of layered surface structure which from the side act in a sandwich-like manner. The shorter, peripheral side of the rotor core extends as far as the cover, which is noticeably flatter by comparison. The cover rests on the round face of the rotor core. In this connection, it may also partially extend into a channel. It may also be said that the second component is inserted into the first component. Principally, there is some kind of contact between the cover and the rotor core. Advantageously there may be linear contact. More advantageously, there may be multiple linear contact. The contact should be made parallel to one side. A covered channel portion is formed by the two components. It is also conceivable that the cover is a horseshoe-shaped or U- section-shaped piece along the channel portion to be covered, so that the perpendicular walls which are located at a 90&#xb0; angle to the planar faces are formed by two components of the composite system of the rotor. These are the side walls of the channel portion extending in the rotor core and the side walls of the corresponding cover.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">With similar channel guides on the two planar faces of the rotor, corresponding covers may also be provided for both faces of the rotor core. In this regard, it depends on the actual channel guide, whether the covers are identical to one another or whether different covers are used.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">It is particularly advantageous if there are covers on the points of the rotor where a stationary part and moving part of the camshaft adjuster are in contact, the add-on parts such as the camshaft, trigger wheel or cover of the camshaft adjuster also being understood as being moving parts of the camshaft adjuster. According to an embodiment, there is a point of contact on the camshaft passage. This is the point at which the camshaft projects into the camshaft adjuster. According to a further aspect of the invention, the cover is in contact with the central screw passage. The central screw passage is the point at which the relevant central axially located screw for fixing the camshaft adjuster to the camshaft leads into the camshaft adjuster.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The channels in the camshaft adjuster have to feed the hydraulic medium, such as for example oil, from the hydraulic regions to the oil feeds, which come from another region of the drive motor. An advantageous channel guide is that the oil supply enters centrally and separately via the camshaft, is transferred by the camshaft to the channels in the camshaft adjuster, and enters the hydraulic regions from the axially positioned central oil feed, like the points of a star, over a very short path, in particular a straight path. Thus the pivoting points in the camshaft adjuster may be covered at the center by a single continuous cover. A particularly advantageous central cover is, for example, an annulus.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Pressure losses in the channels may arise from the channels having numerous branches and diverted portions. In contrast thereto, the pressure losses are reduced when the channels are designed to be sufficiently wide from the central axial inflow and with as few branches and bends as possible and enter the hydraulic regions via the planar faces of the rotor.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A further advantageous aspect is that the covers are mounted to be freely floating in the regions of the channels which they are to cover. When the pressure of the hydraulic medium increases, the covers are pressed outwardly away from the rotor core. The greater the risk of leakage due to an increase in pressure, the better the critical torsionally loaded regions are sealingly closed in the camshaft.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In order to save total construction space, in the rotor circuit an annular groove is provided in which the cover ring formed as an annular groove may be inserted. As a result, the rotor core and its corresponding lateral cover, which only covers part of the rotor core, form a single surface.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A further advantage is that suitable materials are selected. Sintered metal is particularly suitable for the rotor core, in which the appropriate channels have already been inserted during the sintering process. The seals may advantageously be manufactured from plastics material, in particular highly resistant plastics material. By the choice of material the rotor core may be advantageously mounted on the camshaft and continue to operate for the desired running performance, whilst due to their synthetic properties, the seals may develop particularly advantageous sealing properties.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The corresponding manufacturing method for producing a camshaft adjuster according to the invention comprises the steps of producing a rotor core, inserting an appropriate cover and the formation of the entire composite system in the stator housing. In particular with sintered rotor cores, the channels which are open toward the surface may be produced in the rotor cores at the same time as the sintering process. With the use of extruded sections, the rotor core is cut to length at its appropriate thickness from the extruded section and the channels are inserted in the first processing step, for example by milling or stamping.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The invention may be better understood with reference to the accompanying Figures.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a perspective of an open camshaft adjuster,</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a lateral view of an open camshaft adjuster,</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a camshaft adjuster according to the invention, built onto a camshaft in longitudinal section,</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a first embodiment of a rotor according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows a second embodiment of a rotor according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a third embodiment of a rotor according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows a fourth embodiment of a rotor according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> shows a fifth embodiment of a rotor according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a sixth embodiment of a rotor according to the invention,</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a perspective view of a rotor according to the invention, and</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows a known camshaft adjuster.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> show an open camshaft adjuster <b>1</b> in an overall view. In the stator <b>3</b>, a rotor <b>5</b> is located of which the vane <b>11</b> is mounted to be movable to and fro between individual protrusions <b>7</b>, <b>9</b> by means of hydraulic pressure. The one face of the stator <b>3</b> may optionally comprise a further sprocket <b>51</b>. The views of the camshaft adjuster are illustrated with an open stator of the stator housing <b>73</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. The stator housing <b>73</b> may be produced as a dish in a single piece with integral sprocket <b>51</b> or in a plurality of parts in the form of a receiving ring which is covered on one side by the sprocket <b>51</b>. The rotor <b>5</b> may be formed with an axial recess for a means for fastening the rotor to the output shaft, for example a central screw guide <b>57</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The disk-like components of the camshaft adjuster may be held together by countersunk screws distributed over their circumference which may respectively reach the other side of the stator housing <b>73</b> through the protrusion bores <b>53</b> in the protrusions <b>7</b>, <b>9</b>. Seals may be optionally inserted at different points of the camshaft adjuster <b>1</b> in order to seal, during operation, the hydraulic fluids of the first hydraulic region <b>17</b> or the second hydraulic region <b>19</b> relative to the surroundings. By way of example, a peripheral stator seal <b>55</b> peripherally arranged in the edge region of the stator <b>3</b> and annular protrusion bore seals <b>59</b> located around the protrusion bores <b>53</b> are indicated. The rotor <b>5</b> which has a star-shaped appearance with its vanes <b>11</b> to separate the two hydraulic regions <b>17</b>, <b>19</b>, has dihedral faces <b>13</b>, <b>15</b>. During operation, the stator <b>3</b> and the rotor <b>5</b> move almost continuously, whilst the oil of the hydraulic regions <b>17</b>, <b>19</b> should be able to be supplied and discharged in a manner which maintains the chamber as fluid-tight as possible.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The camshaft adjuster <b>1</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, comprising a stator <b>3</b> and a rotor <b>5</b>, has been illustrated in a view through a central screw <b>61</b> on the camshaft <b>67</b>. In addition to the rotor <b>5</b>, the stator housing <b>73</b> also surrounds the various hydraulic regions <b>17</b>, <b>19</b>. In the embodiment shown, the camshaft <b>67</b> is used, amongst other things, to guide the pressurized hydraulic medium via a first groove <b>69</b> and a second groove <b>71</b>, via first and second feed channels <b>63</b>, <b>65</b> extending in the camshaft and via a first and a second channel <b>21</b>, <b>23</b> to the hydraulic regions <b>17</b>, <b>19</b>. The multi-tiered stator housing <b>73</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is sealed by the sprocket <b>51</b> designed as a cover which is located on the camshaft side such that the camshaft <b>67</b>, engaging the rotor <b>5</b> through the camshaft passage <b>37</b> by means of the central screw <b>61</b> which is screwed into the end of the camshaft <b>67</b>, engaging the rotor <b>5</b> through the central screw passage, produces a frictional connection between the camshaft <b>67</b> and the one planar face of the rotor. In the embodiment provided, the central screw guide <b>57</b> is provided with a larger diameter than the shank diameter of the central screw <b>61</b> so that the central screw <b>61</b> flushes round, so to speak, oil carried by the hydraulic medium in the diameter difference used as an oil feed <b>43</b>, a portion of the oil channel may lead to one of the planar faces. Further channel portions, such as for example <b>33</b>, extend partially within the rotor core <b>31</b> and bridge over points of contact <b>35</b> which are provided between rotating parts, such as for example the central screw <b>61</b> and relatively quasi-stationary parts such as a stator housing <b>73</b>, the transition being present between the first and second channel <b>21</b>, <b>23</b> extending on the edge of the rotor core <b>31</b>. The regions <b>41</b> provided as rotary passages are sealingly sealed by the second component <b>27</b> of the multi-tiered rotor <b>5</b> of sandwich-like construction in a manner which is insensitive to friction and torsionally resistant. The first component <b>25</b> (e.g., the rotor core) and the second component <b>27</b> (e.g., the cover(s)), optionally with further components, form the rotor <b>5</b>. The second component <b>27</b> may be inserted at least partially into the first component <b>25</b> such that apertures produced by just a few holes through the channel guide of the first and second channel <b>21</b>, <b>23</b>, produce the interrupted first and second planar faces <b>13</b>, <b>15</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>. The planar faces <b>13</b>, <b>15</b> of the rotor <b>5</b> brush against lines of contact, which may also be individual channel portions <b>33</b>, and against stator side walls <b>49</b>, in particular the inner stator side walls.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Six different embodiments of rotor channel guides as components constructed according to the invention with large, transverse surfaces may be derived from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b>, <b>6</b>, <b>7</b>, <b>8</b> and <b>9</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the oil feed <b>43</b> enters the expanded portions between the vanes <b>11</b>, moving out radially from the center of the rotor <b>5</b> in part of the central screw guide <b>57</b> and moving outwards straight in the direction of the vanes <b>11</b> along the first planar face <b>13</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>. The channel <b>21</b> guided in the edge regions of the rotor <b>5</b> opens out at the circular arc shaped connecting portions between the vanes of the rotor. The channel <b>21</b> ends at a position relative to the channel <b>23</b> offset by the angle of slippage and/or adjustment and which, located on the rear face, the second planar face <b>15</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>, may provide the other hydraulic region. The rotor <b>5</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is of substantially similar design to the rotor <b>5</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The two rotors <b>5</b> comprise hammer-like vanes <b>11</b> with widened sealing lengths on their radial external vane ends. However, the rotors <b>5</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> differ in the type of cover <b>29</b> and/or in the cooperation between the covers <b>29</b> and the channels <b>21</b>. The covers <b>29</b> which in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> are small, quadrilateral, preferably square plates with such lengths which are as long as the contact points between the movable and stationary part of the camshaft adjuster <b>1</b> plus an additional remaining sealing portion. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the covers <b>29</b> are precision-fit clamp covers which are positively inserted in the channel <b>21</b> and with an interference fit in the rotor core <b>31</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the covers <b>29</b> are floatable, fixed in a relative position to the rotor <b>5</b>, height adjustable, and may be pressed outwardly under pressure against the stator side wall <b>49</b>. The two <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b> show in a three-dimensional view the one planar face <b>13</b> of the rotor <b>5</b> whilst the channel <b>23</b> offset by the angle of rotation of the rotor <b>5</b> is only visible in outline on the rear opposing second planar face <b>15</b> through its channel end. The two channels <b>21</b>, <b>23</b> extend within the edge regions of the rotor core <b>31</b>. On the face which faces the interior of the rotor, the channels <b>21</b>, <b>23</b> have semi-circular channel floor regions which open into longitudinal walls extending parallel to one another. The oil feed <b>43</b> extends along and surrounds the central screw guide <b>57</b> in order to diverge radially into the channels <b>21</b> in a star shape at the end of the central screw guide. It is advantageous to design the same number of covers <b>29</b> as channels when it is desirable to save on materials, as only the critical regions particularly affected by leakage are sealed.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> are very similar to one another. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows the pressure-reactive, positionable cover <b>29</b> which can be lifted from the channel floor when the hydraulic medium is pressurized. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> the cover <b>29</b> is in a fixed position on the surrounding rotor core <b>31</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>. The cover <b>29</b> is made of one piece. It bridges all channels <b>21</b> and is held together by a connecting ring in the center of the individual channel covers. The one-piece cover <b>29</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is advantageous when it is desirable to keep production costs as low as possible, because all channels <b>21</b> are completely covered in one operation.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The shape of the cover <b>29</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an annulus which is located in an annular groove <b>47</b> which extends circumferentially over the uncovered surface of the one face <b>13</b> of the rotor core <b>31</b>, in the vicinity of the vanes <b>11</b>. Only the individual portions of the channels <b>21</b> are covered. The rotor <b>5</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is provided with a cover <b>29</b> which is of a precise fit, whilst the rotor <b>5</b> according to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is provided with a flexible, movable cover <b>29</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows the other face <b>15</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>, of which the cover <b>29</b> bridges the channel portion <b>33</b> of the channel <b>23</b> which is located on a different radius, for example a larger radius, from the cover <b>29</b> on the first face <b>13</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>. The oil feed channels are located Outside the central oil feed <b>43</b> of the front face <b>13</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>, radially approaching the vanes <b>11</b> of the rotor core <b>31</b>. To save on the number of parts, the cover <b>29</b>, designed as an annulus, has the same diameter and the same radius as the annular cover of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> or <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> a camshaft adjuster <b>1</b> of the known type is shown screwed to a stator <b>3</b> and a rotor <b>5</b> by an axially extending central screw <b>61</b> on a camshaft <b>67</b> which presses the rotor <b>5</b> non-positively via the head of the central screw <b>61</b> in an oil tight manner to the first and second feed channel <b>63</b>, <b>65</b>. The central screw passage <b>39</b> is present on the side of the screwhead of the central screw <b>61</b>, a camshaft passage <b>37</b> is present on the other face <b>15</b> of the rotor <b>5</b>, the face <b>13</b> facing away from the central screw passage <b>39</b>. The stator <b>3</b> is made up of a plurality of components including the integral sprocket <b>51</b> and stator housing <b>73</b>. The rotor <b>5</b> brushes against the stator side wall <b>49</b> during its angular displacement. The oil feed <b>43</b>, which extends around the central screw <b>61</b>, supplies the hydraulic medium to the hydraulic regions <b>17</b> or <b>19</b> via channels which, in the present embodiment, are completely internal. The hydraulic medium is transferred by the camshaft <b>67</b> to the camshaft adjuster <b>1</b> via the two grooves <b>69</b>, <b>71</b> which are located in the camshaft <b>67</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The channel guide shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 to 9</figref> may also be combined with one of the two channels, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, in a rotor core <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The invention disclosed above may also be denoted, using another term, as a floating ring seal for rotor channels which sealingly and floatingly covers the pressure chamber feed channels, located during operation in the longitudinal faces of the rotor, relative to the rotary passages of the rotor connections, minimizing leakage relative to the cavities in the engine region which are parallel to the rotor. In this regard, the invention is characterized according to one principal aspect in that with increasing pressure, i.e. generally at higher rotational speeds of the oil pump of the internal combustion engine, the sealing function increases further and, as a result, the leakage is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">It should be appreciated that, within the scope of this description, only individual embodiments are explained which are intended to clarify the general inventive concepts without the invention being restricted to the embodiments explained. In this regard it is also reasonable that suitable choices of material which have the same composite system behavior, such as for example plastics-plastics, metal-metal, etc. belong to the invention. The actual channel designs of rotors according to the invention are similarly not restricted to the embodiments disclosed.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="2">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70pt" align="char"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="147pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>Camshaft adjuster</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>Stator</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>Rotor</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7</entry>
<entry>First protrusion</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9</entry>
<entry>Second protrusion</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11</entry>
<entry>Vane</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>13</entry>
<entry>First planar face of the rotor</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>15</entry>
<entry>Second planar face of the rotor</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>17</entry>
<entry>First hydraulic region</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>19</entry>
<entry>Second hydraulic region</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>21</entry>
<entry>First channel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>23</entry>
<entry>Second channel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>25</entry>
<entry>First component</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>27</entry>
<entry>Second component</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>29</entry>
<entry>Cover</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>31</entry>
<entry>Rotor core</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>33</entry>
<entry>Channel portion</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>35</entry>
<entry>Contact point</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>37</entry>
<entry>Camshaft passage</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>39</entry>
<entry>Central screw passage</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>41</entry>
<entry>Rotary passage</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>43</entry>
<entry>Oil feed</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>47</entry>
<entry>Annular groove</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>49</entry>
<entry>Stator side wall</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>51</entry>
<entry>Sprocket</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>53</entry>
<entry>Protrusion bore</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>55</entry>
<entry>Peripheral stator seal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>57</entry>
<entry>Central screw guide (in the rotor)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>59</entry>
<entry>Protrusion bore seal</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>61</entry>
<entry>Central screw</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>63</entry>
<entry>First feed channel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>65</entry>
<entry>Second feed channel</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>67</entry>
<entry>Camshaft</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>69</entry>
<entry>First groove, preferably peripheral</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>71</entry>
<entry>Second groove, preferably peripheral</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>73</entry>
<entry>Stator housing</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A camshaft adjuster according to the vane-type motor principle, comprising:
<claim-text>a stator which has at least two protrusions facing a center of the stator,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotor which has at least one vane located in a vicinity of the at least two protrusions and which is angularly movable, said rotor having a first and a second planar face, at least two contra-rotating hydraulic regions being formed between said at least one vane and the at least two protrusions by an angular movement of the rotor, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>channels to the hydraulic regions, one of the channels being formed at least partially by a central screw passage of the rotor, said central screw passage of the rotor accommodating a central screw for attaching the rotor to a camshaft and having a diameter that is larger than a diameter of said central screw,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the rotor is provided as a composite system of at least two components, a flat cover and a rotor core which upon contact with each other form a covered channel portion parallel to one of said planar faces, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the flat cover sealingly covers at least one point of the rotor which is in contact with both a stationary part of the camshaft adjuster and a moving part of the camshaft adjuster, said moving part of the camshaft adjuster including at least one of the camshaft, a trigger wheel and a camshaft adjuster cover.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first component is the rotor core, the second component is the cover and the second component is inserted into the first component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein channels extend parallel to the first and second face in the rotor and which are covered by one respective component as a covered channel.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said cover covers at least one of a camshaft passage, the central screw passage, and rotary passages between the rotor and stator.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein channels lead from the hydraulic regions to the central screw passage axially positioned in the rotor, and which channels form the covered channel portions by means of a cover divided like the points of a star linked together by an annulus.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the channels lead to the hydraulic regions from axial feed channels, the channels extending in the radial direction over a shortest possible path from the feed channels, without branches and bends in the planar faces of the rotor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the composite system comprises at least two outer covers and said rotor core, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer covers of the composite system are plastics material elements and the rotor core located between the outer covers of the composite system consists of a sintered metal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said flat cover is in contact with the central screw passage for minimizing leakage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A camshaft adjuster according to the vane-type motor principle, comprising:
<claim-text>a stator which has at least two protrusions facing a center of the stator,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotor which has at least one vane located in a vicinity of the at least two protrusions and which is angularly movable, said rotor having a first and a second planar face, at least two contra-rotating hydraulic regions being formed between said at least one vane and the at least two protrusions by an angular movement of the rotor, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>channels to the hydraulic regions, one of the channels being formed at least partially by the rotor,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the rotor is provided as a composite system of at least two components, a cover and a rotor core which upon contact with each other form a covered channel portion parallel to one of said planar faces; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the channels are floating channels which, when filled by a pressurized hydraulic medium, sealingly press the cover away from the rotor core outwardly to a stator side wall.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the cover covers at least one point of the rotor which is in contact with a stationary part and a moving part of the camshaft adjuster, said moving part of the camshaft adjuster including at least one of the camshaft, a trigger wheel and a camshaft adjuster cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the composite system comprises at least two outer covers and said rotor core, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer covers of the composite system are plastics material elements and the rotor core located between the outer covers of the composite system consists of a sintered metal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A camshaft adjuster according to the vane-type motor principle, comprising:
<claim-text>a stator which has at least two protrusions facing a center of the stator,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a rotor which has at least one vane located in a vicinity of the at least two protrusions and which is angularly movable, said rotor having a first and a second planar face, at least two contra-rotating hydraulic regions being formed between said at least one vane and the at least two protrusions by an angular movement of the rotor, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>channels to the hydraulic regions, one of the channels being formed at least partially by the rotor,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the rotor is provided as a composite system of at least two components, a cover and a rotor core which upon contact with each other form a covered channel portion parallel to one of said planar faces;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the channels lead from the hydraulic regions to a central oil feed axially positioned in the rotor, and which channels form the covered channel portions by means of a cover divided like the points of a star linked together by an annulus; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the annulus is located in an annular groove which extends sealed over the entire face of the rotor.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the cover covers at least one point of the rotor which is in contact with a stationary part and a moving part of the camshaft adjuster, said moving part of the camshaft adjuster including at least one of the camshaft, a trigger wheel and a camshaft adjuster cover.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A camshaft adjuster as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>the composite system comprises at least two outer covers and said rotor core, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the outer covers of the composite system are plastics material elements and the rotor core located between the outer covers of the composite system consists of a sintered metal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A method for producing a camshaft adjuster working in accordance to the vane-type motor principle, comprising:
<claim-text>providing a rotor core with channels open toward a surface of the rotor, the rotor having at least one vane in the vicinity of at least two protrusions and which is angularly movable, one of the channels being formed at least partially by a central screw passage of the rotor, said central screw passage of the rotor accommodating a central screw for attaching the rotor to a camshaft and having a diameter that is larger than a diameter of said central screw,</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting a flat cover in at least one annular groove of the rotor core, the flat cover and the rotor core which upon contact with each other form a covered channel portion parallel to a planar face of said rotor core, the flat cover sealingly covering at least one point of the rotor which is in contact with both a stationary part of the camshaft adjuster and a moving part of the camshaft adjuster, said moving part of the camshaft adjuster including at least one of the camshaft, a trigger wheel and a camshaft adjuster cover, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting a composite system comprised of the rotor core and the flat cover into a stator housing.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
