<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640767-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640767</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11422964</doc-number>
<date>20060608</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>350</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62434</main-classification>
<further-classification> 622592</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Low voltage variable speed drive for application on medium/high voltage mains</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3954915</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Schwab et al.</name>
<date>19760500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>525123</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3959704</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McCrea</name>
<date>19760500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4084406</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brenneman</name>
<date>19780400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4147296</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Spethmann</name>
<date>19790400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4270361</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>LaBarge</name>
<date>19810600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4425539</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wills</name>
<date>19840100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4674024</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Paice et al.</name>
<date>19870600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4895005</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Norbeck et al.</name>
<date>19900100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5355691</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sullivan et al.</name>
<date>19941000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5361587</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hoffman</name>
<date>19941100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5625545</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hammond</name>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5746062</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Beaverson et al.</name>
<date>19980500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 622283</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5838144</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Wills et al.</name>
<date>19981100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6346790</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kemp et al.</name>
<date>20020200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6449973</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dodge et al.</name>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 62240</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6564560</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Butterworth et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6679076</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Duga et al.</name>
<date>20040100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00018">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7003971</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kester et al.</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 622592</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00019">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0225270</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Schnetzka et al.</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>318 66</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>14</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62228</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62236</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 62434</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>4</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070283708</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071213</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schnetzka</last-name>
<first-name>Harold R.</first-name>
<address>
<city>York</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Norbeck</last-name>
<first-name>Dean K.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Marco Island</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>McNees Wallace &#x26; Nurick LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Johnson Controls Technology Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Holland</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Jones</last-name>
<first-name>Melvin</first-name>
<department>3744</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present invention is directed to a power transformer and VSD mounted on the chiller equipment. The transformer is preferably a liquid-filled transformer rated for medium/high voltage input, and at least two output low voltages, one voltage for the VSD and other power equipment, and another voltage for the control panel and control equipment. The placement of the power transformer on the chiller eliminates the need to allocate additional floor space for an auxiliary transformer or medium/high voltage VSD. The transformer also includes cooling means in the form of a heat exchanger in which the liquid is cooled by circulating condenser water, chilled water or refrigerant from the chiller system. The cooling means may also be connected to cooling coils connected to the VSD. The size of the power transformer is significantly reduced by the use of the chiller system to remove heat from the transformer while in operation, thereby maintaining the ambient temperature rise of the transformer within its rated operating temperature range. The transformer and VSD heat is discharged to the outside ambient eliminating additional cooling requirements for the equipment room.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="100.67mm" wi="238.00mm" file="US07640767-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="211.67mm" wi="119.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640767-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="246.38mm" wi="189.82mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640767-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="259.67mm" wi="141.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640767-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="241.47mm" wi="139.19mm" file="US07640767-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention is directed to a variable speed drive powered from medium/high voltage mains, and more particularly to a low voltage variable speed drive powered by a medium/high voltage, fluid or gas cooled transformer.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Chiller systems for applications in commercial or industrial building HVAC systems typically include relatively large electric motors for powering a compressor. The motors may range in horsepower from 100 HP up to 5,000 HP or larger. Many of these systems include variable speed drives (VSD) for controlling the speed of the motor in response to cooling demand. Motors and VSDs of this size must be designed for the applicable main distribution voltages. In the case where low voltage mains (600 volts or less) are supplying the chiller system, higher current capacity is required. The relatively high current load requires larger more expensive cables, step-down transformers, and switchgear.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Conversely, where the voltage main supplies medium/high voltage (greater than 600 volts) to the chiller system, the current capacity requirements are low relative to the low voltage system requirements. However, other considerations such as equipment costs, complexity and safety must also be taken into account. Medium/high voltage (MV) switchgear, typically 4,160V, requires sophisticated arc suppression, insulation, and safety characteristics. Moreover, because of the greater potential danger of electrocution, only specially trained and qualified maintenance personnel may be permitted to perform the highly specialized maintenance operations of the medium/high voltage distribution system. Corona, flashover and arcing are some of the adverse factors associated with medium/high voltage distribution systems. The presence of moisture and dust particles further contributes to the adverse factors, resulting in increased switchgear costs. Additionally, power semiconductors are not generally available for medium/high voltage applications, and require especially high reverse-voltage characteristics, further adding to the increased cost size and complexity of such equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An electric system suitable for a typical low voltage chiller system, due to high current requirements, can include large expensive conductors, switchgear and transformers for a low voltage distribution system. Alternatively, due to the lower current requirements, the components of the medium/high voltage switchgear could be smaller; however, due to the higher voltage significantly greater equipment clearances are required. As a result, there is no space saving advantage associated with the medium/high voltage switchgear and drives.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Floor mounted medium/high voltage drives and starters are commercially available. One such motor drive is a model T300 MVi manufactured by the Toshiba International Corporation. The T300 MVi variable speed drive arrangement includes a rather complex 24 pulse input transformer having 12 three-phase secondary windings to supply the drive input rectifiers, plus two secondary windings for two control voltage levels. The floor area required to accommodate most medium/high voltage VSDs, including the T300MVi, is approximately 50 ft.<sup>2 </sup>to 100 ft.<sup>2</sup>, which in many instances is equal to or greater than the floor area required for the chiller. Due to the limited floor area allocated for HVAC systems in buildings, it is desirable to minimize the floor area utilized by the chiller system, while maintaining an appropriately sized chiller system.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">U.S. Pat. No. 5,625,545 discloses an electric drive apparatus and method for controlling medium/high-voltage alternating current motors wherein a multi-phase power transformer supplies multi-phase power to multiple power cells. In one embodiment of the '545 patent which can be applied to 2300 VAC inductive motor loads, three power cells are used for each of the three phase output lines. In another embodiment, which may be applied to a 4160 VAC inductive motor load, five power cells may be used for each of the three phase output lines. Such an embodiment can have eleven voltage states. Such multiple power cell transformers are more costly and consume an excessive amount of space to accommodate the large number of cells and clearances space required for medium/high voltage motors. As a result they require separate mounting cabinets and cannot be mounted directly on the chiller equipment to save floor space.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, there is a need for a low voltage chiller system that can be connected to a medium/high voltage AC power source with a step-down transformer that is sufficiently compact to permit the transformer to be mounted directly on the chiller, integral with the VSD.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The present invention is directed to a power transformer and VSD mounted on the chiller equipment. The transformer is preferably a liquid-filled transformer rated for medium/high voltage input, and at least two output low voltages, one voltage for the VSD and other power equipment, and other voltages for the control panel and control equipment. The placement of the power transformer on the chiller eliminates the need to allocate additional floor space for an auxiliary transformer. The transformer also includes cooling means in the form of a heat exchanger in which the liquid is cooled by circulating condenser water, chilled water or refrigerant from the chiller system. The cooling means may also be connected to cooling coils connected to the VSD. The size of the power transformer is significantly reduced by the use of the chiller system cooling system to remove heat from the transformer while in operation, thereby maintaining the ambient temperature rise of the transformer within its rated operating temperature range.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">One embodiment of the invention is directed to a chiller system. The chiller system includes a refrigerant circuit. The refrigerant circuit includes a compressor, a condenser, and an evaporator connected in a closed refrigerant loop. The refrigerant circuit is configured and disposed as a unit. A transformer is configured for connection to medium AC voltage input mains and low AC voltage output. The transformer has a fluid path therethrough in fluid communication with a cooling circuit. A variable speed drive is connected to the output of the transformer. The variable speed drive is configured to power a motor of the compressor. The transformer and the variable speed drive are mounted on the unit.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">An advantage of the present invention is the ability to provide a refrigeration system having low cost low-voltage electrical components, which can be connected directly to a medium/high-voltage electrical distribution system.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Another advantage of the present invention is that it provides a compact MV transformer that may be mounted on the chiller shells together with the VSD minimizing chiller floor space.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A further advantage of the present invention is the elimination of a power conduits, e.g., between the transformer and VSD, and between the VSD and motor.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Yet another advantage of the present invention is the elimination of the field wiring bending space and the incoming disconnect switch or circuit breaker within the VSD, to provide a less expensive, more compact VSD.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Still another advantage of the present invention is the direct transfer of the power transformer and VSD heat losses into the chiller system, avoiding rejection of the losses into the equipment room, thus maintaining lower ambient temperature of the environment.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Other features and advantages of the present invention will be apparent from the following more detailed description of the preferred embodiment, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings which illustrate, by way of example, the principles of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates schematically a general system configuration of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates schematically an embodiment of variable speed drive of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> illustrates schematically a transformer with a tertiary winding connected to a control panel.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates schematically a chiller cooling system that can be used with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an elevational view of a chiller system arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates a plan view of a chiller system arrangement.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates generally the system configuration of the present invention. An AC power source <b>102</b> supplies AC power to a medium/high voltage (MV) transformer <b>100</b>. The MV transformer <b>100</b> supplies low voltage AC power to a variable speed drive (VSD) <b>104</b>, which in turn, supplies AC power to a motor <b>106</b>. The motor <b>106</b> is preferably used to drive a corresponding compressor of a refrigeration or chiller system (see generally, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The AC power source <b>102</b> provides multi-phase (e.g., three phase), fixed medium/high voltage (e.g., greater than 600 volt), and fixed frequency AC power to the VSD <b>104</b> from an AC power mains or distribution system that is present at a site. The AC power mains can be supplied directly from an electric utility or can be supplied from one or more transforming substations between the electric utility and the AC power mains. The AC power source <b>102</b> can preferably supply a three-phase AC medium/high voltage or nominal line voltage of greater than 600V, preferably 3300V or 4160V, at a nominal line frequency of 50 Hz or 60 Hz to the primary of the MV transformer <b>100</b>. The MV transformer <b>100</b> in turn supplies a fixed secondary voltage of 200 V, 230 V, 380 V, 460 V, or 600 V to the VSD <b>104</b> at the corresponding primary frequency, depending on the corresponding AC power mains. It is to be understood that while the AC power source <b>102</b> can provide any suitable fixed nominal line voltage or fixed nominal line frequency to the MV transformer <b>100</b> depending on the configuration of the AC power mains, the embodiments of the present invention are applicable in general to an AC power source having a nominal voltage greater than 600V, and preferably greater than 2000V.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The MV transformer <b>100</b> receives AC power having medium/high voltage and fixed line frequency from the AC power source <b>102</b>. The MV transformer <b>100</b> may preferably be a liquid-filled transformer, in which the liquid acts as an insulator and cools the unit, while transferring heat to the chiller system. The MV transformer <b>100</b> provides low voltage output or secondary AC power (e.g., 200 V, 230 V, 380 V, 460 V, or 600 V), to the VSD <b>104</b>, and auxiliary control equipment. The MV transformer <b>100</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>) may also include one or more tertiary windings for single-phase or three-phase low voltage (less than 600V AC) control power. The VSD <b>104</b> provides AC voltage to the motor <b>106</b> at a desired voltage and desired frequency, both of which can be varied to satisfy particular requirements. Preferably, the VSD <b>104</b> can provide AC power to the motor <b>106</b> having higher voltages and frequencies or lower voltages and frequencies than the fixed voltage and fixed frequency received from the MV transformer <b>100</b> secondary voltage. The motor <b>106</b> may have a predetermined rated voltage and frequency that is greater than the MV transformer <b>100</b> fixed secondary voltage and frequency, however the rated motor voltage and frequency may also be equal to or lower than the MV transformer <b>100</b> fixed secondary voltage and frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates schematically some of the components in one embodiment of the VSD <b>104</b>. The VSD <b>104</b> can have three stages: a converter stage <b>202</b>, a DC link stage <b>204</b> and an inverter stage <b>206</b>. The converter <b>202</b> converts the fixed line frequency, fixed line voltage AC power from the transformer <b>100</b> into DC voltage. The DC link <b>204</b> filters the DC voltage from the converter <b>202</b> and provides energy storage components such as capacitors and/or inductors. Finally, the inverter <b>206</b> converts the DC voltage from the DC link <b>204</b> into variable frequency, variable voltage AC power for the motor <b>106</b>. The VSD <b>104</b> may be a conventional VSD with a non-boosted DC link voltage, i.e., the maximum output voltage/frequency is equal to the input line voltage/frequency. Alternately, the VSD <b>104</b> may be a VSD that includes an active converter, i.e., the active converter provides a boosted DC link, wherein the boosted DC link has a value greater than the peak of the input AC low voltage into the VSD and the VSD's maximum output voltage/frequency is greater than the input AC voltage/frequency of the low voltage secondary of the transformer. A more detailed explanation of the operation of the active converter configured to boost the DC link voltage of the VSD is contained in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/218,757 filed Sep. 2, 2005, entitled &#x201c;A Ride-Through Method And System For HVAC&#x26;R Chillers&#x201d;, and in U.S. patent application Ser. No. 11/123,685 filed May 6, 2005, entitled &#x201c;Variable Speed Drive For A Chiller System&#x201d;, both of which patent applications are commonly assigned, and are hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The motor <b>106</b> is preferably an induction motor that is capable of being driven at variable speeds. The induction motor can have any suitable pole arrangement including two poles, four poles or six poles. The induction motor is used to drive a load, preferably a compressor as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. In one embodiment of the present invention, the system and method of the present invention can be used to drive a compressor of a refrigeration system.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates generally the system of the present invention connected to a refrigeration system. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the HVAC, refrigeration or liquid chiller system <b>300</b> includes a compressor <b>302</b>, a condenser <b>304</b>, an evaporator <b>306</b>, and a control panel <b>308</b>. The control panel <b>308</b> can include a variety of different components such as an analog to digital (A/D) converter, a microprocessor, a non-volatile memory, and an interface board, to control operation of the refrigeration system <b>300</b>. The control panel <b>308</b> can be used to control the operation of the VSD <b>104</b> and the motor <b>106</b>, as well as other components of the chiller system <b>300</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the chiller structure permits the stacking or vertical arrangement of the major components on top of the chiller cooling system <b>300</b> to provide a prepackaged unit that occupies less floor space with a smaller footprint than a field fabricated unit where the components are arranged horizontally.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Compressor <b>302</b> compresses a refrigerant vapor and delivers the vapor to the condenser <b>304</b> through a discharge line. The compressor <b>302</b> is preferably a centrifugal compressor, but can be any suitable type of compressor, e.g., screw compressor, reciprocating compressor, etc. The refrigerant vapor delivered by the compressor <b>302</b> to the condenser <b>304</b> enters into a heat exchange relationship with a fluid, e.g., air or water, flowing through a heat-exchanger coil connected to a cooling tower (not shown). The refrigerant vapor in the condenser <b>304</b> undergoes a phase change to a refrigerant liquid as a result of the heat exchange relationship with the fluid. The condensed liquid refrigerant from condenser <b>304</b> flows through an expansion device (not shown) to an evaporator <b>306</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The evaporator <b>306</b> includes connections for a supply line <b>310</b> and a return line <b>312</b> of a cooling load. A secondary liquid, e.g., water, ethylene, calcium chloride brine or sodium chloride brine, travels into the evaporator <b>306</b> via return line <b>312</b> and exits the evaporator <b>306</b> via supply line <b>310</b>. The liquid refrigerant in the evaporator <b>306</b> enters into a heat exchange relationship with the secondary liquid to lower the temperature of the secondary liquid. The refrigerant liquid in the evaporator <b>306</b> undergoes a phase change to a refrigerant vapor as a result of the heat exchange relationship with the secondary liquid. The vapor refrigerant in the evaporator <b>306</b> exits the evaporator <b>306</b> and returns to the compressor <b>302</b> by a suction line to complete the cycle. It is to be understood that any suitable configuration of condenser <b>304</b> and evaporator <b>306</b> can be used in the system <b>300</b>, provided that the appropriate phase change of the refrigerant in the condenser <b>304</b> and evaporator <b>306</b> is obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The condenser fluid, preferably water, exits the condenser <b>304</b> via a return line <b>314</b> connected to a cooling tower (not shown), and is circulated from the cooling tower to the condenser <b>304</b> via supply line <b>316</b>. In a preferred embodiment, condenser water is supplied to the low voltage VSD <b>104</b> and MV transformer <b>100</b> from the condenser <b>304</b> via a supply line <b>318</b> connected to supply line <b>316</b>. Supply line <b>318</b> supplies cooling water to the VSD <b>104</b> and to the MV transformer <b>100</b>. Piping is preferably installed within each of VSD <b>104</b> and the MV transformer <b>100</b> for circulation of the condenser water, which absorbs heat generated by the electrical components. A return line <b>320</b> is connected to the return line <b>314</b> to complete the condenser water circuit from the VSD <b>104</b> and the MV transformer <b>100</b>. The heated condenser water from the VSD <b>104</b> and the MV transformer <b>100</b> is mixed with the condenser water in return line <b>314</b> and pumped to the cooling tower. Alternatively, chilled water, refrigerant or similar fluids may be used instead of condenser water to cool the MV transformer <b>100</b>, VSD <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A medium/high voltage disconnect switch <b>322</b> is disposed ahead of the MV transformer <b>100</b> to disconnect the MV transformer <b>100</b> from the input AC power line <b>102</b>. The purpose of the disconnect switch <b>322</b> is to comply with applicable electrical or fire codes that require a local disconnect means for MV equipment. Preferably, the MV disconnect switch <b>322</b> is integrated with or attached to the MV transformer <b>100</b> as a single package.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The HVAC, refrigeration or liquid chiller system <b>300</b> can include many other features that are not shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. These features have been purposely omitted to simplify the drawing for ease of illustration. Furthermore, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates the HVAC, refrigeration or liquid chiller system <b>300</b> as having one compressor connected in a single refrigerant circuit, it is to be understood that the system <b>300</b> can have multiple compressors, powered by a single VSD or multiple VSDs, connected into each of one or more refrigerant circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Preferably, a control panel, microprocessor or controller can provide control signals to the VSD <b>104</b> to control the operation of the VSD <b>104</b> (and thereby the motor <b>106</b>) to provide the optimal operational setting for the VSD <b>104</b> and motor <b>106</b> depending on the particular sensor readings received by the control panel. For example, in the refrigeration system <b>300</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the control panel <b>308</b> can adjust the output voltage and frequency of the VSD <b>104</b> to correspond to changing conditions in the refrigeration system, i.e., the control panel <b>308</b> can increase or decrease the output voltage and frequency of the VSD <b>104</b> in response to increasing or decreasing load conditions on the compressor <b>302</b> in order to obtain a desired operating speed of the motor <b>106</b> and a desired load output of the compressor <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring next to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, an exemplary physical layout of the MV transformer <b>100</b>, the MV disconnect switch <b>322</b> and VSD <b>104</b> is provided. MV transformer <b>100</b> and disconnect switch <b>322</b> are disposed within an enclosure <b>200</b>. The enclosure <b>200</b>, control panel <b>308</b> and the VSD <b>104</b>, are all mounted on top of the chiller cooling system <b>300</b>. The condenser <b>304</b> has an exterior shell and the evaporator <b>306</b> has an exterior shell. The compressor <b>302</b> and the motor <b>106</b> are integrally mounted on at least one of the condenser and evaporator shells. A low voltage VSD <b>104</b>&#x2014;e.g., rated less than 600VAC input&#x2014;is mounted on at least one of the exterior shells and physically attached directly to the motor, <b>106</b>, thereby eliminating the need for a motor terminal box and an electrical power conduit connecting the VSD <b>104</b> and motor <b>106</b>. The MV transformer <b>100</b>, is also mounted on at least one of the condenser and evaporator shells. The MV transformer <b>100</b> is physically directly attached to the VSD <b>104</b>. By directly attaching the MV transformer to the VSD <b>104</b>, the space requirement is reduced, because the incoming field wire and conduit bending space requirement, the VSD input disconnect switch or circuit breaker, and the electrical power conduit between the transformer and VSD are all eliminated. By arranging the MV transformer <b>100</b>, disconnect switch <b>322</b>, and other components on top of the chiller system <b>300</b>, it is possible to mount all of the components of the system on a single packaged system, as discussed above. There is a window <b>323</b> provided in the cabinet of the disconnect switch <b>322</b> to allow viewing of the disconnect switch blades so that the technician can be assured they are open. This window feature is standard on all medium/high voltage equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">While the invention has been described with reference to a preferred embodiment, it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes may be made and equivalents may be substituted for elements thereof without departing from the scope of the invention. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from the essential scope thereof Therefore, it is intended that the invention not be limited to the particular embodiment disclosed as the best mode contemplated for carrying out this invention, but that the invention will include all embodiments falling within the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A chiller system comprising:
<claim-text>a refrigerant circuit comprising compressor, a condenser, and an evaporator connected in a closed refrigerant loop, the refrigerant circuit being configured and disposed as a unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transformer configured for connection to a medium/high AC voltage input mains and low AC voltage output, the transformer having a fluid path therethrough in fluid communication with a cooling circuit; a variable speed drive connected to the output of the transformer, the variable speed drive configured to power a motor of the compressor; the transformer and the variable speed drive mounted on the unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the transformer being configured to provide at least two output low voltage levels, a first output low voltage level for the variable speed drive and other power equipment, and a low voltage for the control panel and control equipment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A chiller system comprising:
<claim-text>a refrigerant circuit comprising compressor, a condenser, and an evaporator connected in a closed refrigerant loop, the refrigerant circuit being configured and disposed as a unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transformer configured for connection to a medium/high AC voltage input mains and low AC voltage output, the transformer having a fluid path therethrough in fluid communication with a cooling circuit; a variable speed drive connected to the output of the transformer, the variable speed drive configured to power a motor of the compressor; the transformer and the variable speed drive mounted on the unit; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the transformer includes insulating heat transfer liquid or gas for cooling the transformer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the variable speed drive includes a fluid path therethrough connected in a heat exchange relation with a fluid selected from the group consisting of:
<claim-text>condenser water, chilled water and refrigerant.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transformer includes a fluid path therethrough connected in a heat exchange relation with a fluid selected from the group consisting of:
<claim-text>condenser water, chilled water and refrigerant.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the variable speed drive also includes:
<claim-text>a converter stage connected to a low voltage AC output of the transformer providing a fixed input AC voltage to the variable speed drive, the converter stage of the variable speed drive being configured to convert the fixed input AC voltage to a boosted DC voltage greater than the peak value of the fixed input AC voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a DC link connected to the converter stage, the DC link being configured to filter the boosted DC voltage and store energy from the converter stage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first inverter stage connected to the DC link, the first inverter stage being configured to convert the boosted DC voltage into an output power having a variable output voltage and a variable output frequency the variable output voltage having a maximum voltage greater in magnitude than the fixed input AC voltage to the variable speed drive and the variable output frequency having a maximum frequency greater than the input frequency to the variable speed drive.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the variable speed drive is physically attached directly to the motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transformer is physically attached directly to the variable speed drive.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the transformer is configured to provide at least two output low voltage levels, the at least two output low voltage levels including a first voltage level for the variable speed drive and other power equipment, and a second voltage level for the control panel and control equipment.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the variable speed drive includes a fluid path therethrough connected in a heat exchange relation with a fluid selected from the group consisting of:
<claim-text>condenser water, chilled water, and refrigerant.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the transformer includes a fluid path therethrough connected in a heat exchange relation with a fluid selected from the group consisting of:
<claim-text>condenser water, chilled water and refrigerant.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the variable speed drive also includes:
<claim-text>a converter stage connected to a low voltage AC output of the transformer providing a fixed input AC voltage to the variable speed drive, the converter stage of the variable speed drive being configured to convert the fixed input AC voltage to a boosted DC voltage greater than the peak value of the fixed input AC voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a DC link connected to the converter stage, the DC link being configured to filter the boosted DC voltage and store energy from the converter stage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first inverter stage connected to the DC link, the first inverter stage being configured to convert the boosted DC voltage into an output power having a variable output voltage and a variable output frequency the variable output voltage having a maximum voltage greater in magnitude than the fixed input AC voltage to the variable speed drive and the variable output frequency having a maximum frequency greater than the input frequency to the variable speed drive.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the variable speed drive is physically attached directly to the motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the transformer is physically attached directly to the variable speed drive.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The chiller system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transformer includes insulating heat transfer liquid or gas for cooling the transformer. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
