<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640737-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640737</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11625220</doc-number>
<date>20070119</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>286</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>16</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>31</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60477</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Screw style hydraulic jack</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2420910</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Richards</name>
<date>19470500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>254 93 H</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4598898</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hsu et al.</name>
<date>19860700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4706937</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chung</name>
<date>19871100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4746097</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Chung et al.</name>
<date>19880500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5522583</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Martin</name>
<date>19960600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5648606</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Spalding</name>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 92140</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7021911</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Moradmand et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>417470</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>8</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60477</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>417470</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080173013</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080724</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hernandez, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Hector Ray</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fullerton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Mayes</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick B.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Logan</city>
<state>UT</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fulwider Patton LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Alltrade Tools LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Long Beach</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Lopez</last-name>
<first-name>F. Daniel</first-name>
<department>3745</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A hydraulic jack system is described, suitable for lifting heavy loads such as automobiles. The jack system is operable by a powered driver fitted with a socket for coupling to a nut rotationally fixed to the jack system, wherein the driver is removable directly after use. As such, no handle is required for activating the hydraulic jack system. The jack system has a low profile, reducing the danger of being accidentally knocked into during operation. When operated by a powered driver, the driver rotates a camshaft mounted to the jack system, the camshaft reciprocally drives a push rod that activates a plunger for hydraulically elevating a piston ram.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="211.33mm" wi="129.96mm" file="US07640737-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="199.39mm" wi="145.20mm" file="US07640737-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="218.78mm" wi="165.52mm" file="US07640737-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="228.60mm" wi="150.03mm" file="US07640737-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to hydraulic jacks for lifting loads such as automobiles and other heavy objects. More specifically, it relates to a device and method for conveniently and rapidly applying input energy needed to raise the ram piston of a hydraulic jack.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Hydraulic pistons are well known in the art, employing the well known principle of hydraulic leverage to impart an enormous force to a lifting ram under mechanical advantage. A small force is repeatedly applied to a plunger in a hydraulic cylinder which connects to a larger cylinder through an orifice. The numerous small repeated force applications to the plunger in the small cylinder are converted to a large force exerted by a ram piston in the large cylinder through known structures.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Typically, the force applied to the plunger in the small cylinder is manually applied through a pivoting handle, which is often removable. The handle acts as a lever having, to some degree, its own mechanical advantage. Thus, while the user applies a hand load to the end of the handle remote from the pivot point, the handle applies a load to the plunger at a moving point on its length nearer the pivot point, thereby multiplying the hand load to a load on the plunger in a range, typically, of about 10-15 times the hand load.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In another configuration known in the art, a motor may be connected to a hydraulic jack system. The motor may be configured to apply a reciprocating load to the plunger through a gear box which then applies a rotational force to an eccentric cam. The cam transmits a reciprocating force to the plunger.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, problems remain in the prior art. Where a handle is used to apply a repeating load to the plunger, the handle presents a dangerous obstacle if it is left connected to the jack after the jack is used to elevate a load. Persons walking by the jack may accidentally knock the protruding handle and move the jack, thereby endangering the security of an elevated load. Storing a jack activated by a removable handle will always require storing the handle along with the jack. In a busy workshop, a handle may easily become separated from the jack, thus creating problems and inconvenience when next the jack is to be used. Where an electrical motor is mounted on a jack system for providing a reciprocating force to the plunger, inconvenience may be caused by electrical conduits extending from the motor. Moreover, the motor itself, when mounted to the jack system, creates an additional protrusion which adds to the profile of the jack, thus providing an additional source of danger by presenting added structure that may be accidentally knocked into when the jack system is supporting an elevated load.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Thus, there remains in the art a need for a low profile hydraulic jacking system that may be conveniently and rapidly activated by a user. The present invention satisfies these and other needs.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, there is described a hydraulic jacking system that overcomes shortcomings in the art. In a preferred embodiment, the hydraulic jack system is of a kind having a large hydraulic cylinder for elevating a ram piston, a small hydraulic cylinder hydraulically interconnected with the large cylinder for applying an input load via a plunger. The hydraulic jacking system of the present invention may include a base plate upon which the large cylinder and the small cylinder are mounted. A push rod is provided for reciprocally moving the plunger on a first axis. A camshaft is provided, configured to rotate about a second axis, the camshaft including a rotor offset from the second axis. The camshaft has a first terminal end and a second terminal end, each terminal end lying on the second axis. At least one terminal end of the camshaft is tipped only by a nut rotationally fixed to the at least one terminal end. In this configuration, the hydraulic jacking system is suitable for operation with a powered driver fitted with a socket for coupling to the nut, the driver being removable after use to leave the jacking system with a low profile for enhanced safety.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In another aspect of the invention, the push rod defines a linear slot extending perpendicular to the first axis, and the rotor is positioned to pass through the slot. The camshaft may be mounted to two frame members, each frame member being mounted on the base plate. A return spring may be configured to surround a portion of the push rod. In a further aspect, a collar may be mounted on the small hydraulic cylinder, and a portion of the push rod be configured to slide within the collar.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In yet a further aspect of the invention, each of the first and second terminal ends of the camshaft may be tipped only by a nut rotationally fixed to each terminal end. Each nut fixed to each terminal end may be positioned in relation to the jack system to receive a socket mounted on a powered driver. In this aspect, the jack system lends itself to operation by a powered driver from one of two points, adding versatility to the jack in that a user may apply a rotational load to the jack via one nut when the other nut is concealed by equipment or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Finally, support may be provided for the camshaft at two positions along the camshaft. The support at the two positions may include ball bearings, and may also include two frame elements mounted to the base plate.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">This configuration overcomes shortcomings in the prior art, and provides a robust, versatile, and inexpensive configuration for a hydraulic jacking system.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">These and other advantages of the invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description thereof and the accompanying exemplary drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a hydraulic jack having features of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partially exploded view of the jack of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side elevational view of the jack of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, taken in partial section</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">With reference to the drawings which are by way of example and not limitation, a hydraulic jack system is disclosed having features of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, there is seen a preferred embodiment of the hydraulic jack system of the present invention, generally identified by numeral <b>20</b>. The jack system <b>20</b> includes a conventional large hydraulic cylinder <b>22</b> from which protrudes a first ram piston <b>24</b>. In an alternative embodiment, the first ram piston <b>24</b> may include a second ram piston <b>26</b> extending co-axially with, and within, the first ram piston in a conventional way.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The large cylinder <b>22</b> may be connected to a base plate <b>28</b> for stabilizing the jack system <b>20</b> as a whole. A small hydraulic cylinder <b>30</b> is provided, and is also connected to the base plate <b>28</b>. The small cylinder <b>30</b> and the large cylinder <b>22</b> are interconnected by fluid passages and valves in a conventional way so as to permit hydraulic forces applied to the small cylinder to be transmitted the large cylinder for exerting hydraulic forces to lift the piston under mechanical advantage. Forces are applied to the small cylinder be means of a plunger <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) that exerts a load directly on the hydraulic contents of the small cylinder</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Mounted on top of the small cylinder <b>30</b> is a cylindrical collar <b>32</b>. Two frame members <b>34</b> flank the collar and are connected to the base plate <b>28</b>. A push rod <b>36</b> is provided for activating the plunger <b>31</b>. The push rod <b>36</b> includes an elongate needle <b>38</b> having an axis, shaped to slide along the axis within the supporting collar <b>32</b> and to contact the plunger <b>31</b> for activating the same. Mounted symmetrically on top of the needle is a generally rectangular window <b>40</b> having a slot <b>42</b> extending perpendicular to the axis of the needle.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A camshaft <b>44</b> is provided for exerting a vertical reciprocating motion to the push rod <b>36</b>. The camshaft includes two opposing discs <b>46</b> each having a center point. The camshaft is configured to rotate about an axis extending through the center points of the two discs. An elongate cylindrical rotor <b>48</b> spans between the two discs, offset from the center points of the discs. Each disc has a bush <b>50</b>, configured to fit snugly in an opening <b>52</b> at an upward extremity of each frame <b>34</b>. Optionally, the bushes and openings may be configured to include ball bearings <b>53</b> as desired.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">When the jack system is assembled, as best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the needle <b>38</b> of the push rod <b>36</b> slides within the collar <b>32</b>, the needle being in contact with the plunger <b>31</b>. The camshaft <b>44</b> rests on the frames <b>34</b> via the bearings <b>50</b>, with the rotor <b>48</b> passing through the slot <b>42</b> in the window <b>40</b>. A return spring <b>52</b>, each terminal end flanked by a washer <b>54</b>, surrounds the collar <b>32</b> and the needle <b>38</b> residing within the collar.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The axial extremities of the camshaft terminate in at least one, preferably two, nuts <b>56</b> which are preferably hexagonal head (hex head). These nuts <b>56</b> protrude from the camshaft to provide an unimpeded and convenient point of coupling for a mating hex head socket (not shown) attached to a driver which may be a pneumatic driver, a power cord driver, or a rechargeable battery powered driver, or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Thus, in use, the operator of the jack system positions the jack under the object which he wishes to elevate, and takes care to expose the nuts <b>56</b> of the system (or one nut where it is not possible to expose two nuts) to a point that provides easy access for further operation by a powered driver. He then takes a powered driver such as described above having a socket shaped to mate with at least one of the nuts <b>56</b> and couples the socket to the nut. By activating the driver, he causes the camshaft <b>44</b> to rotate about its axis while mounted on the bushes <b>50</b>. The rotation of the camshaft causes the rotor <b>48</b> to orbit around the axis of the camshaft, while the rotor is positioned within the slot <b>42</b> of the push rod <b>36</b>. This action causes the needle <b>38</b> to reciprocate vertically in line with the plunger <b>31</b> while in contact with the plunger <b>31</b> of the small cylinder <b>30</b>, thereby activating the hydraulics of the jack system to lift the ram piston <b>24</b>, <b>26</b>. The operator then removes the driver and stores it, leaving the low profile jack system <b>20</b> to hold the load in an elevated position. There is no handle that can be left protruding from the jack to cause a hazardous situation. There are no electric wires protruding from the jack system. There is no motor, or gear system, mounted with the jack to increase the profile of the jack system, as used in a garage or shop work space, and thereby enhance the hazard inherent in a jacking system.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Thus, an operator of the jack system of the present invention has the ability to rapidly deploy the jack system, rapidly elevate a load with a separable powered driver system, and then remove the driver system to leave the jack with a low profile to support the load.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Thus, it is seen that the jack system of the present invention provides novel and useful features for elevating loads within a crowded workshop environment, and overcoming shortcomings in the prior art. The present invention may, of course, be carried out in other specific ways than those herein set forth without departing from the essential characteristics of the invention. The present embodiments are, therefore, to be considered in all respects as illustrative and not restrictive, and all changes coming within the meaning and equivalency range of the appended claims are intended to be embraced therein.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A hydraulic jack system of a kind having a large hydraulic cylinder for elevating a ram piston, a small hydraulic cylinder hydraulically interconnected with the large cylinder for applying an input load via a plunger, comprising:
<claim-text>a base plate upon which the large cylinder and the small cylinder are mounted;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a push rod for reciprocally moving the plunger on a first axis and, thereby, for causing the plunger to apply an input load through the small cylinder to the jack system so as to elevate the ram piston of the large cylinder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camshaft configured to rotate about a second axis and, thereby, to exert a reciprocating motion to the push rod and to the plunger, the camshaft having a first terminal end and a second terminal end, each terminal end lying on the second axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, each of the first and second terminal ends of the camshaft is tipped only by a nut rotationally fixed to each terminal end; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>each nut fixed to each terminal end is positioned in relation to the jack system to receive a socket that is mounted on a powered driver.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the camshaft has a rotor offset from the second axis, and wherein the push rod defines a linear slot extending perpendicular to the first axis, and the rotor is positioned to pass through the slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the camshaft is mounted to two frame members, each frame member being mounted on the base plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the jack system further comprises a return spring surrounding a portion of the push rod.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a collar is mounted on the small hydraulic cylinder, and a portion of the push rod is configured to slide within the collar.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein support for the camshaft is provided at two positions along the camshaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the support for the camshaft at the two positions along the camshaft include ball bearings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The hydraulic jack system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the support for the camshaft at the two positions along the camshaft includes two frame elements mounted to the base plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
