<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640751-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640751</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11440821</doc-number>
<date>20060525</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>762</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>F</section>
<class>02</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60736</main-classification>
<further-classification> 60 395</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Fuel heating system for turbine engines</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2914917</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Van Nest</name>
<date>19591200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60785</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3049878</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Goodall et al.</name>
<date>19620800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3300965</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sherlaw et al.</name>
<date>19670100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3895492</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Forster et al.</name>
<date>19750700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4075831</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McGann</name>
<date>19780200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4085579</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Holzapfel et al.</name>
<date>19780400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4354345</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Dreisbach, Jr. et al.</name>
<date>19821000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4406128</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fanaritis et al.</name>
<date>19830900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5581997</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Janes</name>
<date>19961200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 60 3912</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5794448</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fujioka et al.</name>
<date>19980800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5802841</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Maeda</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6253554</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kobayashi et al.</name>
<date>20010700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6385960</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Kress et al.</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6584778</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Griffiths et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6598400</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nash et al.</name>
<date>20030700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00016">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6711889</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kuo et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00017">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0120715</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Labrador</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60736</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60 395</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60 3952</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 60 39511</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070271928</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071129</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Putnam</last-name>
<first-name>Robert A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Winter Springs</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Siemens Energy, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Orlando</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Cuff</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<department>3741</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A fuel heating system for fuel usable in a turbine engine. The fuel heating system may include at least one fuel heating chamber in communication with an exhaust stack of a turbine engine. The fuel heating chamber may be configured to allow exhaust gases to flow through the at least one fuel heating chamber. The fuel heating system may also include at least one conduit positioned in the fuel heating chamber. The conduit may be configured to receive fuel from a fuel source at a first temperature, allow the fuel to flow through the conduit, and exhaust the fuel at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="107.36mm" wi="130.30mm" file="US07640751-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="228.60mm" wi="134.79mm" file="US07640751-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="221.06mm" wi="135.38mm" file="US07640751-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="138.77mm" wi="138.60mm" file="US07640751-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention is directed generally to turbine engines, and more particularly to fuel systems of turbine engines.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">It is known that in thermal power turbine engines, complete combustion of fuel is desired. In addition, it has further been determined that the efficiency of a turbine engine may be increased by heating fuel before the fuel is ignited in a turbine engine. Numerous heating systems have been created to heat fuel before ignition. However, many of these conventional heating systems place a load on the turbine engines to which they are attached, thereby decreasing the efficiency of the turbine engines. Thus, a need exists for an efficient fuel heating system for turbine engines.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">This invention is directed to a fuel heating system for a turbine engine. The fuel heating system may be configured to increase the temperature of fuel usable in a turbine engine by using heat in exhaust gases of the turbine engine. In particular, the fuel heating system may be formed from one or more fuel heating chambers in communication with an exhaust stack of a turbine engine. The fuel heating system may be configured to allow exhaust gases to flow through the fuel heating chamber to heat the fuel. The fuel heating system may also include one or more conduits positioned in the fuel heating chamber. The conduit may be configured to receive fuel from one or more fuel sources, such as a fuel tank, at a first temperature, allow the fuel to flow through the conduit, and exhaust the fuel at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The fuel heating system may include one or more plates for controlling the flow of exhaust gases into the fuel heating chamber. In at least one embodiment, two plates may be used and include one or more orifices. The orifices may be aligned to enable exhaust gases to flow through the plate. The plates may be moved relative to each other to reduce or increase the size of the openings created by the two plates overlapping the exhaust gas orifices.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The fuel heating system may also include a method of increasing the temperature of fuel for a turbine engine. During use, fuel may be passed into the conduit at a first temperature. The fuel may receive heat from exhaust gases flowing through the fuel heating chamber and may be expelled from the conduit at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature. In particular, exhaust gases may flow into the fuel heating chamber through the exhaust gas orifices in the plates or through the inlets, depending on which embodiment of the fuel heating system is used. The plates may be used to control the flow of exhaust gases into the fuel heating chamber by sliding one plate relative to the other plate, to control the effective opening of the orifices. The exhaust gas flowing through the fuel heating chamber may also be controlled with dampers. In at least one embodiment, the fuel heating system may be capable of heating the fuel to a temperature of about 550 degrees Fahrenheit using an exhaust gas temperature of about 1,100 degrees Fahrenheit. The exhaust gas in the fuel heating chamber may be returned to the exhaust stack through outlets or through the orifices in the plates.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">An advantage of this invention is that fuel heating may be accomplished with exhaust gases without the need to reduce the velocity of exhaust gas flow. Instead, the exhaust gases may be passed through the fuel heating chamber directly from the exhaust stack.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Another advantage of this invention is that direct flow through of exhaust gases is not required to heat fuel in the system. Rather, fuel may be heated to about 550 degrees Fahrenheit with exhaust gases of about 1,100 degrees Fahrenheit using an open valve system in which exhaust gases may flow into and out of the fuel heating chamber through exhaust gas orifices in the plates.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">These and other embodiments are described in more detail below.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and form a part of the specification, illustrate embodiments of the presently disclosed invention and, together with the description, disclose the principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional side view of an exhaust stack in an exhaust system of a turbine engine including an inclined plate forming a cavity utilized by at least one embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is another cross-sectional side view of an exhaust stack in an exhaust system of a turbine engine including aspects of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a partial perspective view of the fuel heating system positioned in an exhaust stack.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an alternative fuel heating system in an exhaust stack of a turbine engine.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of another alternative fuel heating system in an exhaust stack of a turbine engine.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref>, the invention is directed to a fuel heating system <b>10</b> for a turbine engine. The fuel heating system <b>10</b> may be configured to increase the temperature of fuel usable in a turbine engine by using heat found in exhaust gases of the turbine engine. In particular, the fuel heating system <b>10</b> may be formed from one or more fuel heating chambers <b>12</b> in communication with an exhaust stack <b>14</b> of a turbine engine. The fuel heating system <b>10</b> may be configured to allow exhaust gases to flow through the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> to heat the fuel. The fuel heating system <b>10</b> may also include one or more conduits <b>16</b> positioned in the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>. The conduit <b>16</b> may be configured to receive fuel from one or more fuel sources, such as, but not limited to, a fuel tank, at a first temperature, allow the fuel to flow through the conduit <b>16</b>, and exhaust the fuel at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, the fuel heating system <b>10</b> may be positioned inside an exhaust stack <b>14</b> of a turbine engine. The fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may include one or more exhaust flow control structures <b>18</b> configured to control the exhaust flow in the exhaust stack <b>14</b>. The exhaust flow control structures <b>18</b> may be any structure capable of controlling the exhaust flow in the exhaust stack <b>14</b>. In one embodiment, the exhaust flow control structure <b>18</b> may be formed from plates <b>18</b> usable to define the fuel heating chamber. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the fuel heating chamber may be formed from a plate <b>18</b> positioned in a corner <b>20</b> of the exhausts stack. The plate <b>18</b> may be coupled to a first wall <b>22</b> and coupled to a second wall <b>24</b> that is generally orthogonal to the first wall <b>22</b>. However, the first and second walls <b>22</b>, <b>24</b> need not be orthogonal to each other. In other embodiments, the first and second walls <b>22</b> may be positioned in other nonparallel positions relative to each other. In one embodiment, the plate <b>18</b> may be formed from an outer plate <b>26</b> positioned over an inner plate <b>28</b>. The outer plate <b>26</b> may include one or more exhaust gas orifices <b>30</b>, and the inner plate <b>28</b> may include one or more exhaust gas orifices <b>32</b>. The exhaust gas orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> may be positioned on the outer and inner plates <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, respectively, so that the orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> may be aligned. The plates <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> may be moved generally along the major plane of the plates <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> relative to each other to change the size of the opening through the orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b>. The plates <b>26</b>,<b>28</b> may be moved to a position in which no portions of the orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> are aligned, thereby sealing the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> and preventing exhaust gases from flowing through the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In at least one embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the inner and outer plates <b>28</b>, <b>26</b> may include a plurality of exhaust gas orifices <b>32</b>, <b>30</b> in each plate <b>38</b>, <b>26</b>. In one embodiment, the exhaust orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> may be positioned such that all of the orifices <b>30</b> of the outer plate <b>26</b> may be aligned with all of the orifices <b>32</b> of the inner plate <b>28</b>. In addition, the outer plate <b>26</b> may be moved relative to the inner plate <b>28</b> such that all of the orifices <b>32</b> of the inner plate <b>28</b> are covered by the outer plate <b>26</b>. In another embodiment, the orifices <b>32</b> in the inner plate <b>28</b> may be positioned such that some, but not all of the orifices <b>32</b> are aligned with orifices <b>30</b> of the outer plate <b>26</b>. The orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> may have any appropriate size. Movement of the outer plate <b>26</b> relative to the inner plate <b>28</b>, or vice versa, may be remotely controlled through the use of an actuator system.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the conduit <b>16</b> carrying the fuel may be positioned in the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>. In at least one embodiment, the conduit <b>16</b> may be formed from a serpentine shaped conduit <b>16</b>. In other embodiments, the conduit <b>16</b> may have other shapes. The conduit <b>16</b> may be formed from highly conductive materials, such as, but not limited to, carbon steel pipe, with or without additional fins to facilitate heat transfer. The conduit <b>16</b> may have any cross-sectional area sufficient to pass a fuel through the conduit <b>16</b> at a desired flow rate.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In another embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the fuel heating system <b>10</b> may be placed in the exhaust stack <b>14</b> of the turbine engine. In particular, the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may be formed from a baffle <b>34</b> positioned in the exhaust stack <b>14</b>. The baffle <b>34</b> may be aligned generally with a longitudinal axis <b>36</b> of the exhaust stack <b>14</b>. The baffle <b>34</b> may form an inlet <b>38</b> and an outlet <b>40</b> for the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>. A conduit <b>16</b> may be positioned in the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> downstream from the inlet <b>38</b> and upstream from the outlet <b>40</b>. The conduit <b>16</b> may be configured as previously set forth.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The fuel heating system <b>10</b> may include one or more silencers <b>42</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, one or more silencers <b>42</b> may be positioned in the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>. The silencers <b>42</b> may be positioned downstream from the conduit <b>16</b>. The silencers <b>42</b> may also be positioned in the exhaust stack <b>14</b> proximate to the silencers <b>42</b> positioned in the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b>, and <b>4</b>. The silencers <b>42</b> may be, but are not limited to being, an absorptive silencer, produced by Braden Corp. of Tulsa, Okla.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The fuel system <b>10</b> may include one or more dampers <b>44</b> for controlling the exhaust flow. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the damper <b>44</b> may be positioned downstream from the conduit <b>16</b> and downstream from the silencer <b>42</b>. The damper <b>44</b> may be any suitable design capable of substantially preventing exhaust gases from passing through fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>. The damper <b>44</b> may be configured to be adjustable to control the flow of exhaust flows.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In yet another embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may be a self-contained chamber <b>12</b> having an inlet <b>46</b> in an outerwall <b>48</b> of the exhaust stack for receiving exhaust gases, and an outlet <b>50</b> in the outerwall <b>48</b>. The fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may include a conduit <b>16</b> that may be configured as previously set forth. In addition, the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may include one or more dampers <b>44</b> that may be positioned downstream or upstream from the conduit <b>16</b>. One or more silencers <b>42</b> may be positioned in the exhaust stack <b>14</b> proximate to the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b>. The silencer <b>42</b> may be positioned in one, two, or more rows, so as to accommodate the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">During use, fuel is passed into the conduit <b>16</b> at a first temperature. The fuel may receive heat from exhaust gases flowing through the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> and may be expelled from the conduit <b>16</b> at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature. In particular, exhaust gases may flow into the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> through the exhaust gas orifices <b>30</b>,<b>32</b> in the plates <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> or through the inlets <b>38</b>, <b>46</b>, depending on which embodiment of the fuel heating system <b>10</b> is used. The plates <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> may be used to control the flow of exhaust gases into the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> by sliding one plate <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> relative to the other plate <b>26</b>, <b>28</b>, thereby reducing the effective opening of the orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b>. In the embodiments shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4-5</figref>, the exhaust gas flowing through the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may be controlled with dampers <b>44</b>. In at least one embodiment, the fuel heating system <b>10</b> is capable of heating the fuel to a temperature of about 550 degrees Fahrenheit using an exhaust gas temperature of about 1,100 degrees Fahrenheit. The exhaust gas in the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> may be returned to the exhaust stack <b>14</b> through outlet <b>50</b> or may exit the exhaust stack <b>14</b> directly through outlet <b>40</b>. Gases may exit the fuel heating chamber <b>12</b> through exhaust gas orifices <b>30</b>, <b>32</b> as well.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The foregoing is provided for purposes of illustrating, explaining, and describing embodiments of this invention. Modifications and adaptations to these embodiments will be apparent to those skilled in the art and may be made without departing from the scope or spirit of this invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A fuel heating system for a turbine engine, comprising: at least one fuel heating chamber in communication with an exhaust stack of a turbine engine and configured to allow exhaust gases to flow through the at least one fuel heating chamber; and
<claim-text>at least one conduit positioned in the at least one fuel heating chamber and configured to receive fuel from at least one fuel source at a first temperature, allow the fuel to flow through the at least one conduit, and exhaust the fuel at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one fuel heating chamber is positioned in a corner of the exhaust stack of the turbine engine; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least one fuel heating chamber is formed from at least one plate attached to a first wall of the exhaust stack and attached to a second wall of the exhaust stack that is positioned nonparallel to the first wall and wherein the heating chamber is defined by the plate, the first wall, and the second wall.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The fuel heating system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one conduit comprises a serpentine shaped metallic conduit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The fuel heating system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one plate comprises a first plate having at least one exhaust gas orifice positioned over a second plate having at least one exhaust gas orifice, wherein the first plate is movable relative to the second plate to adjust a cross-sectional area of the at least one exhaust gas orifice of the second plate to control flow of exhaust gases into the at least one fuel heating chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The fuel heating system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first plate comprises a plurality of exhaust gas orifices, and the second plate comprises a plurality of exhaust gas orifices.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The fuel heating system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are offset laterally from the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The fuel heating system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are offset laterally from the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate such that in a first position, the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are aligned with the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate, and in a second position, the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate are covered by the first plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The fuel heating system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are offset laterally from the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate such that in a first position, a portion of the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are aligned with the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate, and in a second position, the portion of the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate are covered by the first plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method of heating fuel usable in a turbine engine, comprising:
<claim-text>passing fuel from a fuel storage location to a fuel heating system for a turbine engine, wherein the fuel heating system comprises at least one fuel heating chamber in communication with an exhaust stack of a turbine engine and configured to allow exhaust gases to flow through the at least one fuel heating chamber; and at least one conduit positioned in the at least one fuel heating chamber; receiving fuel from at least one fuel source at a first temperature; passing the fuel through the at least one conduit; and exhausting the fuel at a second temperature that is higher than the first temperature, wherein passing fuel from a fuel storage location to a fuel heating system for a turbine engine comprises passing fuel to a fuel heating system comprising at least one fuel heating chamber positioned in a corner of the exhaust stack of the turbine engine and formed from at least one plate attached to a first wall of the exhaust stack and attached to a second wall of the exhaust stack that is positioned nonparallel to the first wall, wherein the heating chamber is defined by the plate, the first wall, and the second wall; and wherein the at least one plate comprises a first plate having at least one exhaust gas orifice positioned over a second plate having at least one exhaust gas orifice, wherein the first plate is movable relative to the second plate to adjust a cross-sectional area of the at least one exhaust gas orifice of the second plate to control flow of exhaust gases into the at least one fuel heating chamber.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein passing fuel from a fuel storage location to a fuel heating system for a turbine engine comprises passing fuel to a fuel heating system, wherein the first plate comprises a plurality of exhaust gas orifices and the second plate comprises a plurality of exhaust gas orifices, wherein the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are offset laterally from the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate such that in a first position, the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the first plate are aligned with the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate, and in a second position, the plurality of exhaust gas orifices in the second plate are covered by the first plate. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
