<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640882-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640882</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11932854</doc-number>
<date>20071031</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>79</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>63</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>114361</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Boat cover attachment guide and boat cover</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3172419</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lewis</name>
<date>19650300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>135119</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6026761</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Parniske et al.</name>
<date>20000200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>114343</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6032433</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hatziathanasiou</name>
<date>20000300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 5274212</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7281486</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bach et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>114361</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>114361</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090107389</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090430</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Parniske</last-name>
<first-name>Dennis J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Braedenton</city>
<state>FL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Nixon &#x26; Vanderhye P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Taylor Made Group, LLC</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Gloversville</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Swinehart</last-name>
<first-name>Ed</first-name>
<department>3617</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An apparatus for attaching a boat cover to a boat is disclosed. The apparatus includes an elongated member defining a first leg and a second leg. A plurality of notches are defined in the first leg of the elongated member. A flexible cover is affixed to the second leg of the elongated member along at least one edge. A guide is affixable to a deck of a boat. The guide defines at least one securement groove therein. The securement groove accepts the second leg of the elongated member therein.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="145.37mm" wi="135.38mm" file="US07640882-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="206.33mm" wi="149.44mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="235.88mm" wi="131.57mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="160.70mm" wi="114.22mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="166.96mm" wi="125.81mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="135.38mm" wi="147.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="102.19mm" wi="137.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="217.34mm" wi="156.04mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640882-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a first-filed patent application and does not rely on any other patent application for priority.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a boat cover attachment guide and boat cover. More specifically, the invention relates to a design that facilitates installation of a boat cover on a boat.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE RELATED ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In the boating industry, it is common for boat owners to cover their boats during periods of non-use. Alternatively, it is common for boat owners to cover the exposed passenger areas of a boat in unfavorable weather conditions, i.e., when it is raining.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">In the prior art, it is common for a boat to include a plurality of male portions of snap fasteners at the periphery of the area to be covered by the boat cover. At the windshield of the boat, the male portions of the snap fasteners typically are affixed at regular intervals along the top rail of the windshield. Along other structures, such as along a radar arch, which typically extends above the passenger area of the boat, the male portions of the snap fasteners are affixed directly to the deck.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The boat cover has attached to it the female portions of snap fasteners. When the cover is properly positioned on the boat, the male and female portions of the snap fasteners are in register with one another so that they may be connected to one another, thereby affixing the boat cover to the boat.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">One drawback to the use of snap fasteners is that the male portion of the snap fasteners remains on the top rail of the windshield or on the deck of the boat after the cover is removed. This arrangement is considered by some to be unsightly. There are those that would prefer not to have the male portions of the snap fasteners visible.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Snap fasteners are also difficult to connect to one another when the cover of the boat is large. As should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, the cover of the boat may be difficult for the boat operator to lift and, at the same time, manipulate so that the snap fasteners are in register with one another.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In addition, it is not uncommon for a boat owner to have difficulty matching the male and female portions of the snap fasteners to one another without mismatching at least one of the plurality of fasteners to one another. This may lead to some frustration as the boat cover may need to be partially removed in order for the snaps to be realigned and re-attached to one another.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Other prior art attachment systems are illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> illustrate two variations of a prior art track system that permits a cover <b>100</b> to be attached to a boat.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a track <b>102</b> is affixed to the deck of a boat via a plurality of screws <b>104</b>. The cover <b>100</b> engages the track <b>102</b> when an edge welt <b>106</b>, which is part of an insert <b>108</b>, in threaded into a groove <b>110</b> in the track <b>102</b>. As illustrated, the screws <b>104</b> are located within the groove <b>110</b>. Accordingly, when the cover <b>100</b> is removed from the track <b>102</b>, the heads of the screws <b>104</b> are visible. This is considered unsightly by many boat owners.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the insert <b>108</b> includes the welt <b>106</b> and a protruding portion <b>112</b>. An edge of the cover <b>100</b> is sewn onto the protruding portion <b>112</b>, thereby affixing the insert <b>108</b> to the edge of the cover <b>100</b>. The unfinished edge of the cover <b>100</b> is capped with a U-shaped cover <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates a variation of the prior art system shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the track <b>116</b> is largely the same as the track <b>102</b>, except that the track <b>116</b> includes a lateral leg <b>118</b>. The screws <b>104</b> that attach the track <b>116</b> to the deck of the boat are disposed through the lateral leg <b>118</b>. In this embodiment, the heads of the screws <b>104</b> are visible. Again, this is considered unsightly by many boat owners and enthusiasts.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As in the prior art example illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the cover <b>100</b> is attached to the protruding portion <b>112</b> on the insert <b>108</b>. As in the prior example, the insert <b>108</b> slides into a groove <b>110</b> in the track <b>116</b> to secure the cover <b>100</b> to the track <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Regardless of which track <b>102</b>, <b>116</b> is employed, the welt <b>106</b> must be threaded into the groove <b>110</b> to secure the cover to the boat. This is accomplished by inserting one end of the welt <b>106</b> into one end of the groove <b>110</b> and sliding the welt <b>106</b> completely into the groove <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">As should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, the process of threading the welt <b>106</b> into the groove <b>110</b> is cumbersome and often frustrating. Being attached to a large and often heavy cover <b>100</b>, the welt <b>106</b> sometimes binds in the groove <b>110</b>, requiring the boat owner to reorient the cover <b>100</b>, the welt <b>106</b> or both to complete the threading process.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A variation on this system is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. Here, the cover <b>110</b> includes a zipper <b>120</b> disposed adjacent to a lateral edge. The zipper divides the cover <b>110</b> into two sections, a strip section <b>122</b> and a main body section <b>124</b>. Accordingly, the strip section <b>122</b> may be unzipped from the main body section <b>124</b> before its welt <b>106</b> is threaded into the groove <b>110</b>. After the strip <b>122</b> is installed, the main body section <b>124</b> may be re-attached to the strip <b>122</b> by zipping the two sections together.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As may be appreciated, the prior art zipper approach also presents difficulties with installation of the cover <b>100</b> onto a boat. Specifically, it may be cumbersome or frustrating to zip the two sections of the cover <b>100</b> to one another since the main body section <b>124</b> is often large and heavy. In addition, zippers of the length needed for this system are expensive and increase manufacturing cost significantly.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Another difficulty with the track systems <b>102</b>, <b>112</b> is that a watertight seal is not easily formed between the cover <b>100</b> and the deck of the boat. As a result, to create a watertight seal, hook and loop fastener strips (Velcro&#xae;) or rubber gaskets need to be added to the cover <b>100</b> or to the deck of the boat to guarantee an appropriate seal.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">These issues with the prior art have created a need for a simpler attachment of a boat cover to a boat.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">These needs in the prior art remain unaddressed.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">It is, therefore, one aspect of the invention to provide a system for attachment of a boat cover to a boat without the need for traditional snap fasteners.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">It is another aspect of the invention to provide a system for attachment of a boat cover to a boat without the need to thread a welt into a groove on a track that is attached to the deck of a boat.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Another aspect of the invention is to provide an attachment system with an improved aesthetic appearance.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It is still another aspect of the invention to provide a boat cover with a simply, yet easily manipulable construction to facilitate attachment of the boat cover to the boat.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Accordingly, in one embodiment of the invention, an apparatus is provided for attaching a boat cover to a boat. The apparatus includes an elongated member defining a first leg and a second leg. A plurality of notches are defined in the first leg of the elongated member. A flexible cover is affixed to the second leg on the elongated member along at least one edge. A guide is affixable to a deck of a boat. The guide defines at least one securement groove therein, the securement groove accepting the second leg of the elongated member therein.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">When the second leg is inserted into the securement groove in the guide, a watertight seal is created.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In another embodiment of the invention, the elongated member comprises a flexible material.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In still another embodiment, the elongated member comprises plastic.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">One further embodiment of the invention provides for the elongated member to be affixed to the flexible cover via stitching between the protrusion and the flexible cover.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">An additional embodiment of the invention provides that the guide is plastic.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In one further embodiment, the guide further includes a fastener groove through which a plurality of fasteners may be disposed to affix the guide to the deck of a boat.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In yet another embodiment, a fastener cover is insertable in the fastener groove to conceal the fastener groove. The fastener cover may be releasably secured in the fastener groove by engaging side walls of the fastener groove.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In still another embodiment, the flexible cover may be a canvas material.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Other aspects of the invention will be made apparent to those skilled in the art from the description that follows and from the drawings appended hereto.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The invention will now be described in connection with the drawings appended hereto, where like reference numerals refer to like structures, features, and elements, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional side view of a first prior art system for attaching a boat cover to the deck of a boat;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional side view illustration of a second prior art system for attaching a boat cover to the deck of a boat;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a partial side view of a boat including the boat cover attachment system of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-sectional side view of a guide for receiving an edge of a boat cover therein;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional side view of the guide illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, including additional features of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a partial cross-sectional side view of the an edge of the cover of the invention, showing details of the elongated member affixed to one edge of the cover;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top plan view of the elongated member illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a partial perspective illustration of the cover when attached to the guide via the elongated member.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENT(S) OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side view illustration of a portion of a boat <b>10</b> incorporating the guide <b>12</b> and boat cover <b>14</b> according to the invention. The guide <b>12</b> is illustrated in greater detail in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b>, and <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the boat <b>10</b> includes what is referred to as a radar arch <b>16</b>. The radar arch <b>16</b> is a structure that extends over the passenger area of the boat <b>10</b> and supports electronic equipment, such as a radar transmitter and receiver <b>18</b>. The radar arch <b>16</b> also may support other electronic equipment, such as a radio antenna (not illustrated) or the like. The guide <b>12</b> extends along the radar arch <b>16</b>, both at the forward edge and the trailing edge. As should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, the guide <b>12</b> may be disposed along other exposed areas of the boat where the cover <b>14</b> (or another cover) is to be attached.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">With continued reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the boat <b>10</b> also includes a windshield <b>20</b> disposed forward of the radar arch <b>16</b>. The top of the windshield <b>20</b> includes a top rail <b>22</b>. The cover <b>14</b> includes an elongated member <b>24</b> attached along at least one edge via stitching <b>26</b>. The elongated member <b>24</b> removably connects to the guide <b>12</b>, permitting the cover <b>14</b> to be removably attached to the deck of the boat <b>10</b>. As also shown, a plurality of snap fasteners are included on the edge of the cover <b>14</b> adjacent to the top rail <b>22</b> of the windshield <b>20</b>. The snap fasteners include male portions <b>28</b>, which are disposed on the top rail <b>22</b>. The female portions <b>30</b> of the snap fasteners are affixed to the cover <b>14</b>. The snap fasteners provide one possible device for attachment of the cover <b>14</b> to the top rail <b>22</b>. Other fasteners and attachment means also may be employed without departing from the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates one embodiment of the guide <b>12</b>. The guide <b>12</b> includes a bottom surface <b>32</b> that is disposed against the deck <b>34</b> of the boat <b>10</b>, a portion of which is shown. The deck <b>34</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a portion of the radar arch <b>16</b> illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The guide <b>12</b> includes a top surface <b>36</b>, which is visible on the deck of the boat <b>10</b>. At a forward side of the guide <b>12</b>, which may face the area in which the boat cover <b>14</b> is to be positioned, the guide <b>12</b> includes a securement groove <b>40</b> that receives a portion of the elongated member <b>24</b> therein. The securement groove <b>40</b> alternately may face the opposite direction without departing from the scope of the invention. The guide <b>12</b> also includes a fastener groove <b>42</b>. A plurality of guide holes <b>44</b> are disposed through the bottom of the fastener groove <b>42</b>. The guide holes <b>44</b> are in register with fastener holes <b>46</b> in the deck <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">With respect to the guide holes <b>44</b> and the fastener holes <b>46</b>, it is contemplated that the holes <b>44</b>, <b>46</b> may be fashioned in the guide <b>12</b> and in the deck <b>34</b> before installation of the guide <b>12</b> thereon. Alternatively, it is contemplated that the guide <b>12</b> may be installed on the deck <b>34</b> by drilling the guide holes <b>44</b> and the fastener holes <b>46</b>, thereby ensuring that the guide holes <b>44</b> and the fastener holes <b>46</b> are in register with one another. If the holes <b>44</b>, <b>46</b> are drilled into the guide <b>12</b> and the deck <b>34</b>, they would not be included in the guide <b>12</b> at the time the guide <b>12</b> is manufactured.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates the guide <b>12</b> in one contemplated installation on the deck <b>34</b>. As illustrated, fasteners <b>48</b> are inserted into the guide holes <b>44</b> and the fastener holes <b>46</b> to secure the guide <b>12</b> on the deck <b>34</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the fasteners <b>48</b> are screws. However, as should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, any other suitable fastener may be employed without departing from the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">To cover the fastener groove <b>42</b> and the tops of the screws <b>48</b>, a fastener cover <b>50</b> is included as a part of the guide <b>12</b>. The fastener cover <b>50</b> may be made from any suitable flexible material including plastic, rubber, silicone rubber, and the like. The cover <b>50</b> is designed to be pressed into the fastener groove <b>42</b> to be retained by the side walls <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> thereof. In the illustrated embodiment, the side walls <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> are curved to facilitate retention of the cover <b>50</b> therebetween. It is contemplated that the cover <b>50</b> is be press-fitted between the walls <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> of the groove <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the cover <b>14</b> includes the elongated member <b>24</b> disposed along at least one of its edges. A portion of the elongated member <b>24</b> is inserted into the groove <b>40</b> to secure the cover <b>14</b> to the boat <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The elongated member <b>24</b> includes a first leg <b>56</b> and a second leg <b>58</b>. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the elongated member is essentially an L-shaped member with the first leg <b>56</b> being at about a right angle with respect to the second leg <b>58</b>. As should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, this particular configuration is not required to practice the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The flexible material that comprises the cover <b>14</b> is attached to the second leg <b>58</b> of the elongated member <b>24</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the second leg <b>58</b> is affixed to the cover <b>14</b> via stitching <b>60</b>. Of course, as should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, the elongated member <b>24</b> may be affixed to the cover <b>14</b> via any other suitable attachment means, including ultrasonic welding, adhesives, etc., or any combination of such means.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">So that the edge of the cover <b>14</b> has a finished appearance and is aesthetically appealing, the edge of the cover <b>14</b> and the end of the second leg <b>58</b> are capped with a U-shaped cover <b>62</b>. As illustrated, the U-shaped cover <b>62</b> is affixed to the second leg <b>58</b> via the stitching <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">It is contemplated that the cover <b>14</b> will be made from canvas, neoprene, tarpaulin, or any other suitable material. It is also contemplated that the cover <b>62</b> will be made from the same material. As should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, however, using the same material for the cover <b>62</b> is not required to practice the invention. It is contemplated that the cover may be an entirely different material such as rubber, plastic, a composite material, or even a different woven material.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, the first leg <b>56</b> includes a plurality of notches <b>64</b> cut therein. The notches <b>64</b> increase the flexibility of the elongated member <b>24</b> to improve the operator's ability to insert the second leg <b>58</b> into the groove <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the attachment of the cover <b>14</b> to the guide <b>12</b> will now be explained. Specifically, the second leg <b>58</b> of the elongated member <b>24</b> is aligned with the groove <b>40</b>. Pressure is then applied to the first leg <b>56</b> so that the second leg <b>58</b> may be pressed into the groove <b>40</b> by the boat operator. The arrows provided in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> illustrate the direction of the pressure to be applied to the first leg <b>56</b> <i>t </i>insert the second leg <b>58</b> into the groove <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">It is contemplated that the second leg <b>58</b> should be sufficiently resilient and flexible to be retained within the groove <b>40</b> after application of pressure on the first leg <b>56</b>. To facilitate insertion of the second leg <b>58</b> into the groove <b>40</b>, the first leg <b>56</b> may have a curved shape, as illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>. However, a curved first leg <b>56</b> is not required to practice the invention. Any alternative shape may be employed without departing from the scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">As may be appreciated, a retention force applied by the sides of the groove <b>40</b> on the second leg <b>58</b> is distributed along the entire length of the groove <b>40</b> and the second leg <b>58</b>. This provides an improved retention of the cover <b>14</b> on the deck <b>34</b> over snap fasteners, which traditionally are provided at a plurality of discrete locations along the deck <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In addition, since the second leg <b>58</b> does not need to be aligned with the groove <b>40</b> precisely in order to provide an attachment function, the cover <b>14</b> may be more easily installed on the boat <b>10</b>. This arrangement is believed to provide a significant improvement over prior art snap fasteners. As should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, if a boat operator does not match up the snap fasteners exactly, it is likely that the snap fasteners will have to be undone and re-affixed in order for the cover <b>14</b> to be properly installed in the boat <b>10</b>. As may be appreciated, with the attachment apparatus of the invention, this difficulty is avoided altogether.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">With reference to the prior art examples in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, problems associated with threading the edge of the cover into a groove are avoided by the invention. Since the second leg <b>58</b> need only be pressed into the groove <b>40</b>, problems associated with the welt binding in the groove are avoided. In addition, the even force applied along the length of the elongated member <b>24</b> assures a watertight seal between the cover <b>14</b> and the deck <b>34</b> of the boat <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The embodiments discussed herein are meant to be illustrative of the broad scope of the invention. They are not meant to be limiting of the invention solely to the embodiments described or illustrated. To the contrary, as should be appreciated by those skilled in the art, there are variations and equivalents of the invention that may be employed. The invention is intended to encompass those variations and embodiments.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus for attaching a boat cover to a boat, comprising:
<claim-text>an elongated member defining a first leg and a second leg;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of notches defined in the first leg of the elongated member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a flexible cover affixed to the second leg of the elongated member along at least one edge;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a guide affixable to a deck of a boat, the guide defining at least one securement groove therein, the securement groove accepting the second leg of the elongated member therein,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the elongated member is affixed to the flexible cover via stitching between the second leg and the flexible cover.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first leg and the second leg are disposed at about a right angle with respect to one another.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first leg is curved.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the elongated member comprises a flexible material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the elongated member comprises plastic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the guide comprises plastic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the guide further comprises a fastener groove through which a plurality of fasteners may be disposed to affix the guide to the deck of a boat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a fastener cover insertable in the fastener groove to conceal the fastener groove.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the fastener cover is releasably secured in the fastener groove by engaging side walls of the fastener groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the flexible cover is a canvas material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein, when the second leg is inserted into the securement groove, a watertight seal is established therebetween. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
