<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640676-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640676</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11544393</doc-number>
<date>20061006</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>483</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>Q</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 33630</main-classification>
<further-classification> 33628</further-classification>
<further-classification> 83 74</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Power tool measuring device</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3811353</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Miles</name>
<date>19740500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 83 755</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3910142</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Jureit et al.</name>
<date>19751000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 83 74</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5111688</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Houghton et al.</name>
<date>19920500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 73159</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5327653</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pistorius et al.</name>
<date>19940700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 33  1 M</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7036411</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Harris et al.</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 83 34</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7231858</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Oberheim</name>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 834772</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0157782</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hetcher et al.</name>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 834713</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>26</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 33628</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 33630</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 33633</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 33  1 M</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 834772</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 83 34</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 83 74</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>14</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>14</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Poole</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory Scott</first-name>
<address>
<street>1218 Millwright La.</street>
<city>Matthews</city>
<state>NC</state>
<postcode>28104</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Summa, Additon &#x26; Ashe, P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bennett</last-name>
<first-name>G. Bradley</first-name>
<department>2841</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Courson</last-name>
<first-name>Tania C</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">In one embodiment of the present invention, a distance measuring device for use with a power tool having an alignment area for receiving a work piece, comprises a measuring sensor proximate to said alignment area that produces a first signal corresponding to longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area; a processor that receives the first signal, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from the first signal, and outputs a second signal corresponding to the longitudinal distance traveled by said work piece within said alignment area; and a display receiving the second signal from the processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="146.30mm" wi="199.14mm" file="US07640676-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="201.85mm" wi="148.00mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="200.49mm" wi="139.53mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="187.03mm" wi="143.09mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="153.25mm" wi="158.83mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="130.56mm" wi="154.18mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="113.54mm" wi="150.28mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="241.22mm" wi="106.93mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="216.24mm" wi="95.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="175.26mm" wi="136.14mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="151.30mm" wi="124.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="202.52mm" wi="145.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="185.08mm" wi="172.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="234.36mm" wi="134.87mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="222.50mm" wi="131.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640676-20100105-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to power tools and, in particular, to a measuring device for improving an operator's speed and accuracy when using the power tool.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Conventional power tools, such as miter saws, routers, drill presses and the like, offer a distinct advantage over manually operated tools because they can enhance an operator's precision, accuracy, and efficiency while simultaneously reducing the amount of physical labor required of the operator. As a result, the operator may focus his effort on properly laying out and executing the work to be performed on the work piece. In carpentry, woodworking, metal working and pipe fitting, a power tool operator often lays out the work to be performed on a work piece by using a standard measuring tape to determine the location where the power tool must be applied. After measuring the proper position to apply the power tool, the operator scribes a mark on the work piece with a pencil, pen, marker or other marking tool and then loads the work piece on the power tool to cut or drill into the work piece at the marked position.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Standard measuring tapes are marked in 1/16 inch graduations; however, in precision carpentry, such as cabinetry and furniture making, the 1/16 inch graduations on standard measuring tapes often do not offer an acceptable level of precision, and the carpenter must &#x201c;eyeball&#x201d; the measurement when the required distance falls between 1/16 inch graduations. Marking the work piece also inserts a level of imprecision because the operator must account for the thickness of the pencil led or scribing tool when sawing, drilling or routing the work piece. Additionally, when using a saw, the operator must account for the kerf of the saw blade and choose which side of the mark to cut so that the saw blade kerf will not remove too much material from the work piece. This process is inefficient as the carpenter must take the time to measure the distance, mark the work piece, and then stow the measuring tape before actually applying the tool. The present invention seeks to increase a power tool operator's precision and efficiency.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The present invention recognizes and addresses considerations of prior art constructions and methods.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In one embodiment of the present invention, a distance measuring device for use with a power tool having an alignment area for receiving a work piece comprises a measuring sensor proximate to said alignment area that produces a first signal corresponding to longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area; a processor that receives the first signal, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from the first signal, and outputs a second signal corresponding to the longitudinal distance traveled by said work piece within said alignment area; and a display receiving the second signal from the processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In another embodiment of the present invention, a distance measuring device for use with a power tool having an alignment area for receiving a work piece comprises an electronic rotary encoder located proximate to the alignment area having an input shaft and producing a first signal corresponding to longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area; a distance measuring wheel fixed on said electronic rotary encoder input shaft and having an outer circumferential surface in rolling engagement with an outer surface of the work piece; a processor that receives the first signal, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by said work piece within said alignment area from said first signal, and outputs a second signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area; and an electronic digital display receiving the second signal from said processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In yet another embodiment of the present invention, a power tool having an alignment has a distance measuring device comprises: a measuring sensor proximate to the power tool alignment area that produces a first signal corresponding to longitudinal motion of the work piece within said alignment area; a processor that receives the first signal, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from the first signal, and outputs a second signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece; and a display receiving the second signal from the processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by said work piece within alignment area.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In still another embodiment of the present invention, a power tool comprises: a base; an alignment fence; an alignment area defined by said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence for receiving a work piece; and a distance measuring device having an electronic rotary encoder with an input shaft proximate to said alignment area and producing a first signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area; a distance measuring wheel fixed on the electronic rotary encoder input shaft and having an outer circumferential surface in rolling engagement with an outer surface of said work piece; a processor that receives the first signal, determines the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from the first signal, and outputs a second signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area; and an electronic digital display receiving the second signal from the processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate one or more embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A full and enabling disclosure of the present invention, including the best mode thereof, directed to one of ordinary skill in the art, is set forth in the specification, which makes reference to the appended drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front perspective view of a power tool measuring device in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a rear perspective view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a rear view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref> is an enlarged side view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref> is an enlarged side view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a front edge view of a second embodiment of power tool measuring device in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a top edge view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is an enlarged front perspective view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is an enlarged front perspective view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a rear perspective view of a third embodiment of the power tool measuring device in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is an enlarged front perspective view of the power tool measuring device as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a top perspective view of the operation of a power tool measuring device in accordance with the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a top perspective view of the operation of a power tool measuring device in accordance with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Repeat use of reference characters in the present specification and drawings is intended to represent same or analogous features or elements of the invention according to the disclosure.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Reference will now be made in detail to presently preferred embodiments of the invention, one or more examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Each example is provided by way of explanation, not limitation, of the invention. In fact, it will be apparent to those skilled in the art that modifications and variations can be made in the present invention without departing from the scope and spirit thereof. For instance, features illustrated or described as part of one embodiment may be used on another embodiment to yield a still further embodiment. Thus, it is intended that the present invention covers such modifications and variations as come within the scope of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, an embodiment of power tool measuring device <b>10</b> of the present invention is shown configured for use with a standard miter saw <b>12</b> equipped with a base <b>14</b> having an alignment fence <b>16</b> that extends vertically from the base. In the present embodiment, measuring device <b>10</b> is used with a miter saw, but it should be understood that the measuring device may be used in conjunction with any power tool having an alignment fence, such as a drill press, a router table, or other similar tool. Miter saw <b>12</b> preferably has a base <b>14</b>, an alignment fence <b>16</b>, a handle assembly <b>18</b> and a selectively rotatable table <b>20</b>. A handle assembly <b>18</b> supports a motor <b>22</b> with an output shaft <b>21</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) that is rotationally fixed to a saw blade <b>24</b>. Handle assembly <b>18</b> is pivotally connected to a table <b>20</b> by a pivot pin <b>13</b> received in a support hub <b>28</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) that extends vertically from the rear of table <b>20</b>. A torsional handle spring (not shown) biases handle assembly <b>18</b> towards an upright position such that handle assembly will only rotate downward in the direction of arrow <b>11</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) when the operator applies a downward force on the handle assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In one embodiment, fence <b>16</b> has multiple sections <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C, and <b>16</b>D, although it should be understood that fence <b>16</b> may also be a single section spanning the entire length of miter saw base <b>14</b>. Each fence section <b>16</b>A, <b>16</b>B, <b>16</b>C, and <b>16</b>D has a respective forward facing surface <b>15</b>A, <b>15</b>B, <b>15</b>C, and <b>15</b>D, and a respective rearward facing surface <b>17</b>A, <b>17</b>B, <b>17</b>C, and <b>17</b>D. The forward facing surfaces of the fence sections define an alignment area <b>19</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) that allows the saw operator to properly align a work piece (not shown) and slide the work piece longitudinally until the work piece is properly positioned for cutting.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, measuring device <b>10</b> includes a measuring sensor <b>30</b> (in this embodiment a rotary encoder) having an input shaft <b>32</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), a measuring wheel <b>34</b>, a processor <b>36</b>, and a display <b>38</b>. Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a pivot arm <b>40</b> defines a first end <b>42</b> that supports measuring sensor <b>30</b> and a second end <b>44</b> that is pivotally attached to a pivot post <b>46</b>. The pivot post extends vertically from a support bracket <b>48</b> that is rigidly mounted to rearward facing surface <b>17</b>D of alignment fence section <b>16</b>D. Support bracket <b>48</b> provides rigid support to processor <b>36</b> and display <b>38</b> by means of a display support member <b>50</b>. Support bracket <b>48</b> is positioned so that measuring wheel <b>34</b> is disposed between alignment fence sections <b>16</b>C and <b>16</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In a preferred embodiment, pivot arm <b>40</b> is biased by a torsion spring <b>54</b> that surrounds pivot post <b>46</b> and has a first end (not shown) rigidly attached to pivot arm second end <b>44</b> and a second end (not shown) rigidly attached to support bracket <b>48</b>. A torsion load is applied to torsion spring <b>54</b> during assembly such that the engagement between torsion spring second end (not shown) and support bracket <b>48</b> biases torsion spring first end (not shown) in a manner that urges pivot arm first end <b>42</b> in the direction of arrow <b>52</b> so that measuring wheel circumferential surface <b>35</b> extends into alignment area <b>19</b>. In a preferred embodiment, torsion spring <b>54</b> is selected to have a spring constant small enough to allow pivot arm <b>40</b> and measuring wheel <b>34</b> to articulate in the direction opposite to arrow <b>52</b> when measuring wheel circumferential surface <b>35</b> encounters the edge of a work piece. However, torsion spring <b>54</b> should be strong enough that it urges measuring wheel <b>34</b> into continuous rolling engagement with the edge of the work piece as the work piece is maneuvered longitudinally within alignment area <b>19</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>). It should be understood that any suitable biasing element may be substituted for the torsion spring, such as a linear compression spring, a hydraulic cylinder, or other similar device.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As previously mentioned, measuring sensor <b>30</b> has an input shaft <b>32</b> that is fixed to measuring wheel <b>34</b> so that the input shaft and the measuring wheel rotate in unison. Preferably, measuring sensor <b>30</b> is an electronic rotary encoder <b>31</b> that generates signal pulses as input shaft <b>32</b> rotates as described in further detail below. While the operation of rotary encoder <b>31</b> is not considered part of the invention, one of skill in the art should be familiar with their operation and recognize a suitable example of such an encoder to be the Allen-Bradley 845P Size 15 Incremental Encoder. The signal pulses are transmitted from rotary encoder <b>31</b> to processor <b>36</b> by means of a first communication cable <b>62</b>. Communication cable <b>62</b> has a first end <b>62</b>A received by a rotary encoder output port <b>60</b> and a second end <b>62</b>B received by processor <b>36</b>. In a preferred embodiment, processor <b>36</b> is a central processing unit (CPU) (not shown) equipped with a microprocessor, integrated counting circuit, or electronic analog circuit programmed to interpret the pulses generated by rotary encoder <b>31</b> as signaling a linear distance. The CPU transmits information, including the processed signal pulses, through a second communications cable <b>68</b> to display <b>38</b>. While measuring device <b>30</b> is described in detail as a rotary encoder, it should be understood that any suitable rotation motion measuring device, such as a mechanical click-wheel, a linear encoder, or other similar device may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Processor <b>36</b> transmits output information to display <b>38</b> so that the operator may read and interpret the measurements taken by measuring device <b>30</b>. In a preferred embodiment, display <b>38</b> is a digital display that shows the operator an alpha-numeric representation of the length that the work piece has moved longitudinally within alignment area <b>19</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>). Display <b>38</b> may also be equipped with an input keypad <b>75</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</figref>) that the operator may use to input information to CPU <b>37</b>, such as the kerf of a newly installed saw blade. The operator may also use keypad <b>75</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</figref>) to direct the CPU to display the displacement of the work piece in English or Metric units or manually override the CPU functions.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref>, <b>5</b>A and <b>5</b>B, a proximity switch <b>80</b>, which may be an optical sensor, a magnetic sensor, or other similar sensing device, is fixed to a bracket <b>82</b> mounted on support hub <b>28</b>. Handle assembly <b>18</b> supports a flag <b>84</b> mounted proximate to pivot pin <b>13</b> so that proximity switch <b>80</b> may selectively sense the presence of flag <b>84</b>. When saw handle assembly <b>18</b> is in its normal position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5A</figref>, the distance between flag <b>84</b> and proximity switch is great enough to prevent the switch from sensing the flag's presence. However, when the operator rotates the handle assembly into the cutting position, flag <b>84</b> moves into a position where proximity switch <b>80</b> can easily sense the flag's presence, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>. The proximity switch then generates a signal indicating that the saw handle assembly is in the cutting position, and the output signal from proximity switch <b>80</b> is transmitted to CPU <b>37</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) by a communication cable <b>86</b>, as discussed in further detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, and embodiment of the power tool measuring device <b>10</b> having a first deployable stop <b>90</b> and an optional second deployable stop <b>92</b>. First deployable stop <b>90</b> and optional second deployable stop <b>92</b> perform the function of sending an indication signal to the CPU when a work piece has been loaded onto the power tool base as described in detail below. In a preferred embodiment, and as discussed below, first deployable stop <b>90</b> is a standard through-beam photoelectric sensor having an emitter <b>94</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>), a reflector <b>96</b>, and a communications cable <b>98</b> that relays the signal produced by emitter <b>94</b> to CPU <b>37</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). Emitter <b>94</b> produces an infrared light beam that is focused on reflector <b>96</b>. When no objects is placed between emitter <b>94</b> and reflector <b>96</b>, the light beam is reflected by the reflector and returns to the emitter, which receives the light beam and sends a continuous signal to the CPU. If an object is placed between the emitter and the reflector, the light beam is not reflected to the emitter, and the emitter no longer sends a signal to the CPU. The CPU interprets the condition where no signal is sent from first deployable stop <b>90</b> as an indication that a work piece has been loaded on the left-hand side of power tool <b>12</b>. While deployable stop <b>90</b> is preferably a standard through-beam photoelectric sensor, any suitable sensor may be substituted, such as a diffuse reflective photoelectric sensor, a polarized reflex photoelectric sensor, or a mechanical gate-type sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref>, a first mounting bracket <b>100</b> preferably provides rigid support to first deployable stop <b>90</b> and has a first arm <b>93</b> that supports emitter <b>94</b> and a second arm <b>95</b> that supports reflector <b>96</b>. First mounting bracket <b>100</b> is rigidly attached to the underside of power tool base <b>14</b> proximate to alignment fence section <b>16</b>D.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6</figref>, <b>7</b>, and <b>9</b>, optional second deployable stop <b>92</b> is preferably also a standard through-beam photoelectric sensor that operates identically to the sensor described above in accordance with the first deployable stop. Optional second deployable stop <b>92</b> has an emitter <b>104</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 9</figref>), a reflector <b>106</b>, and a communications cable <b>108</b> that relays the signal produced by emitter <b>104</b> to CPU <b>37</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). Emitter <b>104</b> produces an infrared light beam that is focused on reflector <b>106</b>. Under normal operation, the light beam is reflected by the reflector and returns to the emitter, which receives the light beam and sends a continuous signal to the CPU; however, if an object is placed between emitter <b>104</b> and reflector <b>106</b>, the light beam is not reflected to the emitter, and the emitter no longer sends a signal to the CPU. The CPU interprets the condition where no signal is sent from optional second deployable stop <b>92</b> as an indication that a work piece has been loaded on the right-hand side of power tool <b>12</b>. It should be understood that any suitable sensor may be substituted for emitter <b>104</b> and reflector <b>106</b>, such as a diffuse reflective photoelectric sensor, a polarized reflex photoelectric sensor, or a mechanical gate-type sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring specifically to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 9</figref>, a second mounting bracket <b>110</b> preferably provides rigid support to optional second deployable stop <b>92</b>, and has a first arm <b>103</b> that supports emitter <b>104</b> and a second arm <b>105</b> that supports reflector <b>106</b>. Second mounting bracket <b>110</b> is rigidly attached to the underside of power tool base <b>14</b> proximate to alignment fence section <b>16</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>, an embodiment of a power tool measuring device has an optional second measuring device <b>210</b> that is similar to measuring device <b>10</b> discussed above. Second measuring device <b>210</b> has a sensor <b>230</b> with an input shaft <b>232</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>), a measuring wheel <b>234</b> with an outer circumferential surface <b>235</b>, and a second a pivot arm <b>240</b>. The second pivot arm <b>240</b> has a first end <b>242</b> that supports measuring sensor <b>230</b> and a second end <b>244</b> that is pivotally attached to a pivot post <b>246</b>. The pivot post extends vertically from a support bracket <b>248</b> rigidly mounted to alignment fence rearward facing surface <b>17</b>A. The support bracket is positioned so that measuring wheel <b>234</b> is disposed between alignment fence sections <b>16</b>A and <b>16</b>B.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>, in a preferred embodiment, pivot arm <b>240</b> is biased in a direction represented by arrow <b>252</b> by a torsion spring <b>254</b>. The torsion spring surrounds pivot post <b>246</b> and has a first end (not shown) rigidly attached to pivot arm <b>240</b> and a second end (not shown) rigidly attached to support bracket <b>248</b>. A torsion load is applied to torsion spring <b>254</b> during assembly such that the engagement between torsion spring second end (not shown) and support bracket <b>248</b> biases spring first end (not shown) in a manner that urges pivot arm first end <b>242</b> in the direction of arrow <b>252</b>. The biasing action of torsion spring <b>254</b> urges pivot arm first end <b>242</b> and measuring wheel <b>234</b> into alignment area <b>19</b>. Preferably, torsion spring <b>254</b> is selected to have a spring constant small enough to allow pivot arm <b>240</b> and measuring wheel <b>234</b> to articulate in the direction opposite to arrow <b>252</b> when the outer circumferential surface <b>235</b> of measuring wheel <b>234</b> encounters the edge of a work piece. However, torsion spring <b>254</b> should be strong enough that it urges measuring wheel <b>234</b> into continuous rolling engagement with the edge of the work piece as the work piece is maneuvered along longitudinal axis <b>19</b>A (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19A</figref>). It should be understood that any suitable biasing element may be substituted for the torsion spring, such as a linear compression spring, a hydraulic cylinder, or some other similar device.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Second pivot arm first end <b>242</b> supports second sensor <b>230</b>, which is preferably a digital rotary encoder <b>231</b>. Measuring wheel <b>234</b> is fixed to rotary encoder input shaft <b>232</b> so that the measuring wheel and the input shaft rotate in unison. As input shaft <b>232</b> rotates, rotary encoder <b>231</b> generates signal pulses as described in further detail below. The signal pulses are transmitted from the rotary encoder counting device <b>231</b> by a communication cable <b>262</b>. Preferably, both measuring wheel <b>234</b> and rotary encoder <b>231</b> be identical in size and resolution to measuring wheel <b>34</b> and rotary encoder <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>), respectively; however it should be understood that measuring wheel <b>234</b> and rotary encoder <b>231</b> may be of different size and resolution and that rotary encoder <b>231</b> or the CPU may be calibrated to account for the differences in measuring wheel size and encoder resolution.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In operation of a preferred embodiment of the power tool measuring device <b>10</b>, and referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, the operator loads a work piece <b>300</b> onto the power tool base <b>14</b> such that an edge <b>302</b> of the work piece proximate to alignment fence section <b>16</b>D is positioned flush against the alignment fence forward facing surface <b>15</b>D. Work piece <b>300</b> has an end <b>304</b> positioned proximate to the left-hand side of saw blade <b>24</b>, and an end <b>306</b> positioned distal from the left-hand side of the saw blade. As work piece <b>300</b> is loaded into alignment area <b>19</b>, edge <b>302</b> comes into contact with the measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>35</b>. To properly align edge <b>302</b> with alignment fence section <b>16</b>D, pivot arm <b>40</b> must rotate in a direction opposite of arrow <b>52</b> against the bias of torsion spring <b>54</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). In this way, torsion spring <b>54</b> provides resistance against further rotation of pivot arm <b>40</b> and ensures that measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>35</b> remains in constant rolling engagement with work piece edge <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">When work piece edge <b>302</b> is properly positioned against the alignment fence section <b>16</b>D, deployable stop <b>90</b> senses work piece <b>300</b> when the work piece passes between the deployable stop's emitter <b>94</b> and reflector <b>96</b> and breaks the photoelectric beam produced by the emitter and causing the emitter to stop sending its signal to the CPU. The CPU interprets the interruption in the signal from deployable stop <b>90</b> to mean that a cutting process is imminent, and that the operator has loaded the work piece on the power tool at a position to the left of the saw blade. Because the presence of the work piece interrupted the signal produced by first deployable stop <b>90</b>, the CPU chooses to read and process only the output signal generated by rotary encoder <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), which will correspond to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece in alignment area <b>19</b>. If the operator is using an embodiment of the power tool measuring device that does not include a first deployable stop <b>90</b>, the operator may use keypad <b>75</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</figref>) provided on display <b>38</b> to input information to the CPU that indicates that a work piece has been loaded on the left-hand side of power tool <b>12</b> and that the CPU should process cut length information received from rotary encoder <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">After the CPU recognizes an interruption in the signal from the first deployable stop, the CPU waits for an input signal from handle assembly proximity switch <b>80</b>. As part of the pre-cut routine, the operator rotates handle assembly <b>18</b> in the direction of arrow <b>11</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) until saw blade <b>24</b> is placed in the cutting position. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5B</figref>, once handle assembly <b>18</b> is fully rotated into the cutting position, proximity switch <b>80</b> senses the presence of flag <b>84</b> and sends a signal to the CPU that the handle assembly has been put in the cutting position. Once the CPU receives the signal from proximity switch <b>80</b>, the CPU resets and holds the display <b>38</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) so that it shows a cut distance reading of zero. While handle assembly <b>18</b> is in the cutting position, the CPU holds the display reading at zero even though rotary encoder may generate output signal pulses because the CPU will recognize that the signal pulses generated by the rotary encoder are the result of the operator moving the work piece to a zero-point location. The operator places the work piece in zero-point location by sliding the work piece <b>300</b> along alignment fence <b>16</b> in the direction of arrow <b>400</b> until work piece end <b>304</b> engages the left-hand side of saw blade <b>24</b>. In this way, the work piece is located such that the zero reading shown on display <b>38</b> properly reflects the fact that work piece end <b>304</b> is directly adjacent to the saw blade in the zero-point location.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Once the operator places work piece <b>300</b> in the zero-point location, the operator then returns handle assembly <b>18</b> to its resting position, and proximity switch <b>80</b> no longer senses the presence of flag <b>84</b>, causing an interruption in the signal produced by proximity switch <b>80</b>. The CPU recognizes the interruption of the signal from proximity switch <b>80</b> as an indication that the operator has placed the work piece is the zero-point location and that cut measurement is about to begin. The CPU then actively receives and interprets output signal pulses generated by the rotary encoder. As the operator slides work piece <b>300</b> in the direction of arrow <b>400</b>, the rolling engagement between measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>35</b> and work piece edge <b>302</b> forces rotary encoder input shaft <b>32</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) to rotate. As the rotary encoder input shaft rotates, output signal pulses are generated by the rotary encoder <b>31</b> and transmitted to the CPU. The CPU reads and interprets the pulses from rotary encoder <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and processes the signal pulses from the rotary encoder into a display signal that represents the longitudinal movement of the work piece. The CPU then sends the display signal to display <b>38</b>, where the signal is shown as a numerical representation of the length the operator has moved work piece from its original zero point location. The rolling engagement between measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>35</b> and work piece edge <b>302</b> forces rotary encoder input shaft <b>32</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) to rotate in response to movement of work piece edge <b>302</b> in direction of arrow <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The operation of the rotary encoder will now be described in detail. In a preferred embodiment, rotary encoder <b>31</b> generates approximately 360 pulses for each full rotation of measuring wheel <b>34</b> and input shaft <b>31</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). The measuring wheel preferably has a circumference of approximately 11.25 inches so that one full rotation of the measuring wheel corresponds to a work piece displacement of approximately 11.25 inches along longitudinal axis <b>19</b>A. This combination of rotary encoder resolution and measuring wheel circumference is advantageous because a one-inch linear movement of the work piece along longitudinal axis <b>19</b>A results in the generation of 32 pulses: that is to say that the rotary encoder generates one pulse for each thirty-second of an inch that work piece <b>300</b> moves along axis <b>19</b>A in the direction of arrow <b>400</b>. The CPU receives the pulses generated by the rotary encoder, and sums the total number of pulses received from the rotary encoder. In this way, each new pulse received by the CPU is added to the sum of all previously received pulses to create a new sum. The CPU simultaneously stores the new sum, which corresponds to the total distance the work piece has traveled in the direction of arrow <b>400</b>, and relays the new sum to display <b>38</b>, where the digital output shows the total cut distance in both full inches and thirty-seconds of an inch. Increasing or decreasing either resolution of rotary encoder <b>31</b> or the circumference of measuring wheel <b>34</b> will result in a measuring device having a different resolution. For example, using a rotary encoder with a resolution of 90 pulses per input shaft rotation and a measuring wheel with a circumference of 5.625 inches yield a measuring device that generates one pulse for each sixteenth of an inch movement of the work piece. Similarly, a measuring wheel and rotary encoder combination may be selected that will display the cut distance in metric units.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As the operator slides the work piece in the direction of arrow <b>400</b>, the power tool display <b>38</b> provides a precise indication of the cut distance. Once the operator is satisfied that the proper cut distance has been achieved, the operator activates the saw motor, and rotates handle assembly <b>18</b> in the direction of arrow <b>11</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) until the saw blade cuts completely through the work piece. As described above, rotation of the handle assembly into the cutting position causes proximity switch <b>80</b> to sense the presence of flag <b>84</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>) and send a signal to the CPU. The CPU recognizes the signal from proximity switch <b>80</b> as indicating that the cutting function is being performed. After the cut has been performed, the operator removes two cut pieces of the work piece from the miter saw <b>12</b> and returns handle assembly <b>18</b> to its resting position, thus removing flag <b>84</b> from proximity switch <b>80</b> and interrupting the signal sent from proximity switch <b>80</b> to the CPU. The CPU interprets this interruption as an indication that the cutting function has been performed, and the CPU holds the display <b>38</b> so that the display shows only distance measurement value shown on the display at the time that proximity switch <b>80</b> sensed flag <b>84</b> when the cut was performed. In this way, display <b>38</b> will continue to show the cut measurement from the prior cut until a new work piece is loaded into the alignment area and the signal from deployable stop <b>90</b> is interrupted once again.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, when the operator is using a power tool measuring device having an optional second measuring device <b>230</b>, the operator may choose to load work piece <b>300</b> onto the power tool base <b>14</b> such that edge <b>302</b> of the work piece proximate to alignment fence section <b>16</b>A is positioned flush against the alignment fence forward facing surface <b>15</b>A. Work piece end <b>306</b> is positioned proximate to the right-hand side of saw blade <b>24</b>, and work piece end <b>304</b> is positioned distal from the right-hand side of the saw blade. As work piece <b>300</b> is loaded into alignment area <b>19</b>, edge <b>302</b> comes into contact with the measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>235</b>. To properly align edge <b>302</b> with alignment fence section <b>16</b>A, pivot arm <b>240</b> must rotate in a direction opposite of arrow <b>252</b> against the bias of torsion spring <b>254</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>). In this way, torsion spring <b>254</b> provides resistance against further rotation of pivot arm <b>240</b> while ensuring that measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>235</b> remains in constant rolling engagement with work piece edge <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">When work piece edge <b>302</b> is properly positioned against the alignment fence section <b>16</b>A, optional second deployable stop <b>92</b> senses work piece <b>300</b> when the work piece passes between the deployable stop's emitter <b>94</b> and reflector <b>96</b> and breaks the photoelectric beam produced by the emitter and causing the emitter to stop sending its signal to the CPU. The CPU interprets the interruption in the signal from optional second deployable stop <b>92</b> to mean that a cutting process is imminent, and that the operator has loaded the work piece on the power tool at a position to the right of the saw blade. Because the presence of the work piece interrupted the signal produced by second deployable stop <b>92</b>, the CPU chooses to read and process only the output signal generated by optional second rotary encoder <b>231</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>), which will correspond to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece in alignment area <b>19</b>. The CPU will not read and process the output signal generated by first rotary encoder <b>31</b> when the signal from second deployable stop <b>92</b> is interrupted until the CPU resets itself at the completion of the cutting process, as described below. If the operator is using an embodiment of the power tool measuring device that does not include an optional second deployable stop <b>92</b>, the operator may use keypad <b>75</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</figref>) provided on display <b>38</b> to input information to the CPU that indicates that a work piece has been loaded on the right-hand side of power tool <b>12</b> and that the CPU should process cut length information received from second rotary encoder <b>231</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">After the CPU recognizes an interruption in the signal from the first deployable stop, the CPU waits for an input signal from handle assembly proximity switch <b>80</b>. As part of the pre-cut routine, the operator rotates handle assembly <b>18</b> in the direction of arrow <b>11</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) until saw blade <b>24</b> is placed in the cutting position. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5B</figref>, once handle assembly <b>18</b> is fully rotated into the cutting position, proximity switch <b>80</b> senses the presence of flag <b>84</b> and sends a signal to the CPU that the handle assembly has been put in the cutting position. Once the CPU receives the signal from proximity switch <b>80</b>, the CPU resets and holds the display <b>38</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) so that it shows a cut distance reading of zero. While handle assembly <b>18</b> is in the cutting position, the CPU holds the display reading at zero even though optional second rotary encoder <b>231</b> may generate output signal pulses because the CPU will recognize that the signal pulses generated by the rotary encoder are the result of the operator moving the work piece to a zero-point location. The operator places the work piece in zero-point location by sliding the work piece <b>300</b> along alignment fence <b>16</b> in the direction of arrow <b>500</b> until work piece end <b>306</b> engages the right-hand side of saw blade <b>24</b>. In this way, the work piece is located such that the zero reading shown on display <b>38</b> properly reflects the fact that work piece end <b>304</b> is directly adjacent to the saw blade in the zero-point location.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">After placing work piece <b>300</b> in the zero-point location, the operator then returns handle assembly <b>18</b> to its resting position, and proximity switch <b>80</b> no longer senses the presence of flag <b>84</b>, causing an interruption in the signal produced by proximity switch <b>80</b>. The CPU recognizes the interruption of the signal from proximity switch <b>80</b> as an indication that the operator has placed the work piece is the zero-point location and that cut measurement is about to begin. The CPU then actively receives and interprets output signal pulses generated by second rotary encoder <b>231</b>. As the operator slides work piece <b>300</b> in the direction of arrow <b>500</b>, the rolling engagement between measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>235</b> and work piece edge <b>302</b> forces second rotary encoder input shaft <b>232</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) to rotate. As the second rotary encoder input shaft rotates, output signal pulses are generated by the second rotary encoder <b>231</b> and transmitted to the CPU. The CPU reads and interprets the pulses from the second rotary encoder and processes the signal pulses into a display signal that represents the longitudinal movement of the work piece. The CPU then sends the display signal to display <b>38</b>, where the signal is shown as a numerical representation of the length the operator has moved work piece from its original zero point location. The rolling engagement between second measuring wheel outer circumferential surface <b>235</b> and work piece edge <b>302</b> forces second rotary encoder input shaft <b>232</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref>) to rotate in response to movement of work piece edge <b>302</b> in direction of arrow <b>500</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As the operator slides the work piece in the direction of arrow <b>500</b>, the power tool display <b>38</b> provides a precise indication of the cut distance. Once the operator is satisfied that the proper cut distance has been achieved, the operator activates the saw motor, and rotates handle assembly <b>18</b> in the direction of arrow <b>11</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) until the saw blade cuts completely through the work piece. As described above, rotation of the handle assembly into the cutting position causes proximity switch <b>80</b> to sense the presence of flag <b>84</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>) and send a signal to the CPU. The CPU recognizes the signal from proximity switch <b>80</b> as indicating that the cutting function is being performed. After the cut has been performed, the operator removes two cut pieces of the work piece from the miter saw <b>12</b> and returns handle assembly <b>18</b> to its resting position, thus removing flag <b>84</b> from proximity switch <b>80</b> and interrupting the signal sent from proximity switch <b>80</b> to the CPU. The CPU interprets this interruption as an indication that the cutting function has been completed, and the CPU holds the display <b>38</b> so that the display shows only distance measurement value shown on the display at the time that proximity switch <b>80</b> sensed flag <b>84</b> when the cut was performed. In this way, display <b>38</b> will continue to show the cut measurement from the prior cut, and CPU will not begin to read output signal pulses from either of the rotary encoders until the CPU resets itself when a new work piece is loaded into the alignment area and interrupts the signal from either deployable stop <b>90</b> or optional second deployable stop <b>90</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">It should be recognized that the power tool measuring device described above does not account for the kerf of saw blade <b>24</b>. The CPU may be programmed to provide a function that allows the operator to input the saw blade kerf into the CPU's memory each time a new saw blade is installed onto the saw motor output shaft. In an embodiment where display <b>38</b> is equipped with an input key pad <b>75</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 6</figref>, the operator may measure the saw blade kerf and then enter the measurement into the CPU's memory through key pad <b>75</b>. When either of the first or second deployable stops is activated, the CPU recalls the kerf measurement value and subtracts it from the cut measurement relayed to the CPU from the rotary encoder the CPU has chosen to read. In this way, the cut measurement shown on display <b>38</b> is corrected to account for the saw blade kerf.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">When the power tool measuring device is used with miter saws having a selectively rotatable table <b>20</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) that allows for angled or beveled cuts, a rotary encoder (not shown) may be installed at the table's point of rotation. This rotary encoder senses the rotation of table <b>20</b> at the table's point of rotation. When the operator rotates the table such that the saw blade is skewed from its normal position perpendicular to alignment fence <b>16</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), the rotary encoder sends a signal to the CPU that corresponds to the angular displacement of the table. Based upon the known saw blade kerf, the CPU uses simple geometric algorithms to correct the cut measurement to account for both saw blade kerf and the angle of the saw blade with respect to alignment fence <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">While one or more preferred embodiments of the invention are described above, it should be appreciated by those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made in the present invention without departing from the scope and spirit thereof. It is intended that the present invention cover such modifications and variations as come within the scope and spirit of the appended claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A distance measuring device for use with a power tool having a base, an alignment fence, and an alignment area defined by the power tool base and the power tool alignment fence for receiving a work piece, said distance measuring device comprising:
<claim-text>a first electronic rotary encoder having an input shaft, said first electronic rotary encoder being proximate to the alignment area and producing a first output signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages the power tool base and the power tool alignment fence, wherein said first output signal corresponds to the rotation of said first electronic rotary encoder input shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first distance measuring wheel fixed on said first electronic rotary encoder input shaft and having an outer circumferential surface in rolling engagement with an outer surface of the work piece;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electronic rotary encoder having an input shaft, said second electronic rotary encoder being proximate to the alignment area and producing a second output signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages the power tool base and the power tool alignment fence, wherein said second output signal corresponds to the rotation of said second electronic rotary encoder input shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second distance measuring wheel fixed on said second electronic rotary encoder input shaft and having an outer circumferential surface in rolling engagement with an outer surface of the work piece;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first arm having a first end rigidly attached to said first electronic rotary encoder and a second end pivotally attached to said first support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second arm having a first end rigidly attached to said second electronic rotary encoder and a second end pivotally attached to said second support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor that receives said first and second output signals, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by said work piece within the alignment area from said first and second output signals, and outputs a third signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic digital display receiving said third signal from said processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the power tool alignment fence comprises:
<claim-text>a first section disposed distal from a left-hand side of the power tool;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second section disposed proximate to a left-hand side of the power tool;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third section disposed proximate to a right-hand side of the power tool; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth section disposed distal from a right-hand side of the power tool;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first support bracket is rigidly attached to a rear surface of the first alignment fence section and disposed such that said first arm first end extends so as to locate said first measuring wheel between the power tool alignment fence first section and the power tool alignment fence second section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second support bracket is rigidly attached to a rear surface of the fourth alignment fence section and disposed such that said second arm first end extends so as to locate said second measuring wheel between the power tool alignment fence third section and the power tool alignment fence fourth section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the power tool is a miter saw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>:
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second distance measuring wheels have an outer circumference of about 11.25 inches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second rotary encoders generate a signal pulse for each about one degree angular rotation of each of said input shafts and sends each said signal pulse to said processor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said processor comprises a central processing unit that receives each said signal pulse and determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from said signal pulses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein said electronic digital display comprises a key pad for inputting data, said digital display sending an electronic signal to said processor corresponding to said data input on said digital display key pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising at least one deployable stop attached to the power tool base, said at least one deployable stop sending an indication to said processor when an operator loads the work piece into the power tool alignment area such that said deployable stop senses the presence of the work piece in the alignment area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A power tool comprising:
<claim-text>a base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an alignment fence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an alignment area defined by said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence for receiving a work piece; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a distance measuring device comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first electronic rotary encoder having an input shaft, said first electronic rotary encoder being proximate to said alignment area and producing a first output signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within said alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence, wherein said first output signal corresponds to the rotation of said first electronic rotary encoder input shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first distance measuring wheel fixed on said first electronic rotary encoder input shaft and having an outer circumferential surface in rolling engagement with an outer surface of the work piece;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second electronic rotary encoder having an input shaft, said second electronic rotary encoder being proximate to said alignment area and producing a second output signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within said alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence, wherein said second output signal corresponds to the rotation of said second electronic rotary encoder input shaft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second distance measuring wheel fixed on said second electronic rotary encoder input shaft and having an outer circumferential surface in rolling engagement with an outer surface of the work piece;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first arm having a first end rigidly attached to said first electronic rotary encoder and a second end pivotally attached to said first support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second arm having a first end rigidly attached to said second electronic rotary encoder and a second end pivotally attached to said second support bracket;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor that receives said first and second output signals, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by said work piece within said alignment area from said first and second output signals, and outputs a third signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an electronic digital display receiving said third signal from said processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said power tool alignment fence comprises:
<claim-text>a first section disposed distal from a left-hand side of said power tool;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second section disposed proximate to a left-hand side of said power tool;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third section disposed proximate to a right-hand side of said power tool; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fourth section disposed distal from a right-hand side of said power tool;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first support bracket is rigidly attached to a rear surface of said first alignment fence section and disposed such that said first arm first end extends so as to locate said first measuring wheel between said power tool alignment fence first section and said power tool alignment fence second section; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said second support bracket is rigidly attached to a rear surface of said fourth alignment fence section and disposed such that said second arm first end extends so as to locate said second measuring wheel between said power tool alignment fence third section and said power tool alignment fence fourth section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein the power tool is a miter saw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>:
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second distance measuring wheels have an outer circumference of about 11.25 inches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said first and second rotary encoders generate a signal pulse for each about one degree angular rotation of each of said input shafts and sends each signal pulse to said processor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said processor comprises a central processing unit that receives each said signal pulse and determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area from said signal pulses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> wherein said electronic digital display comprises a key pad for inputting data, said digital display sending an electronic signal to said processor corresponding to said data input on said digital display key pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> further comprising at least one deployable stop attached to said power tool base, said at least one deployable stop sending an indication to said processor when an operator loads the work piece into said power tool alignment area such that said deployable stop senses the presence of the work piece in said alignment area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A distance measuring device for use with a power tool having a base, an alignment fence, and an alignment area defined by the power tool base and the power tool alignment fence for receiving a work piece, said distance measuring device comprising:
<claim-text>a first measuring sensor proximate to the alignment area that produces a first signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages the power tool base and the power tool alignment fence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second measuring sensor proximate to the alignment area that produces a second signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within the alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages the power tool base and the power tool alignment fence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor that receives said first and second signals, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from said first or second signal, and outputs a third signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area, said third signal being based on a selected one of said first or second signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display receiving said third signal from said processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the power tool is a miter saw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein each of said measuring sensors comprises a distance measuring wheel having an outer circumference surface in rolling engagement with the work piece outer surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> where each of said measuring sensors further comprises an electronic rotary encoder and a distance measuring wheel, said electronic rotary encoder having an input shaft and producing an output signal that corresponds to the rotation of said input shaft, and said measuring wheel being fixed on said input shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>:
<claim-text>wherein each of said distance measuring wheels has an outer circumference of about 11.25 inches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said electronic rotary encoders generates a signal pulse for each about one degree angular rotation of its corresponding input shaft and sends each said pulse to said processor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said processor comprises a central processing unit that receives said signal pulses and determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within the alignment area from said signal pulses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein said processor comprises a central processing unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein said display comprises an electronic digital display.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The measuring device according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref> wherein said display further comprising a key pad for inputting data, and wherein said display sends an electronic signal to said processor corresponding to the data input on said digital key pad.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A power tool comprising:
<claim-text>a base;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an alignment fence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an alignment area defined by said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence for receiving a work piece; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a distance measuring device comprising:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first measuring sensor proximate to said alignment area that produces a first signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within said alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second measuring sensor proximate to said alignment area that produces a second signal that corresponds to a longitudinal motion of the work piece within said alignment area when an outer surface of the work piece simultaneously slidably engages said power tool base and said power tool alignment fence;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor that receives said first and second signals, determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area from said first or second signal, and outputs a third signal that corresponds to the longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area, said third signal being based on a selected one of said first or second signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display receiving said third signal from said processor and providing an alpha-numeric representation of the distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein said power tool is a miter saw.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein each of said measuring sensors comprises a distance measuring wheel having an outer circumference surface in rolling engagement with the work piece outer surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> where each of said measuring sensors further comprises an electronic rotary encoder and a distance measuring wheel, said electronic rotary encoder having an input shaft and producing an output signal that corresponds to the rotation of said input shaft, and said measuring wheel being fixed on said input shaft.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>:
<claim-text>wherein each of said distance measuring wheels has an outer circumference of about 11.25 inches;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of said electronic rotary encoders generates a signal pulse for each about one degree angular rotation of its corresponding input shaft and sends each said pulse to said processor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said processor comprises a central processing unit that receives said signal pulses and determines a longitudinal distance traveled by the work piece within said alignment area from said signal pulses.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein said processor comprises a central processing unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> wherein said display comprises an electronic digital display.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The power tool according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref> wherein said display further comprising a key pad for inputting data, and wherein said display sends an electronic signal to said processor corresponding to the data input on said digital key pad. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
