<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640852-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640852</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12275617</doc-number>
<date>20081121</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>30</class>
<subclass>B</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>100 88</main-classification>
<further-classification>100 87</further-classification>
<further-classification> 58341</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Round baler belt-tensioning cylinder arrangement also used for bale ejection</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4433619</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Anstey et al.</name>
<date>19840200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>100 40</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7140294</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Anstey et al.</name>
<date>20061100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0235842</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Viaud</name>
<date>20051000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>100 87</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0241499</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Viaud et al.</name>
<date>20051100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>100 89</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>4</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>100  5</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>100 87</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>100 88</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>100 89</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>100100</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 56341</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Anstey</last-name>
<first-name>Henry Dennis</first-name>
<address>
<city>Ottumwa</city>
<state>IA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Derscheid</last-name>
<first-name>Daniel Eric</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hedrick</city>
<state>IA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Deere &#x26; Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Moline</city>
<state>IL</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Jimmy T</first-name>
<department>3725</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A large round baler is equipped with a combined belt-tensioning and bale ejecting arrangement including front and rear tensioning arm assemblies mounted at an upper front location adjacent a baling chamber. Extensible and retractable belt-tensioning actuators are coupled between the arm assemblies and serve to yieldably restrain movement of the arms, which support and or guide runs of bale-forming belts, in response to the growth of a bale being formed in the baling chamber. One end of each of the tensioning actuators is coupled to the rear arm assembly in such a way that the actuator may be cycled to move over center relative to the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly once the bale is completely formed so that the actuators may be used to aid in ejecting the bale once the discharge gate is opened.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="144.95mm" wi="230.46mm" file="US07640852-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="237.57mm" wi="154.26mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="232.92mm" wi="151.55mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="230.97mm" wi="144.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="201.17mm" wi="168.23mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="234.53mm" wi="151.47mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="239.10mm" wi="146.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="233.26mm" wi="144.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="207.69mm" wi="166.88mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640852-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to large round balers, and more specifically relates to combined belt-tensioning and bale ejection arrangements for such balers.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">U.S. Pat. No. 7,140,294, granted on Nov. 28, 2006 concerns a large round baler equipped with a combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement including a tensioning arm assembly located in an upper front region of opposite side walls of the baler and comprising front and rear arm assemblies having separate tensioning and ejecting actuators associated with them and operable in such a way that, after formation of a bale, the ejecting actuator may be operated to cause the rear arm assembly to sweep into the baling chamber and aid in the ejection of the bale.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">It is desired to simplify this tensioning and ejecting arrangement by eliminating the need for a separate ejecting actuator while retaining the ejection function.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">According to the present invention, there is provided an improvement to the above-described patented combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">An object of the invention is to provide a combined belt-tensioning and bale ejection arrangement wherein the tensioning actuator arrangement serves also as the bale ejection actuator arrangement,</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The object is accomplished by mounting the extensible and retractable hydraulic tensioning actuators between front and rear tensioning arm assemblies in a manner establishing an over-center relationship between the lines of action of the actuators and the pivot axis of the rear tensioning arm assembly in such a way that they may be cycled to first effect belt-tensioning during formation of a bale, and then for operating the rear tensioning arm assembly for aiding in the ejection of the completed bale.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">According to a first embodiment, the over-center relationship is established by mounting the actuators to the rear tensioning arm assembly at an elongate opening disposed in the rear tensioning arm assembly such that, when the actuators are located at upper ends of the openings, their lines of action will be above the axis of rotation of the rear tensioning arm assembly, with the actuators extending under resistance during the formation of a bale and with the actuators retracting slightly and having their ends move to lower ends of the openings resulting in their lines of action moving over center so as to be below the axis of rotation of the rear tensioning arm assembly, when the actuators are placed in a float condition after the bale discharge gate is opened, whereby subsequent extension of the actuators, once the bale discharge gate is opened, results in the rear arm assembly being driven so as to aid in the ejection of the formed bale.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">According to a second embodiment, the over-center relationship is established by providing a pair of links respectively coupled between the pair of actuators and the rear tensioning arm assembly, with the links being operable for moving the lines of action of the actuators over-center relative to the axis of rotation of the rear tensioning arm assembly after a bale is formed in the baling chamber, the pair of actuators then being operable for aiding in the ejection of the bale from the baling chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">This and other objects of the invention will become apparent from a reading of the ensuing description, together with the appended drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic, right side view of a round baler equipped with a combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement constructed in accordance with a first embodiment of the invention, wherein tensioning cylinders have first ends coupled for moving along respective slots contained in the rear arm assembly so as to go over center relative to the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly, and with the front and rear tensioning arm assemblies being shown in respective lowered, bale starting positions.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a view like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, but showing a completed bale within the baling chamber, with the front and rear tensioning arm assemblies being shown in respective raised, bale completed positions.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, but showing the discharge gate in its raised bale discharge position, with a bale being discharged beneath it under the assistance of the rear arm assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a right front perspective view of the combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, with the tensioning arms being shown in their respective lowered positions shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a view like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, but showing a second embodiment of the present invention wherein links are used to establish the connections between the actuators and the rear arm assembly which permit the lines of action of the actuators to move over center relative to the pivotal axis of the rear tensioning arm assembly so that the actuators may be used to swing the rear arm assembly for aiding in the ejection of a bale.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a view like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, but showing a completed bale within the baling chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a view like that of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, but showing the discharge gate in its raised bale discharge position, with a bale being discharged beneath it under the assistance of the rear arm assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a right front perspective view of the combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-7</figref>, with the tensioning arms being shown in their respective lowered positions shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> of the drawings, there is shown a large round baler <b>10</b> including a chassis <b>12</b> carrying an axle on which ground wheels <b>14</b> are mounted so that the chassis <b>12</b> is supported for being towed over the ground by an agricultural tractor, not shown, coupled to a tongue <b>16</b> joined to, and projecting forwardly from the chassis <b>12</b>. The chassis <b>12</b> includes a pair of transversely spaced sidewall structures including an inner pair of vertically oriented side walls <b>18</b>, which are parallel to, and respectively spaced transversely from, a pair of outer sidewalls <b>20</b>, with the inner walls <b>18</b>, being shown only in dashed outline, for the sake of clarity. The inner sidewalls <b>18</b> have a rear region shaped so as to define a partial circular outer periphery <b>22</b> having a radius slightly larger than that of a full sized bale <b>24</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>) formed within an expansible baling chamber <b>26</b>, described in more detail below, as crop is fed through an inlet <b>28</b> of the baling chamber by the action of a crop feeding arrangement <b>30</b> including a crop pick-up <b>32</b> and a feed rotor <b>34</b>, which is here shown as working together with a knife arrangement <b>36</b> for cutting the crop into pieces before being baled.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Extending between and rotatably mounted at fixed peripheral locations of the outer sidewalls <b>20</b>, which are beyond the peripheries of the inner pair of sidewalls <b>18</b>, are a plurality of bale-forming belt support rolls, which provide support for a plurality of bale-forming belts <b>38</b> mounted in side-by-side relationship to each other across a width dimension of the rolls. Specifically, a bottom front roll <b>40</b> defines an upper border of the crop inlet <b>28</b> at a location just above a path traced by the tines of the crop feed rotor <b>34</b>. Proceeding counterclockwise from the roll <b>40</b>, there is provided a lower central front roll <b>42</b> spaced upwardly and forwardly from the roll <b>40</b>, an upper central front roll <b>44</b> spaced a short distance above the roll <b>42</b>, a top front roll <b>46</b> spaced upwardly and to the rear from the roll <b>44</b>, and a top rear roll <b>48</b> spaced rearward from the roll <b>46</b>. Located a slight distance below and forward of the top front roll <b>46</b> is a roll <b>50</b>. The bale-forming belt support rolls <b>40</b>-<b>50</b>, thus far described, constitute a set of fixed rolls, with further support for the belts <b>38</b> being afforded by a plurality of rolls mounted for movement, as is described in the immediately following paragraphs.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A light weight discharge gate <b>52</b> includes triangular end members <b>54</b> respectively located between the inner and outer sidewalls <b>18</b> and <b>20</b> at the opposite sides of the baler <b>10</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the light weight discharge gate <b>52</b> is positioned in a lowered baling position, wherein each of the triangular end members <b>54</b> includes an upper corner pivotally mounted, as at <b>56</b>, to the adjacent spaced sidewalls <b>18</b> and <b>20</b>, and about which the light weight discharge gate <b>52</b> may pivot vertically to a discharge position, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The pivotal mountings <b>56</b> define a horizontal transverse pivot axis which is approximately coincident with that of the full sized bale <b>24</b> positioned within the baling chamber <b>26</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The discharge gate <b>52</b> is dimensioned such that front and rear corners of each triangular end member <b>54</b> are located radially beyond the circular periphery <b>22</b> of the adjacent inner sidewall <b>18</b>, with a pair of front and rear rolls <b>58</b> and <b>60</b> extending between, and being rotatably mounted to, front corner regions of the triangular end members <b>54</b>, and with a roll <b>62</b> extending between, and being rotatably mounted to, rear corner regions of the triangular end members <b>54</b>. The roll <b>60</b> is spaced down and to the rear from the roll <b>58</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Referring now also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, it can be seen that a combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement <b>70</b> is mounted to an upper front region of the inner sidewalls <b>18</b>. The arrangement <b>70</b> includes front and rear tensioning arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The front tensioning arm assembly <b>72</b> includes a pair of transversely spaced, parallel arms <b>76</b> having forward ends fixed to a support tube <b>78</b> extending between, and being mounted for rotation at, forward edges of the inner sidewalls <b>18</b> at a location spaced just to the rear of the bale-forming belt support roll <b>44</b>. The arms <b>76</b> are located so that major rear sections of the arms <b>76</b> sweep respective paths spaced a short distance inwardly of the sidewalls <b>18</b>, with rear end sections <b>77</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>) of the arms <b>76</b> being offset toward the sidewalls <b>18</b> so as to follow respective paths closely adjacent the sidewalls <b>18</b>. Extending between, and mounted for rotation to, the rear end sections <b>77</b> of the arms <b>76</b> are front and rear belt guide rolls <b>80</b> and <b>82</b>, respectively. Located at the forward ends of each of the arms <b>76</b>, and disposed at approximately a right angle to a line extending through the centers of the tube <b>78</b> and rolls <b>80</b> and <b>82</b>, is an actuator mounting ear <b>84</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The rear tensioning arm assembly <b>74</b> also includes a pair of transversely spaced, parallel arms <b>86</b>, these arms having upper ends joined to a tube <b>88</b> extending transversely between, and being pivotally mounted to, upper edges of the inner sidewalls <b>18</b> at a location spaced a short distance down and forward of the fixed bale-forming belt support roll <b>50</b>. The arms <b>86</b> are mounted so as to sweep a path closely adjacent the sidewalls <b>18</b> and closely adjacent the arms <b>76</b> when overlapped, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</figref>. Extending between, and being mounted for rotation within, lower ends of the arms <b>86</b> are a front belt guide roll <b>90</b>, and a rear belt-engaging roll <b>92</b>, the latter reducing scuffing, in a manner described below. Provided at the upper end of each of the arms <b>86</b> and disposed at approximately a right angle to a line extending through the center of the tube <b>86</b> and the belt guide roll <b>90</b> is an actuator mounting ear <b>94</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Up to this point, the combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement <b>70</b> is identical to that disclosed in the aforementioned U.S. Pat. No. 7,140,294. The arrangement <b>70</b> described here differs from that contained in the patent by providing each of the mounting ears <b>94</b> with an elongate slot <b>95</b> that is oriented substantially vertically, as viewed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, and extends from an upper location in the ear <b>94</b>, which is spaced above the tube <b>88</b>, to a location in the associated arm <b>86</b> which is below a horizontal transverse axis of rotation defined by the mounting of the tube <b>88</b> to the baling chamber inner side walls <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Control of the front and rear tensioning arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b> is achieved by a pair of double-acting, extensible and retractable hydraulic tensioning actuators <b>96</b>, respectively coupled between the mounting ears <b>84</b> and <b>94</b> at the opposite sides of the assemblies, with the coupling of each actuator <b>96</b> to the mounting ears <b>94</b> being by a connecting element <b>98</b> located in the curved slot <b>95</b>. An elongate flexible down stop <b>102</b>, here shown as a cable, is coupled between a mounting ear <b>104</b> provided on a forward region of the left arm <b>76</b> adjacent the support tube <b>78</b>, and a mounting ear <b>106</b> provided on a bottom region of the left arm <b>86</b> adjacent the support tube <b>88</b>. A spring or other device (not shown) may be provided for taking up the slack in the cable so that it does not interfere with operation of other parts of the baler <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Instead of the cylinder mounting ears <b>84</b> and <b>94</b> being formed integrally with the pairs of arms <b>76</b> and <b>84</b>, and the down stop mounting ears <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> being respectively integral with the left arms <b>76</b> and <b>86</b>, respective mounting ears (not shown) may be appropriately fixed to opposite end regions of each of the support tubes <b>78</b> and <b>88</b>. Further, instead of a pair of tensioning actuators <b>96</b>, a single actuator could be coupled between crank arms respectively provided at central locations between opposite ends of the support tubes <b>78</b> and <b>88</b>. Also, in lieu of the direct connections between the actuators <b>96</b> and the arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b>, the actuators could be connected through means of levers mounted to the arm assemblies for pivoting freely in one direction and for engaging stop pins when pivoted in an opposite direction, with the levers having the actuators <b>96</b> coupled to them.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">With reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, it can be seen that a loop <b>107</b> of the baling belts <b>38</b> extends about the roll <b>50</b> and includes front and rear runs <b>108</b> and <b>110</b>, respectively, that pass between the guide rolls <b>80</b> and <b>82</b> carried at the end of the front tensioning arm assembly <b>72</b>. The front run <b>108</b> extends from the front guide roll <b>80</b> to a lower region of the lower front support roll <b>40</b>, while the rear run <b>110</b> passes about front and lower regions respectively of the rolls <b>58</b> and <b>60</b> carried at the lower front corner region of the light weight discharge gate <b>52</b>. It can be seen that a bale support roll <b>112</b> is located just forward of the roll <b>58</b> and defines a rear side of the crop inlet <b>28</b>. When the baling chamber <b>26</b> is empty, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the front arm assembly <b>72</b> is positioned in its lowered position, wherein the guide rolls <b>80</b> and <b>82</b> effectively close the top of the baling chamber <b>26</b> so as to form a relatively small, wedge-shaped space, sized conducive for starting a bale. At this time, only a minimal length of the belts <b>38</b> is required for engaging the forming bale, with the excess length being contained in a loop <b>114</b> located between the central front rolls <b>42</b> and <b>44</b>, and held by the guide roll <b>90</b> carried at the end of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b>, with the arm assembly <b>74</b> then extending downwardly in overlapping relationship to the front arm assembly <b>72</b>. The hydraulic actuators <b>96</b> are contracted at this time, with the connecting element <b>98</b> at the rear of each actuator being located in an upper end of an associated one of the slots <b>95</b>. Through the agency of a variable pressure relief valve (not shown) located for resisting the flow of fluid from the rod ends of the actuators <b>96</b>, as is well known, upward movement of the tensioning arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b> is yieldably resisted. As crop is fed into the baling chamber <b>26</b> by way of the baling chamber inlet <b>28</b>, the belt runs <b>108</b> and <b>110</b>, which respectively travel upward and downward, cause the crop to be rolled into a bale, with the size of the bale increasing, resulting in the front arm <b>72</b> pivoting clockwise and in the rear arm assembly <b>74</b> pivoting counterclockwise. When a full sized bale has been formed, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the entire loop <b>114</b> of the belts <b>38</b> will be substantially depleted, with the rear tensioning arm assembly <b>74</b> being in engagement with the support tube <b>78</b>. At the same time, the front arm assembly <b>72</b> will have raised to the extent that the guide rolls <b>80</b> and <b>82</b> are near the fixed support roll <b>50</b>, and to the extent that an arcuate stop surface <b>116</b> provided on the top edge of the arms <b>76</b> is close to engagement with the support tube <b>88</b>. At this time, the actuators <b>96</b> will be substantially fully extended. Springs (not shown) could be used in addition to the actuators <b>96</b> for yieldably resisting upward movement of the arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Once a full sized bale <b>24</b> is formed in the baling chamber <b>26</b>, the bale <b>24</b> may be discharged by effecting clockwise rotation of the light weight discharge gate <b>52</b> through the action of one or more hydraulic actuators (not shown) coupled between the sidewalls <b>18</b> and/or <b>20</b> and the discharge gate <b>52</b> so as to move the discharge gate <b>52</b> from its lowered baling position, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, to its raised discharge position, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The completed bale <b>24</b> is then free to fall onto an unloading ramp <b>118</b> provided beneath the baling chamber.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Upon the discharge gate <b>52</b> being raised, the actuators <b>96</b> are placed in a float condition and tension in the baling belts <b>38</b> is released. This results in the connecting elements <b>98</b> moving to the lower ends of the slots <b>95</b> while at the same time resulting in the actuators <b>96</b> retracting a small amount. Once the connecting elements <b>98</b> are in the lower ends of the slots <b>95</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> (a sensor, not shown, could be provided for alerting an operator that this movement has occurred), the actuators <b>96</b> are extended. Because the line of action of the actuators <b>96</b> is now below the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b>, extension of the actuators <b>96</b> will cause the rear arm assembly <b>74</b> to pivot clockwise with the roll <b>92</b> engaging and rolling in a scuff-free manner along the rear side of the front run of belts <b>108</b> of the loop <b>107</b> so as to bring the run <b>108</b> into contact with a central front region of the bale <b>24</b> and exert a force positively ejecting the bale <b>24</b> out of the baling chamber <b>26</b>. Therefore, any hesitation of the bale <b>24</b> to being discharged due to becoming wedged between the inner sidewalls <b>18</b> is avoided. At the time the arm assembly <b>74</b> is acting to eject the bale <b>24</b>, it is also acting to remove any slack in the belts <b>38</b> which results when the bale <b>24</b> leaves the baling chamber, with it being noted that the loop <b>114</b> is once again formed containing a maximum length of the belts <b>38</b>. However, during lowering the discharge gate <b>52</b> back to its baling or closed position, extra belt slack occurs and the down stop <b>102</b> then acts to prevent the rear arm assembly <b>74</b> from coming into contact with the front roll <b>80</b> of the front arm assembly <b>72</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Once the bale <b>24</b> is ejected, the discharge gate <b>52</b> is returned to is lowered, baling position, with the actuators <b>96</b> then being retracted resulting in the front arm assembly being lowered to its baling position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and in the connecting elements <b>98</b> of the actuators <b>96</b> moving to upper ends of the slots <b>95</b> so that the lines of action of the actuators <b>96</b> are once again above the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5-8</figref>, there is shown a second embodiment of the combined tensioning and ejecting arrangement, wherein, instead of the rear ends of the actuators <b>96</b> being attached to the arms <b>86</b> by connecting elements received in elongate slots, the actuators <b>96</b> are connected to the arms <b>86</b> by links <b>120</b> that are sized and located relative to the pivot axis of the mounting tube <b>88</b> so that, when the arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b> are in their lowered positions, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the links <b>120</b> project forwardly from respective pivot connections <b>122</b> with the arms <b>86</b> of the rear assembly <b>74</b> so as to be in substantial axial alignment with the associated actuator <b>96</b> and with the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b>. The actuators <b>96</b> are substantially fully contracted at this time.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">As a bale grows in the baling chamber <b>26</b>, against the resistance afforded by the actuators <b>96</b>, it will press upwardly on the arms <b>76</b> of the front arm assembly <b>72</b>, causing the arm assembly to rotate clockwise about the pivot axis of the front arm assembly <b>72</b>. At the same time, tensile forces in the bale-forming belts <b>38</b> will act through the belt loop <b>114</b> to effect counterclockwise rotation of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b> about its pivot axis. The net result is that when the bale <b>24</b> reaches its complete diameter, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the line of action of each of the actuators <b>96</b> is above the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The actuators <b>96</b> are then placed in a float condition which results in the rear ends of the actuators <b>96</b> and the links <b>120</b> gravitating downwardly until the links come into contact with respective stop pins <b>124</b> provided on each of the arms <b>86</b> such that the lines of action of the actuators <b>96</b> are now below the pivot axis of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">After the discharge gate <b>54</b> is moved to its raised discharge position, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the actuators <b>96</b> are extended to effect downward pivoting movement of the rear arm assembly <b>74</b> so that it sweeps the belt run <b>108</b> into engagement with the bale <b>24</b> so as to aid in the ejection of the bale.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Once the bale is ejected, the actuators <b>96</b> are once again contracted, first causing the links <b>120</b> to be pivoted upwardly away from the stop pins <b>124</b> until they become aligned with the with the actuators <b>96</b>, with further contraction of the actuators then resulting in the front arm assembly <b>72</b> pivoting downwardly to its lowered position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, with the tensioning arm assemblies <b>72</b> and <b>74</b> then both being in position for starting a new bale.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Having described the preferred embodiment, it will become apparent that various modifications can be made without departing from the scope of the invention as defined in the accompanying claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. In a large round baler including a baling chamber defined in part by a plurality of bale forming belts supported in side-by-side relationship across a plurality of fixed rolls supported by opposite sidewall structures, and by a plurality of movable rolls including rolls carried by a discharge gate pivotable between a lowered baling position and a raised discharge position, and at least one tensioning arm assembly mounted to said sidewall structures for pivoting vertically and carrying at least one bale-forming belt guide roller for engaging the bale-forming belts at a location between two adjacent ones of said plurality of fixed rolls, said discharge gate includes triangular end members, said at least one tensioning arm assembly being located for pivoting about a horizontal axis between a lowered position corresponding to a bale-starting condition, wherein said baling chamber is empty and said discharge gate is in its lowered baling position, and a raised position corresponding to a bale-completed condition, wherein said baling chamber contains a completed bale, at least one extensible and retractable tensioning actuator being coupled to said at least one tensioning arm assembly for resisting movement of said at least one tensioning arm assembly between its lowered and raised positions, the improvement comprising: a connection arrangement coupling one end of said at least one tensioning actuator to said at least one tensioning arm assembly such that, once said at least one tensioning arm assembly moves to its raised position, said at least one actuator is actuated so that a line of action of said at least one actuator moves over center relative to said axis and below said axis, and said one end of said at least one tensioning actuator moves from a position above said horizontal axis to a position below said horizontal axis, whereupon said at least one actuator is operated to effect downward movement of said at least one tensioning arm assembly so that it aids in ejecting the bale, once said discharge gate is raised to its discharge position, so that said at least one tensioning arm assembly acts to forcibly eject said completed bale.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The large round baler, as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said connection arrangement includes a slot provided in said at least one tensioning arm assembly so as to extend upwardly from a lower end and a coupling element carried by said at least one tensioning actuator and received for moving along said slot, with the latter being disposed relative to said axis such that the line of action of said at least one actuator moves from above to below said axis when said coupling element moves between an upper end and said lower end of said slot.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The large round baler, as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said connection arrangement includes a link coupled between said at least one tensioning actuator and said at least one tensioning arm assembly, with said link being so located relative to said axis that pivotal movement of said link relative to said at least one tensioning arm results in said line of action moving from above to below said axis when said at least one actuator is placed in a float mode after said at least one tensioning arm assembly moves to said raised position from said lowered position.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The large round baler, as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said at least one tensioning arm assembly is mounted for pivoting clockwise about said axis when moving from said raised position to said lowered position; said plurality of fixed bale-forming belt support rolls including a third roll located above said baling chamber and having said bale-forming belts looped thereabout so as to define front and rear runs of said bale-forming belts; a second tensioning arm assembly carrying second and third belt guide rolls spaced close to each other, with said front and rear runs of said bale-forming belts passing between, and cooperating with, said second and third belt guide rolls to form a top of said baling chamber when said chamber is empty; said second tensioning arm assembly being mounted for pivoting counterclockwise about an axis located forward of said baling chamber when moving from a raised position, corresponding to when the completed bale is contained in the baling chamber, and a lowered position, corresponding to when said baling chamber is empty; and said at least one tensioning actuator being coupled between said at least one tensioning arm assembly and said second tensioning arm assembly so as to resist movement of said at least one and second tensioning arm assemblies from their respective lowered positions to their respective raised positions as a forming bale enlarges said baling chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
