<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641016-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641016</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11924426</doc-number>
<date>20071025</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-293064</doc-number>
<date>20061027</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-243035</doc-number>
<date>20070919</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>167</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>41</main-group>
<subgroup>12</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180230</main-classification>
<further-classification>474 69</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e89">Straddle-type vehicle</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5924954</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Vukovich et al.</name>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>477 46</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5947861</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nobumoto</name>
<date>19990900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>477 37</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>04-131558</doc-number>
<date>19920500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>04-210156</doc-number>
<date>19920700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>07-119804</doc-number>
<date>19950500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180230</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 51- 52</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 54</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>701 56</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>474 69- 70</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>477 44</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>477 46</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>10</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080179126</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080731</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Unno</last-name>
<first-name>Toshio</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shizuoka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Asaoka</last-name>
<first-name>Ryousuke</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shizuoka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Aoki</last-name>
<first-name>Hiroyuki</first-name>
<address>
<city>Shizuoka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hogan &#x26; Hartson LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Yamaha Hatsudoki Kabushiki Kaisha</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Shizuoka-Ken</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Morris</last-name>
<first-name>Lesley</first-name>
<department>3611</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Fiore</last-name>
<first-name>Levon</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A straddle-type vehicle that can be accelerated rapidly by a simple operation irrespective of a selected drive mode includes a control unit that executes first control of switching between a plurality of drive modes A and B, and in each of at least two of the drive modes A and B, and second control of shifting the change gear to a kick-down state A<b>1</b> or B<b>1</b> in which the speed change ratio is lower than that of the drive mode A or B, according to operation of a shift-down operation member.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.65mm" wi="142.58mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="116.50mm" wi="145.54mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="218.78mm" wi="134.45mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="96.35mm" wi="149.35mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="211.67mm" wi="144.70mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="156.63mm" wi="148.08mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="211.41mm" wi="158.33mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641016-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="213.95mm" wi="135.21mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641016-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="218.10mm" wi="140.04mm" file="US07641016-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="213.53mm" wi="145.29mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641016-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="210.57mm" wi="102.70mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641016-20100105-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of priority under 35 USC 119 of Japanese patent application nos. 2006-293064, filed on Oct. 27, 2006, and 2007-243035, filed on Sep. 19, 2007, which applications are hereby incorporated by reference in their entireties.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to straddle-type vehicles (for example, motorcycles), and more particularly, relates to a straddle-type vehicle equipped with an electronically controlled continuously variable transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Straddle-type vehicles such as scooter-type motorcycles widely use a V-belt continuously variable transmission. A V-belt continuously variable transmission includes a pair of primary and secondary sheaves with variable groove widths, the primary sheave being disposed on a primary shaft to which the output of a power source such as an engine is input, and the secondary sheave being disposed on a secondary shaft which takes out the output to the driving wheel. A V-belt is wound around both sheaves, and the winding diameters of the V-belt around the sheaves are adjusted by changing the groove widths of each of the sheaves by a groove-width adjusting mechanism, so that the speed change ratio between both sheaves is controlled in a stepless manner.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The primary sheave and the secondary sheave are generally each composed of a fixed flange and a moving flange between which a V-groove is formed. Each moving flange is movable along the axis of the primary shaft or the secondary shaft. The moving flange is moved by a groove-width adjusting mechanism so that the speed change ratio can be controlled in a stepless manner.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Some conventional V-belt continuously variable transmissions of this type use an electric motor to move the moving flange of the primary sheave to adjust the groove width. This structure allows the groove width to be adjusted freely, since the moving flange can be moved in either a direction to decrease the groove width of the primary sheave (to Top), or in a direction to increase the groove width (to Low), by the moving thrust of the electric motor (for example, refer to Japanese Patent No. 3,043,061).</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Scooter-type motorcycles equipped with a mechanism to electronically control a V-belt type continuously variable transmission change the speed change ratio automatically according to a program (map) input in advance for vehicle speed and engine speed (accelerator position) without the need for the operation of the rider. This provides the rider with ease of driving operability. For this reason, various attempts to apply this automatic continuously variable transmission to various types of vehicle have been made today.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Some motorcycles equipped with this type of automatic continuously variable transmission have a plurality of drive modes with different speed-change characteristics using a plurality of the above-mentioned programs (maps). For example, JP-A-7-119804 discloses a vehicle having programs (maps) for specifying a plurality of drive modes, in addition to a normal mode map for normal driving, a sports mode for frisky and agile driving and an engine braking mode for downhill runs. This vehicle allows the drive mode maps to be selected automatically according to a determination on the driving state of the vehicle (accelerator position, whether under braking or not), enabling the rider to perform accurate driving according to the driving state without any switching operation.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">However, the vehicle of JP-A-7-119804 has the problem that the rider cannot switch among the maps for specifying the respective drive modes according to rider's intention because the maps are selected automatically; for example, the rider cannot accelerate freely even if the rider wants to increase speed sharply during passing or climbing a hill, or the rider cannot apply engine braking freely even if the rider wants to decrease speed before entering a curve.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The present invention has been made in light of such circumstances and provides a straddle-type vehicle that can be accelerated or decelerated by a simple operation irrespective of selected drive mode.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A straddle-type vehicle of the invention includes a control unit for controlling a continuously variable transmission, and a shift-down operation member. The control unit has a plurality of drive modes. The control unit executes first control of switching among the plurality of drive modes and second control of shifting, in at least two of the plurality of drive modes, the change gear to a shift-down state in which the speed change ratio is lower than that of each drive mode, according to the shift-down operation member.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to the invention, in a straddle-type vehicle equipped with a control unit that electrically controls the speed change gear of a continuously variable transmission, a plurality of drive modes can be switched. Furthermore, the change gear in at least two of the drive modes can be shifted to a shift-down state in which the speed change ratio is lower than that of each drive mode according to the operation of a shift-down operation member. This arrangement allows temporary acceleration/deceleration by shift-down control while selecting the optimum drive mode according to driving state, thereby improving rider comfort.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Other features and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following detailed description, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings which illustrate, by way of example, various features of embodiments of the invention.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view of a straddle-type vehicle according to an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram for describing a control unit mounted to the straddle-type vehicle of the embodiment and the peripheral configuration thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram for describing the control of the control unit of the straddle-type vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) is a diagram for describing a control map R(A) for a normal mode A.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) is a diagram for describing a control map R(B) for an assist I mode B.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram for describing the control of the control unit of a straddle-type vehicle according to another embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a diagram for describing a control map R(C) for an assist II mode C.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a block diagram showing the arrangement of a continuously variable transmission of an embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a block diagram for describing a control unit according to another embodiment of the invention and the peripheral configuration thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a block diagram showing the arrangement of a continuously variable transmission according to this embodiment of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a block diagram showing the arrangement of a continuously variable transmission according to another embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Embodiments of the invention are described herein with reference to the drawings, wherein like and corresponding parts in each of the several drawings are identified by the same reference character. It is to be understood that the invention is not limited to the following embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view of a straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> according to an embodiment of the invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 7</figref> are block diagrams for describing a control unit <b>10</b> mounted to straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> and the peripheral configuration thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 7</figref>, straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> includes a primary drive (engine) <b>80</b> whose output is controlled by an accelerator operation member <b>20</b> operated by a rider, a continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> connected to engine <b>80</b>, and a control unit <b>10</b> that controls continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> electronically. Straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> further includes a shift-down operation member <b>40</b>. Control unit <b>10</b> has a plurality of drive modes A and B. Control unit <b>10</b> executes first control <b>11</b> of switching between drive modes A and B. Control unit <b>10</b> further executes second control <b>12</b> of shifting the speed change ratio of drive modes A and B to Low according to operation of shift-down operation member <b>40</b> in at least two of drive modes A and B. Control unit <b>10</b> executes various controls according to a predetermined program.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a scooter-type motorcycle. Driving force generated by engine <b>80</b> is transmitted to a rear (driving) wheel <b>82</b> via continuously variable transmission <b>60</b>. Accelerator operation member <b>20</b> operated by the rider is an accelerator or an accelerator grip mounted to a handle <b>84</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> of this embodiment is an electronically controlled V-belt type automatic continuously variable transmission. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the position of the moving sheave (not shown) of the primary sheave of V-belt type continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> is controlled by a sheave-position moving device <b>67</b> (in this embodiment, an electric motor). The primary sheave whose position is controlled by electric motor <b>67</b> is connected to a primary shaft <b>102</b> (for example, a crankshaft) rotated by engine <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> can be operated in a plurality of switchable drive modes. Here, the &#x201c;drive modes&#x201d; mean speed change modes during driving. This embodiment employs a plurality of gear change modes with different speed change characteristics for continuously variable transmission <b>60</b>. Specifically, continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> operates in two modes, a normal mode A (a so-called economic mode) in which economy is given a high priority in consideration of low fuel consumption and low noise and an assist I mode B (a so-called power mode) in which the output performance of the engine or the like is given a high priority. The drive modes can be switched manually according to operation based on the intention of a rider of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a method of control by control unit <b>10</b> will be described. Control unit <b>10</b> executes first control <b>11</b> of switching the plurality of drive modes A and B. In this embodiment, control unit <b>10</b> can execute the control in such a manner as to switch the drive modes according to operation of a mode-selection operation member <b>30</b> by the rider, provided separately from accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. In the example shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the drive mode is switched between normal mode A and assist I mode B by control unit <b>10</b> (arrow S<b>50</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Control unit <b>10</b> is electrically connected to a mode selector switch (mode selector SW) <b>30</b> as mode-selection operation member <b>30</b>. Switching among the drive modes can be executed when the rider turns on mode selector switch <b>30</b>. Mode selector switch <b>30</b> may be a mode switching button, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Control unit <b>10</b> executes second control <b>12</b> of shifting the speed change ratio of at least two of drive modes A and B to Low according to operation of shift-down operation member <b>40</b>. In this embodiment, second control <b>12</b> can be executed in all drive modes A and B set for control unit <b>10</b>. Specifically, control unit <b>10</b> can execute control, in each of the two drive modes (normal mode A and assist I mode B), to shift the transmission to a shift-down state in which the speed change ratio is lower than that of each drive mode by rider operation of a shift-down operation member <b>40</b> provided separately from accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. That is, when the drive mode is shifted from normal mode A to a shift-down state A<b>1</b> (arrow S<b>51</b>), control unit <b>10</b> can shift the speed change ratio to Low from that of normal mode A, and when the drive mode is shifted from assist I mode B to a shift-down state B<b>1</b> (arrow S<b>52</b>), control unit <b>10</b> can shift the speed change ratio from that of assist I mode B to Low.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In this embodiment, control unit <b>10</b> is electrically connected to a shift-down switch (a shift-down SW) <b>40</b> serving as a trigger for shifting to a shift-down state, as shift down operation member <b>40</b>. The shift down operation can be executed by the rider's turning on shift-down switch <b>40</b>. Shift-down switch <b>40</b> is a shift-down button (SD button), for example.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">According to the embodiment of the invention, in straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> equipped with control unit <b>10</b> which electrically controls the gear change of continuously variable transmission <b>60</b>, control unit <b>10</b> executes control to switch between two drive modes, normal mode A and assist I mode B, and in each drive mode A or B, to shift the speed change ratio to Low (to A<b>1</b> or B<b>1</b>) from each speed change ratio. According to the invention, the rider can accelerate temporarily from either drive mode by shift-down control while selecting the optimum drive mode from the two drive modes A and B according to driving conditions. This improves riding comfort. Moreover, the shift-down control allows temporary speed reduction (that is, speed reduction by engine braking).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">With the above arrangement, for example, even in normal mode A (a mode in which the output performance of the engine or the like is reduced), the rider can accelerate quickly by a simple switching operation. This eliminates the need for switching to assist I mode B (a mode in which the output performance of the engine or the like is given a high priority) during passing or climbing a hill, allowing the rider to enjoy comfortable driving.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Since switching of drive modes is executed by the rider's switching operation, the rider can select the optimum drive mode freely. Moreover, since the shift to a shift-down state is also executed by the rider's switching operation, an appropriate acceleration/deceleration effect according to the rider's intention can be obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">While mode selector switch <b>30</b> and shift-down operation member <b>40</b> of this embodiment are separate switches, mode-selection operation member <b>30</b> may double as shift-down operation member <b>40</b>. For example, one button may be used as both the mode-selection operation member and the shift-down operation member, wherein switching of the drive modes is executed by pressing and holding the button, and the shift to shift-down state is executed by tapping the button.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In this embodiment, switching between normal mode A and assist I mode B is executed manually by the rider (by switching operation). However, the invention is not limited to that, and the drive modes may be switched automatically. For example, a straddle-type vehicle having an automatic drive mode in which the drive modes are switched in accordance with the driving state of the vehicle may be provided. The automatic drive mode selection also allows shift to a shift-down state from the respective drive modes. Therefore, temporary acceleration/deceleration by shift-down control can be achieved, with the respective drive modes held.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) and <b>4</b>(<i>b</i>), control of the control unit of the continuously variable transmission will be described in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Control unit <b>10</b> may be, for example, an electronic control unit (ECU) including a microprocessor unit (MPU). Control unit <b>10</b> calculates a speed change ratio according to the driving state of the vehicle (vehicle speed and throttle opening) from a registered control map (program), and sends a gear change instruction for achieving the speed change ratio to continuously variable transmission <b>60</b>, thereby achieving the speed change ratio.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Control unit <b>10</b> calculates a target value of the speed change ratio (target speed change ratio) from the control map on the basis of information on vehicle speed and throttle opening and drives electric motor <b>67</b> so as to achieve the target speed change ratio, thereby controlling the position of the moving sheave of the primary sheave. The control map is stored in a storage section disposed in control unit <b>10</b>. Alternatively, a storage unit which is electrically connected to control unit <b>10</b> may be provided outside control unit <b>10</b>, in which the control map may be stored.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Examples of control maps are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) and <b>4</b>(<i>b</i>). <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) shows a control map R(A) set for control unit <b>10</b> in normal mode A. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) shows a control map R(B) set for control unit <b>10</b> in assist I mode B. The graphs plot the relationship between vehicle speed and engine speed in the respective drive modes. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows, with the same vehicle speed, the higher the engine speed, the lower the speed change ratio of the continuously variable transmission is set. Control maps (R(A) and R(B)) in the respective drive modes indicate the regions (control regions) specified by the respective control maps. The control regions are surrounded by line L<b>1</b> indicative of the relationship between vehicle speed and target engine speed when the throttle is completely closed and line L<b>2</b> indicative of the relationship between vehicle speed and target engine speed when the throttle is fully open.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">In the example of the normal mode shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), on execution of control for the normal mode, a target engine speed is calculated from information on vehicle speed and throttle opening. Specifically, a position on the horizontal axis in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) is determined from information on vehicle speed. Then, a target engine speed is determined within the range of control map R(A) according to the throttle opening. In this case, the target engine speed is decreased (the change gear is shifted to Top so as to decrease the speed change ratio) as the vehicle speed and the throttle opening increase, and the target engine speed is increased (the change gear is shifted to Low so as to increase the speed change ratio) as the vehicle speed and the throttle opening decrease, thereby achieving smooth acceleration or deceleration.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Control unit <b>10</b> calculates a target engine speed by repeating the above calculation according to information on vehicle speed and throttle opening which change momentarily, thereby controlling the speed change ratio of continuously variable transmission <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">A comparison between control map R(A) for normal mode A in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) and control map R(B) for assist I mode B in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) shows that, with the same vehicle speed, the engine speed is set higher in assist I mode B than in normal mode A. That is, the speed change ratio is set lower in assist I mode B than in normal mode A. The setting of the speed change ratio in assist I mode B lower allows more powerful acceleration to be achieved in assist I mode B than in normal mode A.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Control of control unit <b>10</b> is now described. First, control unit <b>10</b> can switch between the respective control maps of the drive modes shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) and <b>4</b>(<i>b</i>) by rider operation of mode-selection operation member <b>30</b> (for example, pressing mode selector button <b>30</b>) (arrow S<b>50</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">For example, to drive on a street without noise, the rider selects normal mode A so as to drive the vehicle gently and quietly. To increase engine output on a mountain path or the like, the rider selects assist I mode B so as to drive the vehicle crisply with high response.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Then, control unit <b>10</b> can shift the change gear to a shift-down state A<b>1</b> or B<b>1</b> in which the speed change ratio is shifted to lower than that of drive mode A or B by the rider operating shift-down operation member <b>40</b> (for example, by pressing the SD button). In the example illustrated, during driving in normal mode A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), control map R(A) for normal mode A shifts to the region R(A<b>1</b>) lower than the initial position (arrow S<b>51</b>), and during driving in assist I mode B of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>), control map R(B) for assist I mode B shifts to the region R(B<b>1</b>) lower than the initial position (arrow S<b>52</b>). The speed change ratios are thus temporarily shifted downward from those of the drive modes to enable driving using engine braking or to prevent slow acceleration during passing or climbing a hill.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The above arrangement allows acceleration in shift-down state A<b>1</b> even from normal mode A. For example, this arrangement eliminates the need for acceleration after switching to assist I mode B to pass the preceding car while driving in normal mode A, allowing the rider to pass the target car by temporarily accelerating rapidly only by pressing a KD button, providing comfortable driving.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">In this embodiment, shift from each drive mode to a shift-down state can be executed without switching between the control maps. That is, it is executed by multiplying a target speed change ratio calculated from the control map for each drive mode by a predetermined conversion factor. Specifically, a target engine speed in a shift-down state is set by multiplying an engine speed calculated from the control map of each drive mode by a predetermined conversion factor (for example, 1.35). The larger the predetermined conversion factor, the more the speed change ratio in a shift-down state is shifted to Low, thus providing higher engine output. The predetermined conversion factor is stored in a factor map format in a storage unit inside or outside the control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The shift to a shift-down state from each drive mode can be executed with the control maps switched. Specifically, as a control map for specifying a shift-down state, a map in which the speed change ratio is set lower than the control map for each drive mode is stored in a storage unit in advance. After shifted to a shift-down state, a target speed change ratio is calculated using the control map for specifying a shift-down state. In this case, a return from the shift-down state to each drive mode is executed automatically when predetermined conditions are met. The automatic return from the shift-down state to each drive mode will be described later in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The predetermined conversion factor for the multiplication may be different between the drive modes or the same. Multiplying by different conversion factors from one drive mode to another ensures the effects of kick-down control. For example, the control map for assist I mode B is set lower than that for normal mode A. Even if the control map is set to Low as described above, the conversion factor in assist I mode B can be smaller than that in normal mode A so as to provide sufficient shift-down effects (acceleration/deceleration effects of shift-down).</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), a plurality of shift-down states can be set in each drive mode. In this case, a plurality of shift-down states is set to positions shifted to Low from the speed change ratio of each drive mode. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) shows an example in which a shift-down state A<b>2</b> is set lower than shift-down state A<b>1</b> of normal mode A. Control unit <b>10</b> can execute control to shift to the shift-down states in sequence (in the example of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), normal mode A&#x2192;shift-down state A<b>1</b>&#x2192;shift-down state A<b>2</b>) according to operation of shift-down operation member <b>40</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">A method for canceling a shift-down state according to this embodiment will be described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 7</figref>, control unit <b>10</b> includes a first setting section <b>16</b> for setting cancel conditions for canceling a shift-down state. Control unit <b>10</b> executes third control <b>13</b> of canceling the shift-down state according to the cancel conditions set by first setting section <b>16</b> to return to a drive mode before shifting to the shift-down state. Any cancel conditions to cancel the shift-down state can be set in first setting section <b>16</b> of control unit <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The cancel conditions of first setting section <b>16</b> for canceling the shift-down state include a predetermined operation of accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. In this case, third control <b>13</b> is executed according to operation of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> set in first setting section <b>16</b>. Specifically, the cancel conditions of first setting section <b>16</b> for canceling the shift-down state include a predetermined operation of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> to decrease the accelerator opening. Control unit <b>10</b> executes third control <b>13</b> according to operation of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> to decrease the accelerator opening. Third control <b>13</b> is executed according to a program preset in control unit <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In other words, control unit <b>10</b> can execute control to issue a shift-down cancel instruction according to the state of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b>, and cancel the shift-down state to return to each drive mode from the shift-down state (arrows S<b>53</b> and S<b>54</b>). The state of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> can be detected by a sensor <b>25</b> that is electrically connected to control unit <b>10</b>. The state of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> is that of other than shift-down operation member <b>40</b>. Sensor <b>25</b> for detecting the state of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> is, for example, an accelerator position sensor (APS) <b>22</b> for detecting the state of accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. In this case, the shift-down cancel instruction can be configured to be issued according to an accelerator position signal output from the accelerator position sensor.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Control unit <b>10</b> may be set so as to issue the shift-down cancel instruction according to an accelerator position signal indicative of a decrease in the accelerator opening of accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. This arrangement allows the rider, when passing the preceding vehicle, to shift the transmission to a shift-down state and to open the accelerator to accelerate, and after overtaking the target vehicle, to return the accelerator (decrease the accelerator opening), thereby automatically returning to each drive mode from the shift-down state. The return from the shift-down state is thus operatively connected to accelerator operation member <b>20</b> which is responsive to the rider's intension. This also has the advantage of removing the need for a switch operation and simplifying the equipment. The decrement of the accelerator opening may be set as appropriate.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">As an alternative, the shift-down cancel instruction may be issued according to various information during driving. For example, if sensor <b>25</b> for detecting the state of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> is a throttle opening sensor, the shift-down cancel instruction issued according to the state of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> is issued according to a throttle opening signal output from the throttle opening sensor. As another alternative, if sensor <b>25</b> is a vehicle speed sensor for detecting the speed of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b>, the shift-down cancel instruction issued according to the state (or the driving state) of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> may be issued when the vehicle speed is a predetermined level or less.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In this case, the canceling conditions of first setting section <b>16</b> to cancel the shift-down state may include detection of a predetermined throttle opening signal and detection of a vehicle speed lower than a predetermined speed at which the shift-down state is to be canceled.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> may include a shift-down cancel switch (shift-down cancel SW) <b>41</b> as a shift-down cancel operation member, and the conditions to cancel the shift-down state set in first setting section <b>16</b> may include a predetermined operation of shift-down cancel switch <b>41</b>. In this case, third control <b>13</b> is executed according to the operation of shift-down cancel switch <b>41</b> set in first setting section <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">This structure allows a method of returning to each drive mode according to the rider's intention (arrows S<b>55</b> and S<b>56</b>) when a cancel button is pressed in conjunction with automatic return to the drive mode using various information during driving. That is, a shift-down cancel switch (for example, a shift-down cancel button) may be used as a shift-down cancel operation member <b>41</b> for issuing a shift-down cancel instruction to thereby return to each drive mode.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Not only automatic return to the drive mode using accelerator operation member <b>20</b>, but also return to the drive mode using the cancel button, can be made. This arrangement ensures return to each drive mode by a simple operation, facilitating reflecting rider's intention.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The shift-down cancel switch of this embodiment may double as a mode-selection operation member (for example, mode selector SW <b>30</b>). In other words, mode selector SW <b>30</b> may be used both as a shift-down cancel switch (for example, a shift-down cancel button), thereby allowing control, not in a shift-down state, to switch between the drive modes, and in a shift-down state, to return to each drive mode. That is, when straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> is in a shift-down state, the common button can work as shift-down cancel switch <b>41</b>, and when it is not in a shift-down state, the common button can work as mode selector switch <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The shared use of the shift-down cancel switch and mode selector SW <b>30</b> allows switching of drive modes and cancel from a shift-down state to be made with one switch. This simplifies the structure around the switch and prevents complication of the switching operation. The structure simplifies the equipment, offering the advantage of reducing the cost for the switches.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As an alternative, shift-down cancel switch <b>41</b> may double as shift-down operation member <b>40</b>. For example, the first pressure of shift-down operation member <b>40</b> may enable shift to a shift-down state, and the second pressure may enable return to each drive mode. As another alternative, the difference in function between shift-down operation member <b>40</b> and shift-down cancel operation member <b>41</b> may be provided by a difference in the way of pressing button <b>40</b> (for example, press and hold or continuous press of two or more times).</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Another embodiment of the invention is now described. This embodiment is a modification of the control unit of the straddle-type vehicle according to the above-described embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In this embodiment, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref>, control unit <b>10</b> has a plurality of drive modes A, B, and C and a pseudo-manual mode D. Control unit <b>10</b> executes first control <b>11</b> of switching among drive modes A, B, and C. Control unit <b>10</b> further executes second control <b>12</b> of shifting the change gear to a shift-down state in all drive modes A, B, and C. Control unit <b>10</b> includes a second setting section <b>17</b> for setting conditions for shifting to pseudo-manual mode D. Control unit <b>10</b> executes fourth control <b>14</b> of shifting to pseudo-manual mode D in at least one drive mode C of drive modes A, B, and C according to the predetermined conditions set in second setting section <b>17</b>. In this embodiment, control unit <b>10</b> is configured to execute the fourth control according to operation of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> to increase the accelerator opening in a moment.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">A straddle-type vehicle <b>200</b> according to this embodiment is different from straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> in that it has not only normal mode A and assist I mode B but also an assist II mode C.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The continuously variable transmission of straddle-type vehicle <b>200</b> has three drive modes (normal mode A, assist I mode B, and assist II mode C). Added assist II mode C principally has the same speed-change characteristics as those of assist I mode B, and can be shifted to a pseudo-manual mode D under predetermined conditions in which the output performance of the engine or the like is given the highest priority. In other words, the difference between assist II mode C and assist I mode B depends on whether shift to pseudo-manual mode D is permitted. &#x201c;Pseudo-manual&#x201d; means gear change that provides continuous acceleration with the fixed speed change ratio as in a manual transmission (MT) even in an automatic transmission (AT).</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">Control unit <b>10</b> of straddle-type vehicle <b>200</b> executes control to shift assist II mode C to pseudo-manual mode D, that is, to shift the speed change ratio so that engine output becomes close to maximum according to an acceleration position signal indicative of an instantaneous increase in the accelerator opening of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> (arrow S<b>74</b>). In other words, control unit <b>10</b> can execute control to shift the transmission to pseudo-manual mode D when the rider opens accelerator operation member <b>20</b> rapidly.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Referring also to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the control to shift the transmission to pseudo-manual mode D will be described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a control map R(C) set for assist II mode C.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">As described above, assist II mode C principally has the same speed-change characteristics as those of assist I mode B. That is, control map R(C) for assist II mode is the same as that for assist I mode B.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">When the rider opens the accelerator rapidly (for example, turns the accelerator grip rapidly) during driving in assist II mode, control unit <b>10</b> shifts the speed change ratio of assist II mode C to a line R (pseudo-manual mode D) in the neighborhood of the upper limit P of engine speed with the fixed speed change ratio according to an accelerator position signal indicative an instantaneous increase in the accelerator opening of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> (arrow S<b>74</b>). In this embodiment, line R (pseudo-manual mode D) is set so as to fluctuate up and down (in zigzags) because acceleration is made while the stepped fixed speed change ratios are switched with changes in the vehicle speed on the horizontal axis. Pseudo-manual mode D is a drive mode in which the speed change ratio changes stepwise with the vehicle speed. In this embodiment, it is achieved by controlling continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> along line R set in control unit <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The upper limit P of engine speed is set to the vicinity of maximum engine output. Thus, engine output can be increased in a stroke to accelerate the vehicle rapidly by increasing engine speed to the vicinity of the upper limit P of engine speed. In addition, since acceleration is made while the stepped fixed speed change ratios are switched with changes in vehicle speed, as indicated by line R(D), acceleration as in an MT can be achieved in spite of an AT, providing the rider with comfortable acceleration. Moreover, since shift to pseudo-manual mode D can be operatively connected to accelerator operation member <b>20</b> that may reflect the rider's intention, there is no need to operate another switch, providing the advantage of simplifying the equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Instantaneous increment or decrement of accelerator opening can be determined from changes in accelerator opening. If accelerator operation member <b>20</b> is an accelerator grip, a change in accelerator opening is, for example, the rate of turn of the accelerator grip. Instantaneous increment in accelerator opening here may be set to a desired value as appropriate.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In this embodiment, the shift to pseudo-manual mode D is allowed also from a shift-down state C<b>1</b>. Specifically, the rider can shift the transmission to pseudo-manual mode D by shifting the transmission to shift-down state C<b>1</b> by pressing the SD button (arrow S<b>70</b>) and then opening the accelerator rapidly (arrow S<b>72</b>). This arrangement allows a rider to drive when approaching a curve, for example, in such a manner as to shift the transmission to shift-down state C<b>1</b> by pressing SD button <b>40</b>, and turn the curve slowly by engine braking, and then accelerate sharply by rapidly opening the accelerator in pseudo-manual mode D.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The shift to pseudo-manual mode D may be executed according to the rider's intention (for example, with another pseudo-manual operation member <b>31</b> or another operation member) irrespective of the state of accelerator operation member <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">Pseudo-manual mode D may be canceled according to conditions set in a third setting section <b>18</b> provided in control unit <b>10</b>, in which conditions for canceling pseudo-manual mode D are preset. The conditions for canceling pseudo-manual mode D may be the same as those for canceling a shift-down state described above. That is, control unit <b>10</b> can cancel pseudo-manual mode D according to the cancel conditions preset in first setting section <b>16</b>. When canceling pseudo-manual mode D, for example, control unit <b>10</b> may issue a pseudo-manual cancel instruction according to the state of straddle-type vehicle <b>200</b>, thereby canceling the pseudo-manual state to return to assist II mode C (arrow S<b>75</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Another example of the conditions for canceling pseudo-manual mode D is a state in which the rider has closed accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. In this case, the pseudo-manual cancel instruction is issued according to an accelerator position signal indicative of a decrease in the accelerator opening of accelerator operation member <b>20</b>. The decrement of the accelerator opening may be set to a desired value as appropriate.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">A pseudo-manual cancel operation member <b>32</b> for canceling pseudo-manual mode D may be provided separately. In this case, pseudo-manual mode D can be canceled when the rider presses the pseudo-manual cancel button. When pseudo-manual mode D is canceled, the change gear may be returned to assist II mode (C) as shown by arrow S<b>76</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, for example. The conditions for canceling pseudo-manual mode D may be a combination of automatic cancel by a predetermined operation of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> and manual cancel by pseudo-manual cancel operation member <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Although the embodiment takes an example of shifting from assist II mode C to pseudo-manual mode D, the invention is not limited to that; control unit <b>10</b> may shift the transmission from at least one of the plurality of drive modes to pseudo-manual mode D. Thus, control to shift from normal mode A to pseudo-manual mode D is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">In this example, three drive modes A, B, and C are set. The rider can switch among drive modes A, B, and C in sequence by operating mode selector SW <b>30</b> (arrow S<b>50</b>(<b>1</b>) to arrow S<b>50</b>(<b>3</b>)). The rider can also shift the transmission from assist II mode C to shift-down state C<b>1</b> according to operation of shift-down operation member <b>40</b> (arrow S<b>70</b>), or may cancel shift-down state C<b>1</b> according to the state of accelerator operation member <b>20</b> and/or the pressure of the shift-down cancel switch (arrows S<b>77</b> and S<b>78</b>). That is, the rider can shift the transmission from all three drive modes to a shift-down state.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">As shown in this example, the arrangement in which the transmission can be shifted from all of the drive modes to a shift-down state allows rapid acceleration any time irrespective of a selected drive mode, further increasing the rider's comfort during driving. However, in this invention, the transmission may be shifted to a shift-down state from at least two of the drive modes, and a drive mode that cannot shift to a shift-down state may be included. For example, it is also possible to arrange to shift from four of the five drive modes to a shift-down state.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the arrangement of continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> is described. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> includes V-belt type continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> as a transmission mechanism for transmitting power from engine <b>80</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">V-belt type continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> has a structure in which a primary sheave <b>62</b> is connected to a primary shaft <b>102</b> (for example, a crankshaft) rotated by engine <b>80</b>, a secondary sheave <b>63</b> is connected to a secondary shaft <b>103</b> which outputs power to a rear wheel <b>82</b> (driving wheel) via a centrifugal clutch <b>65</b> and a reduction mechanism <b>66</b>, and a V-belt <b>64</b> is stretched between primary sheave <b>62</b> and secondary sheave <b>63</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">Primary sheave <b>62</b> includes a fixed sheave <b>62</b>A and a moving sheave <b>62</b>B, and secondary sheave <b>63</b> includes a fixed sheave <b>63</b>A and a moving sheave <b>63</b>B. Between fixed sheave <b>62</b>A and moving sheave <b>62</b>B and between fixed sheave <b>63</b>A and moving sheave <b>63</b>B are each formed a V-groove around which V-belt <b>64</b> is wound. The driving force of engine <b>80</b> is converted to rotating force for V-belt <b>64</b> by primary sheave <b>62</b>, and the rotating force of V-belt <b>64</b> is transferred to rear wheel <b>82</b> via secondary sheave <b>63</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">V-belt type continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> electrically moves moving sheave <b>62</b>B of primary sheave <b>62</b> along the axis to adjust the width of the V-groove, so that the winding diameters of V-belt <b>64</b> around pulleys <b>62</b> and <b>63</b> change. Thus, the speed change ratio is controlled in a stepless manner between pulleys <b>62</b> and <b>63</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> includes a sheave-position moving device (mainly composed of an electric motor) <b>67</b> for controlling the position of moving sheave <b>62</b>B of primary sheave <b>62</b> and a sheave-position detecting device (corresponding to a mechanism for detecting an actual speed change ratio) <b>68</b> for detecting the position of moving sheave <b>62</b>B. Moving sheave <b>62</b>B is moved by sheave-position moving device <b>67</b> on the basis of the sheave position detected by sheave-position detecting device <b>68</b> to change the winding diameter of V-belt <b>64</b> wound around primary sheave <b>62</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">This embodiment includes, as a sensor for detecting the speed of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b>, a secondary-sheave speed sensor <b>69</b> for detecting rotation of secondary sheave <b>63</b> upstream from centrifugal clutch <b>65</b> and a speed sensor <b>86</b> located downstream from centrifugal clutch <b>65</b> and in the vicinity of rear wheel <b>82</b>, for directly detecting the speed of rear wheel <b>82</b>. Secondary-sheave speed sensor <b>69</b> and rear-wheel speed sensor <b>86</b> detect speed signals proportional to vehicle speed, respectively. Straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> may have only one of the sensors.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b> of this embodiment has speed-change-ratio control unit (control unit) <b>10</b> for controlling the speed change ratio of continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> as a central element of the control system.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Speed-change-ratio control unit <b>10</b> is mainly composed of a microcomputer, to which an acceleration position signal output from acceleration-position sensor <b>22</b>, a speed signal output from sheave speed sensor <b>69</b> or rear-wheel speed sensor <b>86</b>, an engine speed signal output from an engine-speed sensor <b>81</b> for detecting the rotation speed of engine <b>80</b>, a throttle-opening signal output from a throttle opening sensor (not shown), a sheave-position signal output from sheave-position detecting device <b>68</b>, a main switch signal of a main switch for turning on/off the power system of the whole vehicle, and the like are input.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">Control unit <b>10</b> controls engine <b>80</b> and the whole continuously variable transmission <b>60</b> according to the above various signals. Specifically, control unit <b>10</b> determines a target speed change ratio by calculating the vehicle speed and acceleration on the basis of the throttle-opening signal, the secondary-sheave speed, driving-wheel speed signal, the sheave-position signal and the like. Control unit <b>10</b> executes a so-called speed change control, or controlling the position of moving sheave <b>62</b>B of primary sheave <b>62</b> by driving sheave-position moving device <b>67</b> to achieve the target speed change ratio, thereby controlling the actual speed change ratio of straddle-type vehicle <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The structure of the continuously variable transmission is not limited to the foregoing embodiments and may be applied to various continuously variable transmissions having a form in which a V-belt is wound around a primary sheave and a secondary sheave and in which the groove width of the primary sheave can be adjusted by a sheave-position moving device and a control unit.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, a continuously variable transmission having a metal V-belt may be employed. The components and parts in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> that provide the same operations as those of the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> are given the same reference numerals.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">In this embodiment, continuously variable transmission <b>260</b> having a metal V-belt (hereinafter, referred to as a metal-belt CVT as appropriate) is modified variously in addition to metal V-belt <b>264</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">Metal-belt CVT <b>260</b> includes a clutch <b>265</b>, a primary rotation sensor <b>268</b>, hydraulic cylinders <b>267</b>A and <b>267</b>B, and a hydraulic control valve <b>267</b>C.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">Clutch <b>265</b> is disposed between the output shaft of engine <b>80</b> and the input shaft of metal-belt CVT <b>260</b>. Clutch <b>265</b> connects and disconnects transfer of power between the output shaft of engine <b>80</b> and the input shaft of metal-belt CVT <b>260</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">Primary rotation sensor <b>268</b> detects the rotation speed of a primary sheave <b>262</b>. In this embodiment, control unit <b>10</b> calculates the speed change ratio of continuously variable transmission <b>260</b> from the ratio of the rotation speed of primary sheave <b>262</b> detected by primary rotation sensor <b>268</b> to the vehicle speed of the straddle-type vehicle detected by vehicle speed sensor (the rear-wheel speed sensor in the drawing) <b>86</b>. The speed change ratio of continuously variable transmission <b>260</b> may be calculated from the ratio of the rotation speed of primary sheave <b>262</b> detected by primary rotation sensor <b>268</b> to the rotation speed of a secondary sheave <b>263</b> detected by secondary-sheave speed sensor <b>69</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">Hydraulic cylinder <b>267</b>A adjusts the groove width of primary sheave <b>262</b> by applying pressure to a moving flange <b>262</b>B of primary sheave <b>262</b>. Hydraulic cylinder <b>267</b>B adjusts the groove width of secondary sheave <b>263</b> by applying pressure to a moving flange <b>263</b>B of secondary sheave <b>263</b>. Hydraulic control valve <b>267</b>C is a valve for adjusting the oil pressure to be applied to hydraulic cylinders <b>267</b>A and <b>267</b>B. When increasing the oil pressure of one of hydraulic cylinders <b>267</b>A and <b>267</b>B, hydraulic control valve <b>267</b>C controls the oil pressure of the other of hydraulic cylinders <b>267</b>A and <b>267</b>B to be decreased. Hydraulic control valve <b>267</b>C is controlled by control unit <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">The speed change ratio of metal-belt CVT <b>260</b> is changed by operating hydraulic control valve <b>267</b>C with control unit <b>10</b>. Control of control unit <b>10</b> is similar to that of continuously variable transmission <b>60</b>. Control unit <b>10</b> of metal-belt CVT <b>260</b> according to this embodiment uses the rotation speed of primary sheave <b>262</b> as the target value for control in place of the engine speed.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">Although motorcycle <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a scooter-type motorcycle, the invention is not limited to that but may be applied to a motorcycle equipped with a control unit that electronically controls the gear change of a continuously variable transmission. The &#x201c;motorcycle&#x201d; of this specification includes, for example, a motorbike and a scooter. More generally, it includes any vehicle that can be turned with the body tilted. It can thus include tricycles and four-wheel cars (or more) in which the number of tires of at least one of front and rear wheels is two or more. The invention can be applied not only to motorcycles but also to other vehicles that can make use of the advantages of the invention; for example, so-called straddle-type vehicles including four-wheel buggies (all terrain vehicles (ATVs)) and snowmobiles. In the case of four-wheel buggies, the accelerator operation member may have, in addition to the shape of an accelerator grip, the shape of a lever. In addition, although an internal combustion engine is used as driving source <b>80</b>, a straddle-type vehicle that uses a motor as driving source <b>80</b> may be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">While the invention has been described with reference to preferred embodiments, it should be understood that the invention is not limited to the description and that various modifications may be made.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">According to the invention, a straddle-type vehicle is provided that can be accelerated rapidly by a simple operation irrespective of a selected drive mode.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A straddle-type vehicle comprising:
<claim-text>a driving source whose output is controlled by an accelerator operation member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a continuously variable transmission connected to the driving source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit for controlling the continuously variable transmission;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift-down operation member, wherein
<claim-text>the control unit has a plurality of drive modes and executes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first control of switching among the plurality of drive modes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control of shifting, in at least two of the plurality of drive modes, a change gear to a shift-down state in which a speed change ratio is lower than that of each drive mode, according to operation of the shift-down operation member, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit comprises a first setting section for setting cancel conditions for canceling the shift-down state, and executes third control of canceling the shift-down state according to the cancel conditions set by the first setting section to return to the drive mode before shifting to the shift-down state;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift-down cancel operation member, wherein
<claim-text>a predetermined operation of the shift-down cancel operation member is set in the first setting section as the cancel conditions for canceling the shift-down state, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third control is executed according to operation of the shift-down cancel operation member set in the first setting section; and</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mode-selection operation member for switching among the plurality of drive modes, wherein
<claim-text>the first control is executed according to operation of the mode-selection operation member, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the shift-down cancel operation member and the mode-selection operation member are composed of one button.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The straddle-type vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a mode-selection operation member for switching among the plurality of drive modes, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first control is executed according to operation of the mode-selection operation member.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The straddle-type vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a predetermined operation of the accelerator operation member is set in the first setting section as the cancel conditions for canceling the shift-down state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third control is executed according to operation of the accelerator operation member set in the first setting section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The straddle-type vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the third control is executed according to operation of the accelerator operation member to decrease the accelerator opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The straddle-type vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second control can be executed in all of the drive modes set in the control unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The straddle-type vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>the control unit has a pseudo-manual mode to change the speed change ratio of the continuously variable transmission stepwise with a vehicle speed; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit includes a second setting section for setting conditions for shifting to the pseudo-manual mode, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit executes fourth control of shifting at least one of the plurality of drive modes to the pseudo-manual mode according to predetermined conditions set in the second setting section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The straddle-type vehicle according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein a predetermined operation to increase the accelerator opening momentarily is set in the second setting section as the conditions for shifting to the pseudo-manual mode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A continuously variable transmission controlled by a control unit, wherein the control unit has a plurality of drive modes and executes:
<claim-text>a first control of switching among the plurality of drive modes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control of shifting, in at least two of the plurality of drive modes, a change gear to a shift-down state in which a speed change ratio is lower than that of each drive mode, according to operation of the shift-down operation member, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit has a pseudo-manual mode to change the speed change ratio of the continuously variable transmission stepwise with a vehicle speed,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit includes a second setting section for setting conditions for shifting to the pseudo-manual mode, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control unit executes fourth control of shifting from the shift-down state to the pseudo-manual mode according to predetermined conditions set in the second setting section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the first control is executed according to operation of the mode-selection operation member.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the control unit comprises a first setting section for setting cancel conditions for canceling the shift-down state, and executes third control of canceling the shift-down state according to the cancel conditions set by the first setting section to return to the drive mode before shifting to the shift-down state.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a predetermined operation of the accelerator operation member is set in the first setting section as the cancel conditions for canceling the shift-down state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third control is executed according to operation of the accelerator operation member set in the first setting section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the third control is executed according to operation of the accelerator operation member to decrease an accelerator opening.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein
<claim-text>a predetermined operation of the shift-down cancel operation member is set in the first setting section as the cancel conditions for canceling the shift-down state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third control is executed according to operation of the shift-down cancel operation member set in the first setting section.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second control can be executed in all of the drive modes set in the control unit.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The continuously variable transmission according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein a predetermined operation to increase an accelerator opening momentarily is set in the second setting section as the conditions for shifting to the pseudo-manual mode.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A straddle-type vehicle comprising:
<claim-text>a driving source whose output is controlled by an accelerator operation member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a continuously variable transmission connected to the driving source;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control unit for controlling the continuously variable transmission;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift-down operation member, wherein
<claim-text>the control unit has a plurality of drive modes and executes:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first control of switching among the plurality of drive modes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second control of shifting, in at least two of the plurality of drive modes, a change gear to a shift-down state in which a speed change ratio is lower than that of each drive mode, according to operation of the shift-down operation member;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shift-down cancel operation member for canceling the shift-down state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mode-selection operation member for switching among the plurality of drive modes,
<claim-text>wherein the shift-down cancel operation member and the mode-selection operation member are composed of one button.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
