<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640958-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640958</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11631418</doc-number>
<date>20050303</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2004-194030</doc-number>
<date>20040630</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>366</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>15</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>152539</main-classification>
<further-classification>152546</further-classification>
<further-classification>152552</further-classification>
<further-classification>152554</further-classification>
<further-classification>152555</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Pneumatic tire</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6923234</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bestgen et al.</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>152543</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>59-145607</doc-number>
<date>19840800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>62-251202</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19871100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>64-067405</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19890300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>04372403</doc-number>
<date>19921200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>6-247103</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19940900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>10-250321</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-047820</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20010200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-079813</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2002-536225</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20021000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-231405</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2003-237322</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 00/46047</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO 02/096675</doc-number>
<date>20021200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080302459</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081211</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kouno</last-name>
<first-name>Yoshihide</first-name>
<address>
<city>Kunitachi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sughrue Mion, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Bridgestone Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Fischer</last-name>
<first-name>Justin</first-name>
<department>1791</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2005/003647</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20050303</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20070103</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2006/003742</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20060112</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A pneumatic tire (<b>10</b>) according to the present invention includes a first side reinforcement layer (<b>110</b>) and a second side reinforcement layer (<b>120</b>). The first side reinforcement layer (<b>110</b>) has a plurality of reinforcement cords (<b>110</b><i>s</i>), and the second side reinforcement layer (<b>120</b>) has a plurality of reinforcement cords (<b>120</b><i>s</i>) each crossing the reinforcement cords (<b>110</b><i>s</i>). Additionally, an inclination angle of each of the reinforcement cords (<b>110</b><i>s</i>) and the reinforcement cords (<b>120</b><i>s</i>) with respect to a circumferential line extending in a circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire (<b>10</b>) is 5 to 30 degrees. According to the pneumatic tire (<b>10</b>), high speed durability thereof can be further enhanced without reducing wear life of a shoulder portion thereof.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="150.20mm" wi="210.14mm" file="US07640958-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="238.84mm" wi="177.63mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640958-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="215.98mm" wi="158.50mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640958-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="165.27mm" wi="96.18mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640958-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="139.45mm" wi="100.25mm" file="US07640958-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="204.30mm" wi="161.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07640958-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a pneumatic tire whose durability at the time of high-speed rotation is enhanced.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As a traveling speed of a vehicle has been becoming higher, durability of a pneumatic tire, which is mounted on the vehicle, and which is rotated at a high speed (hereinafter, high speed durability), has become more important than ever.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">As to methods of enhancing high speed durability of a pneumatic tire, various proposals have so far been made (such as Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication Nos. Sho 62-251202, Hei 6-247103 and 2003-231405).</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">For example, in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. Sho 62-251202, proposed is a method in which a ribbon-shaped layer member formed of cords made of polyamide-based organic fibers is provided all over the entire circumference of a shoulder portion of a pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">According to such a method, even in a case where a large centrifugal force occurs as the pneumatic tire is rotated at a high speed, a tread portion and the like of the pneumatic tire are restrained from expanding outward in a tire radial direction. For this reason, high speed durability of the pneumatic tire is enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">That is, generally, by increasing the number of layers each configured of a layer member provided to a shoulder portion is increased, the high speed durability itself can be further enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">On the other hand, in order to make a shape of the tread portion contacting with a road surface which is the same as that of a carcass line, it is necessary to keep a cross-sectional shape, in a tread width direction, of an outer surface of the tread portion contacting with a road surface to be the same as that of the carcass line. That is, there is the following problem. When the number of layers each configured of the layer member provided to a shoulder portion is increased, a tread gauge (the thickness of a tread rubber) of the shoulder portion becomes thinner than that of a center portion, and a wear life of the shoulder portion is reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The present invention was made in consideration of such a problem, and aims to provide a pneumatic tire whose high speed durability is further enhanced without reducing a wear life of a shoulder portion thereof.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In order to solve the above described problem, the present invention has the following characteristics. First of all, a first characteristic of the present invention is a pneumatic tire (a pneumatic tire <b>10</b>) having a side reinforcement layer (a side reinforcement layer <b>100</b>) provided in a side portion (side portion <b>26</b>) thereof. The first characteristic is as follows. The side reinforcement layer includes a first side reinforcement layer (a first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b>) and a second side reinforcement layer (a second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b>). The second side reinforcement layer includes an overlapping region (an overlapping region OL), and is provided outside the first side reinforcement layer in a tread width direction. The overlapping region overlaps the first side reinforcement layer in at least a part of a maximum-width portion (a portion, which extends outward in a tire radial direction by 10% of a carcass height H from a tire maximum-width position P, and which extends inward in the tire radial direction by 10% of the carcass height H from the tire maximum-width position P) of the pneumatic tire in the tread width direction. The first side reinforcement layer includes a plurality of first linear members (reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s</i>), and the second side reinforcement layer includes a plurality of second linear members (reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s</i>) each crossing the first linear members. An inclination angle (an inclination angle &#x3b8;) of each of the first and second linear members with respect to a circumferential line (a circumferential line L), which extends in a circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire, is 5 to 30 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to such a characteristic, since the side reinforcement layer composed of the first side reinforcement layer and the second side reinforcement layer is provided to the side portion, circumferential rigidity of the pneumatic tire is effectively enhanced. For this reason, a tread portion and the like of the pneumatic tire are restrained from expanding outward in the tire radial direction, and this makes it possible to enhance high speed durability of the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Furthermore, since the reinforcement layer is provided not to a tread portion side but to the side portion, the thinning of a tread gauge of a shoulder portion as compared with that of a center portion can be avoided. That is, according to such a characteristic, a pneumatic tire whose high speed durability is further enhanced without reducing a wear life of the shoulder portion can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">A second characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to the first characteristic of the present invention. The second characteristic is that the inclination angle is 5 to 20 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">A third characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first and second characteristics of the present invention. The third characteristic is that an overlapping width (an overlapping width B) which is a width of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction is equal to 10 to 50% of the carcass height H which is a height from a corresponding bead portion (a bead portion <b>23</b>) of the pneumatic tire to an end of a carcass layer (a carcass layer <b>22</b>) on the side of the tread portion (tread portion <b>21</b>) of the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A fourth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to the third characteristic of the present invention, and the fourth characteristic is that the overlapping width is equal to 10 to 30% of the carcass height.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A fifth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to fourth characteristics of the present invention. The fifth characteristic is that a folded-back end portion (a folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>e</i>) of the carcass layer of the pneumatic tire has a length which does not cause the folded-back end portion to overlap an inner end portion (a lower end portion <b>120</b><i>b</i>) of the second side reinforcement layer in the tire radial direction, the folded-back end portion being formed by folding back the carcass layer around a bead portion.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A sixth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to fifth characteristics of the present invention. The sixth characteristic is that, in the tire radial direction, a position of the folded-back end portion (the folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>e</i>) of the carcass layer of the pneumatic tire is different from those of an inner end portion of the first and the inner end portion of the second reinforcement layers (the lower end portions <b>110</b><i>b </i>and <b>120</b><i>b</i>) in the tire radial direction, respectively, the folded-back end portion being formed by folding back the carcass layer around the bead portion of the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">A seventh characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to sixth characteristics of the present invention. The seventh characteristic is that an outer end portion intersection angle (&#x3b1;) is at least 3 degrees larger than an inner end portion intersection angle &#x3b2;. The outer end portion intersection angle (&#x3b1;) is an intersection angle on an outer side in the tire radial direction, which is formed by each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members in an outer end portion (a radially outer end portion Et) of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction. The inner end portion intersection angle (&#x3b2;) is an intersection angle on an inner side in the tire radial direction, which is formed by each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members in an inner end portion (a radially inner end portion Eb) of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">An eighth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to seventh characteristics of the present invention. The eighth characteristic is that an inner end portion arrangement distance (d<b>2</b>) is larger than an outer end portion arrangement distance (d<b>1</b>). The inner end portion arrangement distance (d<b>2</b>) is an arrangement distance in the tread width direction between each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members, in the end portion (the radially inner end portion Eb) of the overlapping region on the inner side in the tire radial direction. The outer end portion arrangement distance (d<b>1</b>) is an arrangement distance in the tread width direction between the first linear members and the second linear members in an end portion (the radially outer end portion Et) of the overlapping region on the outer side in the tire radial direction.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A ninth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to the eighth characteristic of the present invention. The ninth characteristic is that the inner end portion arrangement distance (d<b>2</b>) is larger than the outer end portion arrangement distance (d<b>1</b>) by 0.1 to 1 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A tenth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to ninth characteristics of the present invention. The tenth characteristic is that the overlapping width which is the width of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction is not more than 80 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">An eleventh characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to tenth characteristics of the present invention. The eleventh characteristic is that the first linear members or the second linear members are formed of steel monofilaments or steel cords.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A twelfth characteristic of the present invention is the pneumatic tire according to any one of the first to eleventh characteristics of the present invention. The twelfth characteristic is that the first linear members or the second linear members are formed of predetermined highly elastic organic fiber cords.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a partially disassembled perspective view of a pneumatic tire according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view of the pneumatic tire according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view of an overlapping region as viewed in a direction indicated by an arrow F<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partially enlarged view in a cross section of side reinforcement layers in a widthwise-direction of a tread of the tire according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view of a pneumatic tire according to a modification example of the present invention in the widthwise direction of the tread of the tire.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="h-0006" num="0000">(Composition of Pneumatic Tire according to the Present Embodiment)</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Next, a pneumatic tire according to an embodiment of the present invention will be described with reference to the drawings. Note that, in the following explanations on the drawings, the same and similar reference numerals are given to the same and similar elements. However, the drawings are schematic, and it should be noted that a ratio and the like of each of dimensions are not to scale.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">For this reason, specific sizes and the like should be judged in consideration of the following descriptions. Additionally, it goes without saying that, also between the drawings, there are contained parts between which dimensional relation and ratio are different.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a partially disassembled perspective view of a pneumatic tire <b>10</b> according to the present embodiment. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> includes a carcass layer <b>22</b> which forms a skeletal structure of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The carcass layer <b>22</b> is supported by a pair of bead portions <b>23</b> abutting a rim wheel (not illustrated). Additionally, to outer sides of the respective bead portions <b>23</b> in a tire radial direction, rim guards <b>27</b> which protect corresponding rim flange portions of the rim wheel (not illustrated) are provided respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">To the outer side of the carcass layer <b>22</b> in the tire radial direction, a crossing belt layer <b>24</b> composed of a first belt layer <b>24</b><i>a </i>and a second belt layer <b>24</b><i>b</i>, which are formed by rubberizing steel cords, is provided. The steel cords composing the first belt layer <b>24</b><i>a </i>and the second belt layer <b>24</b><i>b </i>are arranged in a manner that each of the steel cords has a predetermined angle (&#xb1;28 degrees in the present embodiment) with respect to a tire equator line CL.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">To the outer side of the crossing belt layer <b>24</b> in the tire radial direction, a cap-and-layer layer <b>25</b> composed of a cap layer <b>25</b><i>a </i>and cap layers <b>25</b><i>b </i>is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The cap layer <b>25</b><i>a </i>is located on the outer side of the crossing belt layer <b>24</b> in the tire radial direction, and is formed by rubberizing organic fiber cords (nylon cords in the present embodiment) aligned substantially in parallel to the tire equator line CL. The cap layer <b>25</b><i>a </i>has a width not less than the entire width of the crossing belt layer <b>24</b>, and reinforces the crossing belt layer <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The cap layers <b>25</b><i>b </i>are also located on the outer side of the crossing belt layer <b>24</b> in the tire radial direction, are also formed by rubberizing organic fiber cords (nylon cords in the present embodiment) aligned substantially in parallel to the tire equator line CL, and are arranged in a manner that the cap layers <b>25</b><i>b </i>cover both end portions of the crossing belt layer <b>24</b>, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">To the outer side of the cap-and-layer layer <b>25</b> in the tire radial direction, a tread portion <b>21</b> which makes contact with a road surface is provided.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> are provided respectively to side portions <b>26</b> of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>. The side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> are provided for the purpose of enhancing durability in a case where the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is rotated at a high speed (high speed durability), which is specifically rigidity in a circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Each of the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> includes a first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b> and a second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b>. In the present embodiment, each of the first side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> is located outside the carcass layer <b>22</b> in the tread width direction, and abuts the carcass layer <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Each of the second side reinforcement layers <b>120</b> has an overlapping region OL, which overlaps the corresponding first side reinforcement later <b>110</b> in a tire maximum-width position P (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>), and is provided more outside the carcass layer <b>22</b> in the tread width direction than the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Additionally, each of the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b> is formed by rubberizing a plurality of reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>(first linear members). Each of the second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b> is formed by rubberizing a plurality of reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>(second linear members) crossing the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s. </i></p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In the present embodiment, the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>and the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>are formed of steel cords. Note that, the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>or the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>may be formed of steel monofilaments. Otherwise, the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>or the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>may be formed of predetermined highly elastic organic fiber cords such as Kevlar, carbon fiber or polyketone.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> in the tread width direction. As has been described above, the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> are provided respectively to the side portions <b>26</b> of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Specifically, each of the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> is provided to a &#x201c;tire maximum-width portion&#x201d; on the corresponding side portion <b>26</b>. Here, the tire maximum-width portion is a portion, which extends outward in the tire radial direction from a tire maximum-width position P by 10% of the height H of the carcass, and which extends inward in the tire radial direction from the tire maximum-width position P by 10% of the height H of the carcass. The tire maximum-width position P is a position corresponding to the maximum-width Wmax of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>. Note that the rim guards <b>27</b> protruding in the tread width direction are not included in the tire maximum-width Wmax.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Additionally, as has been described above, each of the second side reinforcement layers <b>120</b> has the overlapping region OL which overlaps corresponding one of the first reinforcement layers <b>110</b> in at least a part of the tire maximum-width portion.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">It is preferable that an overlapping width B (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) which is a width of the overlapping region OL in the tire radial direction be equal to 10 to 50% of the carcass height H which is a height from the bead portion <b>23</b> to an end of the carcass layer <b>22</b> in a tread portion side thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Note that, from the viewpoint of further restraining interlaminar shear strain occurring between the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b> and the second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b>, or between the carcass layer <b>22</b> and the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b>, it is more preferable that the overlapping width B be equal to 10 to 30% of the carcass height H.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">In the present embodiment, folded-back end portions <b>22</b><i>e </i>of the carcass layer <b>22</b>, which are formed by folding back the carcass layer <b>22</b> respectively around the bead portions <b>23</b> (each including a bead core <b>23</b><i>a </i>and a bead filler <b>23</b><i>b</i>), are located more inside in the tire radial direction than end portions in the tire radial direction of the respective side reinforcement layers <b>100</b>, the end portions being specifically lower end portions <b>120</b><i>b </i>of the respective second side reinforcement layers <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0007" num="0000">(Detailed Configuration of Overlapping Region)</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Next, a detailed configuration of the overlapping region OL will be described. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a view of the overlapping region OL as viewed the overlapping region OL in a direction indicated by an arrow F<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an inclination angle &#x3b8; of the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>(the first linear members) and the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>(the second linear members) with respect to a circumferential line L extending along the circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is set at 5 to 30 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Note that it is preferable, from the viewpoint of effectively further enhancing the circumferential rigidity of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>, that the inclination angle &#x3b8; be 5 to 20 degrees.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Here, in a radially outer end portion Et which is an end portion of the overlapping region OL on the outer side in the tire radial direction, an intersection angle formed by each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members on the outer side in the tire radial direction is represented as an outer end portion intersection angle &#x3b1;. Additionally, in a radially inner end portion Eb which is an end portion of the overlapping region on the inner side in the tire radial direction, an intersection angle formed by each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members on the inner side in the tire radial direction is represented as an inner end portion intersection angle &#x3b2;.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">It is preferable that the outer end portion intersection angle &#x3b1; be set at not less than 3 degrees larger than the inner end portion intersection angle &#x3b2;.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Additionally, it is preferable that the overlapping width B which is a width of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction be set at not more than 80 mm. Note that it is more preferable, from the viewpoint of further restraining interlaminar shear strain at the same time as enhancing the circumferential rigidity by the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> (the first reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and the second reinforcement layers <b>120</b>), that the overlapping width B be not more than 50 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">Note that, as a method of composing the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> in which the outer end portion intersection angle &#x3b1; and the inner end portion intersection angle &#x3b2; are different from each other, the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>are curved in a predetermined direction by slightly twisting upper and lower ends of the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b> (a rubberized layer) in which the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>are aligned at a substantially equal interval.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Likewise, by slightly twisting upper and lower ends of the second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b> (a rubberized layer) in which the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>are aligned at a substantially equal interval, the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>are curved in a direction opposite to the direction in which the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>are curved. By such a method as this, the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> can be composed.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partially enlarged view of the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> in a cross section in the tread width direction. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an arrangement distance in the tread width direction from the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>to the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>in the radially inner end portion Eb is represented as an inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b>. Additionally, an arrangement distance in the tread width direction from the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>to the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s </i>in the radially outer end portion Et is represented as an outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">It is preferable that the inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b> be set larger than the outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b> (d<b>2</b>&#x3e;d<b>1</b>). Note that it is more preferable, from the perspective of restraining interlaminar shear strain, which occurs between each of the first side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and each of the second side reinforcement layers <b>120</b>, and a temperature increase in the side portions <b>26</b>, the inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b> be larger by a range of 0.1 to 1 mm than the outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="h-0008" num="0000">(Comparative Assessment)</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">Next, a description will be given of comparative assessment results with respect to pneumatic tires (hereinafter, Examples) according to the present embodiment, and pneumatic tires (hereinafter, Comparative Examples) prepared so as to be compared with the pneumatic tires according to Examples.</p>
<p id="h-0009" num="0000">(1) Compositions of Pneumatic Tires Used for Comparative Assessment</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Compositions of the pneumatic tires according to Examples and Comparative Examples used for the comparative assessment have the following parts in common with one another:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0060">a tire size of 215/45R17;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0061">a belt layer composition composed of a first belt layer, a second belt layer and a cap-and-layer layer;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0062">a first belt layer composition having a steel cord formed as 1 (cord)*5 (number of twists)*0.225 mm (a filament diameter), a number of embedded cords being 36 cords/50 mm, a steel cord arrangement direction being inclined by +28 degrees (in a right direction in a tread plan view) with respect to a tire equator line, and a width being 170 mm;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0063">a second belt layer composition having steel cords each formed as 1 (cord)*5 (number of twists)*0.225 mm (a filament diameter), a number of embedded cords being 36 cords/50 mm, a steel cord arrangement direction being inclined by &#x2212;28 degrees (in a left direction in the tread plan view) with respect to a tire equator line, and a width being 150 mm;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0005" num="0064">a cap layer composition having a number of layers being 1, nylon cords each being 1260 d/2, a number of embedded cords being 50 cords/50 mm, and a width being 180 mm;</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0006" num="0065">a cap layer composition having a number of layers being 1, nylon cords each being 1260d/2, and a width being 30 mm; and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0007" num="0066">a carcass layer composition having PET cords each being 1500d/2, and a number of embedded cords being 50 cords/50 mm.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0067">Additionally, Table 1 shows: compositions of the side reinforcement layers provided to the pneumatic tires according to Example and Comparative Example used for comparative assessments; and results of a comparative assessment test.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0068">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="11">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="49pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="10" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="10" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>LINEAR</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>NUMBER</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>MEMBER</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>OF</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>TYPE OF</entry>
<entry>INCLINA-</entry>
<entry>AVERAGE</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>OVER-</entry>
<entry>EMBEDDED</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>SIDE</entry>
<entry>TION</entry>
<entry>INTER-</entry>
<entry>OVER-</entry>
<entry>LAPPING</entry>
<entry>CORDS</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>DURA-</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>REINFORCE-</entry>
<entry>ANGLE</entry>
<entry>SECTING</entry>
<entry>LAPPING</entry>
<entry>WIDTH</entry>
<entry>(CORDS/</entry>
<entry>&#x3b1; &#x2212;</entry>
<entry/>
<entry/>
<entry>BILITY</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>MENT LAYER</entry>
<entry>(&#x3b8;)</entry>
<entry>ANGLE</entry>
<entry>RATIO</entry>
<entry>(B)</entry>
<entry>50 mm)</entry>
<entry>&#x3b2;</entry>
<entry>d1</entry>
<entry>d2</entry>
<entry>LEVEL</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="10" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="13">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="49pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="63pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="6" colwidth="14pt" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="7" colwidth="21pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="8" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="9" colwidth="21pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="10" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="11" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="12" colwidth="21pt" align="right"/>
<colspec colname="13" colwidth="28pt" align="left"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>COMPARA-</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;0&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;0&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>226</entry>
<entry>km/h*<sup>1</sup></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>TIVE</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;5&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>266</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>266</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>40&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;5%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>258</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>30&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>60&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;5%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>COMPARA-</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>40&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>80&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;5%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>218</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>TIVE</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>&#x2002;5%</entry>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>10%</entry>
<entry>16</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>266</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>266</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>50%</entry>
<entry>40</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>258</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>60%</entry>
<entry>48</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.6 mm</entry>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>km/h*<sup>2</sup></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>36</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>2.0 mm</entry>
<entry>234</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>12</entry>
<entry>(1*5*0.225 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>STEEL FILAMENT</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>90</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.7 mm</entry>
<entry>266</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>13</entry>
<entry>(&#x3c6;0.21 mm)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>EXAMPLE</entry>
<entry>KEVLAR CORD</entry>
<entry>10&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>20&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>30%</entry>
<entry>24</entry>
<entry>mm</entry>
<entry>40</entry>
<entry>3&#xb0;</entry>
<entry>0.5 mm</entry>
<entry>0.7 mm</entry>
<entry>258</entry>
<entry>km/h</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>14</entry>
<entry>(1500 d/2)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="13" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="13" align="left" id="FOO-00001">*<sup>1</sup>CODE BREAKING UP OCCURRED IN THE CARCASS LAYER.</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="13" align="left" id="FOO-00002">*<sup>2</sup>SEPARATION OCCURRED IN THE RADIALLY INWARD END SECTION OF THE OVERLAPPING REGION(OL).</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="13" align="left" id="FOO-00003">Note that &#x201c;1*5*0.225 mm&#x201d; shown in &#x201c;Linear member type of side reinforcement layer&#x201d; represents 1 (cord)*5 (number of twists)*0.225 mm (a filament diameter) as in the cases with the above described first and second belt layers.</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
<br/>
(2) Method of Comparative Assessment Test
</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0069">The comparative assessment test was carried out with respect to the pneumatic tires shown in Table 1 by setting test conditions as follows:
<ul id="ul0003" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0003-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0004" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0004-0001" num="0070">a set internal pressure of 220 kPa; and</li>
        <li id="ul0004-0002" num="0071">a load of 4.7 kN.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0072">Each of the pneumatic tires set under the above described test conditions was rotated for 120 minutes at a speed of 81 km/h by using a drum testing machine having a diameter of 1.7 m. Thereafter, each of the pneumatic tires was left to stand for 3 hours at an ambient temperature of 38&#xb0; C.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0073">Subsequently, each of the pneumatic tires was rotated sequentially at speeds and time periods shown in Table 2, and the each pneumatic tire was rotated until a failure occurred in the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0074">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00002" num="00002">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="140pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" rowsep="1">TABLE 2</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>SPEED</entry>
<entry>TIME PERIOD</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>(km/h)</entry>
<entry>(MINUTES)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>121</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>130</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>140</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>145</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>153</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>161</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>169</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>177</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>185</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>194</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>202</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>210</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>218</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>226</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>234</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>242</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>250</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>258</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>266</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>274</entry>
<entry>30</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
<br/>
(3) Results of Comparative Assessment Test
</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0075">In a column for &#x201c;durability level&#x201d; in Table 1, speeds at which failures occurred respectively in the pneumatic tires subjected to the comparative assessment test. The failures of the pneumatic tires according to Examples and Comparative Examples were: so-called chunkout in which rubber forming a shoulder portion is torn off; cord breaking up (CBU) in the carcass layer <b>22</b>; and separation which occurred in the radially inner end portion Eb.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0076">As shown in Table 1, the pneumatic tires according to Comparative Examples had failures at speeds in a range of 218 to 226 km/h. On the other hand, the pneumatic tires according to Examples did not have failures until a speed of 234 km/h was reached. Furthermore, the pneumatic tires according to Examples 1, 2, 6, 7 and 13 did not have failures until a speed of 266 km/h was reached.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0077">Here, when considering causes to which the occurrence of separation of the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> is attributed, interlaminar shear strain in the radially inner end portion Eb can be pointed out first, as described above. In order to restrain the occurrence of interlaminar shear strain, increasing an interlayer gauge is simple and effective.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0078">Additionally, as another cause to which the occurrence of the separation is attributed, temperature increase in the side portions <b>26</b> in association with the rotation of the pneumatic tire at a high-speed can be pointed out. In particular, temperature increase in the side portions <b>26</b> in an inner side thereof in the tire radial direction, to each of which the bead filler <b>23</b><i>b </i>and the rim guard <b>27</b> are provided, is conspicuous.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0079">Accordingly, in the present embodiment, the inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b> is configured to be larger by a range of 0.1 to 1 mm than the outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b>, as described above. As can be seen from the results of the comparative assessment test (comparing Example 2 and Comparative Example 2) shown in Table 1, separation of the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> can be effectively restrained when the inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b> is larger than the outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b> by 0.1 mm.</p>
<p id="h-0010" num="0000">(Functions and Effects)</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0080">According to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> according to the above-described present embodiment, circumferential rigidity of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is effectively enhanced because the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> each composed of the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b> and the second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b> are provided respectively in the side portions <b>26</b>. For this reason, the tread portion <b>21</b> and the like of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> are restrained from expanding outward in the tire radial direction, and high speed durability of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0081">Furthermore, thinning of a tread gauge of the shoulder portion of the tread portion <b>21</b> as compared to a center portion thereof can be avoided because the reinforcement layers are provided not in the tread portion <b>21</b> side but in the respective side portions <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0082">Note that, as a method of enhancing circumferential rigidity, a method in which reinforcement cords are wound around in a circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0083">However, in this method, because an expansion rate of the pneumatic tire at the time of molding cannot be made larger, it is necessary to perform shaping on a shape of a green tire before vulcanization so that the shape can become the same as a shape thereof after the vulcanization. Furthermore, after the shaping has been performed on the green tire, the reinforcement cords (for example, steel cords) are wound around in the circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0084">For this reason, this method has a problem that steps and an operating time for manufacturing a pneumatic tire increase. However, the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> eliminates such a problem.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0085">According to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>, the inclination angle &#x3b8; of the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>(<b>120</b><i>s</i>) can be set at 5 to 30 degrees. Because the inclination angle &#x3b8; is set not less than 5 degrees, the generation of extreme rigidity unevenness in a vicinity of the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b>, in which vicinity the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> is not provided, can be avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0086">When it is supposed that the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>(<b>120</b><i>s</i>) are substantially perpendicular (that is, with the inclination angle &#x3b8; being set less than 5 degrees) to carcass cords (not illustrated) of the carcass layer <b>22</b>, a force in association with loaded deformation concentrates on the portion where the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> is not provided, due to the extreme rigidity unevenness between portions where the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> is provided and it is not provided. As a result, durability of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is reduced oppositely.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0087">Additionally, when the inclination angle &#x3b8; is made larger than 30 degrees, the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>(<b>120</b><i>s</i>) are faced excessively in the tire radial direction, and circumferential rigidity of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> cannot be effectively enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0088">According to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>, the overlapping width B can be set at 10 to 50% of the carcass height H. For this reason, a vicinity of the tire maximum-width portion, where a deformation amount in the circumferential direction is the largest, can be reliably reinforced.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0089">According to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>, the outer end portion intersection angle &#x3b1; can be made at least 3 degrees larger than the inner end portion intersection angle &#x3b2;. When the outer end portion intersection angle &#x3b1; is at least 3 degrees larger than the inner end portion intersection angle &#x3b2;, the inclination angle &#x3b8; in the radially outer end portion Et becomes closer to a state parallel to a circumferential line L<b>1</b>, and therefore, the circumferential rigidity of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is further enhanced.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0090">According to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>, the inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b> can be made larger than the outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b> by 0.1 to 1 mm. Interlaminar shear strain (separation) occurring between the first and second side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> can be effectively restrained.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0091">Note that, it is not preferable that the inner end portion arrangement distance d<b>2</b> is made larger than the outer end portion arrangement distance d<b>1</b> by more than 1 mm, because it leads to an increase in a total gauge in vicinities of the bead portions <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0092">According to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b>, the overlapping width B can be set at not more than 80 mm, or not more than 50 mm. Interlaminar shear strain (separation) occurring between the first and second side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> increases as the overlapping width B becomes larger. Consequently, by setting the overlapping width B at not less than 80 mm, more preferably, at not less than 50 mm, interlaminar shear strain occurring between the first and second side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> can be effectively restrained.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">Other Embodiments</heading>
<p id="p-0085" num="0093">Although contents of the present invention have been disclosed by way of one embodiment of the present invention as has been described hereinabove, it should not be understood that any statement or any drawing composing a part of this disclosure limits the present invention. Based on this disclosure, various alternative embodiments, examples and operational techniques will be apparent to those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0094">For example, the pneumatic tire according to the present invention can be modified in the following manner. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view in a tread width direction of a pneumatic tire <b>10</b><i>v </i>according to a modification example of the present invention. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, side reinforcement layers <b>100</b><i>v </i>are provided to the pneumatic tire <b>10</b><i>v</i>. Each of the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b><i>v </i>includes the first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b><i>v </i>and the second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b><i>v </i>as in the case with the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> provided to the above described pneumatic tire <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0095">The side reinforcement layers <b>100</b><i>v </i>are different from the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> provided to the above described pneumatic tire <b>10</b> in how each of the first side reinforcement layers <b>110</b><i>v </i>and the corresponding second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b><i>v </i>overlap each other, and are different in a position of each folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>ve </i>of a carcass layer <b>22</b><i>v. </i></p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0096">Specifically, each of the folded-back end portions <b>22</b><i>ve </i>has a length which does not cause the folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>ve </i>to overlap a lower end portion <b>120</b><i>b </i>which is an end portion in the tire radial direction of the second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b><i>v</i>. That is, a gap G is provided between the folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>ve </i>and the lower end portion <b>120</b><i>b</i>. Moreover, each of the first side reinforcement layers <b>110</b><i>v </i>is longer than the corresponding second side reinforcement layer <b>120</b><i>v</i>, and the entirety of each of the second side reinforcement layers <b>120</b><i>v </i>overlaps the corresponding first side reinforcement layer <b>110</b><i>v. </i></p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0097">Additionally, the position of each of the folded-back end portions <b>22</b><i>e </i>is different, in the tire radial direction, from inner end portions in the tire radial direction (a lower end portion <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the lower end portion <b>120</b><i>b</i>) of the corresponding side reinforcement layer <b>100</b>. For this reason, the occurrence of shear strain between the folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>e </i>and each of the inner end portions in the tire radial direction (the lower end portion <b>110</b><i>b </i>and the lower end portion <b>120</b><i>b</i>) of the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b>, and the occurrence of separation attributed to the shear strain, can be effectively restrained.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0098">Note that, in the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each of the folded-back end portions <b>22</b><i>e </i>may be configured to have a length which does not cause the folded-back end portion <b>22</b><i>e </i>to overlap the lower end portion <b>120</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0099">Moreover, although the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> are provided in both of the side portions <b>26</b> of the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> in the above described embodiment of the present invention, the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> may be provided in any one of the side portions <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0100">Furthermore, although each of the side reinforcement layers <b>100</b> is provided outside the carcass layer <b>22</b> in the tread width direction in the above described embodiment of the present invention, the side reinforcement layer <b>100</b> may be provided inside the carcass layer <b>22</b> in the tread width direction.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0101">Although the cap-and-layer layer <b>25</b> is provided in the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> in the above described embodiment of the present invention, the cap-and-layer layer <b>25</b> does not necessarily have to be provided therein. In addition, materials for cords composing the crossing belt layer <b>24</b> and the cap-and-layer layer <b>25</b> are not limited to those described above.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0102">Although the first and second side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> are formed by rubberizing reinforcement cords (the reinforcement cords <b>110</b><i>s </i>and the reinforcement cords <b>120</b><i>s</i>), the first and second side reinforcement layers <b>110</b> and <b>120</b> do not necessarily have to be formed by rubberizing reinforcement cords.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0103">Additionally, although the pneumatic tire <b>10</b> is a pneumatic tire (having a tire size of 215/45R17) for a general passenger car, the present invention is not limited to a pneumatic tire for a general passenger car, and needless to say, can be applied to a pneumatic tire for a race (a motor sport).</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0104">As described above, it goes without saying that the present invention includes various embodiments and the like which are not herein described. Accordingly, a technical scope of the present invention should be defined by inventive specifications according to the scope of clams, the inventive specifications being appropriate based on the above descriptions.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY</heading>
<p id="p-0097" num="0105">As has been described above, the pneumatic tire according to the present invention is advantageous in a technique and the like of manufacturing a pneumatic tire because high speed durability thereof can be further enhanced in without reducing a wear life of the shoulder portion.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A pneumatic tire provided with a side reinforcement layer in a side portion, wherein:
<claim-text>the side reinforcement layer comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side reinforcement layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side reinforcement layer, which includes an overlapping region overlapping the first side reinforcement layer in at least a part of a maximum-width portion of the pneumatic tire in a tread width direction, and which is provided outside the first side reinforcement layer in the tread width direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first side reinforcement layer includes a plurality of first linear members;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second side reinforcement layer includes a plurality of second linear members each crossing the first linear members; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inclination angle of each of the first and second linear members with respect to a circumferential line extending in a circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire is 5 to 30 degrees,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an outer end portion intersection angle (&#x3b1;) is at least 3 degrees larger than an inner end portion intersection angle (&#x3b2;), the outer end portion intersection angle (&#x3b1;) being an intersection angle on an outer side in the tire radial direction formed by each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members, in an outer end portion of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction, and the inner end portion intersection angle (&#x3b2;) being an intersection angle on an inner side in the tire radial direction formed by each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members, in an inner end portion of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the inclination angle is 5 to 20 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an overlapping width which is a width of the overlapping region in a tire radial direction is equal to 10% to 50% of a carcass height which is a height from a corresponding bead portion of the pneumatic tire to an outermost end in the tire radial direction of a carcass layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the overlapping width is equal to 10% to 30% of the carcass height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a folded-back end portion of the carcass layer has a length which does not cause the folded-back end portion to overlap an inner end portion of the second side reinforcement layer in the tire radial direction, the folded-back end portion being formed by folding back the carcass layer around a bead portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein in the tire radial direction, a position of the folded-back end portion of the carcass layer of the pneumatic tire is different from the inner end portions in the tire radial direction, respectively, of the first and second side reinforcement layers, the folded-back end portion being formed by folding back the carcass layer around a bead portion of the pneumatic tire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an overlapping width which is the width of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction is not more than 80 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein any one of the first linear members and the second linear members are formed of any one of steel monofilaments and steel cords.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein any one of the first linear members and the second linear members are formed of predetermined highly elastic organic fiber cords.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A pneumatic tire provided with a side reinforcement layer in a side portion, wherein:
<claim-text>the side reinforcement layer comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first side reinforcement layer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second side reinforcement layer, which includes an overlapping region overlapping the first side reinforcement layer in at least a part of a maximum-width portion of the pneumatic tire in a tread width direction, and which is provided outside the first side reinforcement layer in the tread width direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first side reinforcement layer includes a plurality of first linear members;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second side reinforcement layer includes a plurality of second linear members each crossing the first linear members; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inclination angle of each of the first and second linear members with respect to a circumferential line extending in a circumferential direction of the pneumatic tire is 5 to 30 degrees,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an inner end portion arrangement distance (d<b>2</b>) is larger than an outer end portion arrangement distance (d<b>1</b>), the inner end portion arrangement distance (d<b>2</b>) being an arrangement distance in the tread width direction between each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members, in the inner end portion of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction, and the outer end portion arrangement distance (d<b>1</b>) being an arrangement distance in the tread width direction between each of the first linear members and each of the second linear members, in the outer end portion of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the inner end portion arrangement distance (d<b>2</b>) is larger than the outer end portion arrangement distance (d<b>1</b>) by 0.1 to 1mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the inclination angle is 5 to 20 degrees.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein an overlapping width which is a width of the overlapping region in a tire radial direction is equal to 10% to 50% of a carcass height which is a height from a corresponding bead portion of the pneumatic tire to an outermost end in the tire radial direction of a carcass layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the overlapping width is equal to 10% to 30% of the carcass height.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein a folded-back end portion of the carcass layer has a length which does not cause the folded-back end portion to overlap an inner end portion of the second side reinforcement layer in the tire radial direction, the folded-back end portion being formed by folding back the carcass layer around a bead portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein in the tire radial direction, a position of the folded-back end portion of the carcass layer of the pneumatic tire is different from the inner end portions in the tire radial direction, respectively, of the first and second side reinforcement layers, the folded-back end portion being formed by folding back the carcass layer around a bead portion of the pneumatic tire.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein an overlapping width which is the width of the overlapping region in the tire radial direction is not more than 80 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein any one of the first linear members and the second linear members are formed of any one of steel monofilaments and steel cords.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The pneumatic tire according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein any one of the first linear members and the second linear members are formed of predetermined highly elastic organic fiber cords. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
