<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641044-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641044</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12024144</doc-number>
<date>20080201</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-109777</doc-number>
<date>20070418</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>75</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198853</main-classification>
<further-classification>1986881</further-classification>
<further-classification>1986991</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Conveyor chain for travel way</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2909271</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Taylor</name>
<date>19591000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5361893</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lapeyre</name>
<date>19941100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5439097</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Takahashi et al.</name>
<date>19950800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>19886701</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5507383</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lapyere et al.</name>
<date>19960400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198853</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5628393</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Steeber et al.</name>
<date>19970500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1986991</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6068112</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kasai et al.</name>
<date>20000500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198853</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6705460</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Weiser et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198850</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6948613</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Guldenfels et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198853</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7222730</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Garbagnati et al.</name>
<date>20070500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198853</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0076218</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Marshall et al.</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198853</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 647 515</doc-number>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>07-172534</doc-number>
<date>19950700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-111449</doc-number>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198850-853</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>1986881</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>1986902</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>1986991</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080257690</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081023</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ozaki</last-name>
<first-name>Hajime</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shibayama</last-name>
<first-name>Katsutoshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Dann, Dorfman, Herrell and Skillman</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Skillman</last-name>
<first-name>Henry H.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsubakimoto Chain Co.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Osaka</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Deuble</last-name>
<first-name>Mark A</first-name>
<department>3651</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A conveyor chain for a travel way on which an operator and/or a work carriage are reliably moved in a nonskid manner. The conveyor chain has a series of modules, each with a nonskid material loaded upper surface with front and rear hinge portions for connecting the modules to each other by connecting pins. The nonskid material loaded upper surface has hollows with the hollow surfaces recessed below the upper surface. The upper surface includes a number of supporting ribs project upwardly from the hollow surfaces and terminate flush with the upper surface, so that the transfer of the work carriage is easy and a back bend radius is decreased. Miniaturization and simplification of the conveyor are attained.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="139.78mm" wi="249.00mm" file="US07641044-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.77mm" wi="151.47mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641044-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="200.15mm" wi="171.53mm" file="US07641044-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="255.78mm" wi="141.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641044-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a conveyor chain for a travel way in which a person or a carriage carrying a workpiece is moved along in an operating area by a conveyor alongside a manufacturing line, an assembly line and the like for articles.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In this kind of conveyor chain for the travel way, there has been a conveyor belt formed by a number of plastic chain modules or links having a plurality of ribs. The links are connected to each other by connecting pins as shown, for example, in Japanese Laid-Open Patent Publication No. 2006-111449 (page 1, FIG. 1).</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">However, since in such a conveyor belt protrusions are protruded upwardly from a transfer surface, when wheels of a work carrier or the like are grounded and rolled on the exposed transfer surface, the traveling vibration and traveling resistance are large. Thus there is a problem that an excessive traveling load is created by the upwardly-projecting protrusions.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Further, when a gap between chain modules in the pitch direction is reduced to provide a transfer surface of high density, a belt inner circumferential side back bend radius cannot be decreased because of a contact interference between adjacent projecting protrusions of the modules. To avoid the interference, an intermediate idler or the like must be appropriately disposed, and there is a problem, in that it is difficult to ensure a suitable belt slack on the belt return run.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Accordingly, an object of the present invention is to solve the above-described problems or to provide a conveyor chain for a travel way which supports an operator or a work carriage reliably in a nonskid manner, so that the transfer of the workpieces is easy, and the back bend radius is decreased so that miniaturization and simplification of the conveyor are attained.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">To attain the above-described object, the invention solves the above-described problems by a novel conveyor chain for a travel way in which a number of synthetic resin chain links having nonskid material loaded surfaces are connected to each other by connecting pins. The novel links are characterized in that the upper surface which is loaded with nonskid material is formed with a number of objective supporting ribs which project from hollows in the upper nonskid material loaded surface in a protruding manner so as to terminate flush with the upper nonskid material surface.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Preferably the cross-sectional shapes of said objective supporting ribs are formed as saw teeth.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Further, in addition, at least some of the objective supporting ribs comprise straight segments arranged in a polygonal pattern consisting of a combination of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Thus, when using a conveyor or travel way of the present invention in an operating area along a manufacturing line, an assembly line and the like for work pieces, the following peculiar effects are obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Since the upper nonskid material loaded surface of the chain links is formed with a number of objective supporting ribs which project from hollows provided in the upper nonskid surfaces in a protruding manner, the rubber bottoms of safety shoes worn by an operator, or the wheels of a work carriage and the like, are pushed into a number of objective ribs formed at positions where the rubber bottoms are grounded and the ribs are deformed. Thus a reliable nonskid function for the operators and work carriages can be realized. Further, since a number of objective supporting ribs are provided from a nonskid surface-carved base surface in a projecting manner so as to be flush with the upper nonskid material loaded surface, traveling vibration and traveling resistance, which are liable to occur when wheels of the work carriage are grounded and rolled, are significantly suppressed. Thus smooth movement of the work carriage can be easily attained.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">And since the nonskid material loaded surface of the chain module is formed with a number of objective supporting ribs, which project from hollows in the upper nonskid loading surface in a protruding manner, contact between the objective supporting ribs in the chain modules can be avoided when a transfer surface is designed in which a number of chain modules are formed in a high density by reducing the mutual gaps of the chain modules in the pitch direction. Thus the back bend radius is decreased so that miniaturization and simplification of the conveyor can be attained.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Further, since a cross-sectional shapes of the objective supporting ribs are formed to be saw teeth, the rubber bottoms of safety shoes worn by an operator, or the wheels of the work carriage are pushed onto a number of objective ribs and cause them to be deformed at positions where the rubber bottoms are grounded. Thus a reliable nonskid function for the operators and work carriages can be further realized.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Further, since the straight segments of the projecting ribs are in a polygonal pattern consisting of a number of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes, even if the operator and/or the work carriage are moved in any direction, a reliable nonskid function for the operator and work carriage can be realized.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">If in a conveyor chain for a travel way, in which a number of nonskid material loaded surface mounted synthetic resin chain modules or links are adapted to be connected to each other by connecting pins, the nonskid material loaded surface of the chain module is formed with a number of objective supporting ribs which project from the bases of hollows provided in an upper nonskid material loaded surface sop as to be flush with the upper nonskid surface, and an operator and a work carriage are reliably allowed to be moved in a nonskid manner so that a transfer of a work carriage is easy and if the backbend radius is decreased whereby miniaturization and simplification of the conveyor are attained.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The synthetic resin material of the chain module used in the present invention can be molded, and can assume strong toughness and shape retention enough to support the operator and work carriage. Any such material having these properties may be used, for example, engineering plastic resins such as polyethylene resin, polypropylene resin, acetal resin and the like, and reinforced resins may be used in which reinforcing fibers such as glass fibers or the like are contained.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Further, if the shapes of the chain modules used in the present invention are those which are formed such that a number of objective supporting ribs are formed to be flush with the upper nonskid material loaded surface while the ribs have hollowed-out nonskid loading surfaces, any shapes may be used. Additionally concretely speaking, the shape of the chain module is of course one in which a number of hinge portions for inserting connecting pins and connecting them to each other interdigitatedly are formed at front and rear edges in the connection longitudinal direction as disclosed in the above-noted Japanese laid-open patent publication No. 2006-111449.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">It is noted that the &#x201c;hollowed-out&#x201d; surface referred to in the present invention means a surface where there is a hollow around the base of the ribs which is recessed toward the inside of a chain module so that the shaped portion is relatively formed in a protruding manner. The shaped portion can be formed by any means such as machining, molding or the like.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Further, with a form of a number of arranged objective supporting ribs adopted in the present invention, if the form is a combination pattern consisting of hexagonal shapes and a rhombus shapes for realizing a reliable nonskid state of an operator and a work carriage even if the operator and the work carriage are moved in any direction, any concrete combination patterns may be used.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A conveyor chain for a travel way, which is an example according to the present invention, will be described in detail with reference to drawings in which</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a chain module or link used in the conveyor chain for a travel way, which is an embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken from the line II-II in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> is a fragmentary enlargement of the portion of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> which is circled; and</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a fragmentary diagram of a travel way embodying a conveyor chain with the modules or links of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF A PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a conveyor chain <b>100</b> for a travel way according to an example of the present invention is used for moving a person P, a working carriage C, or the like extends in a longitudinal direction L in a working area alongside a manufacturing line (not shown). The chain <b>100</b> is composed of a number of polyethylene resin chain modules <b>110</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) adapted to be connected to each other by connecting pins (not shown) which extend in a transverse direction T. The conveyor chain <b>100</b> is driven in a traveling manner along manufacturing lines through transverse driving shafts D.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">It is noted that the reference numeral <b>111</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> denotes a module body portion where the upper nonskid material loaded surfaces <b>110</b>A are hollowed-out to form hollows <b>110</b>B in the upper surface of the chain module <b>110</b>. The reference numerals <b>112</b> denote a number of hinge portions formed in front and rear edges of the chain module <b>110</b> in the longitudinal direction for receiving the above-mentioned connecting pins thereinto to connect the links to each other interdigitatedly, and the reference numeral <b>113</b> denotes hinge holes for inserting the connecting pins. It should be noted that the hinge portions <b>112</b> have semi-circular outlines, and the upper surface <b>110</b>A is tangential to and extends between the semi-circular outlines of the front and rear hinge portions, and has a border portion along the entire periphery of the module.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The nonskid material loaded upper surface <b>110</b>A of the chain module <b>110</b>, which is the most characteristic in the conveyor chain <b>100</b> for a travel way of the present example will be described in more detail with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>2</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The nonskid material loaded upper surface <b>110</b>A of this chain module <b>110</b> is formed with a number of objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> which project upwardly from the nonskid recessed surfaces of the hollows <b>110</b>B, so as to be flush with the upper surface of the module. The objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> are formed as saw teeth shapes as seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref> in an enlarged scale.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">It is noted that the step difference between the nonskid material loaded upper surface <b>110</b>A and the recessed surface <b>110</b>B in the chain module <b>110</b> used in the present example is set to about 1.0 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> forming a nonskid material loaded upper surface <b>110</b>A of the chain module <b>110</b> comprise straight segments arranged in polygonal patterns combining of a number of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes. Here, in the case of the present example, a number of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes forming the nonskid loading surface <b>110</b>A with a number of objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> form polygons having sizes narrower than the wheel width of the work carriage, for example 30.0 mm, so that a drop off of an outer circumferential portion of the work carriage is avoided.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In the conveyor chain <b>100</b> for a travel way, the nonskid material loaded surface <b>110</b>A of this chain module <b>110</b> is formed of a number of objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> which are provided from a nonskid recessed surface <b>110</b>B in a protruding manner. The rubber bottoms of safety shoes worn by an operator, and the wheels of a work carriage or the like, deform a number of objective ribs <b>114</b> formed at positions where the rubber bottoms are grounded. Thus reliable non-skidding support of the operators and work carriages can be realized. Further, since a number of objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> project from a nonskid recessed surface in a protruding manner so as to terminate flush with the nonskid upper surface <b>110</b>A, traveling vibration and traveling resistance, which are liable to occur when wheels of the work carriage are grounded and rolled, are significantly suppressed. Thus the movement of the work carriage on the travel way can be easily attained.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The nonskid material loaded upper surface <b>110</b>A of the chain module <b>110</b> is formed by a number of objective supporting ribs <b>114</b>, which are provided from a nonskid loading recessed surface <b>110</b>B in a protruding manner, contact between the objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> in the chain modules <b>110</b> can be avoided when a transfer surface is designed in which a number of chain modules <b>110</b> are formed in a high density by reducing the mutual gaps of the chain modules in the pitch direction. Thus the back bend radius is decreased so that miniaturization and simplification of the conveyor can be attained.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Further, since a cross-sectional shape of the objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> is formed to be saw teeth as shown <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2A</figref>, the rubber bottoms of safety shoes worn by an operator P, or the wheels of a work carriage C and the like, deform a number of objective ribs <b>114</b> formed at positions where the rubber bottoms are grounded and have an increased contact degree. Thus a reliable nonskid function for the operators and work carriages can be further realized.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Further, since a number of objective supporting ribs forming a nonskid material loaded surface <b>110</b>A of the chain module <b>110</b> are straight segments arranged so as to assume a combination polygonal pattern consisting of a number of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes, even if the operator and work carriage are moved in any direction, longitudinal L, transverse T or rotary R, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a reliable nonskid function for the operator and work carriage can be realized.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Therefore, in the thus obtained conveyor chain <b>100</b>, which is an example of the present invention, the nonskid material loaded surface <b>110</b>A of the chain module <b>110</b> is formed of a number of objective supporting ribs <b>114</b> which are provided from a nonskid material loaded recessed hollow surface <b>110</b>B in a protruding manner so as to terminate flush with the nonskid material loaded surface <b>110</b>A, a reliable nonskid function for the operator and the work carriage is realized and a transfer of the work carriage becomes easy and a back bend radius is decreased so that miniaturization and simplification of the conveyor can be realized. Thus the beneficial effects of the present invention are very large.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A conveyor chain for a travel way in which a number of nonskid material loaded surface mounted synthetic resin chain modules are adapted to be connected to each other by connecting pins, characterized in that
<claim-text>said nonskid material loaded surface of the chain module is formed of a number of supporting ribs which project from a nonskid material loaded recessed hollow surface in a protruding manner so as to be flush with the nonskid material loaded upper surface</claim-text>
<claim-text>selected ones of said supporting ribs of said chain module being straight segments arranged in polygonal Patterns in a combination of a number of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A conveyor chain for a travel way according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that at least some of said supporting ribs have a cross-sectional shape of saw tooth form.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A conveyor chain for a travel way adapted to move in a longitudinal direction alongside a manufacturing line comprising a plurality of nonskid material loaded surface synthetic resin chain modules extending transversely of said travel way and adapted to be connected to each other by transverse connecting pins,
<claim-text>said modules having a nonskid material loaded upper surface, with hollows having recessed surfaces,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said upper surface comprising a plurality of supporting ribs which project upwardly from said recessed hollow surfaces in a protruding manner so as to terminate flush with the nonskid material loaded upper surface</claim-text>
<claim-text>selected ones of said supporting ribs of said chain module being straight segments arranged in polygonal patterns in a combination of a number of hexagon shapes and rhombus shapes.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A conveyor chain according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein each rib has a saw-tooth cross section.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A conveyor chain according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein each said module has hinge portions projecting longitudinally from the front and rear edges, said hinge portions having semi-circular outlines, said upper surface being tangential to said outlines. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
