<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641005-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641005</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11802341</doc-number>
<date>20070522</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2004 1 0091154</doc-number>
<date>20041122</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2005 1 0090760</doc-number>
<date>20050816</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="03" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2005 1 0117451</doc-number>
<date>20051102</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>167</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>8</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>16</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180  22</main-classification>
<further-classification>180  21</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e107">Wind-powered pneumatic engine and a motor vehicle equipped with the engine</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3444946</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Waterbury</name>
<date>19690500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180  22</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3967132</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Takamine</name>
<date>19760600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>290  4 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4179007</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Howe</name>
<date>19791200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180  22</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4254843</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Han et al.</name>
<date>19810300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180165</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6138781</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hakala</name>
<date>20001000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180  22</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6270308</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Groppel</name>
<date>20010800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>415  43</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2073484</doc-number>
<kind>U</kind>
<date>19910300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2242352</doc-number>
<kind>Y</kind>
<date>19961200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>1351228</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>FR</country>
<doc-number>2292129</doc-number>
<date>19760600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180  21</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180  22</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>PCT/CN2005/001911</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20051114</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11802341</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070284155</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20071213</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cong</last-name>
<first-name>Yang</first-name>
<address>
<street>Flat 30C, Block B, Quig Tian Hua Ting, Shang Bao Lu, Fu Tian District</street>
<city>Shenzhen, Guangdong Province</city>
<postcode>518034</postcode>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Jacobson Holman PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dickson</last-name>
<first-name>Paul N</first-name>
<department>3618</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Olszewski</last-name>
<first-name>John R</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A wind-powered pneumatic engine including one or more impeller chambers and one or more impellers disposed in the impeller chambers is provided. One or more air inlets for receiving external wind resistance airflow are disposed on the impeller chambers, and the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output. The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes an air-jet system for jetting HPCA into the impeller chambers, and the internal high-pressure compressed air jetted by the air-jet system in conjunction with the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output. In the present invention, the external resistance airflow around a motor vehicle moving at a speed is converted into power for use, which greatly reduces energy consumption and improves the moving speed of a motor vehicle. A motor vehicle equipped with wind-powered pneumatic engine is also provided.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="155.70mm" wi="361.36mm" file="US07641005-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.61mm" wi="157.73mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641005-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="205.99mm" wi="162.90mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641005-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="218.61mm" wi="134.96mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641005-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="213.53mm" wi="128.86mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641005-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="210.14mm" wi="130.81mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641005-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This patent application is a continuation application of application PCT/CN2005/001911 filed Nov. 14, 2005 and published in Chinese, and claims the benefit of Chinese Patent Application No. 200410091154.2 filed Nov. 22, 2004, Chinese Patent Application No. 200510090760.7 filed Aug. 16, 2005, and Chinese Patent Application No. 200510117451.4 filed Nov. 2, 2005.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to an engine installed in large, medium or small size cargo or passenger vehicles having steering wheels, railway trains, subway trains, marine travel vehicles, aerospace travel vehicles and all other motor vehicles that move at a certain speed, and relates to the field of machines.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Engines using fuels as an energy source consume a large quantity of fuels, and discharge large amounts of waste gases and hot gases, which pollute the environment. In order to save fuel energy source and protect the global environment, there is a need for engines that do not consume fuel, discharge waste gases and hot gases or cause pollution. Conventional engines that convert wind force into mechanical kinetic energy are installed in fixed places. Since the mechanical devices installed with the engines do not move at a speed, the engines can only passively receive limited wind force under natural weather, ambient and wind conditions for driving impellers to operate and generate the mechanical kinetic energy. Therefore, there is a need for an engine capable of actively converting wind resistance airflow around a motor vehicle moving at a speed into mechanical power for use.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention is directed to providing a wind-powered pneumatic engine capable of converting wind resistance airflow around a moving power machine into mechanical power for use without consuming fuels and discharging waste gases or hot gases, and a motor vehicle equipped with the same.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The present invention is further directed to providing a wind-powered pneumatic engine using high-pressure compressed air (HPCA) as a direct power source, and a motor vehicle equipped with the same.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The present invention is further directed to providing a wind-powered pneumatic engine capable of converting the wind resistance airflow into mechanical power, converting the mechanical power into regeneration HPCA and storing the regeneration HPCA for use, and a motor vehicle equipped with the same.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention is still further directed to providing a wind-powered pneumatic engine capable of recycling inertia power when a motor vehicle is decelerated and braked, transforming the inertia power into regeneration HPCA and storing the regeneration HPCA for use, and a motor vehicle equipped with the same.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The technical solution for achieving the above objects is described as follows.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">A wind-powered pneumatic engine includes impeller chambers and impellers disposed in the impeller chambers. Air inlets for receiving external wind resistance airflow are disposed on the impeller chambers, and the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes an air-jet system for jetting the HPCA into the impeller chambers, and the HPCA jetted by the air-jet system in conjunction with the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The air inlets for receiving the external wind resistance airflow are trunk shape inlets, each having a large outer edge and a small inner edge.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes an HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system composed of an air tank and a first HPCA compressor. An output of the air tank is connected with the air-jet system. The power output generated after the operation of the impellers drives the first HPCA compressor. The HPCA regenerated by the first HPCA compressor is input into and stored in the air tank.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes a second HPCA compressor driven by an external braking force. The second HPCA compressor regenerates and converts the external braking force into HPCA, which is then input into and stored in the air tank.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The air-jet system includes a first controller, a distributor, a first air-jet pipe set and a first air-jet nozzle set connected in sequence. The HPCA stored in the air tank is input into the distributor through the first controller, and is then diverged by the distributor and input into each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set. Then, the HPCA is jetted into the impeller chambers by each air-jet nozzle of the first air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The air-jet system further includes a second controller, a distribution controller for converting the input HPCA into intermittent burst HPCA, a second air-jet pipe set, and a second air-jet nozzle set connected in sequence. The HPCA stored in the air tank is input into the distribution controller through the second controller. The intermittent burst HPCA is generated by the distribution controller and distributed to each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set, and is then jetted into the impeller chambers by each air-jet nozzle of the second air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The impeller chambers are dual impeller chambers, each having an impeller disposed therein. Air inlets for receiving the external wind resistance airflow are disposed on at least one of the impeller chambers.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">A motor vehicle, including a vehicle body, a gear box, a drive bridge, and tires, is characterized by further including a wind-powered pneumatic engine having impeller chambers and impellers disposed in the impeller chambers. Air inlets for receiving external wind resistance airflow are disposed on the impeller chambers, and the air inlets are trunk shape inlets, each having a large outer edge and a small inner edge. The outer edge of the trunk shape inlet is disposed at the front end of the vehicle body. The external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output. The power output of the impellers is transmitted by the gear box to drive the drive bridge, and the drive bridge drives the tires supporting the vehicle body.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes an air-jet system for jetting HPCA into the impeller chambers. The internal HPCA jetted by the air-jet system in conjunction with the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes an HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system composed of an air tank and a first HPCA compressor. An output of the air tank is connected with the air-jet system. The power output generated after the impellers' operation drives the first HPCA compressor. The HPCA regenerated by the first HPCA compressor is input into and stored in the air tank.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The wind-powered pneumatic engine further includes a deceleration and brake pressurizing system and a second HPCA compressor. The second HPCA compressor is driven by a braking force generated by the deceleration and brake pressurizing system when the engine is decelerated to regenerate HPCA. The regenerated HPCA is input into and stored in the air tank.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The air-jet system includes a first controller, a distributor, a first air-jet pipe set, and a first air-jet nozzle set connected in sequence, and includes a second controller, a distribution controller for converting the input HPCA into intermittent burst HPCA, a second air-jet pipe set, and a second air-jet nozzle set connected in sequence. The HPCA stored in the air tank is input into the distributor through the first controller, and is then diverged by the distributor and input into each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set. The HPCA is jetted into the impeller chambers by each air-jet nozzle of the first air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set. The HPCA stored in the air tank is input into the distribution controller through the second controller. The intermittent burst HPCA is generated by the distribution controller and distributed to each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set, and is then jetted to the impeller chambers by each air-jet nozzle of the second air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The impeller chambers are dual impeller chambers, each having an impeller disposed therein. Air inlets for receiving the external wind resistance airflow are disposed on at least one of the impeller chambers.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The impeller chambers are dual impeller chambers, each having an impeller disposed therein. The distribution controller includes a valve set and cams for opening or closing the valve set, in which the power output of one impeller drives the first HPCA compressor, and the power output of the other impeller drives the cams.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">With the above technical solution, the present invention has the following beneficial technical effects.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">1. With the air inlets for receiving the external wind resistance airflow disposed on the impeller chambers, the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets is used as power to drive the impellers to operate to generate power output, thereby converting the resistance into power. Moreover, the higher the moving speed of the power machine is, the greater the utilization of the strong wind resistance airflow is. Therefore, the present invention, when adopted as an auxiliary power, can significantly increase the moving speed of the power machine without increasing the amount of energy consumed when moving at a high speed. The wind-powered pneumatic engine of the present invention can be installed in large, medium or small size cargo or passenger vehicles having steering wheels, railway trains, subway trains moving on land, marine power machines, aerospace power machines and all other power machines that move at a speed. In addition, in the present invention, the wind resistance airflow is used to drive the engine directly, without consuming fuels and discharging waste gases or hot gases, thereby greatly reducing exhaust gases of the power machines, especially vehicles that cause pollution to the atmosphere, and thus protecting the global environment.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">2. Furthermore, the HPCA is used as the power, and the HPCA jetted by the air-jet system in conjunction with the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlets drives the impellers to operate to generate power output. Therefore, the present invention has the advantages of no fuel consumption, and no waste gases or hot gases discharges, and can achieve self-start and continuous operation to generate power output without being restricted by natural weather, ambient conditions, particularly wind conditions.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">3. Through the HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system, the power output generated after the operation of the impellers is transmitted to the first HPCA compressor, and the first HPCA compressor inputs the regenerated HPCA into the air tank for storage. The wind resistance airflow around the power machine is regenerated and converted into HPCA which is stored to be recycled for use.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">4. Through the deceleration and brake pressurizing device and the second HPCA compressor, the kinetic energy produced as the motor vehicle decelerates and brakes is transmitted to the second HPCA compressor, and the second HPCA compressor subsequently recycles the braking energy and uses the braking energy to regenerate HPCA to be input into and stored in the air tank, such that the utilization of the energy is further enhanced. This solution is particularly suitable for the motor vehicle that frequently decelerates, brakes, and stops.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">5. Through the automatic intermittent burst and jetted HPCA, the air jet time is greatly shortened, thereby saving large usage amounts of the HPCA. This solution is suitable for the motor vehicles that travels over a long distance and a long time at a low speed or that frequently decelerates, idles, and accelerates, thereby ensuring the continuous moving of the motor vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">6. By installing the air inlets of the wind-powered pneumatic engine at the front end of the motor vehicle, particularly at the position where the wind resistance is the greatest, the wind resistance airflow is used to the maximum extent, thereby generating optimal power output and increasing the moving speed of the motor vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In order to make the aforementioned and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention comprehensible, preferred embodiments accompanied with figures is described in detail below.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are exemplary, and are intended to provide further explanation of the invention as claimed.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The accompanying drawings are included to provide a further understanding of the invention, and are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification. The drawings illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with the description, serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic structural view of a wind-powered pneumatic engine;</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic structural view of the wind-powered pneumatic engine and a central primary power output gear box;</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic structural view of a HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system and an air-jet system of the wind-powered pneumatic engine;</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), (<i>b</i>) are schematic structural views of two types of distribution controllers;</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic structural view of the wind-powered pneumatic engine;</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic structural view of an improved distribution controller;</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic structural view of an internal gear transmission mechanism of a brake disc of a brake of a deceleration and brake pressurizing device;</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic structural view of a deceleration and brake pressurizing system of the wind-powered pneumatic engine; and</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic structural view of a motor vehicle equipped with the wind-powered pneumatic engine.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The present invention is further described in detail with accompanying drawings and embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-8</figref>, a wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b> includes trunk shape inlets, each having an outer edge <b>29</b> and an inner edge <b>30</b>, impeller chambers <b>28</b>, impellers <b>6</b>, impeller flywheels <b>14</b>, a left impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>7</b>, a right impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>15</b>, a primary power output gear box <b>32</b>, and air outlets <b>31</b>; a HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system, including an air tank <b>1</b>, a first HPCA compressor <b>17</b>, and a conical gear <b>16</b> for transmitting the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b>; an air-jet system for start and acceleration, including a first controller <b>2</b> for opening the HPCA to perform start and acceleration, a distributor <b>3</b>, a first air-jet pipe set <b>4</b> connected with the distributor <b>3</b>, a first air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b>, a second controller <b>10</b> for opening the HPCA to perform automatic intermittent burst air-jet acceleration, a distribution controller <b>11</b>, a second air-jet pipe set <b>12</b> connected with the distribution controller <b>11</b>, a second air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b>, a conical gear <b>8</b>, an HPCA jet pipe <b>26</b>, and an HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b>; a deceleration and brake pressurizing system, including a deceleration and brake pressurizing device <b>42</b> and a high-load second air compressor <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>2</b> and <b>5</b>, impellers <b>6</b> and impeller flywheels <b>14</b> are disposed in the symmetrical dual impeller chambers <b>28</b>, and air-jet nozzle sets (<b>5</b>, <b>13</b>) are disposed on the impeller chambers <b>28</b>. The HPCA is jetted into the impeller chambers <b>28</b> through the air-jet nozzle sets (<b>5</b>, <b>13</b>), and the HPCA drives the impellers <b>6</b> to operate and is exhausted via the air outlets <b>31</b>. The impeller chambers <b>28</b> are further provided with the trunk shape inlets for receiving external wind resistance airflow. The trunk shape inlet has the outer edge <b>29</b> and the inner edge <b>30</b>, and the diameter of the outer edge <b>29</b> of the trunk shape inlet is 1-30 times, preferably 3.6 times, of the diameter of the inner edge <b>30</b>. The external wind resistance airflow enters the impeller chambers <b>28</b> through the trunk shape inlets to drive the impellers <b>6</b> to operate, the external wind resistance airflow after driving the impellers <b>6</b> to operate is exhausted via the air outlets <b>31</b>. The power generated after the operation of the impellers <b>6</b> is gear-shifted and output through the central primary power output gear box <b>32</b>. In order to make the impellers <b>6</b> operate directionally, and the airflow jetted from the air-jet nozzles drive the impellers to operate better, the air jetted by the air-jet nozzle set (<b>5</b>, <b>13</b>) is directional.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">With the above technical solution, the HPCA is used to drive the engine, so as to achieve self-start and operation without being restricted by natural weather, ambient, and wind conditions. More importantly, when a power machine moves at a speed, the trunk shape inlets disposed on the impeller chambers <b>28</b> actively receives any external resistance airflow around the power machine to drive the engine, so as to convert strong wind resistance into power for use, thereby greatly reducing the power consumption. The wind-powered pneumatic engine of the present invention is widely applied to large, medium or small size cargo or passenger vehicles having steering wheels, railway trains, subway trains moving on land, marine power machines, aerospace power machines and all other power machines that move at a speed.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</figref>, an HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system is provided, which includes the air tank <b>1</b>, the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b>, and the conical gear <b>16</b> for transmission. The power output of the impellers <b>6</b> is transmitted to the conical gear <b>16</b> through the right impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>15</b>, the conical gear <b>16</b> transmits the power output to the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b>, and the HPCA generated by the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b> is input into and stored in the air tank <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), (<i>b</i>) and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, an air-jet system includes the first controller <b>2</b>, the distributor <b>3</b>, the first air-jet pipe set <b>4</b>, the first air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b>, the second controller <b>10</b>, the distribution controller <b>11</b>, the second air-jet pipe set <b>12</b>, the second air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b>, the conical gear <b>8</b>, the HPCA jet pipe <b>26</b>, and the HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4(</figref><i>a</i>), (<i>b</i>), the distribution controller <b>11</b> is a conventional gas distribution mechanism for motor vehicles, and includes cams (<b>18</b>, <b>19</b>) and a valve set <b>9</b>. The cam <b>19</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>a</i>) has a distribution structure, and the cam <b>18</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4(</figref><i>b</i>) has a synchronous structure. The distribution controller <b>11</b> functions to convert the input HPCA into intermittent burst HPCA. During operation, the impellers <b>6</b> transmit the power to the conical gear <b>8</b> through the left impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>7</b>. If the conical gear <b>8</b> transmits the cam <b>18</b>, the valve set <b>9</b> is opened and closed by the cam <b>18</b> synchronously to generate synchronous intermittent burst and jetted HPCA. If the conical gear <b>8</b> drives the cam <b>19</b> to rotate, or the valve set <b>9</b> is opened or closed in distribution by the cam <b>19</b>, distributional intermittent burst and jetted HPCA is generated. The air tank <b>1</b> is connected with the distributor <b>3</b> through the HPCA jet pipe <b>26</b>, and the first controller <b>2</b> is disposed on the HPCA jet pipe <b>26</b>. The HPCA stored in the air tank <b>1</b> is input into the distributor <b>3</b> through the first controller <b>2</b>, and is then diverged by the distributor <b>3</b> and input into each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set <b>4</b>. Then, the HPCA is jetted into the impeller chambers <b>28</b> by each air-jet nozzle of the first air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b> connected with each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set <b>4</b>. The air tank <b>1</b> is connected with the distribution controller <b>11</b> through the HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b>, and the second controller <b>10</b> is disposed on the HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b>. The HPCA stored in the air tank <b>1</b> enters the distribution controller <b>11</b> through the second controller <b>10</b>. The intermittent burst HPCA is generated by the distribution controller and distributed to each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set <b>12</b>, and the intermittent burst HPCA is then jetted into the impeller chambers <b>28</b> by each air-jet nozzle of the second air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b> connected with each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">During operation, the first controller <b>2</b> for the control of HPCA start and acceleration is turned on, such that the HPCA stored in the air tank <b>1</b> is jetted. The HPCA is distributed to the air-jet pipe set <b>4</b> through the distributor <b>3</b>, and is transmitted to the air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b> by the air-jet pipe set <b>4</b>, and the HPCA airflow jetted by the air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b> impels the impellers <b>6</b>, such that the impellers <b>6</b> is started and accelerated to operate to generate power. The power is transmitted to the conical gear <b>8</b> by the left impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>7</b>, the conical gear <b>8</b> drives the cam (<b>18</b> or <b>19</b>) of the distribution controller <b>11</b> to be start and operate. Under the effect of the cam (<b>18</b> or <b>19</b>), the valve set <b>9</b> is opened and closed continuously, and the second controller <b>10</b> is turned on at the same time, such that the HPCA is jetted from the HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b> to be supplied to the distribution controller <b>11</b>. At this time, as the valve set <b>9</b> is opened and closed continuously, the HPCA is converted into intermittent burst and jetted HPCA by the distribution controller <b>11</b> and is then output. The auto intermittent burst HPCA is then transmitted to the air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b> by the air-jet pipe set <b>12</b> for jetting. The automatic intermittent burst HPCA impels the wind-powered pneumatic engine impellers <b>6</b> including a plurality of sets of impellers to accelerate operation, such that the wind-powered pneumatic engine impeller flywheels <b>14</b> also accelerate operation to generate power accordingly, and the power is output by the gear box <b>32</b> and transmitted to the power machine. As the power machine moves at a speed, the external wind resistance airflow around the power machine during moving is guided into the impeller chambers <b>28</b> through the trunk shape inlets having large outer edges and small inner edges. The wind resistance airflow further impels the impellers <b>6</b> to operate to generate power output, thereby transforming the resistance into power. In addition, the power is output by the right impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>15</b> and transmitted to the conical gear <b>16</b>. The conical gear <b>16</b> transmits the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b> to operate, and the HPCA generated by the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b> is continuously supplemented to the air tank <b>1</b> for storage, such that the wind-powered pneumatic engine can continuously accelerate operation to generate power.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">To meet the requirements of the amount of the HPCA during the controllable HPCA start and acceleration and the automatic intermittent burst air-jet acceleration of the wind-powered pneumatic engine, in the present invention, the diameter of the HPCA jet pipe <b>26</b> and the diameter of the HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b> are respectively several times greater than the total diameter of the diameter of air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b> plus the diameter of the air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In order to make the double impellers <b>6</b> of the wind-powered pneumatic engine start and accelerate directionally to operate to generate power, in the present invention, the air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b> and the air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b> are designed to have a certain directional air-jet function.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, in order to overcome or reduce frictional resistance between valve stem heads <b>22</b> of the valve set <b>9</b> and cams <b>21</b> of the valve set <b>9</b> when the cams <b>21</b> of the distribution controller operate to open or close the valves, the present invention is further provided with a design of adding sliding balls <b>23</b> at the valve stem heads <b>22</b>. In order to make the sliding balls <b>23</b> of the valve stem heads <b>22</b> slide smoothly, a lubrication oil passage <b>24</b> leading to the sliding balls <b>23</b> is added at the valve stem heads <b>22</b>, such that the lubrication oil in a lubrication oil chamber <b>25</b> of the distribution controller <b>11</b> enters the surfaces of the sliding balls <b>23</b> through the lubrication oil passage <b>24</b>, thereby achieving lubrication, reducing frictional resistance, improving operating speed of the wind-powered pneumatic engine, and generating greater output torque.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 8</figref> together, the motor vehicle, when frequently decelerates, brakes, stops or restarts, consumes large amounts of HPCA. In order to supplement the excessive amount of HPCA consumed by the motor vehicle when it frequently decelerates, brakes, stops or restarts, and to ensure the amount of HPCA required when the wind-powered pneumatic engine restarts, the present invention provides a deceleration and brake pressurizing system capable of recycling the inertia power when the motor vehicle moving at a speed frequently decelerates and brakes and converting the inertia power into HPCA to be stored for reuse. The deceleration and brake pressurizing system includes a deceleration and brake pressurizing device <b>42</b> and a high-load second air compressor <b>41</b>. The deceleration and brake pressurizing device <b>42</b> further includes a pedal <b>33</b>, a hydraulic master pump <b>36</b>, a clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b>, a clutch driven disc <b>38</b>, a clutch driving disc <b>39</b>, and an internal gear transmission mechanism <b>40</b> of a brake disc of a brake. The pedal <b>33</b> drives the hydraulic master pump <b>36</b>, the hydraulic master pump <b>36</b> drives the clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b>, the clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b> impels the clutch driven disc <b>38</b> to abut against the clutch driving disc <b>39</b>, and the internal gear transmission mechanism <b>40</b> of the brake disc outputs the inertia power generated when the motor vehicle decelerates to drive the high-load second air compressor <b>41</b> to work.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The operation process is described as follows. When it is required to decelerate, the pedal <b>33</b> is stepped down to reach a position of decelerating and pressurizing travel <b>35</b> from a free travel <b>34</b> of the deceleration and brake pressurizing device of the wind-powered pneumatic engine, the hydraulic master pump <b>36</b> starts to work, and functions on the clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b> to start the clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b> to work. The clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b> drives the clutch driven disc <b>38</b> to abut against the clutch driving disc <b>39</b>, such that the inertia power of the motor vehicle, when decelerates, is directly transmitted by the brake disc internal gear transmission mechanism <b>40</b> to the high-load second air compressor <b>41</b>, and the HPCA regenerated by the high-load second air compressor <b>41</b> is supplemented to the air tank <b>1</b> for storage, so as to be recycled and used.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a motor vehicle equipped with wind-powered pneumatic engine includes a vehicle body <b>44</b>, a wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b>, a drive bridge <b>46</b>, a half-axle <b>47</b> of the drive bridge, and tires <b>48</b>. The structure of the wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b> is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 8</figref>. The wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b> is disposed in the vehicle body <b>44</b>, the outer edge <b>29</b> of the trunk shape inlets of the wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b> is mounted at the front end of the vehicle body <b>44</b> at a position <b>45</b> where the wind resistance is the greatest. In order to increase the speed of the wind resistance airflow entering the impeller chambers <b>28</b>, the diameter of the outer edge <b>29</b> of the trunk shape inlets is 1-30 times, preferably 3.6 times, of the diameter of the inner edge <b>30</b>. An output of a main power output gear box <b>32</b> of the wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b> is connected with the drive bridge <b>46</b> of the motor vehicle. The drive bridge <b>46</b> is connected with the half-axle <b>47</b> of the drive bridge, the half-axle <b>47</b> of the drive bridge is then connected with the tires <b>48</b>, and the tires <b>48</b> are fixedly connected with the internal gear transmission mechanism <b>40</b> of the brake disc of the brake.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">During operation, the first controller <b>2</b> for HPCA start and acceleration is turned on, such that the HPCA stored in the air tank <b>1</b> is jetted. The HPCA is distributed to the air-jet pipe set <b>4</b> through the distributor <b>3</b>, and the HPCA airflow is jetted from the air-jet nozzle set <b>5</b> to impel the impellers <b>6</b> to start and accelerate to operate to generate power. The power is output to the conical gear <b>8</b> by the left impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>7</b>, the conical gear <b>8</b> drives the cam (<b>18</b> or <b>19</b>) of the distribution controller <b>11</b> to be started to operate. The second controller <b>10</b> for HPCA auto intermittent burst air-jet acceleration is turned on at the same time, such that the HPCA is jetted from the HPCA jet pipe <b>27</b> to be supplied to the distribution controller <b>11</b>. The auto intermittent burst and jetted HPCA is output by the distribution controller <b>11</b>, and is jetted through the air-jet nozzle set <b>13</b> after entering the second air-jet pipe set <b>12</b>, so as to impel the impellers <b>6</b> to accelerate operation to generate power output. The internal HPCA stored in the air tank <b>1</b> drives the impellers <b>6</b> to operate to generate power. The power is transmitted to the gear box <b>32</b>, and after the gear-shift of the gear box <b>32</b>, the power is output to drive the tires <b>48</b> through the drive bridge <b>46</b> and the half-axle <b>47</b> of the drive bridge, so that the motor vehicle starts to move. Meanwhile, the power is transmitted to the conical gear <b>16</b> through the right impeller main shaft auxiliary power conical gear <b>15</b>, and starts the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b> to operate through the conical gear <b>16</b>. The HPCA generated by the first HPCA compressor <b>17</b> is supplied to the air tank <b>1</b> for storage, so as to be recycled and used by the wind-powered pneumatic engine, and thereby the wind-powered pneumatic engine <b>20</b> operates continuously to generate power output.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">When the motor vehicle moves at a certain speed, the wind resistance airflow around the motor vehicle is guided by the outer edge <b>29</b> of the trunk shape inlets mounted in the front end of the vehicle body <b>44</b> at the position <b>45</b> where the wind resistance is the greatest, passes through trunk shape inlets and enters the impeller chambers <b>28</b>. The wind resistance airflow further drives the impellers <b>6</b> to operate to generate power. Both the power and the power generated by the HPCA stored in the air tank <b>1</b> are output to the gear box <b>32</b>, and after the gear-shift of the gear box <b>32</b>, the power is output to drive the tires <b>48</b> of the motor vehicle to operate through the drive bridge <b>46</b> and the half-axle <b>47</b> of the drive bridge, such that the motor vehicle equipped with the wind-powered pneumatic engine moves at a higher speed.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">When it is required to decelerate, the pedal <b>33</b> is stepped down to the position of decelerating and pressurizing travel <b>35</b>, the hydraulic master pump <b>36</b> starts to work. The hydraulic master pump <b>36</b> impels the clutch driven disc <b>38</b> to abut against the clutch driving disc <b>39</b> through the clutch driven disc hydraulic working pump <b>37</b>, such that the inertia power of the motor vehicle is transmitted to the high-load second air compressor <b>41</b> to work through the brake disc internal gear transmission mechanism <b>40</b>, so as to recycle the breaking energy and convert it into regenerated HPCA to be stored in the air tank <b>1</b>, so as to recycle and use the regenerated HPCA.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that various modifications and variations can be made to the structure of the present invention without departing from the scope or spirit of the invention. In view of the foregoing, it is intended that the present invention cover modifications and variations of this invention provided they fall within the scope of the following claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A wind-powered pneumatic engine, comprising:
<claim-text>at least one impeller chamber and at least one impeller disposed in the impeller chamber, wherein the impeller chamber comprises an air inlet disposed thereon for receiving external wind resistance airflow, and external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlet drives the impeller to operate to generate power output; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an air-jet system for jetting a high-pressure compressed air (HPCA) into the impeller chamber, wherein the HPCA jetted by the air-jet system in conjunction with the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlet drives the impeller to operate to generate power output.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the air inlet for receiving the external wind resistance airflow is a trunk shape inlet having a large outer edge and a small inner edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the diameter of the outer edge of the trunk shape inlets is 1-30 times of the diameter of the inner edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the diameter of the outer edge of the trunk shape inlets is 3.6 times of the diameter of the inner edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system composed of an air tank and a first HPCA compressor connected with each other, wherein an output of the air tank is connected with the air-jet system, the first HPCA compressor is operably connected with the impeller, the power output generated after the impeller's operation drives the first HPCA compressor, and the HPCA regenerated by the first HPCA compressor is input into and stored in the air tank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising a second HPCA compressor driven by an external braking force, wherein the second HPCA compressor is connected with the air tank, and the second HPCA compressor uses the external braking force to regenerate HPCA which is then input into and stored in the air tank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the air-jet system comprises a first controller, a distributor, a first air-jet pipe set and a first air-jet nozzle set operably connected in sequence, the HPCA stored in an air tank is input into the distributor through the first controller, and is then diverged by the distributor and input into each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set, and the HPCA is then jetted into the impeller chamber by each air-jet nozzle of the first air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the air-jet system further comprises a second controller, a distribution controller for converting the input HPCA into intermittent burst HPCA, a second air-jet pipe set, and a second air-jet nozzle set operably connected in sequence, the HPCA stored in the air tank is input into the distribution controller through the second controller, and the intermittent burst HPCA is generated by the distribution controller and distributed to each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set, and is then jetted into the impeller chamber by each air-jet nozzle of the second air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The wind-powered pneumatic engine as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, comprising two impeller chambers, each having an impeller disposed therein, wherein said at least one air inlet for receiving the external wind resistance airflow is disposed on at least one of the impeller chambers.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A motor vehicle, comprising a vehicle body, a drive bridge located within the vehicle body, a gear box located within the vehicle body and operably connected with the drive bridge, and tires operably connected with the drive bridge, said motor vehicle is characterized by further comprising a wind-powered pneumatic engine located within the vehicle body and having at least one impeller chamber and at least one impeller operably connected with the gear box and disposed in the impeller chamber, wherein the impeller chamber comprises at least one air inlet disposed thereon for receiving external wind resistance airflow, and the air inlet is a trunk shape inlet having a large outer edge and a small inner edge, the outer edge of the trunk shape inlet is disposed at a front end of the vehicle body pointing to a moving direction of the vehicle, the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlet drives the impeller to operate to generate power output, the power output of the impeller is transmitted by the gear box to drive the drive bridge, and the drive bridge drives the tires supporting the vehicle body; and wherein the wind-powered pneumatic engine further comprises an air-jet system for jetting HPCA into the impeller chamber, the HPCA jetted by the air-jet system in conjunction with the external wind resistance airflow entering the air inlet drives the impeller to operate to generate power output.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the diameter of the outer edge of the trunk shape inlets is 1-30 times of the diameter of the inner edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the diameter of the outer edge of the trunk shape inlets is 3.6 times of the diameter of the inner edge.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the wind-powered pneumatic engine further comprises an HPCA regeneration, storage and supply system composed of an air tank and a first HPCA compressor connected with each other, an output of the air tank is connected with the air-jet system, the first HPCA compressor is operably connected with the impeller, the power output generated after the impeller's operation drives the first HPCA compressor, and the HPCA regenerated by the first HPCA compressor is input into and stored in the air tank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the wind-powered pneumatic engine further comprises a deceleration and brake pressurizing system and a second HPCA compressor, the second HPCA compressor is driven by a braking force generated by the deceleration and brake pressurizing system when decelerated to regenerate HPCA, and the regenerated HPCA is input into and stored in the air tank.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the air-jet system comprises a first controller, a distributor, a first air-jet pipe set and a first air-jet nozzle set operably connected in sequence, the HPCA stored in an air tank is input into the distributor through the first controller, and is then diverged by the distributor and input into each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set, and the HPCA is then jetted into the impeller chamber by each air-jet nozzle of the first air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the first air-jet pipe set.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the air-jet system further comprises a second controller, a distribution controller for converting the input HPCA into intermittent burst HPCA, a second air-jet pipe set, and a second air-jet nozzle set operably connected in sequence, the HPCA stored in the air tank is input into the distribution controller through the second controller, and the intermittent burst HPCA is generated by the distribution controller and distributed to each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set, and is then jetted into the impeller chamber by each air-jet nozzle of the second air-jet nozzle set connected with each air-jet pipe of the second air-jet pipe set.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The motor vehicle as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, comprising two impeller chambers, each having an impeller disposed therein, wherein said at least one air inlet for receiving the external wind resistance airflow is disposed on at least one of the impeller chambers.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
