<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641041-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641041</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12175339</doc-number>
<date>20080717</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>47</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>47</main-group>
<subgroup>04</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>1984688</main-classification>
<further-classification>414569</further-classification>
<further-classification>187256</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Conveying device</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>1586768</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Allen</name>
<date>19260600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>187256</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2025575</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Danz</name>
<date>19351200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414594</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2265891</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bertelsen</name>
<date>19411200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>187256</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2609111</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Daves et al.</name>
<date>19520900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414594</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3417857</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hickey</name>
<date>19681200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1984634</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4313266</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Tam</name>
<date>19820200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1984688</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>19846801</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>1984688</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>1984689</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198832</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198835</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>414569</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>414594</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>187256</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>2423524</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>254265</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>254266</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>254278</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Ming-Hsun</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tsai</last-name>
<first-name>Chung-Hsuan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Fa-Chin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shia</last-name>
<first-name>Banger</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Datatronics Technology, Inc.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bidwell</last-name>
<first-name>James R</first-name>
<department>3651</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A conveying device comprises a body in which a power source and two scroll wheels of the same diameter and rotating synchronously are disposed. Each scroll wheel is wound with an elongated elastic extension plate having rigidity, and one end of each elastic extension plate extends out of the body. When in use, the power source is used to drive the two scroll wheel to rotate synchronously, so as to drive the elastic extension plates of the two scroll wheels to synchronously extend out of or retract in the body. When the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body are assembled with a clamp or a loading seat, thereby, the conveying operation can be carried out.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="222.25mm" wi="120.73mm" file="US07641041-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="183.39mm" wi="131.32mm" file="US07641041-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="164.68mm" wi="132.59mm" file="US07641041-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="177.21mm" wi="149.35mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641041-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="241.81mm" wi="141.39mm" file="US07641041-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="178.22mm" wi="126.32mm" file="US07641041-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="168.32mm" wi="153.59mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641041-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a conveying device, and more particularly to a conveying device which utilizes the synchronous movement of two elastic extension plates to offer the conveying function.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Regarding most of the automatic flows, no matter in the fabrication of semiconductor or in the fabrication and burning operation of the optical disc, the conveying step can not be omitted. Conventional conveying devices all utilize a platform which moves along a fixed rail to offer the conveying function. If focusing on the stability, two parallel rails are provided for the movement of the platform. However, the shortcoming of this conveying device is that its rails are positioned on the floor, so the conveying path also must be fixed according to the rails, and the conveying path cannot be changed flexibly.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In addition, when the conveying device is not used, since the rails are positioned on the floor and cannot be disassembled freely, it will cause a spatial obstacle. Consequently, how to solve the abovementioned problems is one objective of making the automatic flow much more progressive.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The present invention has arisen to mitigate and/or obviate the afore-described disadvantages.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The primary objective of the present invention is to provide a conveying device. It utilizes two scroll wheels which are the same in diameter and rotate synchronously to scroll an elastic extension plate with rigidity to extend or retract, respectively. The two elastic extension plates extend or retract synchronously, in order to offer the conveying function when the two elastic extension plates are assembled with a loading seat or a clamp and the like. Thus achieving the objective that rails are not needed to preset.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To achieve the abovementioned objective, the conveying device of the present invention comprises:</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">a body formed with a gap;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">a power source assembled in the body;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">two scroll wheels of the same diameter rotating synchronously, and rotating axes of the two wheels being parallel assembled in the body, the rotating directions of the two scroll wheels are opposite; and</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">at least one of the scroll wheels being driven by the power source; and two elongated elastic extension plates with rigidity, one end of each elastic extension plate being fixed on each scroll wheel, and each elastic extension plate being wound on each scroll wheel from inside to outside, the other end of each elastic extension plate extending out of the body through the gap of the body, each elastic extension plate is driven to extend or retract through rotation of each scroll wheel, thus carrying out a conveying operation.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Both peripheries of the abovementioned two scroll wheels are formed with the same number of teeth, and the two scroll wheels rotate synchronously in opposite directions by an engagement of their teeth.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The power source is a motor.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The body further includes a driving mechanism which is driven to rotate by the power source and used to drive respective scroll wheels to rotate.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The driving mechanism is formed by a coaxial connection of an input part and an output part which are connected with the power source and one of the scroll wheels, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The input part and the output part of the driving mechanism are gears, and the input part and the output part are engaged with the power source and the scroll wheel, respectively.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The driving mechanism is formed by a coaxial connection of an input part, an output part and a driving part, the input part is connected with the power source, the output part and the driving part are, respectively, connected with the two scroll wheels.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Both the input part and the output part of the driving mechanism are gears, and the driving part is a belt pulley, and the input part is engaged with the power source, the output part is engaged with one of the scroll wheels, the driving part utilizes a belt to drive the other scroll wheel to rotate.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">A loading seat is assembled to the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">A clamp is assembled to the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">A conveying method comprises the steps of: winding two elastic extension plates, from inside to outside, onto two parallel scroll wheels of the same diameter and rotating synchronously in opposite directions; positioning an object on the two elastic extension plates, rotating the two elastic extension plates and making the two elastic extension plates move synchronously and equidistantly; releasing the object after it is moved to a predefined position, to accomplish the conveying operation.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The advantages of the present invention are that: when the two scroll wheels are rotated in opposite directions by the power source, the two elastic extension plates will be driven to synchronously extend out of or retract in the body; and when the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body are assembled with a clamp or a loading seat, the conveying operation can be carried out; rails are not needed to preset, because of the two elastic extension plates which are used to perform the conveying operation; additionally, the conveying path can be changed by changing the extending or retracting direction of the two elastic extension plates.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a conveying device in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of the conveying device in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows that two scroll wheels are linked with each other by their teeth in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows that two elastic extension plates are assembled with a loading seat and extend outwards in accordance with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows that the two elastic extension plates are assembled with the loading seat and retract inwards in accordance with the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows that the two scroll wheels are driven to rotate by a belt in accordance with the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The present invention will be more clear from the following description when viewed together with the accompanying drawings, which show, for purpose of illustrations only, the preferred embodiment in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, a conveying device in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention comprises a body <b>10</b>, a power source <b>20</b> and two scroll wheels <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The body <b>20</b> includes a gap <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The power source <b>20</b> is assembled in the body <b>10</b>, and the power source <b>20</b> of this preferred embodiment is a motor.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The two scroll wheels <b>30</b> are assembled in the body <b>10</b>, and the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> are the same in diameter and linked with each other. At least one scroll wheel <b>30</b> is driven by the power source <b>20</b>. Both the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> include a plurality of teeth <b>31</b>. The two scroll wheels <b>30</b> have the same number of teeth <b>31</b> and are engaged with each other, so as to enable themselves to rotate synchronously in opposite directions. Moreover, the power source <b>20</b> utilizes a driving mechanism <b>40</b> to drive one of the scroll wheels <b>30</b> directly to rotate. The driving mechanism <b>40</b> of this embodiment is formed by the coaxial connection of an input part <b>41</b> and an output part <b>42</b>. The input part <b>41</b> and the output part <b>42</b> are connected to the power source <b>20</b> and one of the scroll wheels <b>30</b> respectively. Moreover, both the input part <b>41</b> and the output part <b>42</b> are gears, and the number of the teeth of the input part <b>41</b> is larger than that of the output part <b>42</b>. The input part <b>41</b> and the output part <b>42</b> are engaged with the power source <b>20</b> and one scroll wheel <b>30</b> respectively, by such arrangements that the power source <b>20</b> can utilize the driving mechanism <b>40</b> to drive one scroll wheel <b>30</b> to rotate. Additionally, each scroll wheel <b>30</b> is provided with an elongated elastic extension plate <b>50</b> having rigidity, and the elastic extension plate <b>50</b> is made of flexible alloy, plastic material or other similar materials. One end of each elastic extension plate <b>50</b> is fixed to each scroll wheel <b>30</b>. Each elastic extension plate <b>50</b> is wound on each scroll wheel <b>30</b> from inside to outside. The other end of each elastic extension plate <b>50</b> extends out of the body <b>10</b> from the gap <b>11</b> of the body <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">When in use, the power source <b>20</b> is used to drive at least one scroll wheel <b>30</b> to rotate, and when the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> are linked with each other to rotate synchronously, each elastic extension plate <b>50</b> wound on each scroll wheel <b>30</b> will be scrolled to extend out of or retract into the body <b>10</b>. The power source <b>20</b> utilizes the driving mechanism <b>40</b> to drive one of the scroll wheels <b>30</b> to rotate, and the power source <b>20</b> being a motor is engaged with the input part <b>41</b> of the driving mechanism <b>40</b>, so as to drive the driving mechanism <b>40</b> to rotate. The output part <b>42</b> of the driving mechanism <b>40</b> is engaged with the teeth <b>31</b> of one scroll wheel <b>30</b> to rotate this scroll wheel <b>30</b> to rotate. The two scroll wheels <b>30</b> are linked with each other by the engagement of their teeth <b>31</b>. By such arrangements, the power source <b>20</b> will drive the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> to rotate synchronously, thus enabling the elastic extension plate <b>50</b> of each scroll wheel <b>30</b> to extend or retract synchronously. When the ends of the two elastic extension plates <b>50</b> extended out of the body are assembled with a loading seat A, the two elastic extension plates <b>50</b> can be used to move the loading seat A to change the distance between the loading seat A and the body <b>10</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, thereby, the conveying operation can be carried out.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Moreover, besides the power source <b>20</b> utilizes the engagement of the driving mechanism <b>40</b> and one of scroll wheels <b>30</b> to drive in the abovementioned embodiment, the power source <b>20</b> can also be directly engaged with one or both of the scroll wheels <b>30</b> to drive. The power source <b>20</b> can also, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, utilizes a driving mechanism <b>40</b> to synchronously drive the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> to rotate. The driving mechanism <b>40</b> of this embodiment is formed by the coaxial connection of an input part <b>41</b> and an output part <b>42</b> and a driving part <b>43</b>. The input part and the output part are gears, and the driving part <b>43</b> is a belt pulley. The diameter of the input part <b>41</b> is larger than that of the output part <b>42</b> and the driving part <b>43</b>. The periphery of one of the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> includes a plurality of teeth <b>31</b> used to engage with the output part <b>42</b>, and one side of the other scroll wheel <b>30</b> is coaxially disposed a belt pulley C. A belt B<b>1</b> is wound on the peripheries of the belt pulley C and the driving part <b>41</b>. By such arrangements, the power source <b>20</b> can be engaged with the input part <b>41</b> of the driving mechanism <b>40</b> to drive the driving mechanism <b>40</b> to rotate, and the driving mechanism <b>40</b> utilizes the output part <b>42</b> to engage with and rotate one of the scroll wheels <b>30</b>. The transmission part <b>43</b> utilizes the belt B<b>1</b> to drive the other scroll wheel <b>30</b> with the belt pulley C to rotate. Moreover, the two scroll wheels <b>30</b> can still rotate synchronously in opposite directions, after a proper adjustment of the diameters of the output part <b>42</b> and the driving part <b>43</b> of the driving mechanism <b>40</b> and the diameters of the scroll wheel <b>30</b> with the belt pulley C and the belt pulley C.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In addition, the ends of the two elastic extension plates <b>50</b> extended out of the body can be assembled with not only the abovementioned loading seat A, but also a clamp, a structure which can be used to fix, load or position an object, etc.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As known from the abovementioned structure, the conveying method is to, respectively, from inside to outside, wind two elastic extension plates on two scroll wheels which have the same diameters, rotate synchronously in opposite directions and whose rotating axes are parallel to each other. The two elastic extension plates are elongated and have rigidity. The conveying operation is carried out by the following steps of: firstly, positioning the object on the two elastic extension plates and rotating the two scroll wheels, making the two elastic extension plates carry out the synchronous and equidistant displacement, lastly, releasing the object which has been moved to a predefined position by the two elastic extension plates.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">To summarize, the conveying device of the present invention is assembled with a power source, two scroll wheels that are the same in diameter and linked with each other are assembled inside the body. Each scroll wheel is provided with an elongated elastic extension plate having rigidity. One end of each elastic extension plate is fixed on each scroll wheel. Each elastic extension plate is wound on each scroll wheel from inside to outside, and the other end extends out of the body. When in use, the power source will drive the two scroll wheels to rotate synchronously, so that the elastic extension plates of the two scroll wheels will extend out or retract in the body. When the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body are assembled with a structure which can be used to fix, load or position an object, the conveying operation can be carried out.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">While we have shown and described various embodiments in accordance with the present invention, it is clear to those skilled in the art that further embodiments may be made without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A conveying device comprising:
<claim-text>a body formed with a gap;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a power source assembled in the body;</claim-text>
<claim-text>two scroll wheels of the same diameter rotating synchronously, and rotating axes of the two wheels being parallelly assembled in the body, the two scroll wheels rotating in opposite directions and at least one of the scroll wheels being driven by the power source; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two elongated elastic extension plates with rigidity, one end of each elastic extension plate being fixed on each scroll wheel, and each elastic extension plate being wound on each scroll wheel from inside to outside, the other end of each elastic extension plate extending out of the body through the gap of the body, each elastic extension plate is driven to extend or retract through rotation of each scroll wheel, thus carrying out a conveying operation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that both peripheries of the two scroll wheels are formed with the same number of teeth, and the two scroll wheels rotate synchronously in opposite directions by engagement of their teeth.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the body further includes a driving mechanism which is driven to rotate by the power source and used to drive respective scroll wheels to rotate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, characterized in that the driving mechanism is formed by a coaxial connection of an input part and an output part which are connected with the power source and one of the scroll wheels, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, characterized in that the input part and the output part of the driving mechanism are gears, and the input part and the output part are engaged with the power source and the scroll wheel, respectively.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, characterized in that the driving mechanism is formed by a coaxial connection of an input part, an output part and a driving part, the input part is connected with the power source, the output part and the driving part are, respectively, connected with the two scroll wheels.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, characterized in that both the input part and the output part of the driving mechanism are gears, and the driving part is a belt pulley, and the input part is engaged with the power source, the output part is engaged with one of the scroll wheels, the driving part utilizes a belt to drive the other scroll wheel to rotate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that a loading seat is assembled to the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The conveying device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that a clamp is assembled to the ends of the two elastic extension plates extended out of the body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A conveying method comprising the steps of: winding two elastic extension plates, from inside to outside, onto two parallel scroll wheels of the same diameter and rotating synchronously in opposite directions; positioning an object on the two elastic extension plates, rotating the two elastic extension plates and making the two elastic extension plates move synchronously and equidistantly; releasing the object after it is moved to a predefined position, to accomplish the conveying operation. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
