<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641021-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641021</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11352638</doc-number>
<date>20060213</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>10 2005 007 789</doc-number>
<date>20050219</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>412</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>60</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>23</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180333</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Hand-actuated operating device for an operator's control station of an industrial truck</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3542161</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Ulinski</name>
<date>19701100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>187222</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6089353</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bartels et al.</name>
<date>20000700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>187224</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7278509</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Schroder et al.</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180333</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2002/0074179</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Brandt et al.</name>
<date>20020600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180252</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0098375</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>David et al.</name>
<date>20050500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180333</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0191733</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Paquin</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180333</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0199398</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ott et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 74471 XY</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0023250</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hefner et al.</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>180332</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>295 18 604</doc-number>
<date>19960300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>195 48 950</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>297 14 284</doc-number>
<date>19971100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>00/64801</doc-number>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>180333</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060185938</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060824</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Behncke</last-name>
<first-name>Christoph</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bad Segeberg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Niebuhr</last-name>
<first-name>Michael</first-name>
<address>
<city>Bargteheide</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Vidas, Arrett &#x26; Steinkraus, P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Jungheinrich Aktiengesellschaft</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Hamburg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dickson</last-name>
<first-name>Paul N</first-name>
<department>3616</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Amores</last-name>
<first-name>Karen Jane J</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A hand-actuated operating device for an operator's control unit for an industrial truck, having a stationary, raised rest for the ball of the thumb that is disposed laterally beside and in front of the standing or sitting operator, including an upper support area on which the ball of the thumb of the operator's hand is adapted to be placed from top, a forward surface facing away from the operator and a surface facing the operator, wherein the forward and backward surfaces are dimensioned so to allow the support for the ball of the thumb to be gripped between the fingers and a proximal portion of the ball that faces the wrist, a portion located in front of the forward surface which is lowered with respect to the support area is disposed such as to allow the fingers of the hand resting on the support area to be placed at an angle, and at least one control element for a function of the industrial truck is disposed on the end of the lowered portion that is located opposite the support area so as to enable its actuation by at least one finger.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="175.01mm" wi="150.11mm" file="US07641021-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="168.74mm" wi="149.61mm" file="US07641021-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="238.42mm" wi="171.53mm" file="US07641021-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="206.93mm" wi="150.45mm" file="US07641021-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">Not applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">STATEMENT REGARDING FEDERALLY SPONSORED RESEARCH</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Not applicable.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">DE 297 14 284 U1 has made known a hand-actuated setting device for the operator's control station of a fork-lift reach truck in which three operating levers which are supported about an approximately horizontal axis and are arranged side by side in the direction of travel of the fork-lift truck are seated on a common shaft. Each operating lever has a lever head which can be gripped and actuated from above. The lower ends of the lever portions actuate hydraulic valves in such a way that the inner operating lever, which is disposed nearest to the driver, causes the load-carrying means to be raised and lowered whereas the middle one and the outer, farthest one cause the load-carrying means to move. The heads of the operating levers, as viewed from above, are located on a bent line such that if gripping changes over to another head an elbow supported on a rest will substantially maintain its position.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">WO/00/64801 has made known an operating device for an industrial truck with a control element which can be grasped from above, using several fingers of a hand in order to move the element forwards or backwards in the direction of the fingers. The width of the control element is smaller than the width of the hand so that the little finger and, if needed, the ring finger or even more fingers of the hand can be supported on an area which is located next to the control element. The support area of the control element serves for actuating individual functions of the vehicle.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In the case mentioned last, there is a multi-function lever which is capable of realizing a multiplicity of functions. However, the operator can support his hand only insufficiently. Supporting is possible if there are single-function levers, but several functions cannot be carried out simultaneously. In both of the known instances, it is impossible for the operator to support himself, on one hand, while actuating a function, on the other.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">It is the object of the invention to provide hand-actuated operating device for an operator's control unit of an industrial truck on which the operator can support himself and hold tight, on one hand, and is able to actuate various functions of the industrial truck, on the other, by using one or more fingers of the supporting hand.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The inventive operating device includes a stationary, raised rest for the ball of the thumb that is suitably disposed on a holder laterally and slightly in front of the operator and is provided with an upper support area on which the ball of the thumb of the hand is adapted to be placed from top. The support area is limited in the direction of the fingers of the resting hand because the support area substantially serves for placing the ball of the thumb only. The limitation is pre-defined by a forward area and a backward area declining from the support area. According to the invention, a portion which is lowered with respect to the support area is disposed in order that the fingers of the hand resting on the support area may take an angled posture. This allows to bring the fingers, which are at an angle, to a relaxed position when the operator's hand rests on the support area. At the same time, it is possible for the operator to grip over the rest for the ball of the thumb to absorb dynamic forces originating from the travelling motion through the operator's firm grasp. At this stage, the fingers can lie against the forward area and the proximal portion of the ball of the thumb can be supported on the rearward area. According to the invention, at least one control element for a function of the industrial truck is disposed on the side of the lowered portion that is located opposite the support area so as to enable its actuation by at least one finger.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The inventive rest for the ball of the thumb allows to associate therewith a plurality of control elements for the various functions of an industrial truck, e.g. for a reverse of the direction of travel, the actuation of the horn, a proportional actuation of various hydraulic functions, etc. The invention achieves a hold-fast function which permits the operator to safely support himself when the driver is acted on by dynamic forces on the vehicle accordingly. If the control elements are not actuated a relaxed hand position with the fingers placed at a slight downward angle and, hence, at a relaxed position will become possible by the fact that the lowered portion is in front of the support area for the ball of the thumb. Furthermore, the support area is formed so as to adapt itself to different hand sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to an aspect of the invention, a plurality of adjacently arranged operating levers are provided. The levers preferably serve for actuating hydraulic functions and preferably generate analog control signals to achieve a proportional position of the respective hydraulic functions when the operating levers are swung out.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to another aspect of the invention, at least one further control elements is laterally attached to the rest for the ball of the thumb so as to allow the element to be actuated by the thumb of the hand which rests on the support area. Preferably, the further control element is of an oblong shape in the thumb direction so that it may be actuated from different hand positions. The switching or control organs actuated by the control elements can function in a digital or analogue manner.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">According to another aspect of the invention, the support area is wider than the lowered portion. The support area is so wide that the hand can be soundly placed thereon even if the hand size is at a maximum. Near the lowered portion, it is possible to arrange a further control element which can be actuated, for example, by the little finger or ring finger of the hand which rests on the support area.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">According to another aspect of the invention, the support area is domed to be slightly convex to adapt it to the contour of the ball of the thumb. Towards the wrist, according to another aspect of the invention, the support area declines towards the base in a dome-like fashion in order to ensure sufficient support in the direction of the pressure acting onto the rest of the ball of the thumb.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">According to another aspect of the invention, the support area on the thumb side extends into the interior of the region of the lowered portion. This allows for a tactile orientation by a lateral touch with the index finger (right hand) and a grasp at thumb-actuated control elements and a lateral support at any time.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Another aspect provides that the hand rest defines a common, self-contained functional unit. This allows to mount the inventive operating device on different apparatuses. A combination into a assembly unit also enables to efficiently safeguard it from environmental influences such as moisture and dirt. Moreover, it is possible to house the electronic equipment required for the control of the functional units, e.g. in the form of a printed circuit board, within the rest for the ball of the thumb that is configured in the shape of a shell body, for example.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The functional unit as a whole may simply be exchanged against other control elements or units.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The invention will be described in more detail below with reference to an embodiment shown in the drawings.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a perspective view of an inventive operating device which is configured as a functional unit.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the operating device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with a hand placed thereon with no operation.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a representation similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> with an operating lever actuated in a first position of the hand.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows a representation similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, but with the hand in a different position.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows how to actuate another operating lever in an arrangement of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows a perspective view of a counterweight fork-lift truck including an operating device of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">While this invention may be embodied in many different forms, there are described in detail herein a specific preferred embodiment of the invention. This description is an exemplification of the principles of the invention and is not intended to limit the invention to the particular embodiment illustrated</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a counterweight fork-lift truck <b>50</b> is shown in a conventional construction. A seat <b>52</b> for the driver can be recognized in the cab and, on the right-hand side of the seat, an armrest <b>54</b> at the forward end of which a control unit <b>10</b> is mounted. During an actuation of the control unit <b>10</b>, the lower arm may lie, but need not, on the armrest <b>54</b>. More details of the control unit <b>10</b> are evident from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates more details of the control unit <b>10</b> which has a shell body <b>12</b> of a plastic material. The shell body <b>12</b> is arranged at an appropriate place in the control station of an industrial truck on a base (not shown), e.g. on the right-hand side next to the driver's place at a slightly elevated position, so that the driver may put his arm onto an armrest where the shell body is in front of the armrest. However, the latter is not a prerequisite. The following terms &#x201c;at rear&#x201d; and &#x201c;at front&#x201d;, if applied, will refer to the operator who, using his right hand, actuates a control unit located at his right-hand side and in front thereof at an angle.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The shell body <b>12</b> has an upper support area <b>14</b> which, doming towards the rear, passes over into a rear area <b>16</b>. Towards the front, the support area <b>14</b> is joined by a lower-positioned shoulder <b>18</b> with the passage from the support area <b>14</b> effected via a rounded edge <b>20</b>. The shoulder <b>18</b> is smaller in width than is the support area <b>14</b> (also see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref>) with the edge <b>20</b> having a stand-back step <b>22</b> in the region of the right-hand end of the shoulder <b>18</b>. Next to the shoulder <b>18</b> and at a position slightly lower or equally high as that of the shoulder <b>18</b>, a control key <b>24</b> is arranged the width of which is such that it extends up to the right-hand side of the unit <b>10</b> (also see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">On the left-hand side of the unit <b>10</b>, an oblong control key <b>26</b> is countersunk in the shell body which as is evident from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref> protrudes slightly beyond the remaining side areas of the unit <b>10</b>. Below the oblong control key, another control key <b>28</b> is countersunk in the side of the unit <b>10</b>, but is clearly shorter than is the control key <b>26</b>. Intermediate switches, actuation rockers or the like may be provided in lieu of control keys <b>26</b> and <b>28</b>. Their modes of action may be digital or analogue.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The front side of the shoulder <b>18</b> has hinged thereto four angled levers <b>30</b>, <b>32</b>, <b>34</b>, and <b>36</b> side by side. The lower legs of the levers <b>30</b> to <b>36</b> extend to be approximately horizontal whereas the upper legs extend to be approximately vertical. The upper ends of the vertical legs have mounted or formed thereon heads <b>38</b>, <b>40</b>, <b>42</b>, <b>44</b>. The operating levers <b>30</b> through <b>36</b> are used to perform various hydraulic functions of the industrial truck, which is not shown, the actuated switches being analogue switches to obtain a proportional actuation in dependence on the swing of the levers <b>30</b> through <b>36</b>. The control key <b>26</b> serves for reversing the direction of travel of the industrial truck in the present case and the control key <b>28</b> is provided for an extra function. The control key <b>24</b> also serves for actuating an extra function. The operating heads may be made of a soft and/or rough material to make them movable forwards and backwards by a finger. Moreover, the heads may have a contour which allows for their easy operation.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The heads <b>38</b> through <b>44</b> are disposed on an arc having a large radius and their distances are chosen so as to make possible their appropriate actuation by the fingers of the resting hand.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref> illustrate various positions of a hand which interacts with the control unit <b>10</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows the way the ball of the thumb rest on the support area <b>14</b> while also abutting against the area <b>16</b> extending downwards in a dome. Therefore, forces which strive to move the body of the operator, who is not shown, to the front may be absorbed by a supporting action on the area <b>16</b>. The fingers of the hand are at a downward angle and extend in the direction of the shoulder <b>18</b>. Forces acting on the operator which strive to move the body to the rear can be absorbed by the operator by his gripping behind the area which declines towards the shoulder <b>18</b>. For the rest, the hand may freely lie on the rest for the ball of the thumb and the thumb can casually lie laterally next to or above the control key <b>26</b>, which is not compulsory, however, as can be appreciated from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">What becomes obvious from <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 through 5</figref> is that a portion of the support area <b>14</b> extends beside the shoulder <b>18</b>. The portion is designated <b>46</b> in the Figures. In the representation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the index finger laterally bears on this projection <b>46</b>. It constitutes a tactile orientation for the operator.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows the way the index finger actuates the control key <b>38</b> and pushes the associated lever to the front. At the same time, the control key <b>26</b> is actuated by the thumb <b>26</b>. The same actuation takes place in the representation of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> where the hand, however, takes a somewhat more retracted position relative to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>. The shapes of the support area <b>14</b> and control unit and shell body <b>12</b> altogether are such as to allow the ball of the thumb to take different positions, but allow to actuate the described control keys notwithstanding this. This shape also allows for an adaptation to different hand sizes. The oblong shape of the control key <b>26</b> allows for an actuation, starting from different hand positions (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows the way the buttons <b>40</b> and <b>44</b> are actuated by the index finger and middle finger. At the same time, the control key <b>24</b> could be actuated by the little finger.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 through 5</figref>, a phantom line <b>48</b> can be recognized in the region of the support area <b>14</b>. The line is to indicate that the shoulder area declining towards the shoulder <b>18</b> stands back to the rear in the lower region to offer an efficient possibility for a grasp by the fingers.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Switches and similar components which are actuated by the individual levers or keys are accommodated inside the shell body <b>12</b>, e.g. on a common printed circuit board. It is preferred that the levers, rockers or the like which provide for a possible actuation in opposed directions be given a neutral position to which they are restored by a spring after they were swung.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The above disclosure is intended to be illustrative and not exhaustive. This description will suggest many variations and alternatives to one of ordinary skill in this art. All these alternatives and variations are intended to be included within the scope of the claims where the term &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; means &#x201c;including, but not limited to&#x201d;. Those familiar with the art may recognize other equivalents to the specific embodiments described herein which equivalents are also intended to be encompassed by the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Further, the particular features presented in the dependent claims can be combined with each other in other manners within the scope of the invention such that the invention should be recognized as also specifically directed to other embodiments having any other possible combination of the features of the dependent claims. For instance, for purposes of claim publication, any dependent claim which follows should be taken as alternatively written in a multiple dependent form from all prior claims which possess all antecedents referenced in such dependent claim if such multiple dependent format is an accepted format within the jurisdiction (e.g. each claim depending directly from claim <b>1</b> should be alternatively taken as depending from all previous claims). In jurisdictions where multiple dependent claim formats are restricted, the following dependent claims should each be also taken as alternatively written in each singly dependent claim format which creates a dependency from a prior antecedent-possessing claim other than the specific claim listed in such dependent claim below.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">This completes the description of the preferred and alternate embodiments of the invention. Those skilled in the art may recognize other equivalents to the specific embodiment described herein which equivalents are intended to be encompassed by the claims attached hereto.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A hand-actuated operating device for an operator's control station of an industrial truck, having a stationary, raised rest (<b>12</b>) for the ball of the thumb that is disposed laterally beside and in front of the operator, including an upper support area (<b>14</b>) on which the ball of the thumb of the operator's hand is adapted to be placed from top, a forward surface (<b>20</b>) facing away from the operator and a backward surface (<b>16</b>) facing the operator, wherein the forward and backward surfaces (<b>16</b>) are dimensioned so to allow the support for the ball of the thumb to be gripped between the fingers and a proximal portion of the ball, a portion (<b>18</b>), which is lowered with respect to the upper support area (<b>14</b>), and located in front of the forward surface and is disposed such as to allow the fingers of the hand resting on the support area (<b>14</b>) to be placed at an angle, and at least one control element for a function of the industrial truck is disposed on the end of the lowered portion (<b>18</b>) that is located opposite the support area (<b>14</b>) so as to enable its actuation by at least one finger,
<claim-text>the support area (<b>14</b>), the lowered portion (<b>18</b>), the forward and rearward surfaces (<b>20</b>, <b>16</b>) are formed by a body of a shell body (<b>12</b>), the at least one control element being laterally accommodated by the shell to allow the at least one control element to be actuated by the thumb of the hand which rests on the support area, the shell and the control elements define a common, self-contained functional unit (<b>10</b>) which accommodates switches adapted to be actuated by the control elements and the further accommodates other electric and electronic components for the control of the functions</claim-text>
<claim-text>further characterized in that a plurality of adjacently arranged control elements (<b>30</b> through <b>36</b>) are provided and wherein the plurality of adjacently arranged control elements are disposed on an arc having a large radius, with their distances chosen so as to make their appropriate actuation by the fingers of the operator's hand.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the at least one control element is comprised of control elements (<b>30</b> through <b>36</b>) which are substantially mounted to be movable forwards and backwards.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that at least one lateral control element (<b>26</b>) is of an oblong shape in the thumb direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the support area (<b>14</b>) is wider than the lowered portion (<b>18</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, characterized in that a lateral control element (<b>24</b>) is disposed near the lowered portion (<b>18</b>) so as to enable the at least one control element to be preferably actuated by the little finger or ring finger of the hand which rests on the support area (<b>14</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the support area (<b>14</b>) is convex or cylindrically domed to adapt it to the contour of the ball of the thumb.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the support area (<b>14</b>) passes over in a rounded shape into the rearward area on the side directed to the wrist of the resting hand.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that a portion of the support area (<b>14</b>) on the thumb side extends into the interior of the region of the lowered portion (<b>18</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the raised rest (<b>12</b>) for the ball of the thumb and the support area (<b>14</b>) are designed so as to enable the control elements to be actuated from different rest positions of the hand.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the raised rest (<b>12</b>) for the ball of the thumb and the control elements define a common, self-contained functional unit (<b>10</b>).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The operating device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, characterized in that the shell body accommodates a printed circuit board for electronic components.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
