<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641040-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641040</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12004318</doc-number>
<date>20071219</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>65</class>
<subclass>G</subclass>
<main-group>47</main-group>
<subgroup>14</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198396</main-classification>
<further-classification>19839701</further-classification>
<further-classification>414 13</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Textile separating apparatus</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2954862</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Clark</name>
<date>19601000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198443</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4917562</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Colli et al.</name>
<date>19900400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414420</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4943198</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>McCabe</name>
<date>19900700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5586637</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Aidlin et al.</name>
<date>19961200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>198396</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5617804</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Savio</name>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5810149</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sandberg et al.</name>
<date>19980900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5988356</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Bonnet</name>
<date>19991100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6089810</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Heinz et al.</name>
<date>20000700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6116849</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fesmire et al.</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>414 13</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7284667</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Weir</name>
<date>20071000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198396</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>19839701</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198443</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>198444</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>414 13</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 38  8</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification> 38  9</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>209937</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>4</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60876925</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20061221</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080149460</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080626</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Harris</last-name>
<first-name>David W.</first-name>
<address>
<street>15541 NE. Eilers Rd.</street>
<city>Aurora</city>
<state>OR</state>
<postcode>97002</postcode>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Kolisch Hartwell, P.C.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Bidwell</last-name>
<first-name>James R</first-name>
<department>3651</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A textile separating apparatus may include a textile collection area for supporting the pile of textile items, and a transport mechanism having an inclined face intersecting the pile of textile items. One or more pick members may project from the face of the transport mechanism, and may successively separate and carry individual textile items from the pile of textile items towards a textile receiving area.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="94.32mm" wi="249.85mm" file="US07641040-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="261.03mm" wi="179.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641040-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="265.60mm" wi="181.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641040-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from U.S. Provisional Patent Application Ser. No. 60/876,925 of David William Harris for TEXTILE PACKAGING SYSTEM, filed Dec. 21, 2006, the disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates generally to a textile separating apparatus, and more specifically, to a textile separating apparatus for the separation of individual textile items from a pile of textile items, thereby aiding in inspection, sorting, and/or assembly of the textiles into groups or packages.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Generally, management of textiles requires separation of individual textile items from a pile or heap of textile items so that each textile item may be inspected, counted, and/or distributed into appropriate groups or packages. Each package or group may be desired to have a predetermined number and/or quality of textile items. The current methods used to separate textile items, such as selection and inspection by hand, are operator dependant, thus rates of production are widely variable, and require constant repetitive motions by the operator to process the textile items. Additionally, more than one operator is often needed. Typically, separation and distribution of the textile items by hand is an accurate, but time consuming and labor intensive process that requires each individual textile item, from a pile of textile items of undetermined number and quality, be manually selected and separated from the pile for inspection and counting.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view of a textile separating apparatus in accordance with the present disclosure, showing a textile collection area, a transport mechanism, and a textile receiving area, including an inspection station and an automated bagging system.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view of a textile separating apparatus in accordance with the present disclosure, showing an exemplary transport mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a textile separating apparatus in accordance with the present disclosure, showing an exemplary transport mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a detailed view of a segment of the transport mechanism in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, illustrating pick members projecting from an inclined face of the transport mechanism in accordance with the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In view of the foregoing disadvantages inherent in the existing methods of manual separation of textile items for inspection, counting, and/or packaging, the present disclosure provides a new strategy in textile separation. Namely, the present disclosure describes a textile separating apparatus for the successive selection of a number of individual textile items from a pile of textile items, thereby aiding in inspection, sorting, and/or packaging in groups of a predetermined number and/or quality.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present textile separating apparatus, which will be described subsequently in greater detail, employs a new technology in regards to the textile industry. Some embodiments of a textile separating apparatus may generally include a textile collection area for supporting a pile of textile items, and a textile receiving area. A transport mechanism having an inclined face may span the distance between the textile collection area and the textile receiving area, and may further intersect the pile of textile items. A pick member projecting from the face of the transport mechanism may separate and carry a textile item towards the textile receiving area.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Some embodiments of a textile separating apparatus may include a looped transport mechanism intersecting a pile of textile items supported by the textile collection area. Further, in some embodiments, a pick member projecting from the transport mechanism may move in a continuous circuit to successively separate, and carry away individual textile items to a textile receiving area.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In some embodiments, the textile collection area may further include an advancement mechanism for the movement of textile items towards the transport mechanism at a controlled rate. The rate may be adjustable to insure that the rate of travel is timed to supply an appropriate quantity of textile items to the transport mechanism.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The textile receiving area may further include mechanism for further processing the separated textile items, such as an inspection station moving at a controlled rate away from the transport mechanism, a photoelectric eye to count textile items, a gate programmed to alternatively allow or impede the progression of the textile items, and/or an automated bagging system.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As described herein, a textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> may be configured in accordance with the present disclosure to separate, and carry away, individual textile items from a pile of textile items. The separated textile items may then be further processed as desired into packages of textiles of a predetermined number, and/or quality. For example, the separated textile items may be inspected for quality purposes, counted, and/or bagged. For clarity, textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> is illustrated without textile items in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, and with textile items in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> may include a textile collection area <b>12</b> supporting plural textile items such as those shown in pile P, and a powered transport mechanism <b>14</b> intersecting the pile of textile items P. In accordance with the present disclosure, a pick member <b>16</b>, projecting from a face <b>34</b> of transport mechanism <b>14</b>, may separate and carry away a textile item up an incline from the pile of textile items P towards a textile receiving area <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In some embodiments, textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> may further include mechanism for processing of separated textile items at textile receiving area <b>18</b>. For example, textile receiving area <b>18</b> may include an inspection station <b>38</b> to receive and convey the separated textile items from transport mechanism <b>14</b>, and/or an automated bagging system <b>20</b> for packaging the separated textile items.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Textile collection area <b>12</b> may include structure to contain the pile of textile items P. In some examples of textile separating apparatus <b>10</b>, textile collection area <b>12</b> may include a bin <b>22</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, bin <b>22</b> may include side walls <b>24</b>, a rear wall <b>26</b> distal with respect to transport mechanism <b>14</b>, and a front wall <b>28</b> adjacent transport mechanism <b>14</b>. Bin <b>22</b> may be characterized by angles and dimensions suitable for containing the pile of textile items P, and, further, may be shaped and/or configured to direct the pile of textiles items P towards transport mechanism <b>14</b>. For example, part or all of side walls <b>24</b> may be inwardly sloping towards the bottom of bin <b>22</b>. Further, as best seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, front wall <b>28</b> may be angled towards transport mechanism <b>14</b> to aid in intersection of transport mechanism <b>14</b> with the pile of textiles P. The size and shape of bin <b>22</b> may further depend on the size and shape of the pile of textile items P to be separated.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In some embodiments, textile collection area <b>14</b> may include a powered advancement mechanism <b>30</b> to direct, compel, advance, or otherwise move the pile of textile items P towards transport mechanism <b>14</b>, such that transport mechanism <b>14</b> may continuously intersect with the pile of textile items P. Examples of advancement mechanism <b>30</b> may include a belt conveyor, a pushing device, a lifting device, a vibration device and/or other known movement means.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Textile collection area <b>12</b> may include an advancement mechanism <b>30</b> to move the supported pile of textile items P towards transport mechanism <b>14</b>, as illustrated by directional arrow D<b>1</b>. Advancement mechanism <b>30</b> may span all, or part of, the length of textile collection area <b>12</b>. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, advancement mechanism <b>30</b> may include raised members <b>32</b> for increased frictional movement of the pile of textile items P towards transport mechanism <b>14</b>. A plurality of textile items of undetermined quantity and/or quality may thereby enter textile collection area <b>12</b> for continuous movement by advancement mechanism <b>30</b> towards transport mechanism <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">As discussed above, transport mechanism <b>14</b>, in accordance with the present disclosure, may define an inclined face <b>34</b> that intersects the pile of textile items P. For example, as best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, textile collection area <b>12</b> may lie generally in the plane of the floor, whereas transport mechanism <b>14</b> may operate at an incline of 100-120 degrees relative to textile collection area <b>12</b>. Transport mechanism <b>14</b> thus may be inclined such that a separated textile item may be partially supported by transport mechanism <b>14</b> as it travels away from the pile of textile items P, as illustrated by directional arrow D<b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Transport mechanism <b>14</b> may extend between textile collection area <b>12</b> and textile receiving area <b>18</b>. In some embodiments, transport mechanism <b>14</b> may span the entire distance between textile collection area <b>12</b> and textile receiving area <b>18</b>, thereby providing for delivery of individual textile items from textile collection area <b>12</b> to textile receiving area <b>18</b>. As best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, one or more guidewalls <b>36</b> may line the sides of transport mechanism <b>14</b> to ensure that separated textile items do not fall off the sides of transport mechanism <b>14</b>. Referring still to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, it will be appreciated that transport mechanism <b>14</b> may form a loop, such that pick member <b>16</b> travels in a continuous circuit that intersects with the pile of textile items P to catch hold of a textile item from the pile of textile items P, deliver the textile item up an incline and over a precipice to textile receiving area <b>18</b>, and then return to textile collection area <b>12</b> to catch hold of another textile item.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, pick member <b>16</b> may project from face <b>34</b> of transport mechanism <b>14</b>. In some examples, pick member <b>16</b> may be approximately &#xbd;-inch long, and may project from face <b>34</b> at an approximate 110-degree upward angle. In other words, pick member <b>16</b> may project from face <b>34</b> at an approximate 70 degree acute angle <b>17</b> with respect to face <b>34</b>. In other examples, pick member <b>16</b> may take the form of a metal hook. In still other examples, pick member <b>16</b> may take another shape adapted to catch, hold, and pull a textile item from a pile, and may be angled depending on the type of textile item to be separated. The size of pick member <b>16</b> may also depend on the size and/or weight of the textile item to be separated.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, one or more pick members <b>16</b> may project from transport mechanism <b>14</b>, and may be uniformly or variably spaced along the length or a partial length of transport mechanism <b>14</b>. For example, one of more pick members <b>16</b> may be spaced from 3-inches to 24-inches apart along a length of transport mechanism <b>14</b>. In the examples shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</figref>, one or more pick members <b>16</b> are mounted adjacent opposite side edges of face <b>34</b> of transport mechanism <b>14</b> in an alternating pattern. The alternating pattern may allow a greater number of pick members <b>16</b> to project from transport mechanism <b>14</b>. The locations of pick members <b>16</b> also may depend on the size of the items selected.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In some embodiments, it may be possible to move the pick members along a stationary surface, thereby providing for movement of textile items along the incline. In these embodiments, pick member <b>16</b> may project openings in the stationary surface. In other embodiments, pick member <b>16</b> may be coupled or mounted to face <b>34</b> such that pick member <b>16</b> moves with face <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">As explained above, in some examples it may be desirable to further process textile items after textile items have been separated, and carried away from the pile of textile items P. Further processing may include processing within textile receiving area <b>18</b>, located in a textile receiving relationship with respect to transport mechanism <b>14</b>. As best shown in the example in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, transport mechanism <b>14</b> may project over textile receiving area <b>18</b>. In some examples, a textile item separated by pick member <b>16</b> may travel over a precipice of transport mechanism <b>14</b>, and may drop onto textile receiving area <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Textile receiving area <b>18</b> may include an inspection station employing a powered conveyer <b>38</b> for conveyance of separated textile pieces away from transport mechanism <b>14</b>, as illustrated by directional arrow D<b>3</b>. The rate of conveyance through the inspection station may depend on the time needed for inspection, sorting, and/or collection of the textile items. A human operator may inspect the separated textile items or, alternatively, textile receiving area <b>18</b> may include an optical inspection machine or scanner. Alternative examples of textile receiving area <b>18</b> may include other known mechanisms for spaced movement of textile items. Textile receiving area <b>18</b> may further include a gate <b>40</b>, illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, to selectively impede movement of the textile items.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, in some examples, textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> may include automated bagging system <b>20</b> to provide automatic bagging and sealing of the separated textile items. For example, textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> may include a Max&#x2122; Bagging Machine, manufactured by Sharp Packaging Systems of Sussex, Wis. Other exemplary automated bagging systems include the Titan 6500 Semi-automatic Packaging Machine manufactured by James Dawson Enterprises, Ltd. of Plattsburg, N.Y.; the T1000 Advance Poly-Bagger manufactured by Advanced Poly Packaging of Akron, Ohio; or the Autobagger manufactured by Automated Packaging Systems of Streetsboro, Ohio. Each of these systems is capable of bagging and sealing up to 60 bags per minute. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, automated bagging system <b>20</b> may include an exit conveyer <b>46</b> for conveying filled bags away from the area surrounding automated bagging system <b>20</b>, as illustrated by directional arrow D<b>4</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Inspection station <b>38</b> may further include a photoelectric eye <b>42</b>. Photoelectric eye <b>42</b> may count the textile items at inspection station <b>38</b>, for example, as they pass on a belt conveyor. Photoelectric eye <b>42</b> may be mounted approximately 10-inches from the distal end of inspection station <b>38</b>. Photoelectric eye <b>42</b> may be protected by a photoelectric eye cover <b>44</b>. In some examples of textile separating apparatus <b>10</b>, photoelectric eye <b>42</b> may be operationally interconnected with gate <b>40</b> and/or automated bagging system <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">An exemplary method of separating textiles in accordance with the present disclosure and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref> may proceed as follows. A number of textile items may be loaded in to textile collection area <b>12</b>, all at once, or in intermittent loads. Advancement mechanism <b>30</b> may advance the resulting pile of textile items P towards transport mechanism <b>14</b>, so that the pile of textile items P and transport mechanism <b>14</b> intersect. Pick member <b>16</b>, projecting from face <b>34</b> of transport mechanism <b>14</b>, may separate individual textile items from the pile of textile items P, and carry the separated textile items towards textile receiving area <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Once separated, textile items may be released or dropped into textile receiving area <b>18</b>. Pick member <b>16</b> may then return in a continuous loop to successively separate additional textile items from the pile of textile items P. Upon being dropped into textile receiving area <b>18</b>, textile items may be conveyed in a spaced manner through the inspection station. Prior to the textile items leaving the inspection station, individual textile items may be sorted by human action or automatic mechanism, and/or counted by photoelectric eye <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In some embodiments, after a predetermined quantity of textiles (set by automated bagging system <b>20</b>) are counted, photoelectric eye <b>42</b> may send a signal to gate <b>40</b>, directing gate <b>40</b> to close (typically after a time delay). While gate <b>40</b> is closed, automated bagging system <b>20</b> may cycle, reposition a new bag to collect the textile items coming off the end of belt conveyor <b>38</b>, and then signal gate <b>40</b> to open so that textile items may begin to fill the next bag. The filled bag may then leave the area surrounding automated bagging system <b>20</b> via exit conveyor <b>46</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Some examples of a textile separating apparatus may include additional control features to further the accuracy and efficiency of the textile separating apparatus. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, in the examples of a textile separating apparatus including advancement mechanism <b>30</b>, advancement mechanism <b>30</b> may feed textiles towards transport mechanism <b>14</b> at a controlled rate and/or on an intermittent timed basis with the use of a repeat cycle timer <b>48</b>, which provides for control of advancement mechanism <b>30</b>. Rate of processing may therefore be independent of the speed of any individual operator, and productivity of the system may be readily determined.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The feed rate may be adjustable to ensure that the rate of travel is timed to supply an appropriate quantity of textile items to transport mechanism <b>14</b> based on the size of the textile items. If the rate of travel is too slow, there may be a gap in the textile items selected and fed through the process. If the rate is too high, the textile items may &#x201c;bunch up&#x201d; at transport mechanism <b>14</b> and cause double picks (meaning that pick member <b>16</b> may select more than one item at a time), thereby causing extra work for an inspector. Other operations and/or conveyors in the textile separating apparatus may also have rate adjustment ability. The present textile separating apparatus typically may be operated to process approximately 4,800 textile items per operator hour.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The components expressed so far descriptively, may be mounted on a framework that supports such components so that they are positioned for the maximum mechanical and operational advantage inherently possible between the components. Scaling of the individual components, and overall machine proportions, are variable and relative to the users operational specifications. As illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</figref>, some examples of textile separating apparatus <b>10</b> may be mounted on a wheeled framework for ease of movement, for example, around a warehouse.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">With respect to the above description then, it is to be realized that the optimum dimensional relationships for the parts of the claimed method and apparatus for separating textiles, to include variations in size, materials, shape, form, function and manner of operation, assembly and use, are deemed readily apparent and obvious to one skilled in the art, and all equivalent relationships to those illustrated in the drawings and described in the specification are intended to be encompassed by the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Therefore, the foregoing is considered as illustrative only of the principles of the system. Further, since numerous modifications and changes will readily occur to those skilled in the art, it is not desired to limit the disclosure to the exact construction and operation shown and described, and accordingly, all suitable modifications and equivalents may be resorted to, falling within the scope of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A textile separating apparatus, comprising;
<claim-text>a textile collection area for supporting plural textile items;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a textile receiving area;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transport mechanism having an inclined face, wherein the transport mechanism extends between the textile collection area and the textile receiving area, the transport mechanism intersecting the plural textile items; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pick member projecting from the face of the transport mechanism, wherein the pick member separates and carries a textile item from the plural textile items to the textile receiving area and the inclined face of the transport mechanism is inclined such that at least a portion of the separated textile item is partially supported on the inclined face of the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the textile collection area includes a bin containing the plural textile items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the textile collection area includes an advancement mechanism, wherein the advancement mechanism moves the plural textile items towards the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the transport mechanism includes a looped conveyor intersecting the plural textile items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the textile receiving area includes a belt conveyor in a textile receiving relationship with the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the pick member projects from the face of the transport mechanism at an acute angle with respect to the face of the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising more than one pick member evenly distributed along a length of the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein pick members alternately project from adjacent opposite sides of the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the advancement mechanism includes raised members projecting from a face of the advancement mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the textile receiving area further includes a gate to selectively block advancement of textile items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a photoelectric eye, wherein the photoelectric eye counts the separated textile items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the advancement mechanism controls the rate the plural textile items move toward the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising an automated bagging system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method of separating textiles, comprising;
<claim-text>advancing a pile of textile items towards a transport mechanism having an inclined face;</claim-text>
<claim-text>successively separating individual textile items from the pile of textile items on a pick member projecting from the face of the transport mechanism; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>carrying the separated textile items to a textile receiving area, wherein carrying the separated textile items includes supporting at least a portion of the separated textile items on the inclined face of the transport mechanism.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of separating textiles of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising releasing the separated textile items from the pick member at the textile receiving area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of separating textiles of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising counting the separated textile items at the textile receiving area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method of separating textiles of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising bagging the separated textile items into packages at the textile receiving area, wherein each package includes a predetermined number of textile items.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method of separating textiles of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising inspecting the separated textile items for quality at the textile receiving area.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A textile separating apparatus, comprising;
<claim-text>a bin for containing a pile of textile items, the bin including an advancement mechanism;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a looped conveyor intersecting the pile of textile items; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pick member projecting from a face of the looped conveyor at an acute angle with respect to the face of the looped conveyor, wherein the advancement mechanism moves the pile of textile items towards the looped conveyor at a controlled rate, and, further wherein, the pick member separates a textile item from the pile of textile items and carries the separated textile item towards a textile receiving area.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The textile separating apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, wherein the textile receiving area further includes an automated bagging system. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
