<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07640855-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07640855</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10526255</doc-number>
<date>20030828</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>10</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>102 41 284</doc-number>
<date>20020906</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>695</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>B</section>
<class>41</class>
<subclass>F</subclass>
<main-group>27</main-group>
<subgroup>06</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>101409</main-classification>
<further-classification>101378</further-classification>
<further-classification>101383</further-classification>
<further-classification>1014151</further-classification>
<further-classification>271 82</further-classification>
<further-classification>271277</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Clamping device for a printing plate</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3650211</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Nentwich</name>
<date>19720300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>101409</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3658002</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Preuss</name>
<date>19720400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4947748</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hiltwein et al.</name>
<date>19900800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>101409</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5168810</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kojima</name>
<date>19921200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5322013</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Haupenthal</name>
<date>19940600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1014151</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5374093</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Klopfenstein</name>
<date>19941200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>271277</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5927202</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hirokawa et al.</name>
<date>19990700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>1014151</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6736396</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Fukui</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>101409</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>20 06 773</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>19710800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>690 20 463</doc-number>
<kind>T2</kind>
<date>19960300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 435 410</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>19910700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2000-218765</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20000800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>101409</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>2</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060117976</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060608</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hoier</last-name>
<first-name>G&#xfc;nther Josef</first-name>
<address>
<city>Veitsh&#xf6;chheim</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Schaede</last-name>
<first-name>Johannes Georg</first-name>
<address>
<city>W&#xfc;rzburg</city>
<country>DE</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>DE</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Crompton, Seager &#x26; Tufte, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>KBA-Giori S.A.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Lausanne</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Culler</last-name>
<first-name>Jill E</first-name>
<department>2854</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
<pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>PCT/DE03/02863</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20030828</date>
</document-id>
<us-371c124-date>
<date>20051129</date>
</us-371c124-date>
</pct-or-regional-filing-data>
<pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
<document-id>
<country>WO</country>
<doc-number>WO2004/024450</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20040325</date>
</document-id>
</pct-or-regional-publishing-data>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed is a clamping device (<b>02</b>) for fastening a plate (<b>03</b>) to the periphery of a cylinder (<b>01</b>). Said clamping device (<b>02</b>) comprises a first clamping element (<b>04</b>), a pivotally mounted second clamping element (<b>06</b>), a spring part (<b>07</b>), and a bracing element that is embodied as a pivotable spindle (<b>08</b>) and is movable between a clamping position in which the bracing element maintains the plate in a clamped state between the clamping elements and a released position in which the clamping elements release the plate. The spindle (<b>08</b>) is mounted in a groove so as to be displaceable, is fixed in an intermediate space between the spring part (<b>07</b>) and the second clamping element (<b>06</b>), and is pressed against the second clamping element by means of the spring part in the clamping position.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="129.96mm" wi="152.99mm" file="US07640855-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="148.67mm" wi="155.87mm" file="US07640855-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="138.01mm" wi="132.59mm" file="US07640855-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The invention relates to a clamping device for a printing plate on a cylinder according to the preamble of claim <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The subject of the invention is a cylinder having a clamping device for fastening a plate, in particular a printing plate, to the periphery of the cylinder, the clamping device comprising a first clamping element, a pivotably mounted second clamping element, a spring part and a tensioning element, which can be moved between a clamping position, in which it holds the printing plate clamped in between the clamping elements, and a released position, in which the clamping elements release the printing plate. With the cylinder for example incorporated in a rotary press, printing plates with different thicknesses, such as those which occur in what is known as the letterpress process, for example, can be fastened to the periphery of the cylinder.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">PRIOR ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A clamping device for fastening a printing plate to a press cylinder is disclosed, for example, by DE 690 20 463 T2. The clamping device comprises a clamp W for an upper edge of the printing plate and a clamp S for a lower edge of the printing plate. The two clamps W and S each comprise two clamping bars, between which the corresponding edge of the printing plate is clamped.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The necessary clamping force is respectively ensured by a tensioning spindle, which is rotatably mounted between the clamping bars. The tensioning spindle has a cross section which is substantially circular, apart from a flat. It can be rotated into a position in which it presses with a maximum diameter against the two clamping bars and, in the process, clamps the printing plate between them, or else rotated into a position in which, because of a width shortened by the flat, it can no longer exert any clamping force on the clamping bars and the printing plate is released. However, with the embodiment shown, it is not possible to set the clamping force optimally to a specific thickness of the printing plate in order to fasten printing plates of different thicknesses. For example, printing plates with a low thickness are not clamped in firmly enough or even not at all in a gap between the clamping bars, while printing plates with a greater thickness under certain circumstances cannot even be inserted into the gap between the clamping bars.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In EP 04 35 410 B2, a clamping device that is configured differently is shown. In the case of this clamping device, too, an edge of the printing plate is clamped in between two clamping bars. One of the clamping bars is pivotably mounted and is pressed against the other clamping bar by a resilient spring. In order to open the two clamping bars, a spindle with an eccentric cross section is provided, with which the pressure of the resilient spring can be counteracted. Although, in the case of this device, in the event of different thicknesses of the printing plate, the resilient spring is pressed in to different extents, which leads to a correspondingly changed spring force and therefore to a changed clamping force for the printing plate, this clamping force is firstly weak, because the resilient spring can exert only small spring forces, as a result of which printing plates with an excessively high thickness cannot be held in this clamping device. Secondly, during the insertion of the printing plate between the clamping bars, care must be taken that the spindle acts permanently counter to the spring force. This requires a fixing mechanism for the spindle, which means increased mechanical complexity, since without such a fixing mechanism there is the risk that, during the insertion of the printing plate, the spindle will slip and release the pivotable clamping bar again, which will then be pressed immediately against the other clamping bar because of the spring force. However, even with such a fixing device for the spindle, the insertion of the printing plate is cumbersome and associated with a risk of injury, since, in particular when the printing plate has a great thickness, it has a certain stiffness, which has to be overcome when bending over the printing plate and introducing it between the two clamping bars.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">As a consequence of this stiffness, the printing plate continually attempts to bend back again, so that it has to be held between the clamping bars while the fixing device for the spindle is released, in order that the clamping bars are able to grip the printing plate. In this case, there is the risk to a person holding the printing plate that his fingers will be clamped in between the clamping bars. If the printing plate is mounted by only one person, the risk of injury is increased considerably, since he has to hold the printing plate with one hand while he simultaneously has to operate the fixing device for the spindle with the other hand.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">DE 26 06 773 B2 discloses a device for fastening a printing plate on a cylinder, in which the printing plates are held between fixed clamping bars and movable clamping elements. The clamping elements are moved by a pivotable, flattened spindle by means of interposed disk springs.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The invention is based on the object of providing a clamping device for a printing plate.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">According to the invention, the object is achieved by the features of claim <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The advantages that can be achieved with the invention are in particular that printing plates with different thicknesses can be fastened to the cylinder. By means of the special design of the clamping device, it is ensured that each printing plate experiences a clamping force from the clamping device which corresponds to its thickness, and is gripped securely by the clamping elements. Furthermore, the play of the tensioning element between the clamping elements in the released position prevents the clamping elements inadvertently snapping shut and, as a result, reduces the risk of injury. In addition, the mounting of the printing plate is simplified considerably, since it can firstly be introduced carefully between the clamping elements and is held by the latter before it is acted on with a clamping force by moving the tensioning element into the clamping position.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The spring part preferably comprises at least one disk spring. As opposed to tensioning springs, disk springs have a considerably greater spring constant with a compact design and are therefore capable of exerting a much higher spring force with less compression. This permits a more compact and space-saving design of the clamping device, which is additionally capable of holding printing plates with a thickness in which a clamping device designed with resilient springs could not supply the clamping force needed for this purpose.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The clamping device is preferably arranged in an elongated groove in the cylinder. Because the clamping device is countersunk completely in the groove, the cylinder can be used, for example, as a plate cylinder in a rotary press without the clamping device impeding the printing operation.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In this case, a clamping device which can be displaced within the groove is particularly preferred. Using such a clamping device, the printing plate held by the clamping device can be tensioned by displacing the clamping device in the peripheral direction within the groove, so that the printing plate rests closely on the periphery of the cylinder, or can be displaced as a whole in the peripheral direction. The clamping device can also be displaceable along the groove. In a machine which has a plurality of plate cylinders for multicolor printing, the individual printing plates can be adjusted in register with the aid of such clamping devices.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In this case, at least one of the clamping elements is preferably a bar running parallel to the groove. By using such bars, a printing plate can be clamped in along an entire length of one of its end sections, which improves the clamping.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">One side of the first clamping element, with which the first clamping element clamps the printing plate, preferably has a curved profile in section transversely with respect to the axis of the cylinder. In this case, depending on the suitability, the curved profile can be curved in the shape of a circular arc or a section of an ellipse or in any other desired way. Such a configuration of the first clamping element benefits kink-free clamping of the printing plate.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Likewise preferred is a tensioning element which is a spindle running parallel to the groove. In the case of bar-like clamping elements, by means of a tensioning element embodied in this way, a clamping force may be applied along an entire length of the clamping elements, which benefits the secure clamping of the printing plate.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The spindle preferably has a cross section substantially in the form of a circular segment with a first flat. Such a spindle may be moved from the clamping position into the released position and vice versa by means of simple rotation. Here, in the released position, the flat is oriented substantially toward one of the two clamping bars, which results in the play of the spindle in the interspace between the clamping bars.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">A further embodiment of the spindle has a second flat and a third flat, which are arranged diametrically with respect to each other on the spindle, in the clamping position the second flat pressing against the second clamping element and the third flat being pressed by the spring part. The second and the third flat have the effect that the spindle latches in the clamping position.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">There are advantageously pins in one of the clamping elements, on which pins the printing plate is hooked in. By virtue of the pins, the mounting of the printing plate is simplified further, since it is prevented from sliding out between the two clamping elements.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">As already mentioned, the cylinder is particularly preferably a part of a rotary press.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">An exemplary embodiment of the invention is illustrated in the drawings and will be described in more detail in the following text.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In the drawings:</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a cross section through a part of a cylinder and a clamping device;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a front view of a first clamping element.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a cross section through a part of a cylinder <b>01</b> with an associated clamping device <b>02</b>. In this case, the clamping device <b>02</b> is arranged within a longitudinal groove <b>11</b> in the cylinder <b>01</b> and entirely accommodated in this groove <b>11</b>. Fastened to the periphery of the cylinder <b>01</b> is a plate <b>03</b>, for example a printing plate <b>03</b>, which is bent down in one end section and is clamped in the clamping device <b>02</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The clamping device <b>02</b> includes a first clamping element <b>04</b>, a second clamping element <b>06</b>, a bearing block <b>17</b> having a spring part <b>07</b> and a tensioning element <b>08</b>. The first clamping element <b>04</b> is an L-profile bar <b>04</b> extending through the length of the groove <b>11</b>. Arranged in a limb <b>18</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b> which is vertical in the drawing are pins <b>16</b>, which project with one end section out of the end of the limb <b>18</b> and reach with a form fit through holes in the edge of the printing plate <b>03</b>. In a limb <b>19</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b> which is horizontal in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, on the side of the limb <b>18</b>, a recess <b>21</b> is provided in an end section of the limb <b>19</b> opposite the limb <b>18</b>. The L-profile bar <b>04</b> is arranged within the groove <b>11</b> in such a way that the limb <b>18</b> is oriented toward an aperture <b>22</b> of the groove <b>11</b> in the surface of the cylinder <b>01</b>, and the limb <b>19</b> points away from the aperture <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The bearing block <b>17</b> rests on the horizontal limb <b>19</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b> and on the vertical limb <b>18</b>. At an end section facing the vertical limb <b>18</b>, the bearing block <b>17</b> has a rotary bearing <b>23</b>. In an end section facing away from the vertical limb <b>18</b>, the bearing block <b>17</b> has a channel-like groove <b>24</b> running parallel to the groove <b>11</b>. The second clamping element <b>06</b> is attached to the rotary bearing <b>23</b>, while the groove <b>24</b> serves as a bearing <b>24</b> for the tensioning element <b>08</b>. At the lowest point of the bearing <b>24</b> an aperture <b>26</b> is provided as an engagement for the spring part <b>07</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The second clamping element <b>06</b> extends through the length of the groove <b>11</b> and is attached to the rotary bearing <b>23</b> such that it can pivot about a longitudinal axis. Thus, the clamping element <b>06</b> acts like a two-armed lever. A lever arm facing the aperture <b>22</b> forms a clamping bar <b>06</b>, which rests on the vertical limb <b>18</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b>. The clamping bar <b>06</b> has holes <b>27</b>, into which the pins <b>16</b> projecting from the limb <b>18</b> project.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The tensioning element <b>08</b> is a spindle <b>08</b> which extends through the length of the groove <b>11</b>. The spindle <b>08</b> substantially has a cross section in the form of a circular segment with a wide first flat <b>12</b>. Provided on the spindle <b>08</b>, diametrically with respect to each other, are two further flats <b>13</b> and <b>14</b>, which are parallel to each other and are both arranged at right angles to the flat <b>12</b>. The flats <b>13</b> and <b>14</b> are much narrower than the flat <b>12</b>. The spindle <b>08</b> extends over the entire length of the bearing block <b>17</b> and is rotatably mounted in its groove <b>24</b>. The spacing of the flats <b>13</b>, <b>14</b> from the axis of rotation of the spindle <b>08</b> corresponds to the radius of curvature of the part of the cross section that is in the form of a circular segment; the spacing of the flat <b>12</b> from the axis of rotation is smaller.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The spring part <b>07</b> comprises a plurality of springs <b>09</b>, for example disk springs <b>09</b>, on which a plate <b>28</b> is mounted. The plate <b>28</b> has a protrusion <b>29</b> on a side facing away from the disk springs <b>09</b>. The disk springs <b>09</b> and the plate <b>28</b> are accommodated by the recess <b>21</b> in the horizontal limb <b>19</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b>. In this case, the protrusion <b>29</b> reaches through the aperture <b>26</b> in the bearing block <b>17</b> into the interior of the bearing <b>24</b> and presses against the spindle <b>08</b> located in the latter.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">When the spindle <b>08</b> is in a released position, it is oriented with the first flat <b>12</b> either toward a lever arm of the clamping bar <b>06</b> facing away from the aperture <b>22</b> or toward the protrusion <b>29</b> of the spring part <b>07</b>. It then has play within the bearing <b>24</b>, that is to say in an interspace between the spring part <b>07</b> or the protrusion <b>29</b> of the spring part <b>07</b> and the clamping bar <b>06</b>. The disk springs <b>09</b> press the plate <b>28</b> against the bearing block <b>17</b>. The clamping bar <b>06</b> can pivot freely about the rotary bearing <b>23</b> and can be pivoted back in order to release the pins <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In order to fasten the printing plate <b>03</b>, first of all an edge section of the printing plate <b>03</b> provided with holes is pushed through the aperture <b>22</b> in the groove <b>11</b> in the periphery of the cylinder <b>01</b> and hooked onto the pins <b>16</b> by means of the holes. The printing plate <b>03</b> is then bent around the cylinder <b>01</b> and an opposite edge section is hooked in a second groove <b>11</b> in the same way. In order to avoid the bending leading to permanent deformation of the printing plate <b>03</b>, the limb <b>18</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b> has a curved profile in section transversely with respect to an axis of the cylinder <b>01</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. In the embodiment of the L-profile bar <b>04</b> shown, the curvature has the form of a circular section.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In order to clamp the printing plate <b>03</b> between the two clamping elements <b>04</b> and <b>06</b>, the spindle <b>08</b> is rotated into the clamping position shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. In this position, it presses with its second flat <b>13</b> against the clamping bar <b>06</b> and with the third flat <b>14</b> against the protrusion <b>29</b> of the spring part <b>07</b>. In order to assume this position, an additional expenditure of force, which can easily be applied, is necessary so that the spindle <b>08</b> is latched in the clamping position by virtue of the flats <b>13</b> and <b>14</b>. The disk springs <b>09</b> are compressed by the spindle <b>08</b> via the protrusion <b>29</b>. They react to this with a spring force which, via the protrusion <b>29</b>, acts on the spindle <b>08</b> and on the second clamping element <b>06</b>. Since the second clamping element <b>06</b> acts like a two-armed lever as a result of its pivotable mounting on the rotary bearing <b>23</b>, the printing plate <b>03</b> is clamped in between the clamping bar <b>06</b> of the second clamping element <b>06</b> and the limb <b>18</b> of the L-profile bar <b>04</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Depending on the thickness of the printing plate <b>03</b> clamped in, the disk springs <b>09</b> are compressed either more or less and react with a correspondingly different spring force, that is to say the clamping force for the printing plate <b>03</b> increases with the thickness of the printing plate <b>03</b>, since the disk springs <b>08</b> are compressed to a greater extent with increasing thickness of the printing plate <b>03</b>. Thus, in this embodiment of the clamping device <b>02</b>, a clamping force corresponding to the thickness of the printing plate <b>03</b> is automatically established by itself.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">After the printing plate <b>03</b> has been clamped in between the L-profile bar <b>04</b> and the clamping element <b>06</b>, the clamping device <b>02</b> is pushed away from the aperture <b>22</b> within the groove <b>11</b>, in order to tension the printing plate <b>03</b> on the periphery of the cylinder <b>01</b>. For this purpose, a tensioning screw <b>31</b> is provided, which strikes a wall of the groove <b>11</b> and with which the clamping device <b>02</b> can be displaced toward the aperture <b>22</b> or away from the aperture <b>22</b> within the groove <b>11</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">After printing has been carried out, the printing plate <b>03</b> is removed from the cylinder <b>01</b> by the spindle <b>08</b> being rotated into the released position again, in which said plate has play in the interspace between the spring part <b>07</b> and the second clamping element <b>06</b>, so that the second clamping element <b>06</b> can again be pivoted freely. Now, the clamping bar <b>06</b> of the second clamping element <b>06</b> can easily be pivoted back, as a result of which the pins <b>16</b> are exposed and the printing plate <b>03</b> can be unhooked from the pins <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The invention is not restricted to the embodiment described. Instead, alternative configurations of the clamping device <b>02</b> shown are possible without departing from the idea of the invention. For example, in the described configuration of the clamping device <b>02</b>, the first clamping element <b>04</b> or the L-profile bar <b>04</b> is a bar that extends over the entire length of the groove <b>11</b>, the second clamping element <b>06</b> also being configured as a continuous bar. As an alternative to this, the second clamping element <b>06</b> can be composed of a plurality of clamping levers which are attached to a plurality of bearing blocks <b>17</b>. Likewise, the first clamping element <b>04</b> can be composed of a plurality of L-profile pieces <b>04</b>, on which the bearing blocks <b>17</b> rest, instead of being formed as a continuous L-profile bar <b>04</b>. Quite generally, the first clamping element <b>04</b> and the second clamping element <b>06</b> can be formed in any desired combination in one piece as bars or can be composed of a plurality of pieces.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">LIST OF DESIGNATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0039" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0038"><b>01</b> Cylinder</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0039"><b>02</b> Clamping device</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0040"><b>03</b> Plate, printing plate</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0041"><b>04</b> First clamping element, L-profile bar</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0042"><b>05</b> -</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0043"><b>06</b> Second clamping element, clamping bar</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0044"><b>07</b> Spring part</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0045"><b>08</b> Tensioning element, spindle</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0046"><b>09</b> Spring, disk springs</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0047"><b>10</b> -</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0048"><b>11</b> Groove</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0049"><b>12</b> First flat</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0050"><b>13</b> Second flat</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0051"><b>14</b> Third flat</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0052"><b>15</b> -</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0053"><b>16</b> Pin</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0054"><b>17</b> Bearing block</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0055"><b>18</b> Vertical limb</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0056"><b>19</b> Horizontal limb</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0057"><b>20</b> -</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0058"><b>21</b> Recess</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0059"><b>22</b> Aperture</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0060"><b>23</b> Rotary bearing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0061"><b>24</b> Groove, bearing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0062"><b>25</b> -</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0063"><b>26</b> Aperture</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0064"><b>27</b> Holes</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0065"><b>28</b> Plate</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0066"><b>29</b> Protrusion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0067"><b>30</b> -</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0068"><b>31</b> Tensioning screw</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A clamping device for fastening a plate to the periphery of a cylinder, the clamping device comprising a first clamping element, a pivotably mounted second clamping element, a spring part and a tensioning element which is formed as a pivotable spindle which can be moved between a clamping position, in which it holds the plate clamped in between the clamping elements, and a released position, in which the clamping elements release the plate,
<claim-text>wherein the spindle is mounted rotably in a groove,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the spindle is fitted in an interspace between the spring part and the second clamping element</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, in the clamping position, the spindle is pressed against the second clamping element by the spring part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein, in the released position, the clamping device has a play in the interspace between the spring part and the second clamping element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the spring part comprises at least one disk spring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the clamping device is arranged in an elongated groove in the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the clamping device can be displaced within the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the clamping elements is a bar running parallel to the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein one side of the first clamping element, with which the first clamping element clamps the plate, has a curved profile in section transversely with respect to the axis of the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the spindle is arranged to run parallel to the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the spindle has a cross section substantially in the form of a circular segment with a first flat.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, further comprising a second flat and a third flat, which are arranged diametrically with respect to each other on the spindle, in the clamping position the second flat pressing against the second clamping element and the third flat being pressed by the spring part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein there are pins on one of the clamping elements, on which pins the plate is hooked in.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cylinder is arranged in a rotary press.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the spindle has eccentric sections.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. A clamping device for fastening a plate to the periphery of a cylinder, the clamping device comprising a first clamping element, a pivotably mounted second clamping element, a spring part and a tensioning element which is formed as a pivotable spindle which can be moved between a clamping position, in which it holds the plate clamped in between the clamping elements, and a released position, in which the clamping elements release the plate,
<claim-text>wherein the spindle is mounted in a variable location in a groove,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the spindle is fined in an interspace between the spring part and the second clamping element</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein, in the clamping position, the spindle is pressed against the second clamping element by the spring part,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the clamping device is arranged in an elongated groove in the cylinder, wherein the spindle is arranged to run parallel to the groove,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the spindle has a cross section substantially in the form of a circular segment with a first flat, further comprising a second flat and a third flat, which are arranged diametrically with respect to each other on the spindle, in the clamping position the second flat pressing against the second clamping element and the third flat being pressed by the spring part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the spring part comprises at least one disk spring.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the clamping device can be displaced within the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the clamping elements is a bar running parallel to the groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein one side of the first clamping element, with which the first clamping element clamps the plate, has a curved profile in section transversely with respect to the axis of the cylinder.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein there are pins on one of the clamping elements, on which pins the plate is hooked in.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the cylinder is arranged in a rotary press.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The clamping device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the spindle has eccentric sections. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
