<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641523-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641523</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12190975</doc-number>
<date>20080813</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2008 1 0096014</doc-number>
<date>20080421</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439825</main-classification>
<further-classification>439 65</further-classification>
<further-classification>439 78</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Power connector assembly</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4416504</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sochor</name>
<date>19831100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439825</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4526429</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kirkman</name>
<date>19850700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 82</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5051108</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lincoln</name>
<date>19910900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439825</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5791923</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Picaud et al.</name>
<date>19980800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439188</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6074326</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sakakibara et al.</name>
<date>20000600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>477169</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6319075</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Clark et al.</name>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6890221</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wagner</name>
<date>20050500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439855</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7070464</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Clark et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439825</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7309242</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Clark et al.</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 79</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7314377</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Northey et al.</name>
<date>20080100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 79</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7488222</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Clark et al.</name>
<date>20090200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439825</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0181106</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Schell et al.</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439825</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0194481</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Clark et al.</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439825</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0214027</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Schell et al.</name>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 79</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00015">
<document-id>
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>200820031892.1</doc-number>
<date>20080200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439825</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 65</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 78</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4399472</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439188</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090263984</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20091022</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chen</last-name>
<first-name>Chu-Lin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Jhonghe</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sughrue Mion, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Alltop Electronics (Su Zhou) Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taicang, Jiangsu Province</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Paumen</last-name>
<first-name>Gary F.</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A power connector is provided which includes an insulating housing having a plurality of contact receiving passages, each of said plurality of contact receiving passages receives a contact pair having a pair of independent conductive contacts, each of said independent conductive contacts has a base portion and a contacting portion extending from said base portion, a retention portion extends from at least one of said independent conductive contacts to another one of said independent conductive contacts, and rests on said another one of said independent conductive contacts when said contacting portion deforms under force, so as to prevent said contacting portion of said conductive contact from over deforming under force, and ensure the stability of power transmission.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="58.17mm" wi="149.01mm" file="US07641523-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="230.72mm" wi="108.29mm" file="US07641523-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="230.38mm" wi="168.99mm" file="US07641523-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="232.24mm" wi="154.26mm" file="US07641523-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="243.92mm" wi="175.01mm" file="US07641523-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="247.31mm" wi="151.89mm" file="US07641523-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a power connector and a contact retention structure used thereof, and more particularly to an assembly of a receptacle and a plug connectors for transmitting power between circuit boards and the mating receptacle and plug contacts used thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Designers of electronic circuits generally are concerned with two basic circuit portions, the logic or signal portion and the power portion. In designing logic circuits, the designer usually does not have to take into account any changes in electrical properties, such as resistance of circuit components that are brought about by changes in conditions, such as temperature, because current flows in logic circuits are usually relatively low. However, power circuits can undergo changes in electrical properties because of the relatively high current flows. Consequently, connectors designed for use in power circuits must be capable of dissipating heat (generated primarily as a result of the Joule effect) so that changes in circuit characteristics as a result of changing current flow are minimized</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">U.S. Pat. No. 6,319,075 discloses a power connector assembly used in power transmission application, which includes a receptacle connector and a mating plug connector assembled on a circuit board, said receptacle connector includes an insulating receptacle housing and receptacle contact assembly assembled in said insulating receptacle housing, said plug connector includes an insulating plug housing and plug contact assembly assembled in said insulating plug housing. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, each of said receptacle contact <b>10</b> includes two pieces of planar base portions <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> connected on the top, and an upper and a lower curved contacting arms <b>16</b>, <b>20</b> extending forwardly from the front of said base portion. When said receptacle connector is mated with said plug connector to be electrically connected, said plug and said receptacle contacting arms resiliently contact with each other, said receptacle contact <b>10</b> deforms under the pressing force when said plug contact being inserted, while the U shaped connection portion <b>42</b>, <b>44</b> on top of said planar base portions <b>12</b>, <b>14</b> of said receptacle contact <b>10</b> can provide an opposite supportive force to keep the contacting portion of said receptacle contact <b>10</b> from over deforming. Also, the receptacle as disclosed in this patent is configured in one piece, the connection portion of said base portion of the contact is U shaped, which needs to be bent after the base portion of the contact has been stamped, the process of bending normally results in a crack of the contact at a position where is bent, consequently the electrical conductive characteristics of the material could be influenced and the quality could be affected as well. Moreover, the high temperature during welding could also cause the relief of the inner metal stress of the bent contact, which could influence the precision of welding foot of the contact due to the expanding of the contact, as a result, the contact could not be smoothly contacted with circuit board and the welding foot of the contact could also be broken.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">To overcome the disadvantages as disclosed in this patent, another Chinese Utility Model patent No. 200820031892.1 of the present applicant on an invention of a power connector assembly and mating contacts used thereof discloses an improved receptacle contact. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each of the receptacle contact pair <b>220</b> includes a pair of independent receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b>. Each of the receptacle contacts includes a rectangular planar base portion, a mounting leg extending downwardly from said base portion, and a contacting arm extending forwardly from said base portion. Said receptacle contact is configured in two pieces and manufactured directly by injection mould without the above problems as occurred during bending process, therefore the quality can be effectively improved while the cost of manufacturing can be reduced, also it can be easily assembled, and the manufacturing process becomes simple while the quality can be stabilized. In addition, because no connection or support is provided between said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b>, the contacting arm of said receptacle contact could be over deformed or crumpled due to the pressing force exerted when the plug contact is inserted into the contacting arm of the receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b>, therefore the performance of power transmission of the receptacle contacts could be influenced.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, there are still some rooms that could be further improved about the configuration of the contact used in the power connector.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Accordingly, an object of the present invention is to provide a power connector, the design of contact retention structure of the contact enhances the stability and reliability of the power transmission of said power connector.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In order to achieve above mentioned object, a power connector according to one of the preferred embodiments of the present invention includes an insulating housing having a plurality of contact receiving passages, each of said plurality of contact receiving passages receives a contact pair having a pair of independent conductive contacts, each of said independent conductive contacts has a base portion and a contacting portion extending from said base portion, wherein a retention portion extends from at least one of said independent conductive contacts to another one of said independent conductive contacts, and said retention portion rests on said another one of said independent conductive contacts when said contacting portion deforms under force.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">As an advantageous embodiment of the present invention, said pair of independent conductive contacts of said contact pair is spaced and mirrorly secured in the same one of said contact receiving passages.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">As another advantageous embodiment of the present invention, each of said conductive contacts has said retention portion extending opposite to said another one of said independent conductive contacts.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">As a further advantageous embodiment of the present invention, said retention portion of said pair of said independent conductive contacts of each of said contact pair is apart from each other when no force exerted on said contacting portion of said conductive contact.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">As another advantageous embodiment of the present invention, said retention portion is disposed on said base portion of said conductive contact, comprising a resilient clip obliquely extending from said base portion to a space formed between said base portion of said pair of independent conductive contacts and a retention end portion defined at the end of said resilient clip.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Moreover, as another advantageous embodiment of the present invention, said power connector is a receptacle connector, said contact pair is a receptacle contact pair received in said contact receiving passage of said receptacle insulating housing of said receptacle connector.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Furthermore, as another advantageous embodiment of the present invention, said conductive contacts of said receptacle contact pair are receptacle contacts, comprising said base portion and a resilient contacting arm extending from said base portion.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In addition, as another advantageous embodiment of the present invention, said power connector is plug connector, said contact pair is a plug contact pair received in said contact receiving passage of said insulating plug housing of said plug connector.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to another preferred embodiment of the present invention, a power connector assembly includes a receptacle connector and a mating plug connector, said receptacle connector has an insulating receptacle housing and receptacle contact pairs received in contact receiving passages of said insulating receptacle housing, said plug connector has an insulating plug housing and plug contact pairs received in contact receiving passages of said insulating plug housing, wherein each of said receptacle contact pairs has a pair of independent receptacle contacts received in a corresponding contact receiving passage of said insulating receptacle housing, wherein each of said receptacle contact pair has a retention portion extending opposite to another one of said receptacle contact, and said retention portion of said pair of receptacle contacts of said receptacle contact pair rests on each other when said receptacle connector is mated with said plug connector.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">As an advantageous embodiment of present invention, said pair of receptacle contacts of said receptacle contact pair is mirrorly received in the same one of said contact receiving passages. Said receptacle contact includes a base portion and a resilient contacting arm extending from said base portion, said retention portion being defined on said base portion of said receptacle contact. Said retention portion includes a resilient clip extending to a space formed between said base portion of said pair of independent conductive contacts.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">According to another preferred embodiment of the present invention, a conductive contact pair includes a pair of independent conductive contacts received in a corresponding contact receiving passage of a power connector, each of said conductive contacts has a base portion and a contacting portion extending from said base portion, wherein at least one of said conductive contacts has a retention portion extending opposite to another one of said conductive contacts.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The technical results of the present invention are as follows. Firstly the contact is configured in two pieces to simplify the manufacturing process while stabilize the quality, so as to improve the distribution of high voltage and current. Secondly the retention structure between two pieces of contact can keep the contact from over deforming when being contacted and ensure the reliability of power transmission.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of the conductive contact used in one known power connector;</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the conductive contact used in another known power connector;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of an assembly of a receptacle connector and a plug connector according to a power connector assembly of present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is an explosively perspective view of a receptacle connector according to present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a receptacle contact of the receptacle connector according to present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an explosively perspective view of a plug connector according to present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view of a plug contact of the plug connector according to present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view of an assembly of the receptacle contact of the receptacle connector and the plug contact of the plug connector before mating according to present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a top plan view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a perspective view of an assembly of the receptacle contact of the receptacle connector and the plug contact of the plug connector after mated according to present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a top plan view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view of a power connector assembly taken along the line A-A of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a power connector assembly according to the present invention includes a pair of mating power connectors, i.e. a first power connector and a second power connector, contacts of each connectors being mated for realizing the transmission of high voltage and current. Said first power connector includes a first insulating housing and a plurality of first power contacts received in said first insulating housing, said second power connector includes a second insulating housing and a plurality of second power contacts received in said second insulating housing. As a preferred embodiment of the present invention, said first power connector is a receptacle connector <b>2</b>, said second power connector is a plug connector <b>1</b>, said first power contacts received in said receptacle connector <b>2</b> are receptacle contacts, said second power contacts received in said plug connector <b>1</b> are plug contacts, said plug connector <b>1</b> and said receptacle connector <b>2</b> are assembled on one circuit board respectively, and can be mated to be electrically connected for power transmission between two circuit boards.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, said receptacle connector <b>2</b> includes an insulating receptacle housing <b>21</b>, a plurality of receptacle contact pairs <b>220</b> received in said insulating receptacle housing <b>21</b> in an array, and a first signal contact assembly <b>23</b>. Said first signal contact assembly <b>23</b> is inserted in a plurality of through holes arranged near to the middle of said insulating receptacle housing <b>21</b> in an array, and includes a plurality of pin type signal contacts arranged in an array for transmitting signals.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">Approximately being an injection molded longitudinally cubic plastic body; said insulating receptacle housing <b>21</b> includes a main portion <b>210</b> for receiving said contacts and side portion <b>211</b> in both sides of said main portion <b>210</b> in a longitudinal direction. Said main portion <b>210</b> includes a top wall <b>212</b> and a bottom wall <b>213</b> in parallel relation to said top wall <b>212</b>, a middle wall between said top wall <b>212</b> and said bottom wall <b>213</b>, and a longitudinal mating space <b>215</b> with an opening in front of said main portion <b>210</b> formed between said top wall <b>212</b> and said bottom wall <b>213</b>. A through guiding space <b>216</b> is defined on said side wall <b>211</b> from the front to the back to connect said mating space <b>215</b>, a through hole <b>217</b> is further defined on top of said side wall <b>211</b> to connect said guiding space <b>216</b> with said mating space <b>215</b>. And a plurality of ribs <b>218</b> extend from the front to the back of said main portion <b>210</b> along the inside surface of said top wall <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Each of said receptacle contact pairs <b>220</b> consists of a pair of independent receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, each of said receptacle contact includes a rectangular planar base portion <b>2201</b>, a mounting leg <b>2202</b> extending downwardly from said base portion <b>2201</b>, and a contacting arm <b>2203</b> extending forwardly from said base portion <b>2201</b>. According to the preferred embodiment of present invention, each of said receptacle contacts has four said mounting legs <b>2202</b> extending downwardly from the back bottom edge of said base portion <b>2201</b> to be welded to the corresponding circuit board by Through-hole Technology. Of course, the number of said mounting leg <b>2202</b> may vary to meet the requirements in different designs according to other embodiments of present invention. Moreover, the way to connect said mounting leg with circuit board may also be realized by other common known technologies, for example, SMT, or Press-fit Technology. At the top side and bottom side in front of said base portion <b>2201</b> a barbed retention portion <b>2204</b> is formed respectively. According to the preferred embodiment of present invention, said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> of said receptacle contact pair <b>220</b> are configured in a manner of face-to-face, and symmetrically mirrored. Being a cantilever in a shape of narrow in front and wide in back, said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contact pair <b>220</b> includes a pair of bending portion <b>2205</b> bent from the front of said base portion <b>2201</b> respectively to converge at the inner side, and a contacting portion <b>2206</b> bent outwardly further from said bending portion <b>2205</b> and extending backwardly to gradually open outwardly, a guiding portion <b>2207</b> bent inwardly from the end of said contacting portion <b>2206</b> and a contacting point <b>2208</b> formed at where is bent. A retention portion further is formed on said base portion <b>2201</b>. According to the preferred embodiment of present invention, said retention portion includes an opening <b>2210</b> defined on said base portion and a spring clip <b>2211</b> laterally extending from said opening <b>2210</b> with regards to said base portion <b>2201</b>. The structure and function of said spring clip <b>2211</b> of said retention portion will be described in more details later.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, said plug connector <b>1</b> includes an insulating plug housing <b>11</b>, plug contact pairs <b>120</b> assembled in said insulating plug housing <b>11</b> and a second signal contact assembly <b>13</b>. said second signal contact assembly <b>13</b> inserted in a plurality of through holes with a matrix array near to the middle of main portion <b>110</b> of said insulating plug housing <b>11</b> includes a plurality of second signal contacts with a matrix array for signal transmission, wherein the contacting portion of said second signal contact is configured in two-piece of cantilever to receive the first pin signal contact of said receptacle connector <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Approximately being an injection molded longitudinally cubic plastic body, said insulating plug housing <b>11</b> includes a main portion <b>110</b> for receiving said contacts and side portion <b>111</b> in both sides of said main portion <b>110</b> in a longitudinal direction. Said main portion <b>110</b> includes a top wall <b>112</b>, a bottom wall <b>113</b> in parallel relation to said top wall <b>112</b>, two side walls <b>114</b> and a row of plurality of spacer <b>115</b> between said top wall <b>112</b> and said bottom wall <b>113</b>. Said spacer <b>115</b> extends backwardly from the front of said main portion <b>110</b>, wherein a contact receiving passage <b>117</b> is formed between every two said spacers <b>115</b> and has an opening in front of said main portion <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Each of said plug contact pairs <b>120</b> consists of a pair of independent plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, each of said plug contacts includes a rectangular planar base portion <b>1201</b>, a mounting leg <b>1202</b> extending downwardly from said base portion <b>1201</b>, and a contacting portion <b>1203</b> extending forwardly from the front of said base portion <b>2201</b>. A contacting area for mating with said receptacle contact of said receptacle connector <b>2</b> is formed on inner side of said contacting portion <b>1203</b>. According to the preferred embodiment of present invention, each of said plug contacts has four said mounting legs <b>1202</b> extending downwardly from the back bottom edge of said base portion <b>1201</b> to be welded to the corresponding circuit board by Through-hole Technology. Of course, the number of said mounting leg <b>1202</b> may vary to meet the requirements in different designs according to other embodiments of present invention. Moreover, the way to connect said mounting leg with circuit board may also be realized by other common technologies, for example, SMT, or Press-fit Technology. At the top side and bottom side in front of said base portion <b>1201</b> a barbed retention portion <b>1204</b> is formed respectively. According to the preferred embodiment of present invention, said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b> of said plug contact pair <b>120</b> are configured parallel, spaced face-to-face with a predetermined distance to form a mating space <b>1205</b> (Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>), and symmetrically mirrored. Said retention portion <b>1204</b> on top side edge of said base portion <b>1201</b> is near to the middle, said retention portion <b>1204</b> on bottom side edge of said base portion <b>1201</b> is in front of said mounting leg <b>1202</b>, a guiding portion <b>1206</b> is formed from a chamfer in front of said contacting portion <b>1203</b> of said plug contact.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 8 and 9</figref>, said pair of receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> of said receptacle contact pair <b>220</b> is configured in an identical structure and arranged in mirror. A space is formed between the base portion <b>2202</b> of said pair of receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> of said receptacle contact pair, said spring clip <b>2211</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> includes an extending portion <b>2212</b> obliquely extending in said space with regards to said base portion of the other receptacle contact and a retention end <b>2213</b> formed at the end of said extending portion <b>2212</b>. Said retention end <b>2213</b> of said pair of receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> is spaced with a small gap, which means they are not contacted with each other. Said guiding portion <b>2207</b> at the end of said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> is in accordance with the guiding portion <b>2206</b> at the end of said contacting portion <b>1203</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>, so as to help insert said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> to said mating space <b>1205</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>, and the sum of the width of said contacting portion <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> is slightly more than the width of said mating space of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 10 and 11</figref>, after said receptacle contact pair <b>220</b> being mated with said plug contact pair <b>120</b>, said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> is inserted in said mating space <b>1205</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>, which enables said contacting portion <b>2206</b> at the front of said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contact to be contacted with said contacting portion <b>1203</b> of said plug contact. Further referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref>, since said main body <b>1201</b> and contacting portion <b>1203</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b> are tightly attached to side wall of said contact receiving passage <b>117</b> and held in said contact receiving passage <b>117</b> by said retention portion <b>1204</b>, said main body <b>1201</b> and contacting portion <b>1203</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b> will not deform after said receptacle contacts being inserted, whereas the sum of the width of said contacting portion <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> is slightly more than the that of the mating space <b>1205</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>, therefore said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> will inevitably be bent to each other under the force of said contacting portion <b>1203</b> of said plug contacts <b>121</b>, <b>122</b>. The deformation of said contacting arm <b>2203</b> results in that the retention portion of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> will converge to each other, so as to enable said retention end <b>2213</b> of said pair of spring clips <b>2211</b> to rest on each other, and to provide an opposite force to said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b>, said opposite force will offset the pressing force exerted on said contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b> by the contacting portion <b>1203</b>, to reduce the deformation of the contacting arm <b>2203</b> of said receptacle contacts <b>221</b>, <b>222</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">According to present invention, said receptacle contact of the power connector is configured in two pieces, and the contact retention structure is also configured in two pieces structure. The advantages of two-piece configuration are that the contacts can be manufactured by a continuous injection mould without the problems as occurred when being bent, therefore the quality can be effectively improved, and the cost of manufacturing can be lowered as well. At the same time, it makes the assembly and manufacturing processes easier but ensures the quality, meanwhile the contacts can transmit higher voltage and current under the specification of material conductive characteristics; Furthermore, the advantage of said contact retention structure is that it can prevent the contacts from over deforming under force exerted when the contacts being contacted, so as to ensure the reliability of power transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">While the description as set forth is only a preferred embodiment of the present invention, it can also achieved by other various embodiments, for example, according to the preferred embodiment of the present invention, the contact retention structure is defined on said receptacle contact, but in other embodiments, the contact retention structure can also be defined on said plug contact (for instance, between the base portion of said plug contact and side wall of said contact receiving passage). For another example, said contact retention structure is defined on the base portion of the receptacle contact, but in other embodiments, the contact retention structure can also be defined on other portions of the receptacle contact (for instance, at the end of the contacting arm of said receptacle contact in proximity to said base portion). For a further example, said plug connector <b>1</b> and said receptacle connector <b>2</b> can also be configured in that one of them is assembled on main board or other circuit boards, and the other is connected with a cable, in other words, one of the mounting leg of said receptacle contact could be replaced by a common structure used to connect with a cable. Any equivalent modifications made by a person skilled in the art according to the teaching of the present invention should be construed to be included within the scope or spirit of the appended claims as defined in the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present invention have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the invention, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A power connector, comprising:
<claim-text>an insulating housing having a plurality of contact receiving passages,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a contact pair having a pair of independent conductive contacts received in one of said plurality of contact receiving passages, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>said independent conductive contact has a base portion, a contacting portion extending from said base portion, and a retention portion extends from at least one of said independent conductive contacts toward another one of said independent conductive contacts, and said retention portion rests on said another one of said independent conductive contacts when said contacting portion deforms under force.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said pair of independent conductive contacts of said contact pair is spaced and mirrorly secured in the same one of said contact receiving passages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein each of said conductive contacts has said retention portion extending opposite to said another one of said independent conductive contacts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein said retention portion of said pair of said independent conductive contacts of each of said contact pair is apart from each other when no force exerted on said contacting portion of said conductive contact.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein said retention portion is disposed on said base portion of said conductive contact, comprising a resilient clip obliquely extending from said base portion to a space formed between said base portion of said pair of independent conductive contacts and a retention end portion defined at the end of said resilient clip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said power connector is a receptacle connector, said contact pair is a receptacle contact pair received in said contact receiving passage of said insulating receptacle housing of said receptacle connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive contacts of said receptacle contact pair are receptacle contacts, comprising said base portion and a resilient contacting arm extending from said base portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The power connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said power connector is a plug connector, said contact pair is a plug contact pair received in said contact receiving passage of said insulating plug housing of said plug connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The conductive contact pair according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive contact pair is receptacle contact pair to be received in said contact receiving passage of an insulating receptacle housing of a receptacle connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The conductive contact pair according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive contact of said receptacle contact pair is a receptacle contact, having a base portion and a resilient contacting arm extending from said base portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. A power connector assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a receptacle connector having an insulating receptacle housing and receptacle contact pairs received in contact receiving passages of said insulating receptacle housing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mating plug connector having an insulating plug housing and plug contact pairs received in contact receiving passages of said insulating plug housing, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said receptacle contact pairs has a pair of independent receptacle contacts received in a corresponding contact receiving passage of said insulating receptacle housing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said receptacle contacts has a retention portion extending opposite to another one of said receptacle contacts, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said retention portion of said pair of receptacle contacts of said receptacle contact pair rests on each other when said receptacle connector is mated with said plug connector.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The power connector assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein said pair of receptacle contacts of said receptacle contact pair is mirrorly received in the same one of said contact receiving passages.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The power connector assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, characterized in that said receptacle contact has a base portion and a resilient contacting arm extending from said base portion, said retention portion being defined on said base portion of said receptacle contact.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The power connector assembly according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein said retention portion has a resilient clip extending to a space formed between said base portion of said pair of independent conductive contacts and a retention end defined at the end of said resilient clip.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A conductive contact pair, comprising:
<claim-text>a pair of independent conductive contacts adapted to be received in a contact receiving passage of a power connector,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of said conductive contacts having a base portion and a contacting portion extending from said base portion, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of said conductive contacts has a retention portion extending opposite to another one of said conductive contacts; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said retention portion is defined on said base portion and has a resilient clip extending from said base portion, and a retention end is formed at the end of said resilient clip.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The conductive contact pair according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein said pair of independent conductive contacts mirrors each other and a space is formed therebetween.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The conductive contact pair according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein each of said conductive contacts has a retention portion extending opposite to another independent conductive contact.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The conductive contact pair according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein said retention portion of said pair of independent conductive contacts of each of said contact pair is apart from each other when no force exerted on said contacting portion of said conductive contacts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The conductive contact pair according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein said conductive contact pair is plug contact pair to be received in contact receiving passage of an insulating plug housing of a plug connector. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
