<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641478-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641478</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12286308</doc-number>
<date>20080929</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>96216775 U</doc-number>
<date>20071008</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 64</main-classification>
<further-classification>439630</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Card bus connector assembly</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7080991</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Wang</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 79</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7125258</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Nakakubo et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 64</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7351108</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ting et al.</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439630</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7357642</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Masubuchi et al.</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 64</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>2766377</doc-number>
<date>20070600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>5</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 64</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 73</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 79</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439159</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439630</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439633</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090093139</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090409</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Yung-Chang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tu-cheng</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew C.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Wei Te</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Ming Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Ind. Co., Ltd</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Khiem</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A card bus connector assembly mounted within a housing (<b>40</b>) includes a card bus connector (<b>10</b>) and an electronic card (<b>20</b>) having a number of grounding pads (<b>23</b>) disposed on a bottom surface thereof and a wedge-shaped protruding portion (<b>29</b>) disposed in an end portion of the electronic card. The card bus connector has a base (<b>11</b>) and a grounding plate (<b>4</b>) mounted to a bottom surface of the base. The grounding plate has a number of grounding terminals (<b>431</b>) extending upwardly for engaging with the grounding pads of the electronic card.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="151.47mm" wi="217.76mm" file="US07641478-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.95mm" wi="161.12mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641478-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="202.44mm" wi="138.43mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641478-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.03mm" wi="175.94mm" file="US07641478-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="144.27mm" wi="127.59mm" file="US07641478-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="152.82mm" wi="136.48mm" file="US07641478-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention is directed to a card bus connector assembly mounted within a wedge-shaped housing, and particularly to a card bus connector assembly having a card bus connector for electrically connecting an electronic card to a printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Prior Arts</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Portable computers equipped with card bus connectors for receiving therein an electronic card which expands the function of the computer have become dominating projects in the market. The card bus connector is mounted on a printed circuit board of the computer and the electronic card has metallic covers. A grounding path must be provided between the electronic card and the printed circuit board so that when the electronic card is inserted into the card bus connector, electrostatic charges accumulated on the metallic covers of the electronic card can be discharged therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Taiwan Patent No. 314456 issued on Jun. 21, 2007, discloses such a card connector for electrically connecting an electronic card to a printed circuit board. The card connector is mounted within a computer housing of rectangular configuration and comprises a header connector having a base and a number of terminals mounted into the base, a grounding plate assembled to an upper portion of the base in a top-to-bottom direction and having a plurality of ground contacts extending downwardly to electrically connecting with a plurality of contacts disposed on the electronic card. More recently, the computer housing is of wedge-shaped configuration. During assembly, the electronic card which has a wedge-shaped protruding portion disposed at end portion thereof resists against the housing. Thus, the electronic card cannot be completely inserted into the card connector for electrically connecting with the printed circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Hence, it is desirable to provide an improved card bus connector assembly to overcome the aforementioned disadvantages.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">An object of the present invention is to provide a card bus connector assembly having a card bus connector mounted within a wedge-shaped housing and adapted for insertion of an electronic card having a wedge-shaped protruding portion.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">To achieve the above object, a card bus connector assembly mounted within a housing has a card bus connector and an electronic card mounted into the card bus connector for connecting to a printed circuit board. The electronic card has a plurality of first contacts mounted therein, a plurality of grounding pads disposed on a bottom surface thereof. The card bus connector has a base, a plurality of second contacts mounted into the base for engaging with the first contacts, a grounding plate mounted to a bottom surface of the base and having a plurality of grounding terminals extending upwardly for engaging with the grounding pads of the electronic card. The card bus connector further has an ejector mechanism for moving the electronic card to an ejected position and a shield enclosing the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The grounding plate is mounted to a bottom portion of the header connector. When the electronic card having the wedge-shaped protruding portion dispose on the end portion thereof and the grounding pads disposed on the bottom surface thereof is inserted into the housing, the grounding terminals of the grounding plate could be in electrical communication with the grounding pads of the electronic card.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Other objects, advantages and novel features of the invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of the present embodiment when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWING</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an assembled perspective view of a card bus connector assembly mounted within a wedge-shaped housing of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an assembled perspective view of card bus connector assembly when an electronic card is not inserted into the card bus connector;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded perspective view of the card bus connector and a printed circuit board;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a grounding plate mounted to a header connector; and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is another perspective view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Reference will now be made to the drawing figures to describe the present invention in detail. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a card bus connector assembly mounted within a wedge-shaped housing <b>40</b> for connecting to a printed circuit board <b>7</b> comprises a card bus connector <b>10</b> and an electronic card <b>20</b> inserted into the card bus connector <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the electronic card <b>20</b> has a plurality of first contacts (not shown) mounted therein, a plurality of grounding pads <b>23</b> disposed on a bottom surface thereof and a wedge-shaped protruding portion <b>29</b> disposed on an end portion thereof for coupling with the wedge-shaped housing <b>40</b>. The electronic card <b>20</b> further has a pair of recesses <b>25</b>, <b>27</b> defined on opposite side edge portions thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the card bus connector <b>10</b> has a header connector <b>1</b> comprising a base <b>11</b> and a plurality of second contacts (not shown) mounted into the base <b>11</b> for engaging with the first contacts of the electronic card. The card bus connector <b>10</b> further has a grounding plate <b>4</b> mounted to a bottom portion of the base <b>11</b>, an ejector mechanism <b>6</b> operatively associated with the header connector <b>1</b> for moving the electronic card <b>20</b> to an ejected position and a shield <b>5</b> enclosing the header connector <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref>, <b>4</b> and <b>5</b>, the base <b>11</b> has a pair of first holes (not labeled) defined on opposite corner portions thereof, a first arm <b>13</b> and an opposite second arm <b>15</b> projecting forwardly and forming a receiving space <b>30</b> therebetween for receiving the electronic card <b>20</b>. The first arm <b>13</b> and the second arm <b>15</b> respectively has a first guiding slot <b>131</b> and a second guiding slot <b>151</b> for guiding the electronic card <b>20</b>. The first arm <b>13</b> has a first protrusion <b>133</b> disposed on an upper portion of the inner surface of the first slot <b>131</b>. The second arm <b>15</b> includes a second protrusion <b>153</b> disposed on a central portion of the inner surface of the second guiding slot <b>151</b>. The first protrusion <b>133</b> and the second protrusion <b>153</b> respectively engages with the recesses <b>25</b>, <b>27</b> of the electronic card <b>20</b> for anti-mismating.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the grounding plate <b>4</b> includes a connecting portion <b>41</b> mounted to a bottom portion of the base <b>11</b>, a grounding portion <b>43</b> extending forwardly from the connecting portion <b>41</b> and having a plurality of grounding terminals <b>431</b> extending upwardly for connecting with grounding pads <b>23</b> of electronic card <b>20</b>. The grounding plate <b>4</b> further has a pair of ear portions <b>45</b> each extending upwardly and outwardly and defining a second hole <b>451</b> thereon, corresponding to the first hole.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The shield <b>5</b> comprises a pair of third hole <b>51</b> defined thereon and a side wall <b>53</b> having an opening <b>531</b> defined thereon for coupling with the a bulge <b>155</b> disposed on the second arm <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-3</figref>, during assembly, firstly, the grounding plate <b>4</b> and the shield <b>5</b> are respectively mounted to the bottom portion of the base <b>11</b> and a top portion of the base <b>11</b> by a screw (not shown) inserting through the third hole <b>51</b>, the first hole and screwing into the second hole <b>451</b> of the ear portion <b>45</b>. Secondly, the electronic card <b>20</b> is inserted into the receiving space <b>30</b>, with the wedge-shaped protruding portion <b>29</b> coupling with the wedge-shaped housing <b>40</b>. The first contacts of the electronic card <b>20</b> engage with the second contacts of the base <b>11</b> of the header connector <b>1</b>. The grounding terminals <b>431</b> of the grounding plate <b>43</b> electrically connect with the grounding pads <b>23</b> of the electronic card <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">It is to be understood, however, that even though numerous characteristics and advantages of the present invention have been set forth in the foregoing description, together with details of the structure and function of the invention, the disclosure is illustrative only, and changes may be made in detail, especially in matters of shape, size, and arrangement of parts within the principles of the invention to the full extent indicated by the broad general meaning of the terms in which the appended claims are expressed.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A card bus connector assembly mounted within a housing, for connecting to a printed circuit board, comprising: an electronic card having a plurality of first contacts mounted therein and a plurality of grounding pads disposed on a bottom surface thereof; and a card bus connector, comprising: a base; a plurality of second contacts mounted into the base for engaging with the first contacts; a grounding plate mounted to a bottom surface of the base and having a plurality of grounding terminals extending upwardly for engaging with the grounding pads of the electronic card; a shield enclosing the connector; and an ejector mechanism mounted to the shield, wherein said base comprises a first arm and a second arm projecting forwardly from opposite side portions thereof and a receiving space defined therebetween, wherein said first arm and the second arm respectively have a first guiding slot and a second guiding slot for guiding the electronic card, wherein said electronic card has a pair of recesses defined on opposite side edge portions thereof, said first arm has a first protrusion disposed on an upper portion of the inner surface of the first guiding slot, and said second arm includes a second protrusion disposed on a central portion of the inner surface of the second guiding slot for coupling with the recesses, wherein the electronic card comprises a wedge-shaped protruding portion disposed on an end portion thereof for coupling with the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The card bus connector assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said grounding plate has a connecting portion mounted to the bottom surface of the base, and a grounding portion extending forwardly from the connecting portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The card bus connector assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein said grounding plate further has a pair of ear portions each extending upwardly and outwardly from the connecting portion and defining a hole thereon.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The card bus connector assembly as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, further comprising a screw inserting through the hole of the grounding plate for connecting the grounding plate to the base and the shield.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An electrical connector assembly comprising: an printed circuit board defining a mounting face thereon; a header having a first surface mounted to the mounting face and including a plurality of terminals therein; a metallic shell mounted on a second surface of the header which is opposite to the first surface under a condition that said shell, said header and said printed circuit board commonly define a card receiving space into which said terminals extend; an ejection mechanism mounted to at least one of said shell and said header; and a metallic grounding plate sandwiched between the printed circuit board and the header around said mounting face and said first surface; wherein said grounding plate defines at least one grounding tang extending into the card receiving space for engagement with a grounding pad formed on an electronic card which is received within the card receiving space, wherein a lever of said ejection mechanism is sandwiched between the shell and the header around said second surface, wherein said mounting face directs upwardly, wherein said grounding plate and said shell are respectively located on two opposite sides of the receiving space in a vertical direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
