<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641506-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641506</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12405277</doc-number>
<date>20090317</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="regional">
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>08152900</doc-number>
<date>20080318</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439485</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Electrical connection device and connector</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5080593</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Neumann et al.</name>
<date>19920100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5505167</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kennedy</name>
<date>19960400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>123 4184</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5584490</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Inoue et al.</name>
<date>19961200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>277595</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5616973</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Khazanov et al.</name>
<date>19970400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>310 54</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5636684</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Teytu et al.</name>
<date>19970600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0045150</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Krause</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0035488</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Bosco et al.</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>1 266 383</doc-number>
<kind>B</kind>
<date>19680400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>88 01 086</doc-number>
<kind>U1</kind>
<date>19880300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 005 429</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19791100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 401 640</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19901200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00012">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>0 720 420</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>19960700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00013">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 289 074</doc-number>
<kind>A2</kind>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00014">
<document-id>
<country>EP</country>
<doc-number>1 833 123</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00015">
<othercit>European Search Report (with English language translation of category of cited documents) dated Aug. 28, 2008.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439376</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439485</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439196</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 18</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439700</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090239408</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090924</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sacher</last-name>
<first-name>Robert</first-name>
<address>
<city>Birr</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Knapp</last-name>
<first-name>Wolfgang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lenzburg</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CH</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Buchanan Ingersoll &#x26; Rooney PC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>ABB Schweiz AG</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Baden</city>
<country>CH</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Abrams</last-name>
<first-name>Neil</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Phuong</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The disclosure relates to a connection device, in particular a heavy-duty plug-type connection, with a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors; the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state; at least one of the connectors comprising a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant; the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements; all of the access points of the coolant line being arranged outside of the connection region.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="220.73mm" wi="162.73mm" file="US07641506-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="223.77mm" wi="146.81mm" file="US07641506-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="256.71mm" wi="163.66mm" file="US07641506-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="224.45mm" wi="168.99mm" file="US07641506-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority under 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;119 to European Patent Application No. 08152900.0 filed in Europe on Mar. 18, 2008, the entire content of which is hereby incorporated by reference in its entirety.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The disclosure relates to an electrical connection device and to a connector, in particular for producing electrical connections for conducting high currents.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND INFORMATION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Electrical plug-type connections have a wide variety of uses. They make it possible to connect electrical devices or assemblies by manually joining together mutually complementary connection elements. In order that said elements can be joined together without a large amount of force being used, the required plug-in forces are designed to be as low as possible. However, this means that the contact force in such plug-type connections is lower than is the case in screw-type connections or clamping connections, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A lower contact force in plug-type connections results in increased contact resistance at the contact point, at which a power loss is produced in the event of a current flow owing to the voltage drop. This results in heating at the contact point of the plug-type connection, which can result in accelerated contact degradation as a result of oxidation or a change to the structure of the contact materials used and ultimately in thermal destruction of the contacts.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">A possible way of avoiding the disadvantages of excessive heating of the contact point consists in cooling of the plug-type connector. For example, the document US 2006/035488 specifies an air-cooled plug, which is intended to reduce the heating of the contact point. The plug has cooling laminates, which are thermally connected to the contacts. One disadvantage is the fact that the cooling laminates have a negative effect on the physical size of the plug and another is the fact that they make insulation of the plug more difficult.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Improved cooling of the contact point is achieved if the plug-type connection is cooled with a liquid coolant, e.g., water. The document EP 0 401 640 has disclosed such a liquid-cooled plug-type connection with complementary connection elements. During assembly, there is both an electrical connection and a coolant connection produced between the connection elements. The coolant connection exists, in the connected state, as a coolant line through the plug-type connection.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">However, one disadvantage is the fact that the coolant channel is also opened, as well as the current path, when the plug-type connection is disconnected, with the result that the liquid coolant needs to be removed before the disconnection.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Exemplary embodiments disclosed herein can provide an improved connection device which has sufficient cooling at a contact point of a connector, has a low space requirement and can be joined together and disconnected without any preparatory measures.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">A connection device for a heavy-duty plug-type connection is disclosed. Such a connection device has a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors; the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state; at least one of the connectors comprising a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant; the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements. All of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside the connection region. The first connector comprises a housing with a contact-making element accommodated therein, a section of the coolant line being formed between the housing and the contact-making element, the housing having a passage for accommodating the contact-making element of the second connector, the passage being formed in such a way that it is closed in the connected state by means of the contact-making element of the second connector so as to prevent the eergence of the coolant, and a closure element being provided in order to close the passage in the non-connected state so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">A connection device for a heavy-duty plug-type connection is disclosed. Such a connection device has a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors; the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state; at least one of the connectors comprising a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant; the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements. All of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside the connection region. The coolant line is arranged in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element of the at least one connector.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">An electrical connector, in particular a heavy-duty plug, for producing an electrical connection is disclosed. Such an electrical connector comprises: a contact-making element in order to make contact with a further contact-making element of a further connector in a connected state so as to produce the electrical connection; a connection region, which is provided to bear, in the connected state, on a corresponding further connection region of the further connector; and a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant; the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point at the contact-making element. All of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside of the connection region, and a housing with a contact-making element accommodated therein is provided, with a section of the coolant line being formed between said housing and said contact-making element, the housing having a passage for accommodating the contact-making element of the further connector, a closure element being provided in order to close, in the non-connected state, the passage so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">An electrical connector, in particular a heavy-duty plug, for producing an electrical connection is disclosed. Such an electrical connector comprises: a contact-making element in order to make contact with a further contact-making element of a further connector in a connected state so as to produce the electrical connection; a connection region, which is provided to bear, in the connected state, on a corresponding further connection region of the further connector; and a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant; the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point at the contact-making element. All of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside of the connection region. The coolant line is arranged in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In another aspect, a method of providing a heavy-duty plug-type connection is disclosed. Such a method is based on a connection device having a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors; the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state. The method comprises providing with at least one of the connectors a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant, the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements; arranging all of the access points of the coolant line outside the connection region; and arranging the coolant line in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element of the at least one connector.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Exemplary embodiments of the disclosure will be explained in more detail below with reference to the attached drawings, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a </i>and <b>1</b><i>b </i>show a schematic illustration of a plug-type connection, in which connection element is provided with a coolant line, in a connected and a non-connected state;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a </i>and <b>2</b><i>b </i>show a schematic illustration of a plug-type connection, in which two complementary connection elements are provided with coolant lines, in a connected and a non-connected state;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b </i>show a schematic illustration of a plug-type connection, in which a cooling unit with a coolant line as a separate element is fitted on a connection element, in a connected and a non-connected state;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b </i>show a schematic illustration of a plug-type connection, in which the coolant flows directly around the contact point, in a connected and a non-connected state;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> shows an illustration of a plug-type connection system with a plurality of plug-type connections, which are each connected to a coolant pump.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In the drawings, the same reference numerals denote elements with an identical or similar function.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In accordance with a first aspect, a connection device, in particular a heavy-duty plug-type connection, is provided. The connection device comprises a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors. The connectors bear against one another at a connection region in the connected state. At least one of the connectors comprises a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant. The coolant line is coupled to the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements. All of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside of the connection region.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">One aspect of the disclosure provides a coolant line in at least one of the connectors for the connection device, which coolant line is not impaired by the connection device being disconnected and assembled, with the result that the coolant remains within the respective connector irrespective of whether the connection device is in the connected or non-connected state. The coolant line is arranged close to the contact point of the connection device, with the result that heat generated there is transported away by a coolant moving through the coolant line.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Furthermore, the first connector can be in the form of a female connector and the second connector can be in the form of a male connector.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">In accordance with one exemplary embodiment, the coolant line is arranged in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element of the at least one connector.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The first connector comprises a housing with a contact-making element accommodated therein, with a section of the coolant line being formed between said housing and said contact-making element. The housing has a passage for accommodating the contact-making element of the second connector, the passage being designed in such a way that it is closed, in the connected state, by the contact-making element of the second connector so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant. A closure element is furthermore provided in order to close the passage in the non-connected state so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Furthermore, the closure element can be prestressed by a spring element, which presses the closure element, in the non-connected state, against a stop into the passage in order to close said passage.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The contact-making element of the second connector can have, for example, a cylindrical form.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The passage can be provided with a sealing element in order to seal off the passage so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">In accordance with another exemplary embodiment, a further section of the coolant line is formed within the contact-making element.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In accordance with a further aspect, an electrical connector, in particular a heavy-duty plug, for producing an electrical connection is provided. The electrical connector comprises a contact-making element in order to make contact with a further contact-making element of a further connector in a connected state so as to produce the electrical connection. A connection region, is provided to bear, in the connected state, on a corresponding further connection region of the further connector. The connector furthermore has a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant. The coolant line is coupled to the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point at the contact-making element. All of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside of the connection region.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">Furthermore, the coolant line can be arranged in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In accordance with one exemplary embodiment, a housing with a contact-making element accommodated therein is provided, with a section of the coolant line being formed between said housing and said contact-making element, the housing having a passage for accommodating the contact-making element of the further connector. In the non-connected state, the passage can be closed with the aid of a closure element so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Furthermore, the closure element can be prestressed by a spring element, which presses the closure element, in the non-connected state, against a stop into the passage.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In accordance with a further aspect, a connection module with the one or more electrical connectors above is provided, which connectors are coupled to a coolant pump and a heat exchanger via coolant lines.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a </i>and <b>1</b><i>b </i>show a plug-type connection <b>1</b> with a first connection element (connector) <b>2</b> and a second connection element <b>3</b> in a plugged-together or joined (connected) state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a</i>) and in a separated (non-connected) state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b</i>).</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The first connection element <b>2</b> has two mutually opposite contact arms <b>4</b>, which are arranged around a cutout <b>5</b>. The contact arms <b>4</b> have two contact-making regions <b>7</b>, which are arranged as elevations pointing towards one another on the two contact arms <b>4</b>. The second connection element <b>3</b> has a contact pin <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The contact pin <b>6</b> of the second connection element <b>3</b> can be inserted into the cutout <b>5</b> of the first connection element <b>2</b>, with the result that the contact-making regions <b>7</b> of the contact arms <b>4</b> slide along the contact pin <b>6</b> and, in the completely connected state, bear against respective contact faces of the contact pin <b>6</b>. When the two connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> are plugged together, the contact arms <b>4</b> are deflected elastically, with the result that the contact-making regions <b>7</b> are pressed with a certain contact force against the respective contact face of the contact pin <b>6</b>. As a result, an electrical connection at a contact point between the contact arms <b>4</b> and the contact pin <b>6</b> of the two connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> is produced in a connection region.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Generally, the connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>, i.e. the distance between the contact-making regions <b>7</b>, the elasticity of the contact arms <b>4</b> and the thickness of the contact pin <b>6</b>, are designed in such a way that it is possible to manually plug together the two connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> without a large amount of force. However, this limits the possible contact force between the contact-making regions <b>7</b> and the contact pin <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The contact force at the contact point between the contact-making region <b>7</b> and the contact pin <b>6</b> is a critical measure determining the contact resistance which in turn substantially influences the overall resistance of the plug-type connection. A considerable power loss in the form of heat therefore arises in particular at the contact point in the event of a high current flow through the plug-type connection. In order that the heat does not result in degradation or destruction of the contact-making region <b>7</b> and/or of the contact pin <b>6</b>, said heat therefore needs to be dissipated in a suitable manner.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In order to dissipate the heat, in the case of the plug-type connection in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a </i>and <b>1</b><i>b </i>the disclosure provides that a cooling device is integrated in the second connection element <b>3</b>, which cooling device is in the form of a coolant line <b>8</b>. The coolant line <b>8</b> has an inlet opening <b>9</b> and an outlet opening <b>10</b>, via which the coolant is supplied and discharged. During operation of the plug-type connection <b>1</b>, the coolant is guided through the coolant line <b>8</b>, with the result that heat located in the second connection element is dissipated.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The inlet opening <b>9</b> and the outlet opening <b>10</b> are arranged on the second connection element <b>3</b> in such a way that they are accessible irrespective of the connection state of the plug-type connection <b>1</b>. That is to say that, when the connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> are plugged together or joined together, neither the inlet opening <b>9</b> nor the outlet opening <b>10</b> of the coolant line <b>8</b> located in the second connection element <b>3</b> is covered or accommodated in the first connection element <b>2</b>. Furthermore, there is also no coolant line which runs from the first connection element <b>2</b> to the second connection element <b>3</b>. This makes it possible to disconnect the plug-type connection without first stopping the coolant cycle and/or without the coolant being let out of the connection element <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">In the exemplary embodiment shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1</figref><i>a </i>and <b>1</b><i>b</i>, the inlet opening <b>9</b> and the outlet opening <b>10</b> are arranged on a side face of the second connection element <b>3</b>, which side face extends substantially parallel to the direction in which the connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> are joined together. It is also possible for the inlet opening <b>9</b> and the outlet opening <b>10</b> to be arranged on respectively different side faces of the second connection element <b>3</b> or on a rear side of the second connection element <b>3</b>, which is opposite the contact pin <b>6</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The coolant line <b>8</b> can be arranged in loops in the second connection element <b>3</b>, with the result that the coolant line <b>8</b> extends in meandering fashion in the second connection element <b>3</b>. As a result, the interface between the coolant line <b>8</b> and the surrounding material is increased, with the result that improved heat dissipation is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">As is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a </i>and <b>2</b><i>b</i>, the two connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> can be equipped with corresponding coolant line <b>8</b>, with the result that cooling can take place both via the contact pin <b>6</b> of the second connection element <b>3</b> and via the contact arms <b>4</b> of the first connection element <b>2</b>. The coolant line <b>8</b> can be designed to be identical or different. Of course it is also possible for only the first connection element <b>2</b> to be provided with the coolant device. In the case of the provision of only one cooling device, said cooling device should be provided in the connection element <b>2</b>, <b>3</b> in which better heat dissipation from the contact point to the cooling device is ensured.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b </i>show a further variant of a plug-type connection <b>14</b> in the plugged-together state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>a</i>) and in the disconnected state (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref><i>b</i>). In the plug-type connection <b>14</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b</i>, a cooling device in the form of a separate cooling element <b>15</b> made from a highly thermally conductive material is illustrated. The cooling element <b>15</b> is fastened on one of the connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>, with the result that heat can be dissipated from the contact point between the contact arm <b>4</b> and the contact pin <b>6</b> via the cooling element <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The cooling element <b>15</b> has a coolant line <b>16</b>, through which coolant is introduced via an inlet opening <b>17</b> and coolant is passed out via an outlet opening <b>18</b>. The coolant line <b>16</b> can have loops in order to increase the interface between the coolant line <b>16</b> and the material of the cooling element <b>15</b>, with the result that the heat dissipation from the material of the cooling element <b>15</b> is improved. As an alternative or in addition, further measures for enlarging the interface between the coolant line <b>16</b> and the material of the cooling element <b>15</b>, such as laminates or the like, for example, can be provided.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The cooling element <b>15</b> is fastened on the second connection element <b>3</b> with as low a thermal resistance as possible. The fastening can take place, for example, by means of adhesive-bonding or another mechanical connection, such as by means of a clamping connection or a screw-type connection <b>19</b>, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In a further exemplary embodiment, the plug-type connection <b>14</b>, which is shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref><i>a </i>and <b>3</b><i>b</i>, can also have a corresponding cooling element <b>15</b> on the two connection elements <b>2</b>, <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b </i>illustrate a further plug-type connection <b>20</b>. The further plug-type connection <b>20</b> comprises a first connection element <b>21</b>, which can be connected to a complementary second connection element <b>22</b>. The first connection element <b>21</b> comprises a housing <b>23</b>, in which an electrically conductive conductor element <b>24</b> is arranged fixedly. The cross section of the housing <b>23</b> may be circular-cylindrical or quadrilateral or have another form.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The conductor element <b>24</b> has contact arms <b>25</b>, which are each provided with a contact-making region <b>26</b>. The contact arms <b>25</b> surround a cutout, in which a contact pin <b>29</b> of the second connection element is accommodated in the connected state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>. The contact-making region <b>26</b>, in the connected state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>, makes contact with the contact pin <b>29</b> at a contact point and thus produces the electrical connection. In the embodiment in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4</figref><i>a </i>and <b>4</b><i>b</i>, the faces at which the connection elements <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> bear against one another in the connected state represent the connection region.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">In the conductor element <b>24</b>, a first coolant line section <b>27</b> for conducting a coolant is provided. An interspace between an inner wall of the housing <b>23</b> and the conductor element <b>24</b> is furthermore used as a second coolant line section <b>28</b>, through which the coolant is conducted. The second coolant line section <b>28</b> can be provided so as to run around the periphery (tangentially with respect to the connection direction) or only at certain regions. A part of the second coolant line section <b>28</b> can be formed between the housing <b>23</b> and one or more of the contact arms <b>25</b> in order to be able to dissipate the heat generated at the contact point as efficiently as possible. The first coolant line section <b>27</b> and the second coolant line section <b>28</b> are parts of the coolant line through which a coolant is conducted in order to dissipate heat generated at the contact point. The direction of flow of the coolant in the coolant line sections <b>27</b>, <b>28</b> is essentially as desired.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The housing <b>23</b> has a passage in the form of an accommodating opening <b>34</b>, by means of which the contact pin <b>29</b> of the second connection element <b>22</b> can be accommodated into the cutout when the connection elements <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> are plugged together. The accommodating opening <b>34</b> has substantially the cross section of the contact pin <b>29</b>, with the result that the contact pin <b>29</b> can be accommodated in the accommodating opening <b>34</b> with little play. The accommodating opening <b>34</b> can furthermore be provided with a sealing element <b>35</b> in order to seal off the accommodating opening <b>34</b> so as to prevent a loss of coolant if the contact pin <b>29</b> is accommodated therein.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The contact pin <b>29</b>, in the connected state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>, reaches through the accommodating opening <b>34</b> between the contact arms <b>25</b>, with the result that the contact-making regions <b>26</b> of the contact arms <b>25</b> make contact with the contact pin <b>29</b> and press with a certain contact force laterally (with respect to the connection direction) onto the contact pin <b>29</b>. The contact force can be produced, for example, by an elastic deflection of the contact arms <b>25</b> when the contact pin <b>29</b> is accommodated.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In order to avoid coolant provided in the coolant line flowing out in the disconnected state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>, a closure element <b>36</b> is provided which has a closure section <b>37</b> and a stop <b>38</b>. The closure element <b>36</b> acts as a closure for the accommodating opening in the disconnected state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The closure section <b>37</b> is pressed into the accommodating opening <b>34</b> of the housing <b>23</b> with the aid of a spring <b>39</b>, the stop <b>38</b> of the closure element <b>36</b> ensuring that the closure element <b>36</b> remains in the housing <b>23</b>. In the uncoupled state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>, the stop <b>38</b> can bear against the conductor element <b>24</b>, for example by means of a suitable restraining element. Alternatively, the contact-making region <b>26</b> of one or both contact arms <b>25</b> can act as the restraining element for the closure element <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The spring <b>39</b> is arranged between the closure element <b>36</b> and a holding edge <b>40</b> on the conductor element <b>24</b> and can be prestressed. The holding edge <b>40</b> can be formed, for example, by a stepped enlargement of the cross section of the first coolant line section <b>27</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">When the connection elements <b>21</b>, <b>22</b> are plugged together, an end face of the contact pin <b>29</b> presses onto an end face of the closure element <b>36</b> and presses the latter into the cutout of the first connection element <b>21</b> against the spring force exerted by the spring <b>39</b>. In this case, the end faces bear flush against one another. As a result, the contact pin <b>29</b> replaces the closure element <b>36</b> in the accommodating opening <b>34</b> of the housing <b>23</b>, wherein at no point in time is it is possible for coolant to flow out of the housing <b>23</b> through the accommodating opening <b>34</b>. Alternatively, the end faces of the closure element <b>36</b> and the contact pin <b>29</b> can be provided with a mutually complementary topology, in particular can have complementary conical forms in order to avoid the end faces sliding away from one another when the connection elements are plugged together.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The closure element <b>36</b>, as is the housing <b>23</b>, can be formed from an electrically nonconductive material, with the result that sufficient insulation can be achieved in the disconnected state of the further plug-type connection <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a connection system <b>50</b> with a plurality of plug-type connections is provided. First connection elements <b>51</b> are provided in a first connection module <b>52</b> and second connection elements <b>53</b> are provided in a second connection module <b>54</b>. Each of the first and second connection elements <b>51</b>, <b>53</b> can be constructed in one of the abovedescribed ways. The connection elements <b>51</b>, <b>53</b> are arranged in the respective connection modules <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> in such a way that they can be connected to a complementary connection module by being plugged in a connection direction.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The first connection elements <b>51</b> are coupled to a first coolant pump <b>55</b> via first coolant lines <b>60</b>, with the result that the coolant channels in the individual first connection elements <b>51</b> of the first connection module <b>52</b> are connected in serial fashion with respect to the coolant cycle. The first coolant pump <b>55</b> can be arranged within the first connection module <b>52</b> or separately therefrom. The first coolant line <b>60</b> passes through a first heat exchanger <b>62</b> in order to dissipate the heat dissipated from the first connection elements <b>51</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The second connection elements <b>53</b> are coupled to a second coolant pump <b>56</b> via second coolant lines <b>61</b>, with the result that the coolant channels in the individual second connection elements <b>53</b> of the second connection module <b>54</b> are likewise connected in serial fashion with respect to the coolant cycle. The second coolant pump <b>56</b> can be arranged within the second connection module <b>52</b> or separately therefrom. The second coolant line <b>61</b> passes through a second heat exchanger <b>63</b> in order to dissipate the heat dissipated from the second connection elements <b>53</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In order to ensure sufficient electrical insulation between the individual connection elements <b>51</b>, <b>53</b> of a connection module <b>52</b>, <b>54</b>, nonconducting coolant lines <b>60</b>, <b>61</b>, or ones which are sufficiently insulated from the connection elements, and a nonconductive coolant can be used. In particular, electrically insulating liquids, such as water, oils, fluorinated liquids or the like, for example, can absorb a lot of heat and at the same time insulate high electrical voltages.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As an alternative to the configuration illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, it is also possible for only one connection module <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> of the connection system <b>50</b> to be provided with cooling devices or a coolant pump.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In accordance with a further exemplary embodiment, it is also possible for only one coolant pump <b>55</b> or <b>56</b> to be provided which ensures circulation of the cooling liquid through both connection modules <b>52</b>, <b>54</b>. The coolant pump <b>55</b> can then be arranged separately from the connection modules <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> or in one of the two connection modules <b>52</b>, <b>54</b>. The connection modules <b>52</b>, <b>54</b> then have corresponding additional disconnection points in the coolant line (forward flow and return flow) for complete disconnection as the interfaces.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the present invention can be embodied in other specific forms without departing from the spirit or essential characteristics thereof. The presently disclosed embodiments are therefore considered in all respects to be illustrative and not restricted. The scope of the invention is indicated by the appended claims rather than the foregoing description and all changes that come within the meaning and range and equivalence thereof are intended to be embraced therein.</p>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">LIST OF REFERENCE SYMBOLS</heading>
<p id="p-0067" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0066"><b>1</b> Plug-type connection</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0067"><b>2</b> First connection element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0068"><b>3</b> Second connection element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0069"><b>4</b> Contact arm</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0070"><b>5</b> Cutout</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0071"><b>6</b> Contact pin</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0072"><b>7</b> Contact-making region</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0073"><b>8</b> Coolant line</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0074"><b>9</b> Inlet opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0075"><b>10</b> Outlet opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0076"><b>14</b> Plug-type connection</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0077"><b>15</b> Cooling element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0078"><b>16</b> Coolant line</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0079"><b>17</b> Inlet opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0080"><b>18</b> Outlet opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0081"><b>19</b> Screw-type connection</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0082"><b>20</b> Plug-type connection</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0083"><b>21</b> First connection element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0084"><b>22</b> Second connection element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0085"><b>23</b> Housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0086"><b>24</b> Conductor element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0087"><b>25</b> Contact arms</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0088"><b>26</b> Contact-making region</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0089"><b>27</b> First coolant line section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0090"><b>28</b> Second coolant line section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0091"><b>29</b> Contact pin</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0092"><b>34</b> Accommodating opening</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0093"><b>35</b> Sealing element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0094"><b>36</b> Closure element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0095"><b>37</b> Closure section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0096"><b>38</b> Stop</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0032" num="0097"><b>39</b> Spring</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0033" num="0098"><b>50</b> Connection system</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0034" num="0099"><b>51</b> First connection element</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0035" num="0100"><b>52</b> First connection module</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0036" num="0101"><b>53</b> Second connection elements</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0037" num="0102"><b>54</b> Second connection module</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0038" num="0103"><b>55</b> First coolant pump</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0039" num="0104"><b>56</b> Second coolant pump</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0040" num="0105"><b>60</b> First coolant line</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0041" num="0106"><b>61</b> Second coolant line</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0042" num="0107"><b>62</b> First heat exchanger</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0043" num="0108"><b>63</b> Second heat exchanger</li>
</ul>
</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connection device for a heavy-duty plug-type connection, with a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors;
<claim-text>the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the connectors comprising a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>all of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside the connection region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first connector comprises a housing with a contact-making element accommodated therein, a section of the coolant line being formed between the housing and the contact-making element, the housing having a passage for accommodating the contact-making element of the second connector,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the passage being formed in such a way that it is closed in the connected state by means of the contact-making element of the second connector so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a closure element being provided in order to close the passage in the non-connected state so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first connector is in the form of a female connector and the second connector is in the form of a male connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the closure element is prestressed by a spring element, which presses the closure element in the non-connected state against a stop into the passage in order to close said passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein a further section of the coolant line is formed within the contact-making element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the contact-making element of the second connector has a cylindrical form.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the passage is provided with a sealing element in order to seal off the passage so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the passage is provided with a sealing element in order to seal off the passage so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein a further section of the coolant line is formed within the contact-making element.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A connection device for a heavy-duty plug-type connection, with a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors;
<claim-text>the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one of the connectors comprising a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>all of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside the connection region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coolant line is arranged in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element of the at least one connector.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The connection device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the first connector is in the form of a female connector and the second connector is in the form of a male connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An electrical connector, in particular a heavy-duty plug, for producing an electrical connection, comprising:
<claim-text>a contact-making element in order to make contact with a further contact-making element of a further connector in a connected state so as to produce the electrical connection;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection region, which is provided to bear, in the connected state, on a corresponding further connection region of the further connector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point at the contact-making element; wherein all of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside of the connection region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing with a contact-making element accommodated therein is provided, with a section of the coolant line being formed between said housing and said contact-making element,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the housing having a passage for accommodating the contact-making element of the further connector,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a closure element being provided in order to close, in the non-connected state, the passage so as to prevent the emergence of the coolant.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A connection module with one or more electrical connectors as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, which are coupled to a coolant pump and a heat exchanger via coolant lines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, wherein the closure element is prestressed by a spring element, which presses the closure element, in the non-connected state, against a stop into the passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A connection module with one or more electrical connectors as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, which are coupled to a coolant pump and a heat exchanger via coolant lines.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An electrical connector, in particular a heavy-duty plug, for producing an electrical connection, comprising:
<claim-text>a contact-making element in order to make contact with a further contact-making element of a further connector in a connected state so as to produce the electrical connection;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection region, which is provided to bear, in the connected state, on a corresponding further connection region of the further connector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point at the contact-making element; wherein all of the access points of the coolant line are arranged outside of the connection region, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the coolant line is arranged in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method of providing a heavy-duty plug-type connection based on a connection device having a first connector and a second connector, which each have a contact-making element in order to produce an electrical connection in the connected state of the connectors; the connectors bearing against one another at a connection region in the connected state, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing with at least one of the connectors a coolant line with one or more access points for the supply and discharge, respectively, of a coolant, the coolant line being provided at the contact-making element in order to dissipate heat from a contact point between the contact-making elements;</claim-text>
<claim-text>arranging all of the access points of the coolant line outside the connection region; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>arranging the coolant line in a separate cooling unit, which is fastened on the contact-making element of the at least one connector. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
