<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641507-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641507</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12313239</doc-number>
<date>20081117</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2007 1 0190349</doc-number>
<date>20071116</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>24</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439497</main-classification>
<further-classification>439597</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Cable connector</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6619985</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ko</name>
<date>20030900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6659791</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ko et al.</name>
<date>20031200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439353</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6705893</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Ko</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439607</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>11</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439497</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439597</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439607</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439610</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090130888</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090521</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Ko</last-name>
<first-name>David Tso-Chin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Fullerton</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chung</last-name>
<first-name>Wei Te</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cheng</last-name>
<first-name>Andrew C.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="03" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Ming Chieh</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Inc. Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Le</last-name>
<first-name>Thanh-Tam T</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A cable connector includes an insulative housing, some terminals, an insert and a shield. The insulative housing includes a main body, a pair of side arms respectively rearward extending from the middle of the two sides of the main body to form a receiving space between the two side arms. The forward section of said main body is a mating portion with some evenly disposed grooves. The rearward section of said main body is a connecting portion with some troughs corresponding to the grooves. Each side arm includes two pair of separated receiving slots on the tail thereof to be connected to the receiving space. Each of terminals includes a mating piece on the forward part thereof to be received in the mating portion and a connecting piece on the rearward part thereof to be received in the connecting portion. The insert includes a main body with a grid to form some passages corresponding to the troughs of the housing and two pair of fastening portions respectively extending from two sides of the main body. The main body of insert is received in the receiving space between the two side arms of the housing through said fastening portions being inserted into the receiving slots of the housing. The shield includes an upper cover assembled on the upper surface of the housing to cover the connecting portion and the insert, and a lower cover assembled on the lower surface of the housing to cover the connecting portion and the insert.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="147.83mm" wi="226.48mm" file="US07641507-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="172.72mm" wi="131.91mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="226.91mm" wi="154.52mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="192.62mm" wi="146.05mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="153.67mm" wi="118.96mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="176.28mm" wi="142.66mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="230.72mm" wi="163.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="200.49mm" wi="148.00mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="173.48mm" wi="122.51mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641507-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to a cable connector, and more particularly to a low-structure cable connector used to transmit electrical signals between a liquid crystal display and a mother board.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Miniaturization is a trend for portable electric devices. Thus, connectors, used in the portable electric devices, becomes thinner and smaller. U.S. Pat. No. 6,619,985 discloses a micro coaxial cable connector. The micro coaxial cable connector comprises an insulative housing, a terminal block, a grounding plate, and a metal shield. The micro coaxial cable connector has a shield firmly assembly on a redesigned dielectric housing. However, the grounding plate and the terminal block of the connector are received in the housing, so that the housing has a receiving space with a lower wall to receive the grounding plate and the metal shield. Both the wall of the receiving space and the grounding plate have a certain height, thus, it is difficult to make the connector thinner because of the connector's complicated components.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Hence, in this art, a cable connector to overcome the above-mentioned disadvantages of the prior art should be provided.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A primary object, therefore, of the present invention is to provide a cable connector with low structure.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In order to implement the above object, the cable connector comprises an insulative housing, some terminals, an insert and a shield. The insulative housing comprises a main body, a pair of side arms respectively rearward extending from the middle of the two sides of the main body to form a receiving space between the two side arms. The forward section of said main body is a mating portion with some evenly disposed grooves. The rearward section of said main body is a connecting portion with some troughs corresponding to the grooves. Each side arm comprises two pair of separated receiving slots on the tail thereof to be connected to the receiving space. Each of terminals comprises a mating piece on the forward part thereof to be received in the mating portion and a connecting piece on the rearward part thereof to be received in the connecting portion. The insert comprises a main body with a grid to form some passages corresponding to the troughs of the housing and two pair of fastening portions respectively extending from two sides of the main body. The main body of insert is received in the receiving space between the two side arms of the housing through said fastening portions being inserted into the receiving slots of the housing. The shield comprises an upper cover assembled on the upper surface of the housing to cover the connecting portion and the insert, and a lower cover assembled on the lower surface of the housing to cover the connecting portion and the insert.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Other objects, advantages and novel features of the invention will become more apparent from the following detailed description of a preferred embodiment when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a first embodiment of a cable connector in according with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded, perspective view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a partially assembled view of the cable connector assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross-section view taken along lines <b>4</b>-<b>4</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a second embodiment of a cable connector in according with the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is an exploded, perspective view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a partially assembled view of the cable connector assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-section view taken along lines <b>8</b>-<b>8</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>;</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Reference will now be made in detail to a preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a cable connector in according with a first embodiment of the present invention is shown. The cable connector <b>100</b> comprises an insulative housing <b>10</b>, a group of terminals <b>20</b>, an insert <b>30</b>, a metal shield <b>40</b> and some wires <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The terminals <b>20</b> are respectively received in the housing <b>10</b>. Each terminal <b>20</b> comprises a lathy mating piece <b>211</b> to form the forward part thereof, a lathy connecting piece <b>212</b> to form the rearward part thereof and a slight protrusion <b>21</b> forward extending from the middle of the nose of the mating piece <b>211</b>. The mating piece <b>211</b> is higher than the connecting piece <b>212</b> to form a step-shape structure.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The insulative housing <b>10</b> comprises a first main body <b>11</b> and a pair of block-shape, side arms <b>12</b> rearward extending from the middle of two sides of the housing <b>11</b>. The main body <b>11</b> comprises a mating portion <b>13</b> to form a forward section thereof, a supporting portion <b>14</b> to form a rearward section thereof, and a bar <b>15</b> across the mating portion <b>13</b> to be connected to said two side arms <b>12</b>. The mating portion <b>13</b> has some grooves <b>130</b>, each of which is aligned with each other, to receive the mating pieces <b>211</b> of the terminals <b>20</b>. Thus, the bar <b>15</b> crosses all grooves <b>130</b> to presses the terminals <b>20</b> received in the housing <b>10</b> to protect these terminals <b>20</b> from moving. Each groove <b>130</b> has a contracting portion <b>131</b> on the front end thereof to receive the protrusions <b>22</b> of the terminals <b>20</b>. The supporting portion <b>14</b> has a grid <b>141</b> to form some troughs <b>142</b> respectively corresponding to the grooves <b>130</b> of the mating portion <b>13</b> to receive the connecting pieces <b>212</b> of the terminals <b>20</b>. The grooves <b>130</b> are on the upper surface of the mating portion <b>13</b> and the troughs <b>142</b> are on the upper surface of the supporting portion <b>14</b>. The mating portion <b>13</b> is higher than the supporting portion <b>14</b> to form a step-shape structure <b>1314</b> corresponding to the same structure of the terminals <b>20</b>. A receiving space without upper or lower limit is formed between the two tails of the two side arms <b>12</b>. Each side arm <b>12</b> comprises two separated half-open receiving slots <b>120</b>, <b>121</b> on the lower surface of the tail thereof to be connected to the receiving space, and some holes <b>124</b> irregularly distributed thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The metal shield <b>40</b> comprises an upper cover <b>41</b> and a lower cover <b>42</b>. Both the upper cover <b>41</b> and the lower cover <b>42</b> are designed to adapt to the shape of the housing <b>10</b>. A few of fixing pieces <b>412</b>, <b>422</b> respectively extend from the two sides of both the upper cover <b>41</b> and the lower cover <b>42</b> to fix the metal shield <b>40</b> on the housing <b>10</b>. The site of the fixing pieces <b>412</b>, <b>422</b> is arranged to correspond to the holes <b>124</b> of the housing <b>10</b>, thus, the fixing pieces <b>412</b>, <b>422</b> are respectively inserted into the holes <b>124</b> to fix the upper cover <b>41</b> on the upper surface of the housing <b>10</b> and lower cover on the lower surface of the housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The insert <b>30</b> comprises a main body <b>31</b> located between the two side arms <b>12</b> of the housing <b>10</b> and two pair of fastening portions <b>321</b>, <b>322</b> fixing the insert <b>30</b> on the housing <b>10</b>. The main body <b>31</b> has a grid <b>311</b> to form some passages <b>312</b> corresponding to the troughs <b>142</b> of the supporting portion <b>14</b> to receive cables <b>50</b>. Each pair of fastening portions comprises two fastening portions respectively extending form the two opposite sides of the main body <b>31</b> along two opposite directions. Each of the fastening portions <b>321</b>, <b>322</b> comprises a rib <b>3210</b>/<b>3220</b> on the middle of the front surface thereof to make the fastening portion <b>321</b>, <b>322</b> respectively interferentially inserted into the receiving slots <b>120</b>, <b>121</b> of the housing <b>10</b>. Thus, the insert <b>30</b> is arranged side by side with the housing <b>10</b> to make the lower surfaces of both the insert <b>30</b> and connecting portion <b>14</b> on a same plane to reduce the height of the integrated cable connector <b>100</b>. Cables <b>50</b> respectively pass through the corresponding one of the passages <b>312</b> to be soldered on the connecting piece <b>212</b> of the terminals <b>20</b>. When cables <b>50</b> are soldered on the terminals <b>20</b>, the step-shape structure of the terminals <b>20</b> make soldering tin not flow to the mating pieces <b>211</b> of the terminals <b>20</b>, thus, the mating pieces <b>211</b> is able to transmit current well.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a cable connector in according with a second embodiment of the present invention is shown. The cable connector <b>100</b>&#x2032; comprises a insulative housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;, a group of terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;, an insert <b>30</b>&#x2032;, a metal shield <b>40</b>&#x2032;, some wires <b>50</b>&#x2032; and a pair of latches <b>60</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032; are received in the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;. Each terminal <b>20</b>&#x2032; comprises a lathy mating piece <b>211</b>&#x2032; to form a the forward part thereof, a lathy connecting piece <b>212</b>&#x2032; to form the rearward part thereof and a slight protrusion <b>21</b>&#x2032; forward extending from the middle of the nose of the mating piece <b>211</b>&#x2032;. The mating piece <b>211</b>&#x2032; is higher than the connecting piece <b>212</b>&#x2032; to form a step-shape structure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The insulative housing <b>10</b>&#x2032; comprises a first main body <b>11</b>&#x2032; and a pair of side arms <b>12</b>&#x2032; extending from the two sides of the main body <b>11</b>&#x2032;. The main body <b>11</b>&#x2032; comprises a mating portion <b>13</b>&#x2032; to form a forward section thereof, a supporting portion <b>14</b>&#x2032; to form a rearward section thereof, and a bar <b>15</b>&#x2032; across the mating portion <b>13</b>&#x2032; to be connected to said two side arms <b>12</b>&#x2032;. The mating portion <b>13</b>&#x2032; has some grooves <b>130</b>&#x2032;, each of which is aligned with each other, to receive the mating pieces <b>211</b>&#x2032; of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;. Each groove <b>130</b>&#x2032; has a contracting portion <b>131</b>&#x2032; on the top thereof to receive the protrusions <b>22</b>&#x2032; of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;. The supporting portion <b>14</b>&#x2032; has a grid <b>141</b>&#x2032; to form some through <b>142</b>&#x2032; corresponding to the grooves <b>130</b>&#x2032; of the mating portion <b>13</b>&#x2032; to receive the connecting pieces <b>212</b>&#x2032; of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;. The grooves <b>130</b>&#x2032; are on the upper surface of the mating portion <b>13</b>&#x2032; and the through <b>142</b>&#x2032; are on the upper surface of the supporting portion <b>14</b>&#x2032;. Thus, the bar <b>15</b>&#x2032; crosses all grooves <b>130</b>&#x2032; to presses the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032; received in the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032; to protect these terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032; from moving. The mating portion <b>13</b>&#x2032; is higher than the supporting portion <b>14</b>&#x2032; to form a step-shape structure <b>1314</b>&#x2032; corresponding to the same structure of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;. A receiving space without upper or lower limit is formed between the two tails of the two side arms <b>12</b>&#x2032;. Each side arm <b>12</b>&#x2032; comprises two separated half-open receiving slots <b>120</b>&#x2032;, <b>121</b>&#x2032; on the lower surface of the tail thereof to be connected to the receiving space, and some holes <b>124</b>&#x2032; irregularly distributed thereon.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The metal shield <b>40</b>&#x2032; comprises an upper cover <b>41</b>&#x2032; and a lower cover <b>42</b>&#x2032;. The shape of the upper cover <b>41</b>&#x2032; and the lower cover <b>42</b>&#x2032; are designed according to the shape of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;. Some fixing pieces <b>412</b>&#x2032;, <b>422</b>&#x2032; respectively extends from the two sides of both the upper cover <b>41</b>&#x2032; and the lower cover <b>42</b>&#x2032; to fix the metal shield <b>40</b> on the housing <b>10</b>. The site of the fixing pieces <b>412</b>&#x2032;, <b>422</b>&#x2032; is arranged to correspond to the holes <b>124</b>&#x2032; of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;, thus, the fixing pieces <b>412</b>&#x2032;, <b>422</b>&#x2032; are respectively inserted into the holes <b>124</b>&#x2032; to fix the upper cover <b>41</b>&#x2032; on the upper surface of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032; and the lower cover <b>42</b>&#x2032; on the lower surface of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The insert <b>30</b>&#x2032; comprises a main body <b>31</b>&#x2032; located between the two side arms <b>12</b>&#x2032; of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032; and two pair of fastening portions <b>321</b>&#x2032;, <b>322</b>&#x2032; fixing the insert <b>30</b>&#x2032; on the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;. The main body <b>31</b>&#x2032; has a grid <b>311</b>&#x2032; to form some passages <b>312</b>&#x2032; corresponding to the troughs <b>142</b>&#x2032; of the supporting portion <b>14</b>&#x2032; to receive cables <b>50</b>&#x2032;. Each pair of fastening portions <b>14</b>&#x2032; comprises two fastening portions <b>14</b>&#x2032; respectively extending form the two opposite sides of the main body <b>31</b>&#x2032; along two opposite directions. Each of the fastening portions <b>321</b>&#x2032;, <b>322</b>&#x2032; comprises a rib <b>3210</b>&#x2032;/<b>3220</b>&#x2032; on the middle of the front surface thereof to make the fastening portion <b>321</b>&#x2032;, <b>322</b>&#x2032; respectively interferentially inserted into the receiving slots <b>120</b>&#x2032;, <b>121</b>&#x2032; of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;. Thus, the insert <b>30</b>&#x2032; is arranged side by side with the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032; to make the lower surfaces of both the insert <b>30</b>&#x2032; and connecting portion <b>14</b>&#x2032; on a same plane to reduce the height of the integrated cable connector <b>100</b>&#x2032;. Cables <b>50</b>&#x2032; respectively pass through the corresponding one of the passages <b>312</b>&#x2032; to be soldered on the connecting piece <b>212</b>&#x2032; of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;. When cables <b>50</b>&#x2032; are soldered on the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;, the step-shape structure of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032; make soldering tin not flow to the mating pieces <b>211</b>&#x2032; of the terminals <b>20</b>&#x2032;, thus, the mating pieces <b>211</b>&#x2032; is able to transmit current well.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The two latches <b>60</b>&#x2032; are respectively connected to the two opposite sides of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032;. Each latch <b>60</b>&#x2032; is composed of an upper wall (not signed), a lower wall (not signed) and a side wall (not signed). And each latch <b>60</b>&#x2032; comprises a clasp <b>61</b>&#x2032; on the forward end of the lower wall, a spring <b>62</b>&#x2032; extending from the rear end of the side wall and then reversing to face forward, and a pair of fixing apertures <b>63</b>&#x2032; respectively on the upper wall and lower wall. The spring <b>62</b>&#x2032;, the upper wall and the lower wall are on the same side of the side wall. One fixing aperture <b>63</b>&#x2032; is corresponded to one post <b>126</b>&#x2032; of the side arm <b>12</b>&#x2032; of the housing <b>10</b>&#x2032; to fix the latch <b>61</b>&#x2032; on the side arm <b>12</b>&#x2032;. When one latch <b>60</b>&#x2032; is fixed on one side arm <b>12</b>&#x2032;, the spring <b>62</b>&#x2032; touches the outer side of the side arm <b>12</b>&#x2032;. For the spring <b>12</b>&#x2032; having flexibility, the latch <b>61</b>&#x2032; is able to be forced to revolve around the post <b>126</b>&#x2032;, and then automatically reset when force is released. When latches <b>60</b>&#x2032; are revolving, the tails of the latches move inward and the clasps <b>61</b>&#x2032; move outward. Thus, when the cable connector <b>100</b>&#x2032; is connected to the complementary connector (not shown), the latches <b>60</b>&#x2032; make the two connectors connected firmer through the clasps <b>61</b>&#x2032; and separated from each other easily under force.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">While the foregoing description includes details which will enable those skilled in the art to practice the invention, it should be recognized that the description is illustrative in nature and that many modifications and variations thereof will be apparent to those skilled in the art having the benefit of these teachings. It is accordingly intended that the invention herein be defined solely by the claims appended hereto and that the claims be interpreted as broadly as permitted by the prior art.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A cable connector, comprising:
<claim-text>an insulative housing, comprising a main body, and a pair of side arms respectively rearward extending from the middle of the two sides of the main body to form a receiving space between the two side arms, a forward section of said main body being a mating portion with some evenly disposed grooves and a rearward section of said main body being a connecting portion with some toughs corresponding to the grooves, each side arm comprising two receiving slots spaced apart from each other in the rear thereof to be connected to the receiving space;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a group of terminals, each of which comprising a mating piece on the forward part thereof to be received in the mating portion and a connecting piece on the rearward part thereof to be received in the connecting portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an insert, comprising a main body with a grid to form some passages corresponding to the troughs of the housing and two pair of fastening portions respectively extending from two sides of the main body, said main body being received in the receiving space between the two side arms of the housing through said fastening portions being inserted into the receiving slots of the housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a shield, comprising an upper cover assembled on the upper surface of the housing to cover the connecting portion and the insert, and a lower cover assembled on the lower surface of the housing to cover the connecting portion and the insert.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said mating piece of the terminal is higher than said connecting piece to form a step-shape structure, and said mating portion is higher than said connecting portion to form a step-shape structure corresponding to match the terminal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said terminal further comprises a protrusion and said mating portion of the housing comprises a contracting portion to receive said protrusion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said housing further comprises a bar crossing all the grooves to connect to said two side arms.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said lower surface of the connecting portion of the housing and the lower surface of the insert are located at a same plane.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of said fastening portions of the insert comprises a rib on the middle of the front surface thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each of said cables comprises an inner conductor connected to the connecting piece of the terminal and an outer conductor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein said upper cover comprises a lengthwise rib inward extending from the upper surface thereof to be soldered with the cables.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said cable connector further comprises a pair of latch respectively assembled on the two side arms of the cable connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each said latch is composed of an upper wall, a lower wall and a side wall connecting the upper wall and the lower wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The cable connector as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein each said latch comprises a clasp on the forward end of the lower wall, a spring extending from the rear end of the side wall and then reversing to face forward, and a pair of fixing apertures respectively on the upper wall and tower wall. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
