<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641495-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641495</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12346783</doc-number>
<date>20081230</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2008 1 0306261</doc-number>
<date>20081216</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>62</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439327</main-classification>
<further-classification>439328</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Mounting apparatus for expansion card</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6183284</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Gill et al.</name>
<date>20010200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439327</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6305964</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Pon et al.</name>
<date>20011000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439327</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6319037</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lai</name>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439327</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0074850</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Kuo</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439327</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>10</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439327</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439328</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sun</last-name>
<first-name>Zheng-Heng</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Zhigang Ma</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tu-Cheng, Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ta</last-name>
<first-name>Tho D</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A mounting apparatus for fixing an expansion card includes a connector configured for engagingly receiving a bottom portion of the expansion card, and a latching member made by thin strip material. The latching member includes a top wall, and two sidewalls extending down from opposite sides of the top wall configured for sandwiching the expansion card therebetween. An elastic tab extends between the sidewalls from the top wall, configured for elastically resisting against a top of the expansion card. A clipping portion is formed on a bottom of each sidewall, to engage with the connector.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="158.07mm" wi="167.22mm" file="US07641495-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="176.02mm" wi="166.88mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641495-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="79.42mm" wi="149.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641495-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="216.07mm" wi="152.48mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641495-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Technical Field</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present disclosure relates to mounting apparatuses and, more particularly, to a mounting apparatus for an expansion card.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An expansion card, such as a memory card, is installed in an electronic device, such as a computer or a server with a mounting apparatus. The mounting apparatus generally includes two opposite fixing latches for clamping two opposite ends of the expansion card. However, the fixing latches may block airflow to the expansion card. In a chassis having a plurality of expansion cards fixed in parallel, heat produced by the expansion cards can only be dissipated through the narrow spaces between the cards, which is inefficient.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded, isometric view of an exemplary embodiment of a mounting apparatus, together with an expansion card and a printed circuit board, the mounting apparatus including two latching members.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged view of a latching member of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an assembled view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, an exemplary embodiment of a mounting apparatus is provided for fixing an expansion card <b>100</b> to a printed circuit board (PCB) <b>200</b>. The mounting apparatus includes a connector <b>20</b> mounted on the PCB <b>200</b> and two latching members <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Two horizontally spaced, aligned contacts <b>102</b> are formed on a bottom portion of the expansion card <b>100</b>. The expansion card <b>100</b> includes two opposite ends <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The connector <b>20</b> is elongated and includes a top surface <b>21</b> and two sidewalls <b>23</b> perpendicularly connected between the top surface <b>21</b> and the PCB <b>200</b>. The connector <b>20</b> further includes two opposite end portions. The top surface <b>21</b> defines a slot <b>22</b> arranged in a line between the end portions, for receiving and being electrically connected to the contacts <b>102</b>. Two bridge-shaped locking parts <b>24</b> protrude from the sidewalls <b>23</b> at each end portion. A through hole <b>26</b> is defined between each locking part <b>24</b> and the corresponding sidewall <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, each latching member <b>30</b> is generally U-shaped and made from a bent thin metal strip. The latching member <b>30</b> includes a top wall <b>32</b> and two sidewalls <b>34</b> perpendicularly extending down from opposite sides of the top wall <b>32</b>. The top wall <b>32</b> and the sidewalls <b>34</b> bound a receiving space <b>36</b>. An elastic tab <b>38</b> slantingly extends down from the bottom of the top wall <b>32</b> into the receiving space <b>36</b>. An upside down U-shaped slot <b>39</b> is defined in a lower part of each sidewall <b>34</b>, with two elastic parts <b>40</b> formed on the sidewall <b>34</b> at opposite sides of the slot <b>39</b>. An L-shaped clipping portion <b>41</b> extends from a distal end of each elastic part <b>40</b> opposite to the top wall <b>32</b>. The clipping portion <b>41</b> includes a horizontal part <b>42</b> perpendicularly extending outward from the distal end of the elastic part <b>40</b>, and a clipping part <b>44</b> perpendicularly extending down from a distal end of the horizontal part <b>42</b> opposite to the elastic part <b>40</b>. A hook <b>46</b> extends outward from a side of the clipping part <b>44</b>, coplanar with the clipping part <b>44</b>. An operation tab <b>48</b> perpendicularly extends up from a side of the horizontal part <b>42</b> opposite to the slot <b>39</b>, for convenient manipulation of the clipping portion <b>41</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, in use, the contacts <b>102</b> of the expansion card <b>100</b> are inserted into the slot <b>22</b> of the connector <b>20</b>. The receiving space <b>36</b> of each latch member <b>30</b> receives a corresponding end of the expansion card <b>100</b>. Two elastic parts <b>40</b> of each sidewall <b>34</b> are squeezed toward each other to deform, to make the clipping parts <b>44</b> of the two clipping portions <b>41</b> pass through the through hole <b>26</b> of the connector <b>20</b>. The elastic parts <b>40</b> are then released, and the clipping portions <b>41</b> restore to engage with the locking part <b>24</b> of the connector <b>20</b>, via the hooks <b>46</b> of the clipping portions <b>41</b> hooking opposite ends of the locking part <b>24</b>. The horizontal part <b>42</b> of each clipping portion <b>41</b> resists against the top surface <b>21</b> of the connector <b>20</b>, and the clipping part <b>44</b> of each clipping portion <b>41</b> resists against a corresponding sidewall <b>23</b> of the connector <b>20</b>. The elastic tab <b>38</b> elastically resists against the top of the expansion card <b>100</b> to deform.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In disassembling the expansion card <b>100</b>, the operation tabs <b>48</b> of the sidewalls <b>34</b> are squeezed toward each other, to deform the elastic parts <b>40</b> and the clipping portions <b>41</b>. As a result, the hooks <b>46</b> disengage from the locking part <b>24</b>. The elastic tab <b>38</b> is restored to pry up the latching member <b>30</b>, resulting in the clipping parts <b>44</b> disengaging from the locking part <b>24</b>. Therefore, the expansion card <b>100</b> can be removed from the slot <b>22</b> of the connector <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In other embodiments, the clipping parts <b>44</b> of each latching member <b>30</b> may extend from the sidewalls <b>34</b> directly with the operation tabs <b>48</b> formed on the elastic parts <b>40</b>, to omit the horizontal parts <b>42</b>, and the through hole <b>26</b> may be defined in the top of each end portion of the connector <b>20</b>. In use, the hooks <b>46</b> of each sidewall <b>34</b> are engaged with a sidewall bounding an edge of the through hole <b>26</b>. In another embodiment, each latching member <b>30</b> can be made of elastic plastic material.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Each latching member <b>30</b> is made of thin plate, resisting against the connector <b>20</b> and the expansion card <b>100</b>, and blocks only a little, if any, airflow, greatly enhancing dissipation of heat of the expansion card <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">It is believed that the present embodiments and their advantages will be understood from the foregoing description, and it will be apparent that various changes may be made thereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure or sacrificing all of its material advantages, the examples hereinbefore described merely being exemplary embodiments of the disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A mounting apparatus for fixing an expansion card, the mounting apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a connector configured for engagingly receiving a bottom portion of the expansion card; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latching member made by thin strip material, wherein the latching member comprises a top wall, and two sidewalls extending down from opposite sides of the top wall configured for sandwiching the expansion card therebetween; an elastic tab extends between the sidewalls from the top wall, configured for elastically resisting against a top of the expansion card; at least one clipping portion is formed on a bottom of each sidewall, to engage with the connector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an upside down U-shaped slot is defined in the lower part of each sidewall, with two elastic parts formed at opposite sides of the slot, the elastic parts are capable of being deformed toward each other, the at least one clipping portion comprises two clipping portions extending from distal ends of the elastic parts, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the connector comprises a top surface, and two sidewalls perpendicular to the top surface; each clipping portion comprises a horizontal part perpendicularly extending outward from the distal end of a corresponding elastic part to resist against the top surface of the connector, and a clipping part perpendicularly extending down from a distal end of the horizontal part opposite to the elastic part to resist against a corresponding sidewall of the connector.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the latching member is made of metal.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the latching member is made of plastic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connector further comprises two opposite end portions, the sidewalls of the connector are located between the end portions; two bridge-shaped locking parts extend from the sidewalls at each end portion, each for engaging with the clipping part of a corresponding clipping portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein a through hole is defined between each locking part and a corresponding sidewall of the connector, for the corresponding clipping part extending therethrough, a hook extends from each clipping part to engage with the locking part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the hook is coplanar with the corresponding clipping part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The mounting apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein an operation tab extends from the horizontal part of each clipping portion, for convenient manipulation of the clipping portion to deform the clipping portion, resulting in the clipping part engaging with or disengaging from the corresponding locking part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A latching member for fixing an expansion card to a connector, the latching member comprising:
<claim-text>a top wall; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>two sidewalls extending down from opposite sides of the top wall, configured for sandwiching the expansion card therebetween, wherein a slot is defined in each sidewall to form two elastic parts at opposite sides of the slot, a clipping portion is formed on a bottom end of each elastic part, configured to engage with the connector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the top wall comprises an elastic tab slantingly extending between the sidewalls from the bottom of the top wall, configured for elastically resisting against the top of the expansion card; the top wall and the sidewalls are formed by thin metal material or thin plastic material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the elastic parts of each sidewall are capable of being deformed toward each other, the clipping portions extend from the bottom ends of the elastic parts, respectively;</claim-text>
<claim-text>each clipping portion comprises a horizontal part perpendicularly extending outward from the bottom end of a corresponding elastic part, and a clipping part perpendicularly extending down from a distal end of the horizontal part opposite to the elastic part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The latching member of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein a hook extends from the clipping part and is coplanar with the corresponding clipping part.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The latching member of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein an operation tab extends from the horizontal part of each clipping portion, for convenient manipulation of the clipping portion to deform the clipping portion.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
