<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641515-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641515</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12196140</doc-number>
<date>20080821</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>648</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439607</main-classification>
<further-classification>4395415</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Center plate for a connector assembly</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6478622</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Hwang</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6558191</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bright et al.</name>
<date>20030500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6943287</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Lloyd et al.</name>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7001217</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Bright et al.</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7070446</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Henry et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4395415</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7249966</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Long</name>
<date>20070700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>4395415</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7357673</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Long</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439608</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0057786</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Gu et al.</name>
<date>20080300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439607</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0299826</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Cheng et al.</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439607</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439607</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4395415</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Szczesny</last-name>
<first-name>David S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Hershey</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shirk</last-name>
<first-name>Michael Eugene</first-name>
<address>
<city>Grantville</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Phillips</last-name>
<first-name>Michael J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Camp Hill</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="004" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Murr</last-name>
<first-name>Keith McQuilkin</first-name>
<address>
<city>York</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tyco Electronics Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Berwyn</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hyeon</last-name>
<first-name>Hae Moon</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A connector assembly includes a shielding cage and a center plate. The shielding cage includes side walls with ports disposed between the side walls. The ports are configured to receive a mating connector through a mating interface of the shielding cage. The center plate is disposed between and couples the side walls to one another. The center plate separates the ports and includes dividing plates and a connecting plate formed with the dividing plates. The dividing plates include spring members extending into the ports to engage the mating connectors received in the ports. The connecting plate extends along the mating interface to interconnect the dividing plates at a location proximate to the mating interface.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="152.65mm" wi="217.25mm" file="US07641515-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="218.02mm" wi="152.65mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641515-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="200.07mm" wi="114.05mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641515-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="218.36mm" wi="154.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641515-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="190.92mm" wi="153.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641515-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="207.26mm" wi="148.42mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641515-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="208.28mm" wi="148.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641515-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The subject matter herein generally relates to electrical connector assemblies and, more particularly, to center plates for connector assemblies.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Known connector assemblies are shaped to receive one or more mating connectors. These connector assemblies include ports through which the mating connectors are loaded. For example, some known connector assemblies include shielding connector cages that include several ports. The connector cages include walls that define the ports. The walls are electrically grounded to shield other components near the connector cage from electromagnetic interference.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The connector cages have a mating interface through which the mating connectors are loaded into the ports. The ports are separated from one another by a center plate. The mating connectors are loaded into the ports to mate with electrical connectors located in the connector assemblies. The center plate in each of the ports includes a spring member that extends into the port and engages the mating connector that is loaded into the port to retain the mating connector in the port. The center plates for adjacent ports are separated by gaps. The center plates may be separate components, or may be components that are coupled together in a location remote from the mating interface of the connector cage. The gap between the center plates provides a path for electromagnetic interference to radiate from the connector cage. Some known connector cages attempt to reduce the amount of electromagnetic interference that radiates through the gap between the center plates by adding an additional component that closes off the gap. Yet, introducing additional components to the connector cages increases the cost and complexity of manufacturing the connector cages.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Some known connector assemblies having connector cages include one or more indicator lights. These indicator lights are disposed in one or more of the ports. The indicator lights emit a light that indicates a state of one or more connectors located in the connector cage. For example, indicator lights such as one or more light pipes may emit a light that indicates that a mating connector is in communication with a connector located in the connector cage. Placing these indicator lights in the ports of the connector cage, however, consumes valuable space in the connector cage. For example, a mating connector cannot be loaded into a port that includes the indicator lights. As a result, fewer ports are available for mating connectors to be loaded into in order to mate with the connectors in the connector cage. In other known connector assemblies, the indicator lights are provided above the ports and outside of the connector cage. Yet, this placement of the indicator lights consumes additional space outside of the connector cage and increases the overall size of the connector assembly.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In one embodiment, a connector assembly includes a shielding cage and a center plate. The shielding cage includes side walls with ports disposed between the side walls. The ports are configured to receive a mating connector through a mating interface of the shielding cage. The center plate is disposed between and couples the side walls to one another. The center plate separates the ports and includes dividing plates and a connecting plate formed with the dividing plates. The dividing plates include spring members extending into the ports to engage the mating connectors received in the ports. The connecting plate extends along the mating interface to interconnect the dividing plates at a location proximate to the mating interface.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">In another embodiment, a center plate is configured to retain mating connectors loaded into ports in a shielding cage through a mating interface of the shielding cage. The shielding cage includes side walls of the ports. The center plate includes dividing plates and a connecting plate formed with the dividing plates. The dividing plates separate the ports and couple the side walls. The dividing plates include spring members extending into the ports to engage the mating connectors received in the ports. The connecting plate extends along the mating interface to interconnect the dividing plates at a location proximate to the mating interface.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front perspective view of a connector assembly according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side elevational view of the connector assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with top, bottom, exterior side, and rear walls of the connector assembly and shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> removed.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a center plate shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a center plate according to another embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a set of co-nested center plates according to one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of the center plates shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> and a side wall between the center plates according to one embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a front perspective view of a connector assembly <b>100</b> according to one embodiment. While the connector assembly <b>100</b> is described herein with particular reference to a vertically stacked receptacle connector assembly, it is to be understood that the benefits herein described are also applicable to other connectors in alternative embodiments. The following description is therefore provided for purposes of illustration, rather than limitation, and is but one potential application of the subject matter herein. For example, the connector assembly <b>100</b> may include a horizontally stacked receptacle assembly. The connector assembly <b>100</b> includes a shielding connector cage <b>102</b> that is shaped to receive a plurality of mating connectors (not shown). The connector cage <b>102</b> is a shielding connector cage in one embodiment. For example, the connector cage <b>102</b> includes, or is formed from, a conductive material such as a metal. The connector cage <b>102</b> and/or one or more components of the connector cage <b>102</b> may be stamped and formed from a sheet of metal. In another example, the connector cage <b>102</b> includes, or is formed from, a non-conductive material, such as a polymer, that is at least partially plated with a conductive material. The connector cage <b>102</b> includes a plurality of grounding pins <b>104</b> that mechanically and electrically couples the connector cage <b>102</b> with at least one of a substrate and another connector assembly. For example, the grounding pins <b>104</b> may be press-fit into corresponding cavities (not shown) in a circuit board (not shown) to retain the connector cage <b>102</b> with respect to the circuit board and to electrically connect the connector cage <b>102</b> with an electrical ground of the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The connector cage <b>102</b> includes a plurality of walls. For example, the connector cage <b>102</b> includes a top wall <b>108</b>, an opposing bottom wall <b>110</b>, a plurality of interior side walls <b>112</b>, a plurality of exterior side walls <b>114</b> and a rear wall <b>130</b>. The top and bottom walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> are approximately parallel to one another. The side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> are approximately parallel to one another and approximately perpendicular to the top and bottom walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>. The rear wall <b>130</b> is approximately perpendicular to the top, bottom and side walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>. Each of the top, bottom, side and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>130</b> includes, or is formed from, a conductive material, such as a metal, in one embodiment. For example, the top, bottom, side and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>130</b> may be stamped and formed from a sheet of metal. Alternatively, each of the top, bottom, side and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>130</b> may include or be formed from a non-conductive material, such as a polymer, that is at least partially plated with a conductive material. A plurality of the top, bottom, side and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>130</b> may be homogeneously formed as a unitary body. For example, the top, exterior side and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>130</b> may be stamped and formed from a common sheet of metal.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The connector cage <b>102</b> includes one or more center members, or center plates <b>116</b>. Each of the center plates <b>116</b> extends between one of the exterior side walls <b>114</b> and one of the interior side walls <b>112</b> or between a pair of the interior side walls <b>112</b> in the illustrated embodiment. For example, with the exception of one or more nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) and/or forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>), the center plates <b>116</b> may be mounted in the connector cage <b>102</b> so the center plates <b>116</b> extend from one side wall <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> to a neighboring side wall <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> without extending beyond either side wall <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>. The center plates <b>116</b> may couple neighboring side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>. For example, the center plates <b>116</b> may mechanically and/or electrically couple neighboring side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>. The center plates <b>116</b> include apertures <b>122</b> that permit light to emanate from interior chambers <b>202</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) of the center plates <b>116</b> in one embodiment. Alternatively, the center plates <b>116</b> do not include the apertures <b>122</b>. The apertures <b>122</b> may provide openings through which a plurality of light pipes <b>124</b> may emit light. The light pipes <b>124</b> may protrude through the apertures <b>122</b> or may be recessed within the center plates <b>116</b> and emit light through the apertures <b>122</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The center plates <b>116</b> and the top, bottom, side and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>130</b> define a plurality of ports <b>106</b> in the connector cage <b>102</b>. Each of the ports <b>106</b> is defined by a portion of the top, bottom and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>130</b>, a portion of each of a pair of opposing side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> and one of the center plates <b>116</b>. The ports <b>106</b> have an interior width <b>126</b> that extends between opposing side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> that define the ports <b>106</b>. The ports <b>106</b> have an interior height <b>128</b> that extends between the center plate <b>116</b> and one of the top and bottom walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>. The vertical spacing of the ports <b>106</b> with respect to one another may be adjusted by changing the vertical height of the center plate <b>116</b> in the connector cage <b>102</b>. The side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> include a plurality of upper and lower slots <b>134</b>, <b>136</b> that are positioned in the side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> to establish the vertical position of the center plates <b>116</b>. For example, the slots <b>134</b>, <b>136</b> are positioned and shaped to receive one or more of laterally protruding nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) of the center plates <b>116</b>. The loading of the tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> into the slots <b>134</b>, <b>136</b> vertically supports and positions the center plates <b>116</b> in the connector cage <b>102</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The ports <b>106</b> extend between the rear wall <b>130</b> and a mating interface <b>118</b> of the connector cage <b>102</b>. The mating interface <b>118</b> includes a plane disposed at the front of the connector cage <b>102</b> that is framed by the top, bottom, and exterior side walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>114</b>. The mating interface <b>118</b> is approximately parallel to the rear wall <b>130</b> and is approximately perpendicular to the top, bottom, and side walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The ports <b>106</b> are shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as being arranged in sets <b>132</b> of pairs of ports <b>106</b>. For example, the ports <b>106</b> are arranged in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> as vertically stacked sets <b>132</b> of two ports <b>106</b> separated by the center plate <b>116</b>, with a plurality of sets <b>132</b> of the ports <b>106</b> being adjacent to one another. In another embodiment, the ports <b>106</b> may be disposed in a different arrangement. For example, a different number of ports <b>106</b> may be provided in each set <b>132</b> of ports <b>106</b> and/or a different number of sets <b>132</b> of ports <b>106</b> may be provided in the connector cage <b>102</b>. In another example, the ports <b>106</b> in each set <b>132</b> may be oriented horizontally rather than vertically, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The connector cage <b>102</b> receives a mating connector (not shown) in one or more of the ports <b>106</b>. The mating connectors are placed into communication with the ports <b>106</b> by loading the mating connectors into the ports <b>106</b>. The mating connectors are loaded into the ports <b>106</b> to mate with one or more connectors <b>200</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) housed within the connector cage <b>102</b>. The mating connectors are loaded into the ports <b>106</b> through the mating interface <b>118</b> of the connector cage <b>102</b>. A spring member <b>120</b> of the center plate <b>116</b> engages the mating connector inserted into a corresponding port <b>106</b> to retain the mating connector in the port <b>106</b>. The spring member <b>120</b> may include a latch that engages the mating connector, for example. In one embodiment, the light pipes <b>124</b> emit an indicator light through corresponding apertures <b>122</b> in the center plates <b>116</b> to indicate whether a mating connector is in communication with a connector <b>200</b> in a corresponding port <b>106</b>. The indicator light indicates whether a mating connector is loaded into the port <b>106</b> and/or is in communication with a corresponding mating connector in the port <b>106</b>. For example, a light pipe <b>124</b> in a center plate <b>116</b> that defines a bottom side of a port <b>106</b> may emit light through an aperture <b>122</b> in that center plate <b>116</b> when a mating connector is loaded into that port <b>106</b> and in communication with a corresponding mating connector.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a side elevational view of the connector assembly <b>100</b> with the top, bottom, exterior side, and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>130</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) removed. The top, bottom exterior side, and rear walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>114</b>, <b>130</b> are removed to illustrate the connectors <b>200</b> and light pipes <b>124</b> housed in the connector cage <b>102</b>. The connectors <b>200</b> include mating faces <b>204</b> that mate with the mating connectors (not shown) loaded into the ports <b>106</b>. The center plates <b>116</b> each define an interior chamber <b>202</b>. The interior chamber <b>202</b> is partially enclosed by a plurality of the side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> on opposing sides of the center plate <b>116</b>. The interior chamber <b>202</b> accommodates one or more of the light pipes <b>124</b>. For example, the light pipes <b>124</b> may pass through the interior chamber <b>202</b> from a location that is proximate to a light source end <b>208</b> of the light pipes <b>124</b> to a location that is proximate to the mating interface <b>118</b> of the connector cage <b>102</b>. The light source end <b>208</b> is the end of the light pipes <b>124</b> that receives light emanating from a light source (not shown), such as a light emitting diode (&#x201c;LED&#x201d;). The light passes through the light pipes <b>124</b> and is emitted from the light pipes <b>124</b> through the apertures <b>122</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The indicator lights thus may be provided without using one or more of the ports <b>106</b> in the connector assembly <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the center plate <b>116</b>. The center plate <b>116</b> includes a plurality of dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> interconnected by a connecting plate <b>302</b>. The center plate <b>116</b> is homogeneously formed as a unitary body in one embodiment. For example, the dividing and connecting plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b>, <b>302</b> may be stamped and formed from a common sheet of a conductive material, such as metal. Alternatively, the center plate <b>116</b> includes, or is formed from, a non-conductive material, such as a polymer, that is at least partially plated with a conductive material. The dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> define top and/or bottom sides of the ports <b>106</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in the set <b>132</b> of ports <b>106</b>. For example, the dividing plate <b>300</b> defines a bottom side of a top port <b>106</b> in the set <b>132</b> of ports <b>106</b> and the dividing plate <b>336</b> defines a top side of a bottom port <b>106</b> in the set <b>132</b> of ports <b>106</b>. The connecting plate <b>302</b> extends between the dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> and between the side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> for a plurality of the ports <b>106</b> and prevents electromagnetic interference inside the chamber <b>202</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) from radiating from the center plate <b>116</b> through the mating interface <b>118</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The center plate <b>116</b> can prevent or reduce the amount of electromagnetic interference that escapes from the chamber <b>202</b> through the mating interface <b>118</b> without requiring additional components or parts to be added to the connector assembly <b>100</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) in one embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Each of the dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> includes the spring member <b>120</b> to engage and retain a mating connector (not shown). The dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> are approximately parallel to one another and the connecting plate <b>302</b> is approximately perpendicular to the dividing plates <b>300</b>. When the connector assembly <b>100</b> is assembled, the dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> are approximately parallel to the top and bottom walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the connector cage <b>102</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and are approximately perpendicular to the rear and side walls <b>130</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and to the mating interface <b>118</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The connecting plate <b>302</b> is approximately perpendicular to the top, bottom, and side walls <b>108</b>, <b>110</b>, <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> and is approximately parallel to the rear wall <b>130</b> and the mating interface <b>118</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> laterally protrude from opposing sides <b>328</b>, <b>330</b>, <b>332</b>, <b>334</b> of the dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b>. For example, the nesting tabs <b>304</b>, <b>308</b> protrude from the side <b>328</b>, the nesting tabs <b>306</b>, <b>310</b> protrude from the side <b>330</b>, and the nesting tabs <b>312</b>, <b>314</b> protrude from the side <b>334</b>. Although not visible in the view shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the side <b>332</b> may include a plurality of laterally protruding nesting tabs similar to one or more of the nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b>. In one embodiment, a plurality of the nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> is arranged in one or more corresponding pairs of nesting tabs. For example, the nesting tabs <b>304</b>, <b>306</b> may be arranged in one pair of nesting tabs and the nesting tabs <b>308</b>, <b>310</b> may be arranged in another pair of nesting tabs. Similarly, the nesting tab <b>314</b> may be arranged in a pair of nesting tabs with another nesting tab (not shown) that laterally protrudes from the side <b>332</b> and the nesting tab <b>312</b> may be arranged in another pair of nesting tabs with a nesting tab (not shown) that laterally protrudes from the side <b>332</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> in each pair of nesting tabs may be offset by different distances from the connecting plate <b>302</b>. For example, in the pair of nesting tabs that includes the nesting tabs <b>304</b>, <b>306</b>, the nesting tab <b>304</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>302</b> by a distance <b>338</b> that is less than a distance <b>340</b> that the nesting tab <b>306</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>302</b>. In another example, in the pair of nesting tabs that includes the nesting tabs <b>308</b>, <b>310</b>, the nesting tab <b>308</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>302</b> by a distance <b>348</b> that is greater than a distance <b>350</b> that the nesting tab <b>310</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>302</b>. Although not visible in the view illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the pair of nesting tabs that includes the nesting tab <b>312</b> and the corresponding nesting tab protruding from the side <b>332</b> similarly may be offset from the connecting plate <b>302</b> by different distances along the direction <b>342</b>, and the pair of nesting tabs that includes the nesting tab <b>314</b> and the corresponding nesting tab protruding from the side <b>332</b> may be offset from the connecting plate <b>302</b> by different distances along the direction <b>342</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the distances <b>338</b>, <b>340</b>, <b>348</b>, <b>350</b> are measured parallel to a direction <b>342</b> that is transverse to directions <b>344</b>, <b>346</b> in which the nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> laterally protrude from the center plate <b>116</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the positions of the center plates <b>116</b> in the connector cage <b>102</b> define the height <b>128</b> and the width <b>126</b> of the ports <b>106</b>. For example, the locations of the slots <b>134</b>, <b>136</b> in the side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> can be changed to adjust the location of the center plates <b>116</b> and thus the height <b>128</b> of the ports <b>106</b>. The width <b>126</b> of the ports <b>106</b> that extends between opposing side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> can be adjusted by changing an exterior width <b>352</b> of the center plate <b>116</b>. The exterior width <b>352</b> is measured in a direction parallel to the directions <b>344</b>, <b>346</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a center plate <b>400</b> according to another embodiment. Similar to the center plate <b>116</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), the center plate <b>400</b> includes a plurality of dividing plates <b>402</b>, <b>404</b> coupled by a connecting plate <b>406</b>. The dividing plates <b>402</b>, <b>404</b> may be similar to the dividing plates <b>300</b>, <b>336</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and the connecting plate <b>406</b> may be similar to the connecting plate <b>302</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>). In the illustrated embodiment, the connecting plate <b>406</b> does not include the apertures <b>122</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) present in the connecting plate <b>302</b>. Also in the illustrated embodiment, the dividing plates <b>402</b>, <b>404</b> include a plurality of laterally protruding forward tabs <b>408</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>412</b>. The dividing plate <b>402</b> includes the forward tab <b>408</b> laterally protruding from one side <b>414</b> of the dividing plate <b>402</b> and the forward tab <b>410</b> laterally protruding from an opposing side <b>416</b> of the dividing plate <b>402</b>. The dividing plate <b>404</b> includes the forward tab <b>412</b> laterally protruding from one side <b>418</b> of the dividing plate <b>404</b> and, although not shown in the view of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, an opposing side of the dividing plate <b>404</b> includes a forward tab laterally protruding from the opposing side.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The forward tabs <b>408</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>412</b> and the forward tab opposing the forward tab <b>412</b> may be arranged in a plurality of pairs. The forward tabs <b>408</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>412</b> and the forward tab opposing the forward tab <b>412</b> in each pair may be offset from the connecting plate <b>406</b> by different distances. For example, in the pair of tabs that includes the forward tabs <b>408</b>, <b>410</b>, the forward tab <b>408</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>406</b> by a distance <b>420</b> that is less than a distance <b>422</b> that the forward tab <b>410</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>406</b>. In another example, in the pair of forward tabs that includes the forward tab <b>412</b> and the forward tab protruding from the side opposing the side <b>418</b>, the forward tab <b>412</b> may be offset from the connecting plate <b>406</b> by a distance <b>424</b> that is smaller than the distance that the forward tab that protrudes from the side opposing the side <b>418</b> is offset from the connecting plate <b>406</b>. In the illustrated embodiment, the distances <b>420</b>, <b>422</b>, <b>424</b> are measured parallel to a direction <b>426</b> that is transverse to directions <b>428</b>, <b>430</b> in which the forward tabs <b>408</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>412</b> laterally protrude from the center plate <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a perspective view of a set <b>500</b> of co-nested center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> according to one embodiment. Each of the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> may be similar to one or more of the center plates <b>116</b>, <b>400</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 4</figref>). The center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> each include a plurality of nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> laterally protruding from opposing sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b> of each center plate <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. The nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> protrude from the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> in directions parallel to a lateral axis <b>580</b> in the illustrated embodiment. The lateral axis <b>580</b> is approximately transverse to the sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> are similar to the nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) in one embodiment. In the illustrated embodiment, the center plate <b>502</b> includes nesting tabs <b>508</b>, <b>510</b>, <b>512</b>, <b>514</b>, the center plate <b>504</b> includes nesting tabs <b>516</b>, <b>518</b>, <b>520</b>, <b>522</b> and the center plate <b>506</b> includes nesting tabs <b>524</b>, <b>526</b>, <b>528</b>, <b>530</b>. Although not visible in the view shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, each of the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> may include a lower dividing plate similar to the lower dividing plate <b>336</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and/or the lower dividing plate <b>404</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). For example, the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> may include lower dividing plates that have laterally protruding nesting tabs (not shown) similar to one or more of the nesting tabs <b>304</b> through <b>314</b> and/or the nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> each include a plurality of nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>566</b> in the opposing sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b> of each center plate <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. The nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>562</b> are similar to the nesting slots <b>316</b> through <b>326</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) in one embodiment. In the illustrated embodiment, the center plate <b>502</b> includes the nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>550</b>, the center plate <b>504</b> includes the nesting slots <b>552</b> through <b>558</b>, and the center plate <b>506</b> includes the nesting slots <b>560</b> through <b>566</b>. Although not visible in the view shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, each of the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> may include a lower dividing plate similar to the lower dividing plate <b>336</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and/or the lower dividing plate <b>404</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). For example, the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> may include lower dividing plates that have nesting slots (not shown) similar to one or more of the nesting slots <b>316</b> through <b>326</b> and/or the nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>566</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> and the nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>566</b> are positioned and shaped to be received within one another such that the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> can co-nest within one another. For example, the nesting tabs <b>512</b>, <b>514</b> of the center plate <b>502</b> may be received in the nesting slots <b>552</b>, <b>554</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>504</b>; the nesting tabs <b>516</b>, <b>518</b> of the center plate <b>504</b> may be received in the nesting slots <b>548</b>, <b>550</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>502</b>; the nesting tabs <b>520</b>, <b>522</b> of the center plate <b>504</b> may be received in the nesting slots <b>560</b>, <b>562</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>506</b>; and the nesting tabs <b>524</b>, <b>526</b> of the center plate <b>506</b> may be received in the nesting slots <b>556</b>, <b>558</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>504</b>. Additional center plates may similarly co-nest with neighboring center plates, including the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. By way of example only, one or more of the nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> may extend through the upper and/or lower slots <b>134</b>, <b>136</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) of the side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) and be received in corresponding nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>566</b>. The side walls <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> may be disposed between neighboring center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. For example, the interior side walls <b>112</b> may be disposed between the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b> and between the center plates <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. The exterior side wall <b>114</b> may be disposed proximate to the side <b>542</b> of the center plate <b>506</b>. The nesting tabs <b>528</b>, <b>530</b> may be inserted through one or more of the upper slots <b>134</b> and bent such that the center plate <b>506</b> is retained in place with respect to the exterior side wall <b>114</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> include a plurality of forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b>. The forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> protrude from the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> in directions parallel to the lateral axis <b>580</b> in one embodiment. The forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> are similar to the forward tabs <b>408</b>, <b>410</b>, <b>412</b> in one embodiment. The forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> of one center plate <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> engage the sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b> of a neighboring center plate <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. For example, the forward tab <b>570</b> of the center plate <b>502</b> engages the side <b>536</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>504</b>; the forward tab <b>572</b> of the center plate <b>504</b> engages the side <b>534</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>502</b>; the forward tab <b>574</b> of the center plate <b>504</b> engages the side <b>540</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>506</b>; and the forward tab <b>576</b> of the center plate <b>506</b> engages the side <b>538</b> of the neighboring center plate <b>504</b>. The engagement between one or more of the forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> and one or more of the sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b> inhibits lateral displacement of one or more of the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> in either direction parallel to the lateral axis <b>580</b>. For example, the engagement between the forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> and the sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b> can reduce the distance that one or more of the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> can be displaced in a direction parallel to the lateral axis <b>580</b> relative to the other center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of the center plates <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> and a side wall <b>600</b> between the center plates <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> according to one embodiment. The side wall <b>600</b> is disposed between the center plates <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> in a manner similar to the location of one or more of the interior side walls <b>112</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) between neighboring center plates <b>116</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The side wall <b>600</b> may be disposed between a different pair of the center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b>. The side wall <b>600</b> includes a plurality of upper slots <b>602</b>, <b>604</b> that are similar to the upper slots <b>134</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The forward tabs <b>568</b> through <b>578</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) may engage one or more of the sides <b>532</b> through <b>542</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of neighboring center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) through the upper slot <b>602</b>. For example, the forward tab <b>576</b> of the center plate <b>506</b> may extend through the upper slot <b>602</b> to engage the side <b>538</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of the center plate <b>504</b>, and the forward tab <b>574</b> of the center plate <b>504</b> may extend through the upper slot <b>602</b> to engage the side <b>540</b> of the center plate <b>506</b>. The nesting tabs <b>508</b> through <b>530</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) may be received in one or more of the nesting slots <b>544</b> through <b>566</b> (shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>) of neighboring center plates <b>502</b>, <b>504</b>, <b>506</b> through the upper slot <b>604</b>. For example, the nesting tab <b>524</b> may extend through the upper slot <b>604</b> and be received in the nesting slot <b>558</b> of the center plate <b>504</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">It is to be understood that the above description is intended to be illustrative, and not restrictive. For example, the above-described embodiments (and/or aspects thereof) may be used in combination with each other. In addition, many modifications may be made to adapt a particular situation or material to the teachings of the invention without departing from its scope. Dimensions, types of materials, orientations of the various components, and the number and positions of the various components described herein are intended to define parameters of certain embodiments, and are by no means limiting and merely are example embodiments. Many other embodiments and modifications within the spirit and scope of the claims will be apparent to those of skill in the art upon reviewing the above description. The scope of the invention should, therefore, be determined with reference to the appended claims, along with the full scope of equivalents to which such claims are entitled. In the appended claims, the terms &#x201c;including&#x201d; and &#x201c;in which&#x201d; are used as the plain-English equivalents of the respective terms &#x201c;comprising&#x201d; and &#x201c;wherein.&#x201d; Moreover, in the following claims, the terms &#x201c;first,&#x201d; &#x201c;second,&#x201d; and &#x201c;third,&#x201d; etc. are used merely as labels, and are not intended to impose numerical requirements on their objects. Further, the limitations of the following claims are not written in means&#x2014;plus-function format and are not intended to be interpreted based on 35 U.S.C. &#xa7;1102, sixth paragraph, unless and until such claim limitations expressly use the phrase &#x201c;means for&#x201d; followed by a statement of function void of further structure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connector assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a shielding cage comprising side walls with ports disposed between the side walls, the ports configured to receive mating connectors through a mating interface of the shielding cage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second center plates each extending between the side walls, the first and second center plates aligned and adjacent one another, each of the first and second center plates comprising dividing plates interconnected by a connecting plate formed with the dividing plates proximate to the mating interface of the shielding cage, the dividing plates of the first and second center plates including a forward tab and a nesting tab protruding from a common side of the dividing plates and a nesting slot extending into the side of the dividing plates, wherein the nesting tab of the first center plate is received into the nesting slot of the second center plate and the forward tab of each of the first and second center plates abuts the common side of the other one of the first and second center plates to prevent lateral displacement of the first and second center plates with respect to one another.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting plates are disposed transverse to the side walls.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the center plates define chambers configured to hold light pipes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting plates comprise apertures configured to permit an indicator light to emanate from the connector assembly, the indicator light communicating whether at least one of the mating connectors is in communication with at least one of the ports.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting plates prevent electromagnetic interference between the dividing plates from radiating out of the connector assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second center plates are formed by stamping and forming the connecting plates and the dividing plates of each of the first and second center plates from sheets of conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the nesting tabs project from the side of each of the first and second center plates by a larger distance than the forward tabs of the corresponding one of the first and second center plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the forward tab of the first center plate is offset from the connecting plate of the first center plate by a distance that is larger than a distance that the forward tab of the second center plate is offset from the connecting plate of the second center plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of the side walls of the shielding cage includes a slot through which the forward tab of each of the first and second center plates extends to abut against the other one of the first and second center plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. A connector assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a shielding cage comprising side walls with ports disposed between the side walls, the ports configured to receive mating connectors through a mating interface of the shielding cage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second center plates extending between the side walls, the first and second center plates aligned and adjacent one another, each of the first and second center plates comprising dividing plates interconnected by a connecting plate formed with the dividing plates proximate to the mating interface of the shielding cage, the dividing plates separating the ports from one another and including forward tabs and nesting tabs protruding from opposing sides of at least one of the dividing plates and nesting slots extending into the sides of the at least one of the dividing plates, wherein the nesting tabs and the nesting slots of the first and second center plates co-nest with one another and the forward tabs of the first and second center plates engage the sides of the other of the first and second center plates to prevent lateral movement of the first and second center plates.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second center plates define chambers in the shielding cage, the chambers configured to accommodate light pipes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting plates comprise apertures that are configured to permit indicator lights to emanate from the center plates, the indicator lights indicating whether at least one of the mating connectors is in communication with at least one of the ports of the shielding cage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the connecting plates prevent electromagnetic interference from radiating out of the connector assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein each of the first and second center plates comprises a common sheet of conductive material that is stamped and formed to produce the dividing plates and the connecting plate of the corresponding one of the first and second center plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the nesting tabs project from the sides of each of the first and second center plates by a larger distance than the forward tabs of the corresponding one of the first and second center plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the forward tabs of the first center plate are offset from the connecting plate of the first center plate by distances that are larger than distances that the forward tabs of the second center plate are offset from the connecting plate of the second center plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the side walls of the shielding cage include slots through which the forward tabs of the first and second center plates extend to abut against the other one of the first and second center plates.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
