<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641502-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641502</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12127288</doc-number>
<date>20080527</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2007-145116</doc-number>
<date>20070531</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>648</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439383</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Connector device</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3137535</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Collier et al.</name>
<date>19640600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439350</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6419400</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Wiltjer et al.</name>
<date>20020700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>385 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6443764</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Makita</name>
<date>20020900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439587</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7104831</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Fukatsu et al.</name>
<date>20060900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439385</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7114983</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Fukatsu et al.</name>
<date>20061000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439358</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7311546</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Itou</name>
<date>20071200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439385</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7458838</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Itou</name>
<date>20081200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439281</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7553186</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Morikawa et al.</name>
<date>20090600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439587</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439350</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439358</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439383-385</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439587</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080299816</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081204</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Itou</last-name>
<first-name>Tomonari</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokkaichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hata</last-name>
<first-name>Takao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokkaichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Morikawa</last-name>
<first-name>Satoshi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokkaichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hespos</last-name>
<first-name>Gerald E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Casella</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sumitomo Wiring Systems, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Luebke</last-name>
<first-name>Renee</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Tsukerman</last-name>
<first-name>Larisa</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Front shake preventing ribs (<b>37</b>) are provided at positions spread over the entire inner periphery of a front end of an inner housing (<b>23</b>) and contact a receptacle (<b>14</b>) of a male housing (<b>10</b>) to prevent shaking between an inner housing (<b>23</b>) and a receptacle (<b>14</b>). A wall (<b>31</b>) faces an opening edge portion of the receptacle (<b>14</b>) at a rear end of the inner housing (<b>23</b>) with respect to the connecting direction with the male connector (<b>10</b>). The receptacle (<b>14</b>) is formed with an annular rib (<b>18</b>) projecting in a connecting direction the connectors (<b>10, 20</b>) at a position to surround the inner housing (<b>23</b>) over the entire periphery. The wall (<b>31</b>) has an annular groove (<b>32</b>) that engages the annular rib (<b>18</b>) to prevent shaking between the connectors (<b>10, 20</b>).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="114.72mm" wi="185.34mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="199.64mm" wi="127.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641502-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="121.24mm" wi="121.33mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="88.56mm" wi="72.56mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="125.56mm" wi="119.80mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="146.73mm" wi="126.75mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="191.35mm" wi="110.32mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641502-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="155.62mm" wi="103.12mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="89.66mm" wi="88.22mm" file="US07641502-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a pair of connectors connectable with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">U.S. Pat. No. 7,311,546 discloses male and female connectors that are connectable with each other. The male connector has a receptacle that opens forward, and male terminals project into the receptacle.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The female connector has a female housing that can fit into the receptacle. Female terminals are mounted in the female housing and connect with the male terminals when the female housing is fit into the receptacle. A tube surrounds the outer peripheral surface of the female housing and can fit on the receptacle of the male connector. The tube is formed with a lock arm that can be engaged with a lock of the male connector to lock the two connectors in a properly connected state.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A retaining cap is mounted on the front of the female housing, and first shake preventing portions project from the outer peripheral surface of the retaining cap. Further, second shake preventing portions are provided at the back end of the inner peripheral surface of the tube.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The first shake preventing portions closely contact the inner peripheral surface of the receptacle and the second shake preventing portions closely contact the outer peripheral surface of the receptacle when the connectors reach the properly connected state to prevent shaking of the two connectors. The prevention of shaking of the connectors before and after contact parts of the male and female terminals is intended to prevent the terminals from abrading against each other. Such abrasion could cause gold plating to be peeled off the contact parts and could increase electrical resistance or cause other damage to the terminals.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The above-described construction cannot provide shake prevention on the cut part of the tube where the lock arm is provided. Thus, the second shake preventing portions necessarily are arranged in a nonuniform manner, thereby limiting efforts to improve shake prevention between the connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The invention was developed in view of the above situation and an object thereof is to provide a connector device capable of improving a function of restricting shaking between connectors.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The invention relates to a connector assembly comprising first and second connectors that are connectable with each other. The first connector includes a receptacle that is open in a connecting direction with the second connector and a first terminal projects into the receptacle. The second connector has a housing configured to fit into the receptacle and includes a second terminal connectable with the first terminal. At least one front shake preventing rib is provided near a front end of the housing with respect to a connecting direction with the second connector. The front shake preventing rib at least partly surrounds the housing and contacts the housing or the receptacle when the connectors reach a properly connected state for preventing shaking between the connectors. At least one wall is provided near a rear end of the housing with respect to the connecting direction with the first connector and is arranged to face an opening edge of the receptacle. One of the opening edge of the receptacle and the wall includes at least one rear shake preventing rib projecting substantially in the connecting direction of the connectors at a position to surround at least part of the housing. The other of the opening edge of the receptacle and the wall includes at least one groove that engages the rear shake preventing rib when the connectors reach a properly connected state for preventing shaking between the connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Accordingly, shaking between the properly connected connectors is prevented at positions surrounding the housing over substantially the entire periphery at both front and rear ends of the housing. Thus, shake prevention between the connectors is improved as compared with the case, for example, where shake prevention is provided at a position biased in the peripheral direction of the housing at one of the front and rear ends of the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The front shake preventing rib may be formed integrally or unitarily on the outer surface of the housing. Thus, shaking of the housing is prevented without a separate member and abrasion of the terminal is prevented.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The second connector may include an outer housing separate from the housing and adapted to cover the housing. The outer housing may include at least one locking mechanism for locking the first connector in the connecting direction when the connectors reach the substantially properly connected state.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The outer housing and the housing may be slidably displaceable relative to each other in the connecting direction of the connectors, and at least one resilient member may be mounted between the outer housing and the housing. The resilient member is pressed by the outer housing and the housing when the connectors reach the properly connected state and resiliently contracts in the connecting direction of the connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Thus, the resilient force of the resilient member biases the housing forward in the connecting direction when the connectors reach the properly connected state to prevent shaking between the connectors in forward and backward directions. Further, the outer housing is pressed backward in the connecting direction to prevent the shaking of the locking mechanism in forward and backward directions.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The resilient member may be made of rubber, and hence expands upon being pressed between the housing and the outer housing. Accordingly contact pressures acting on the housing and the outer housing are distributed to become smaller, eliminating the need for a measure against creep caused by the contact pressures.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The resilient member, the housing portion and the outer housing may include positioning portions in the form of one or more projections and one or more recesses engageable with each other. Thus, the resilient member is not displaced when pressed between the outer housing and the housing, and resilient forces on the housing and the outer housing are predictable.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The positioning portions may include positioning projections formed on the resilient member and positioning recesses formed in the housing and the outer housing.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The rear shake preventing rib and the groove may be ring-shaped to surround the housing over substantially the entire periphery.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The rear shake preventing rib may be formed at or near the opening edge of the receptacle, and the groove may be formed in the wall.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The groove or the rear shake preventing rib may include a projection to be pressed between the groove and the rear shake preventing rib when the connectors reach the properly connected state. Thus, the groove and the rear shake preventing rib are fixed firmly.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The projection may be arranged at a position to surround the housing over the entire periphery.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">At least one seal ring may be mounted between the receptacle and the housing near an opening end of the receptacle. The seal ring is pressed by the receptacle and the housing to provide sealing therebetween. Accordingly, the rear shake preventing rib is pressed out by the resilient force of the seal ring and is pressed against the peripheral surface of the groove so that the groove and the rear shake preventing rib are fixed firmly.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">At least one outer shake preventing rib may be provided on the inner peripheral surface of the outer housing or the outer peripheral surface of the receptacle. The outer shake preventing rib contacts the inner peripheral surface of the outer housing or the outer peripheral surface of the receptacle when the connectors reach the properly connected state for preventing the shaking between the connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">At least one projection may project in on part of the inner peripheral surface of the receptacle for contacting the front shake preventing rib.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">These and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent upon reading of the following detailed description of preferred embodiments and accompanying drawings. It should be understood that even though embodiments are separately described, single features thereof may be combined to additional embodiments.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view in section of a connector device according to a first embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 2</figref><i>a </i>are sections showing an engaged state of a back end portion of the receptacle and a front end portion of an inner housing.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a section showing an engaged state of an annular rib and an annular groove.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a front view of a female connector.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a side view in section of a connector device according to a second embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side view of a resilient member.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a front view of the resilient member.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a section of the resilient member.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">A connector assembly in accordance with a first embodiment of the invention is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref>. The connector assembly has a male connector <b>10</b> and a female connector <b>20</b> that are connectable with each other.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In the following description, in the respective constituent members, ends of the connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> to be connected are referred to as the front ends and reference is made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> concerning upper and lower sides.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The male connector <b>10</b> has two male terminals <b>11</b> that are long in forward and backward directions, and a male housing <b>12</b> that is made e.g. of synthetic resin. A terminal holding portion <b>13</b> penetrates the male housing <b>12</b> in forward and backward directions and is configured for holding the male terminals <b>11</b>. A wide tubular receptacle <b>14</b> projects forward from the outer periphery of the terminal holding portion <b>13</b> and surrounds parts of the male terminals <b>11</b> that project forward from the terminal holding portion <b>13</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">A lock <b>15</b> projects from the top surface of the receptacle <b>14</b> at an intermediate position with respect to forward and backward directions and width directions. A riding surface <b>15</b>A is formed the front of the lock projection <b>15</b> and inclines to reduce a projecting distance gradually towards the front.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, guide ribs <b>16</b> extend in forward and backward directions at ten positions on the outer peripheral surface of the receptacle <b>14</b>. More particularly, the guide ribs <b>16</b> are arranged at the opposite sides of the lock <b>15</b> on the top surface of the receptacle <b>14</b>; at each of the upper, lower and intermediate positions of the opposite side surfaces; and at opposite widthwise ends of the bottom surface.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Six projections <b>17</b> extend in from the back side of the inner peripheral surface of the receptacle <b>14</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the respective projections <b>17</b> are narrow and long in forward and backward directions and extend in a part of the receptacle <b>14</b> from an intermediate position in forward and backward directions to the rear end of the receptacle <b>14</b>, i.e. in a part of the receptacle <b>14</b> where the male terminals <b>11</b> are arranged. A dimension of the projections <b>17</b> in forward and backward directions is slightly longer than the length of the male terminals <b>11</b> projecting into the receptacle <b>14</b>. A guiding surface <b>17</b>A is formed at the front of each projection <b>17</b> and is inclined to reduce a projecting distance of the projection <b>17</b> gradually towards the front. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the six projections <b>17</b> are arranged so that two are near the widthwise ends of the upper side of the inner peripheral surface of the receptacle <b>14</b>, two are at vertical intermediate positions of the opposite sides, and two are in the widthwise intermediate position of the lower side.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">An annular rib <b>18</b> is provided near the open front end of the receptacle <b>14</b>. The annular rib <b>18</b> projects forward along the inner peripheral surface of the receptacle <b>14</b> and is formed by thinning the outer periphery of the receptacle <b>14</b>. The thickness of the annular rib <b>18</b> in inward and outward directions is substantially half the thickness of the receptacle <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The female connector <b>20</b> includes female terminals <b>21</b> that are long in forward and backward directions. A substantially box-shaped connecting portion <b>21</b>A is formed at the front end of each female terminal <b>21</b> and is connectable with the male terminal <b>11</b>. A wire connection barrel <b>21</b>B is formed at the rear end and is crimped, bent or folded into connection with an end of a wire W and with a resilient rubber plug <b>22</b> mounted on the wire W. The resilient plug <b>22</b> is held in close contact with the inner circumferential surface of a terminal accommodating chamber <b>24</b> to provide sealing.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The female connector <b>20</b> includes an inner housing <b>23</b> made e.g. of synthetic resin and configured for accommodating the female terminals <b>21</b>. The inner housing <b>23</b> is in the form of a block that is long in forward and backward directions and is fittable into the receptacle <b>14</b> of the male housing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Two terminal accommodating chambers <b>24</b> are formed substantially side by side in the inner housing <b>23</b> and are capable of accommodating the female terminals <b>21</b> inserted from behind. The rear end of the inner housing <b>23</b> has cylindrical terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A arranged side by side and communicating with the respective terminal accommodating chambers <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A locking lance <b>25</b> is cantilevered forward from the lateral bottom wall of each terminal accommodating chamber <b>24</b> of the inner housing <b>23</b>. The locking lances <b>25</b> are deformable up and down. Parts of the inner housing <b>23</b> before the locking lances <b>25</b> open forward.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">A retainer mounting portion <b>26</b> is provided at a position behind the center of the inner housing <b>23</b> in forward and backward directions. The retainer mounting portion <b>26</b> communicates with the terminal accommodating chambers <b>24</b> and opens in the bottom surface of the inner housing <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">A side-type retainer <b>27</b> made e.g. of synthetic resin can be mounted into the retainer mounting portion <b>26</b>. The retainer <b>27</b> includes locks <b>28</b> for engaging the connecting portions <b>21</b>A of the female terminals <b>21</b> from behind to retain the female terminals <b>21</b> in the terminal accommodating chambers <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">Insertion openings <b>29</b> penetrate the front wall of the inner housing <b>23</b> substantially in forward and backward directions at positions corresponding to the terminal accommodating chambers <b>24</b>. Thus, the male terminals <b>11</b> can be inserted through these insertion openings <b>29</b> from the front to be guided into the terminal accommodating chambers <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">A wall <b>31</b> projects out from the entire outer periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b> at a rear end of the inner housing <b>23</b> before the terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A and is aligned orthogonal to a connecting direction of the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b>. The outer shape of the wall <b>31</b> corresponds to the outer shape of the receptacle <b>14</b>. Thus, the outer peripheral surface of the receptacle <b>14</b> and the projecting end surface of the wall <b>31</b> are substantially flush with each other in forward and backward direction when the wall <b>31</b> and the receptacle <b>14</b> are substantially opposed to each other. The terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A project back from the wall <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">An annular groove <b>32</b> is formed in the front surface of the wall <b>31</b> for receiving the annular rib <b>18</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the annular groove <b>32</b> has a wide ring shape and extends around the entire periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b>. A bottom surface <b>32</b>A of the groove <b>32</b> is aligned substantially at right angles to the connecting direction of the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b>. Inner and outer surfaces <b>32</b>B and <b>32</b>C extend substantially parallel to the connecting direction along the inner and outer extremes of the bottom surfaces <b>32</b>A.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The annular groove <b>32</b> is formed at a position retracted inwardly by a constant distance from the projecting end surface of the wall <b>31</b>, i.e. the projecting end surface of the wall portion <b>31</b> and the outer surface <b>32</b>C of the annular groove <b>32</b> are substantially parallel. Additionally, the width of the annular groove <b>32</b> is set to a specified dimension.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Eight projections <b>33</b> are provided on the outer surface <b>32</b>C of the annular groove <b>32</b> so that two projections <b>33</b> are provided on each of the upper, lower, left and right sides of the annular groove <b>32</b>. Accordingly, the projections <b>33</b> are distributed over substantially the entire periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Eight guide projections <b>35</b> are formed on the projecting end surface of the wall <b>31</b> so that guide projections <b>35</b> are provided at three spaced apart positions on each of the opposite sides and at two spaced apart positions on the bottom. The guide projections <b>35</b> are provided at positions (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>) corresponding to the guide ribs <b>16</b> of the receptacle <b>14</b>. The top of the projecting end surface of the wall <b>31</b> is a substantially flat surface. The two projections <b>35</b>A provided at the middle of the opposite sides of the outer end surface are engageable with engageable portions <b>43</b> of an outer housing <b>38</b> to be described later.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The rear surface of the wall <b>31</b> is substantially flat and substantially perpendicular to the outer peripheral surface of the inner housing <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">An annular recess <b>34</b> is formed at the base of the front surface of the wall <b>31</b> and is substantially continuous with the inner housing <b>23</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The annular recess <b>34</b> is ring-shaped and is between the inner wall defining the annular groove <b>32</b> and the outer circumferential surface of the inner housing <b>23</b>. The annular recess <b>34</b> is not as deep as the annular groove <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">A seal ring <b>36</b> is mounted on the outer peripheral surface of the inner housing <b>23</b> at a position before the wall <b>31</b>. The seal ring <b>36</b> is shaped so that an intermediate part thereof in forward and backward directions bulges radially outward, and the front and rear ends thereof are thinned. The seal ring <b>36</b> is mounted on the inner housing <b>23</b> with the rear end thereof fit into the annular recess <b>34</b> and the bulging part projects before the annular groove <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Six front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> project unitarily out from the outer peripheral surface of the front part of the inner housing <b>23</b> and are long in forward and backward directions. The front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> are at positions corresponding to the projections <b>17</b> of the male housing <b>12</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. More specifically, the front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> are arranged so that two are at positions near the opposite sides of the top surface of the inner housing <b>23</b>, one is at an intermediate position of each of the opposite side surfaces, and two are at positions near the widthwise center of the bottom surface between the locking lances <b>25</b>. Thus, the front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> are distributed over substantially the entire periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b>. A structurally and functionally similar variation of the receptacle and inner housing is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>. More particularly, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a </i>shows an optional arrangement where shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> are formed on the respective projections <b>17</b> and project inwardly for contacting the inner housing <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> arranged on the top surface of the inner housing <b>23</b> extend from the front end of the inner housing <b>23</b> to positions immediately before the seal ring <b>36</b>, and the front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> formed on the other surfaces extend to positions immediately before the retainer mounting portion <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The outer housing <b>38</b> of the female connector <b>20</b> partly covers the inner housing <b>23</b>. The outer housing <b>38</b> is formed separate from the inner housing <b>23</b> and is assembled with the inner housing <b>23</b> to be displaceable in forward and backward directions. The outer housing <b>38</b> is made e.g. of synthetic resin and includes a back wall <b>38</b>A with an outer shape slightly larger than the wall <b>31</b>. An outer tube <b>38</b>B projects forward from the peripheral edge of the back wall <b>38</b>A and is capable of surrounding the wall <b>31</b>. A space is defined between the outer tube portion <b>38</b>B and the inner housing <b>23</b> for receiving the receptacle <b>14</b> of the male connector <b>10</b>. Loose insertion holes <b>39</b> penetrate the back wall <b>38</b>A in forward and backward directions and can loosely receive the terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A of the inner housing <b>23</b>. The front surface of the back wall <b>38</b>A is a substantially flat surface substantially parallel to the rear surface of the wall <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The outer housing <b>38</b> includes a lock arm <b>41</b> for engaging the lock <b>15</b> of the male connector <b>10</b> to lock the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> in a properly connected state. The lock arm <b>41</b> is cantilevered forward from the upper wall of the outer tube <b>38</b>B so that the front end is free and resiliently displaceable up and down. An engaging hole <b>41</b>A is formed near the front end of the lock arm <b>41</b> and is engageable with the lock <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The outer tube <b>38</b>B is formed with guide grooves <b>42</b> at positions corresponding to the respective guide ribs <b>16</b> and guide projections <b>35</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. Thus, the guide grooves <b>42</b> can receive the respective guide ribs <b>16</b> of the receptacle <b>14</b> and the respective guide projections <b>35</b> of the wall <b>31</b> in forward and backward directions. Movement of the guide ribs <b>16</b> and the guide projections <b>35</b> in forward and backward directions is guided by the guide grooves <b>42</b>. The inner housing <b>23</b> is assembled with the outer housing <b>38</b> and slid in forward and backward directions with the guide projections <b>35</b> of the wall <b>31</b> fit in the guide grooves <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The guide grooves <b>42</b> corresponding to the guide projections <b>35</b>A of the wall <b>31</b> are formed with the engageable portions <b>43</b>. The guide projections <b>35</b>A are engaged with the engageable portions <b>43</b> to prevent the inner housing <b>23</b> from being separated forward from the outer housing <b>38</b>. It should be noted that the inner housing <b>23</b> can slide in forward and backward directions in a range where the guide projections <b>35</b>A move forward and backward behind the engageable portions <b>43</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Two outer shake preventing ribs <b>44</b> are provided in each of the guide grooves <b>42</b> at the upper and lower positions of the opposite side surfaces of the outer tube <b>38</b>B. More specifically, the outer shake preventing ribs <b>44</b> are provided on the side and upper surfaces of each upper guide groove <b>42</b> and are provided on the side and lower surfaces of each lower guide groove <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">A resilient member <b>45</b> is mounted between the back wall <b>38</b>A of the outer housing <b>38</b> and the wall <b>31</b> of the inner housing <b>23</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). The resilient member <b>45</b> preferably is made of rubber and is in the form of a wide tube fittable on the terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A. An intermediate part of the resilient member <b>45</b> in forward and backward directions bulges radially out, and lips <b>46</b> are formed on the inner circumferential surface thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> are positioned opposed to each other and are brought closer together. As a result, the front end of the inner housing <b>23</b> is inserted into the receptacle <b>14</b> and the receptacle <b>14</b> is inserted between the inner housing <b>23</b> and the outer tube <b>38</b>B of the outer housing <b>38</b>. At this time, the guide ribs <b>16</b> of the receptacle <b>14</b> enter the guide grooves <b>42</b> of the outer tube <b>38</b>B and are guided to squeeze the outer shake preventing ribs <b>44</b> of the guide grooves <b>42</b>. Further, the front end of the inner housing <b>23</b> contacts the guiding surfaces <b>17</b>A of the projections <b>17</b> at the back of the receptacle <b>14</b> to have its posture corrected and is inserted smoothly into a space inside the projections <b>17</b>. At this time, the front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> of the inner housing <b>23</b> are pressed by the projecting ends of the projections <b>17</b>. The male terminals <b>11</b> are inserted through the insertion openings <b>29</b> of the inner housing <b>23</b> to enter the connecting portions <b>21</b>A of the female terminals <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">The two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> are pressed further towards each other so that the leading end of the receptacle <b>14</b> reaches the outer side of the seal ring <b>36</b> and the receptacle <b>14</b> moves farther towards the back side while squeezing the seal ring <b>36</b> inwardly. The annular rib <b>18</b> of the receptacle <b>14</b> is inserted into the annular groove <b>32</b> of the wall <b>31</b> and is pressed out by the resilient restoring force of the seal ring <b>36</b>. Thus, the annular rib <b>18</b> is accommodated in the annular groove <b>32</b> while pressing the projections <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">The two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> are pressed still further towards each other. Thus, the leading end of the receptacle <b>14</b> presses the wall <b>31</b> and the resilient member <b>45</b> arranged between the wall <b>31</b> and the back wall <b>38</b>A resiliently contracts. The outer housing <b>38</b> moves forward relative to the inner housing <b>23</b>, and the terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A gradually project back from the back wall <b>38</b>A through the loose insertion holes <b>39</b>. Further, the leading end of the lock arm <b>41</b> moves onto the riding surface <b>15</b>A of the lock <b>15</b> to deform the lock arm <b>41</b> up.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The leading end of the lock arm <b>41</b> moves over the lock <b>15</b> when the connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> reach the properly connected state. As a result, the lock arm <b>41</b> resiliently restores and the lock <b>15</b> enters the engaging hole <b>41</b>A. In this way, the lock arm <b>41</b> and the lock <b>15</b> are engaged from the front and behind to lock the connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> in their properly connected state. At this time, the resilient member <b>45</b> is squeezed between the wall <b>31</b> and the back wall <b>38</b>A. Further, the seal ring <b>36</b> is squeezed resiliently between the receptacle <b>14</b> and the inner housing <b>23</b>, thereby hermetically holding the space between the receptacle <b>14</b> and the inner housing <b>23</b>. The resilient force of the seal ring <b>36</b> presses the annular rib <b>18</b> against the outer surface <b>32</b>C of the annular groove <b>32</b> and engages the projections <b>33</b> on the outer surface <b>32</b>C. Thus, the annular rib <b>18</b> and the annular groove <b>32</b> are fixed strongly over substantially the entire periphery. This engagement of the annular rib <b>18</b> and the annular groove <b>32</b> over substantially the entire periphery at the rear end of the inner housing <b>23</b> prevents radial movements of the wall <b>31</b> relative to the receptacle <b>14</b> and hence prevents shaking between the inner housing <b>23</b> and the receptacle <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">The front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> at the front of the inner housing <b>23</b> are pressed in close contact with the projections <b>17</b> of the receptacle <b>17</b> to prevent shaking between the inner housing <b>23</b> and the receptacle <b>14</b>. The front shake preventing ribs could be formed, for example, on a front holder, a front retainer or the like separate from the inner housing. However, such an arrangement could result in shaking between the separate part and the inner housing and could cause abrasion of the contact parts of the terminals. However, in this embodiment, abrasion of the terminals <b>11</b>, <b>21</b> is prevented reliably, since the shaking of the inner housing <b>23</b> accommodating the female terminals <b>21</b> is prevented directly without a separate part.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">As described above, shaking of the male housing <b>12</b> and the inner housing <b>23</b> is prevented at positions spread over substantially the entire periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b> at both front and rear ends of the inner housing <b>23</b> and at both front and rear ends of connected parts of the terminals <b>11</b>, <b>21</b> when the connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> are connected properly. If shaking was prevented, for example, not over the entire periphery of the inner housing, but only at the opposite sides and the lower side, then vertical shaking is permitted more or less. However, in this embodiment, shaking is prevented at positions spread over the entire periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b>. Therefore the function of preventing the shaking between the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">Abrasion of the terminals <b>11</b>, <b>21</b> is prevented even if the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> are subjected to strong vibration since shaking is prevented at both front and rear ends of the inner housing <b>23</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The resilient member <b>45</b> presses the inner housing <b>23</b> forward and against the terminal holding portion <b>13</b> to prevent shaking, and also presses the outer housing <b>38</b> backward in the engaging direction of the lock arm <b>41</b> with the lock <b>15</b> to prevent shaking in forward and backward directions at the locked part. Further, the guide ribs <b>16</b> of the receptacle <b>14</b> press the outer shake preventing ribs <b>44</b> of the guide grooves <b>42</b> of the outer housing <b>38</b> to prevent shaking of the receptacle <b>14</b> and the outer housing <b>38</b>. In this way, shaking of the connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> is prevented reliably and high vibration can be withstood.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In addition, the resilient member <b>45</b> expands along the surfaces of the wall <b>31</b> and the back wall <b>38</b>A when pressed between the inner and outer housings <b>23</b> and <b>38</b>. Thus, contact pressure on the wall <b>31</b> and the back wall <b>38</b>A are distributed and become smaller. In the case of using a metallic spring or the like, the area of the contact part does not expand like e.g. rubber and contact pressure concentrates on one point without being distributed. Thus, the wall <b>31</b> and the back wall <b>38</b>A would need to be thickened as an anti-creep measure. However, the connector need not be enlarged in the present application since such a measure need not be taken.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">As described above, according to the first embodiment, shaking between the inner housing <b>23</b> and the male housing <b>12</b> is prevented at both front and rear ends of the inner housing <b>23</b> and at positions distributed over substantially the entire periphery of the inner housing <b>23</b> when the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> are connected properly. Thus, the function of preventing the shaking of the connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b> is improved remarkably.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">A connector assembly according to a second embodiment of the invention is described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">The connector assembly of this embodiment differs from the first embodiment in that the resilient member <b>50</b>, the inner housing <b>23</b> and the outer housing <b>38</b> include positioning portions in the form of recesses and projections that are engageable with each other. It should be noted that elements of the second embodiment that are identical or similar to the first embodiment are identified by the same reference numeral, but are not described again.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">The resilient member <b>50</b> preferably is made of rubber and is substantially in the form of a wide tube that fits on the terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A as in the first embodiment (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). The resilient member <b>50</b> is shaped so that an intermediate part in forward and backward directions bulges radially out, and two lips <b>51</b> are formed on the inner peripheral surface thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Positioning projections <b>52</b> are provided at both front and rear ends of the resilient member <b>50</b>. The positioning projections <b>52</b> are in the form of rings formed at radially intermediate positions of the front and rear end surfaces of the resilient member <b>50</b>, and project substantially forward from the front end surface and backward from the rear end surface.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">The inner and outer housings <b>23</b> and <b>38</b> have positioning recesses <b>53</b> that engage the respective positioning projections <b>52</b> of the resilient member <b>50</b>. The positioning recesses <b>53</b> in the rear surface of the wall <b>31</b> of the inner housing <b>23</b> are ring-shaped and surround the terminal inserting portions <b>23</b>A over the entire circumference, whereas those in the front surface of the back wall <b>38</b>A of the outer housing <b>38</b> are ring-shaped and surround the loose insertion holes <b>39</b> over the entire circumference. The positioning recesses <b>53</b> are shaped identically and face each other in forward and backward directions.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the resilient member <b>50</b> is mounted with the positioning projections <b>52</b> respectively engaged with the positioning recesses <b>53</b> of the inner and outer housings <b>23</b> and <b>38</b>. The engagement of the positioning projections <b>52</b> and the positioning recesses <b>53</b> prevents the resilient member <b>50</b> from being displaced in directions substantially along the surfaces of the wall <b>31</b> and the back wall <b>38</b>A even if squeezed between the inner housing <b>23</b> and the outer housing <b>38</b>. Thus, a resilient force from the resilient member <b>50</b> acts substantially uniformly on the inner and outer housings <b>23</b> and <b>38</b> to prevent shaking of the two connectors <b>10</b>, <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The invention is not limited to the above described and illustrated embodiments. For example, the following embodiments are also embraced by the technical scope of the present invention as defined by the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The annular rib <b>18</b> and the annular groove <b>32</b> are ring-shaped to surround the inner housing <b>23</b> over substantially the entire periphery in the above embodiments. However, the invention is not limited thereto. As long as they are provided at positions to at least partly surround the inner housing <b>23</b> over the substantially entire circumference, they may not be ring-shaped. For example, they may e.g. be ribs and grooves intermittently formed at the upper, lower, left and right sides of the inner housing.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">The receptacle <b>14</b> has the annular rib <b>18</b> and the wall <b>31</b> has the annular groove <b>32</b> in the above embodiments. However, the receptacle may have an annular groove and the wall may have an annular rib.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Although the projections <b>33</b> are formed in the annular groove <b>32</b> in the above embodiments, they may not be necessarily formed or they may be formed, for example, on the annular rib.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Although the front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> are in contact with the projections <b>17</b> in the receptacle <b>14</b> in the above embodiments, the invention is not limited thereto and they may directly contact, for example, the flat inner peripheral surface of the receptacle.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The outer housing <b>38</b> is separate from the inner housing <b>23</b> in the above embodiments. However, both housings may be integral or unitary.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">Although the front shake preventing ribs <b>37</b> are formed on the inner housing <b>23</b> in the above embodiments, they may be formed in the receptacle.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">The outer shake preventing ribs <b>44</b> are formed in the guide grooves <b>42</b> in the above embodiments. However, they may not be necessarily formed or they may be formed, for example, on the guide ribs or parts of the outer tube other than the guide grooves.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Although the resilient member <b>45</b> (<b>50</b>) is made of rubber in the above embodiments, it may not be made of rubber provided that it can resiliently contract. It may be, for example, a metallic spring.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">Although the seal ring <b>36</b> is mounted between the receptacle <b>14</b> and the inner housing <b>23</b> in the above embodiments, it may not necessarily be mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">The resilient member <b>50</b> is formed with the positioning projections <b>52</b> and the inner and outer housings <b>23</b> and <b>38</b> are formed with the positioning recesses <b>53</b> in the second embodiment. However, the resilient member may be formed with positioning recesses and the inner and outer housings may be formed with positioning projections.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connector assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a first connector with a forwardly open receptacle and a first terminal projecting into the receptacle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector with a housing configured for fitting into the receptacle and accommodating a second terminal connectable with the first terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one front shake preventing rib at a position for contacting the housing or the receptacle when the connectors reach a properly connected state and preventing shaking between the connectors near a front end of the housing with respect to a connecting direction with the second connector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one wall provided near a rear end of the housing with respect to the connecting direction with the first connector and arranged to substantially face an opening edge of the receptacle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>one of the opening edge of the receptacle and the wall includes at least one rear shake preventing rib projecting substantially in the connecting direction at a position around the housing, whereas the other of the opening edge of the receptacle and the wall includes at least one groove for engaging the rear shake preventing rib when the connectors reach the properly connected state for preventing shaking between the connectors.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the front shake preventing rib is formed unitarily on a periphery of the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the second connector includes an outer housing separate from the housing and adapted to at least partly cover the housing, the outer housing includes at least one locking mechanism for locking the first connector in the connecting direction when the connectors are connected properly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the outer housing and the housing are slidable relative to each other in the connecting direction of the connectors, at least one resilient member being mounted between the outer housing and the housing, the resilient member being pressed by the outer housing and the housing and resiliently contracting in the connecting direction when connectors are connected properly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the resilient member is made of rubber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the resilient member, the housing and the outer housing include positioning portions in the form of projections and recesses engageable with each other.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning portions include at least one positioning projection on the resilient member and at least one positioning recess in the housing or the outer housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the rear shake preventing rib and the groove are ring-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the rear shake preventing rib is formed near the opening edge of the receptacle, and the groove is formed in the wall.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a projections to be pressed between the groove and the rear shake preventing rib when the connectors are connected properly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00010">claim 10</claim-ref>, wherein the projections are arranged at a position to surround the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one seal ring is mounted between the receptacle and the housing near an opening end of the receptacle, the sealing ring being pressed by the receptacle and the housing to provide sealing between the receptacle and the housing.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one outer shake preventing rib extends between the inner peripheral surface of the outer housing and the outer peripheral surface of the receptacle for preventing the shaking between the connectors when the connectors are connected properly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein at least one projection projects inwardly on a part of the inner peripheral surface of the receptacle corresponding to the front shake preventing rib, and the front shake preventing rib contacts the projecting end of the projection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. A connector assembly, comprising:
<claim-text>a first connector with opposite front and rear ends, a forwardly open receptacle at the front end of the first connector, a forwardly facing first shake preventing structure at the front end of the first connector and substantially surrounding the receptacle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector with an inner housing having opposite front and rear ends and an outer periphery, portions of the outer periphery adjacent the front end of the inner housing being configured for fitting into the receptacle, front shake preventing ribs at a plurality of spaced apart positions around the outer periphery of the inner housing and substantially adjacent the front end of the inner housing for contacting the receptacle when the connectors reach a properly connected state and preventing shaking between the connectors near the front end of the inner housing, a wall near the rear end of the inner housing, a forwardly facing second shake preventing structure on the wall engaging the first shake preventing structure when the connectors reach are connected properly for preventing shaking of the connectors.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, wherein the first shake preventing structure is an annular rib and the second shake preventing structure is an annular groove.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein the second connector further has an outer housing covering at least part of the inner housing, the outer housing includes a locking mechanism for locking the first connector in the connecting direction when the connectors are connected properly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00017">claim 17</claim-ref>, wherein the outer housing and the inner housing are slidable relative to each other in a connecting direction of the connectors, a resilient member being mounted between the inner and outer housings, the resilient member being pressed by the inner and outer housing and resiliently contracting in the connecting direction when connectors are connected properly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The connector assembly of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising a projections in the groove for engaging the annular rib when the connectors are connected properly. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
