<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641379-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641379</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11751520</doc-number>
<date>20070521</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>232</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>33</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>05</class>
<subclass>K</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362652</main-classification>
<further-classification>362640</further-classification>
<further-classification>362800</further-classification>
<further-classification>361807</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Press fit electronic component</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5096425</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Takahashi</name>
<date>19920300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 55</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0035410</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shiffer</name>
<date>20060200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438111</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-44507</doc-number>
<date>20010200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<nplcit num="00004">
<othercit>Product Brochure [online]. Khatod Optoelectronic [retrieved on May 22, 2007]. Retrieved from the Internet: &#x3c;URL: http://www.khatod.com/pdf/k35.pdf&#x3e;, 32 p.</othercit>
</nplcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>19</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362640</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362652</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>362800</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361806-807</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>361813</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 91</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080293270</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081127</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Gisler</last-name>
<first-name>Gregory Joseph</first-name>
<address>
<city>Los Gatos</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Schwegman, Lundberg &#x26; Woessner, P.A.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cisco Technology, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Alavi</last-name>
<first-name>Ali</first-name>
<department>2875</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed is a press fit electronic component for a light emitter. The electronic component comprises at least one light emitter and at least one connection lead in electrical communication with the light emitter, the lead being configured for forming a frictional fit with a corresponding hole, the lead further being sufficiently rigid to withstand a compressive insertion force into the hole.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="123.70mm" wi="130.56mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="255.78mm" wi="131.49mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="256.03mm" wi="149.69mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="169.08mm" wi="99.91mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="188.21mm" wi="97.03mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="232.75mm" wi="114.55mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="247.99mm" wi="95.08mm" file="US07641379-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application relates to an electronic component for emitting light.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Electrical or electronic apparatus, such as network switches or routers, often include a plurality of ports or sockets to receive cables, such as network cables. High port-count server switches attempt to have as many ports as possible on a front panel to maximize functionality. The front panel is most easily accessible to a user, but space on the front cover is often limited. A printed circuit board (PCB), on which the ports are mounted, dictates the number of ports which will fit in any given space.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Further, an indication is usually provided of the status of each of the ports. Such an indication may be provided by a light source or light emitter, such as a light emitting diode (LED). Since it is useful to have a LED for each port, the available space on the PCB becomes even more limited. The LEDs may even compete for space with ports and other devices on the front panel of a server.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Typical right angled LEDs (having their leads orientated transversely to the LED) are too wide to fit, leaving only the narrowest LED to be considered. In general, right angled LEDs have leads or metal pins which fit into plated holes on the PCB and require wave soldering to complete the electrical connection and physical attachment of the LED to the PCB. Once soldered, LEDs can only be removed by de-soldering them. LEDs with solder pins are often misaligned during the wave soldering process and therefore may not line up with apertures provided on the front panel. The soldering process itself requires specific pin lengths and component orientation to minimize soldering defects. Also, LEDs with solder pins require the additional cost to wave solder, as most PCBs use components that are surface mount devices which have no pins and use a re-flow solder process.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Surface mount right angled LEDs are available. The surface mount process can also cause the LEDs to &#x201c;float&#x201d; and become misaligned during soldering. Removal of surface mounted LEDs requires the difficult task of de-soldering.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Example embodiments are illustrated by way of example and not limitation in the figures of the accompanying drawings, in which like references indicate similar elements and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a three-dimensional view of an electronic component in accordance with an example embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows a side elevational view of the electronic component of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> shows a longitudinal cross-sectional view of the electronic component of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> shows an exploded view of a portion of the electronic component of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref> show side elevational views of partially constructed connector leads, in accordance with an example embodiment, showing incrementally how the connector leads of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> may be constructed;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> shows a side-elevational view of an electronic component in accordance with another example embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows a top-plan view of the electronic component of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> shows a front-elevational view of the electronic component of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXAMPLE EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">In the following description, for purposes of explanation, numerous specific details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of one or more example embodiments. It will be evident, however, to one skilled in the art that the example embodiments may be practiced without these specific details.</p>
<p id="h-0005" num="0000">Overview</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The electronic component is described that comprises at least one light emitter and at least one connection lead in electrical communication with the light emitter, the lead being configured for forming a frictional fit with a corresponding hole, the lead further being sufficiently rigid to withstand a compressive insertion force into the hole.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref>, reference numeral <b>100</b> generally indicates an electronic component, in accordance with an example embodiment, comprising at least one light emitter. In the example embodiment illustrated, the electronic component <b>100</b> comprises two light emitters in the form of LEDs <b>102</b>. The electronic component <b>100</b> further comprises four leads, generally indicated by reference numeral <b>104</b>, two leads for each LED <b>102</b>. The leads <b>104</b> each comprise an internal portion <b>110</b> and an exposed connection portion or end <b>111</b>. Internal portions <b>110</b> are connected to respective LEDs <b>102</b> (refer to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and the exposed connection portions <b>111</b> provide positive and negative connection terminals by which the LEDs <b>102</b> may be powered. The leads <b>104</b> are generally L-shaped and the electronic component <b>100</b> is therefore a right angled connector. In the example right angled LEDs <b>102</b> the exposed connection end <b>111</b> and the light emitter <b>102</b> are orientated transversely to each other to define a right angle electronic component.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Example embodiments will be further described with reference to the right angled electronic component <b>100</b>, although it is to be understood that teaching of the specification could also be applied to vertically mounted electronic components or other types of electronic components. The LEDs <b>102</b> may be round (as illustrated), rectangular, or any other desired shape.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> show the electronic component <b>100</b> attached to a substrate, for example a PCB <b>120</b>. The PCB <b>120</b> includes a plurality of holes <b>122</b> which are aligned with the connection ends <b>111</b> of the leads <b>104</b>. The holes <b>122</b> may be electroplated to facilitate an electrical connection with the leads <b>104</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">In accordance with an example embodiment, the connection ends <b>111</b> are configured to achieve a frictional interference fit (e.g. press fit) with the respective matched holes <b>122</b>. Thus, the connection ends <b>111</b> may have larger respective dimensions or diameters than the respective holes <b>122</b>. The leads <b>104</b> may be of a resiliently compressible material such as a metal, for instance copper or a copper alloy. The connection end <b>111</b> of each lead <b>104</b> may be enlarged relative to the internal portion <b>110</b> and may bulge outwardly. The connection end <b>111</b> may further be hollow or have an aperture therethrough to facilitate inward deformation or compression during insertion so that, as in this example embodiment, the connection end <b>111</b> is eye- or loop-shaped, particularly resembling the eye of a needle.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">In an example embodiment, the connection end <b>111</b> may have an unstressed diameter of about 3 mm while the hole may have a diameter of 2 mm. Therefore, the connection end <b>111</b> may be compressed radially inwardly, as indicated by arrows <b>132</b>, during insertion into the hole <b>122</b>. The connection end <b>111</b> may take any shape or configuration that allows radially inward compression of the connection ends <b>111</b>. In the above example embodiment, diameters of 2 mm and 3 mm are mentioned merely by way of example. It will be appreciated that in other embodiments different diameters or sizes may be provided where the relative diameters or sizes are such the connection end <b>111</b> is received within the hole <b>122</b> with a friction fit.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Because of its resilient resistance to compression, the connection end <b>111</b> may form a frictional interference fit in the hole <b>122</b>. Due to this press fit, a reliable electrical connection is formed between the electronic component <b>100</b> and the walls of the hole <b>122</b>, while the electronic component <b>100</b> is held rigidly in place. Thus, no soldering is required. Furthermore, as the electronic component <b>100</b> is not soldered to the PCB <b>120</b>, it may be removed (e.g., replaced when the electronic component <b>100</b> has failed) without any de-soldering being required. Also, as the electronic component <b>100</b> is held firmly in place, lateral movement or shifting of the electronic component <b>100</b> relative to the PCB <b>120</b> is inhibited by the press fit connection.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">In an example embodiment, the connection end <b>111</b> is shaped and dimensioned and made of a sufficiently rigid conductive material to withstand an axially compressive insertion force during insertion, so that it does not deform undesirably (e.g. by buckling or bending). For instance, the connection end <b>111</b> may be sufficiently rigid not to buckle under a compressive insertion force or pressure of at least 10 psi. The leads <b>104</b>, or least the connection ends <b>111</b> thereof, may thus be of a relatively strong metal, e.g. copper or a copper alloy.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">It is to be understood that the connection ends <b>111</b> of the leads <b>104</b> may be shaped and dimensioned to be connected to standard diameter PCB holes <b>122</b>. Thus, modification of the PCB <b>120</b> may not necessarily be needed and the electronic component <b>100</b> may simply be slotted into existing PCBs.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref> illustrate graphically an example of how the electronic component <b>100</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> may be constructed. Unless otherwise indicated, like numerals in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 4</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 to 8</figref> refer to the same or similar parts. The leads <b>104</b> are formed (e.g. stamped) to include at successive heights along their respective lengths a resiliently deformable formation, in this example a loop- or eye-shaped formation, which ultimately will define the connection end <b>111</b> of the lead <b>104</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>). The LEDs <b>102</b> are then attached to the internal portion <b>110</b> of the leads <b>104</b> (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The leads <b>104</b> may then be severed or broken immediately below the resiliently deformable connection ends <b>111</b> and are bent at right angles roughly halfway along their length (see <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). A housing <b>106</b> (e.g., of a synthetic plastics material) is molded and assembled with, or molded around the LEDs <b>102</b> and leads <b>104</b> such that the connection ends <b>111</b> lie in a plane transverse to a front face of the electronic component <b>100</b> which contains the LEDs <b>102</b>. Thus, the electronic component <b>100</b> may therefore be termed a right angled electronic component. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the connection ends <b>111</b> are exposed from the housing <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 to 11</figref>, another example embodiment of an electronic component is generally indicated by reference <b>200</b>. The electronic component <b>200</b> comprises a single LED <b>202</b> with a corresponding single pair of leads <b>204</b> which are shown to include the same example eye-shaped resiliently deformable formation as the electronic component <b>100</b>. The electronic component <b>200</b> is shown to include a housing <b>206</b> from which the LED <b>202</b> stands proud. The electronic components <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> may be configured to match holes in existing PCBs.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The electronic components <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> in accordance with example embodiments, may have a number of advantages over electronic components in accordance with the prior art.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">For example, electronic components in accordance with the prior art generally have leads configured for soldering (e.g. wave soldering) so as to make electrical contact with, and be rigidly mounted to, the PCB. For instance, the leads (in accordance with the prior art) fit into holes with clearance thus providing a non-rigid or &#x201c;rattle fit&#x201d;. Therefore mere insertion of the lead into the hole does not create a reliable electrical connection nor rigidly mount the electronic component to the PCB. The lead relies on soldering to create the electrical connection and to hold the lead, and thus component, in rigidly in place.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">A disadvantage of this approach may be that once soldered, the electronic components are not easily removable. A further disadvantage may be that because the leads fit into the hole with clearance, they tend to move or shift during the soldering process and can potentially become misaligned with apertures into which they are intended to be received.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In addition, the leads in accordance with the prior art typically have a relatively small diameter so that they are not received within the holes with a friction fit. The leads are also of a malleable material and thus buckle or bend when resistance to insertion is encountered. Thus, the leads are typically not configured to withstand an axially compressive force or pressure experienced during frictional insertion. However, the leads <b>104</b>, <b>204</b> in accordance with example embodiments described herein may have a greater diameter to length ratio and/or be of a stronger material so that they can withstand a higher load (or axial compression) without buckling (e.g. as determined by Euler's formula).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The electronic components <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> in accordance with example embodiments provide leads <b>104</b>, <b>204</b> which are configured to deform inwardly upon insertion into a hole <b>122</b> but do not buckle or break. As the leads <b>104</b>, <b>204</b> (particularly the connection ends <b>111</b>) are resilient, they exert an outward force against the hole walls thereby retaining the electronic component <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> in position and forming a reliable electrical connection between the LEDs <b>102</b> and the PCB <b>120</b>. Furthermore, the electronic components <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> are removable and insertable by hand and no soldering or de-soldering is required. This may be advantageous because defective electronic components can easily be replaced and/or electronic components having LEDs of different colors can be arranged as desired. In fact, because the sole purpose of wave soldering is often for attaching LEDs to PCBs in accordance with the prior art, use of the electronic component <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> in accordance with an example embodiment may remove an entire step in the production of a PCB, thereby reducing production costs. In an example embodiment, a completely manufactured electronic device including the electronic components <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> has no solder mounting the components <b>100</b>, <b>200</b> to a PCB.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Also, the leads <b>104</b>, <b>204</b> may be self-aligning. Therefore the LEDs <b>102</b>, <b>202</b> may always fit ideally into the apertures for which they are configured.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The Abstract of the Disclosure is provided to comply with 37 C.F.R. &#xa7; 1.72(b), requiring an abstract that will allow the reader to quickly ascertain the nature of the technical disclosure. It is submitted with the understanding that it will not be used to interpret or limit the scope or meaning of the claims. In addition, in the foregoing Detailed Description, it can be seen that various features are grouped together in a single embodiment for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure. This method of disclosure is not to be interpreted as reflecting an intention that the claimed embodiments require more features than are expressly recited in each claim. Rather, as the following claims reflect, inventive subject matter lies in less than all features of a single disclosed embodiment. Thus the following claims are hereby incorporated into the Detailed Description, with each claim standing on its own as a separate embodiment.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A press fit electronic component comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one light emitter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two connection leads connected to the light emitter, each connection lead comprising an internal portion located within the housing and connected to the light emitter, and an exposed connection end exposed from the housing for connection to a printed circuit board (PCB), the exposed connection end being configured to form a frictional fit with a corresponding hole in the PCB and be sufficiently rigid to withstand a compressive insertion force into the hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the light emitter comprises a light emitting diode (LED).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the exposed connection end is sufficiently rigid to withstand an insertion force of at least 10 psi.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connection lead comprises copper or a copper alloy.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the exposed connection end and the light emitter are orientated transversely to each other to define a right angled electronic component.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the housing is molded from a synthetic plastics material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the connection lead comprises a connection end defining a resiliently deformable formation.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the deformable formation is eye-shaped or loop-shaped.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the deformable formation has a cross-sectional dimension of 3 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The press fit electronic component as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each connection lead has a connection end shaped and dimensioned to be received with a 2 mm hole in the PCB.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. An electronic device comprising:
<claim-text>a printed circuit board (PCB) including a plurality of holes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one press fit electronic component comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one light emitter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection lead connected to the light emitter, the connection lead comprising an internal portion located within the housing and connected to the light emitter, and an exposed connection end exposed from the housing for connection to a printed circuit board (PCB), the exposed connection end being configured to form a frictional fit with a corresponding hole in the PCB and be sufficiently rigid to withstand a compressive insertion force into the hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. An electronic device comprising:
<claim-text>a printed circuit board (PCB) including a plurality of holes; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one press fit electronic component comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one light emitter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two connection leads connected to the light emitter, each connection lead including an internal portion located within the housing and connected to the light emitter, and an exposed connection end exposed from the housing for connection to the PCB, the exposed connection end received within one of the plurality of holes with an interference fit to rigidly mount the electronic component to the PCB and make an electrical connection with the PCB without soldering.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The electronic device as claimed <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the electronic device has been completely manufactured.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the light emitter comprises a light emitting diode (LED).</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the exposed connection end has a cross-sectional diameter of 3 mm and the one hole in which the exposed connection end is received has a diameter of 2 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the exposed connection end is sufficiently rigid to withstand an insertion force of at least 10 psi.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The electronic device as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the exposed connection end is defined by a bulbous portion with a cross-sectional diameter of 3 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. A press fit electronic component comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for emitting light; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two connection means connected to the means for emitting light, each connection means comprising an internal portion located within the housing and connected to the means for emitting light, and an exposed connection end exposed from the housing for connection to a printed circuit board (PCB), the exposed connection end being configured to form a frictional fit with a corresponding hole in the PCB and be sufficiently rigid to withstand a compressive insertion force into the hole.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. A press fit electronic component comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one light emitter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connection lead connected to the light emitter, the connection lead comprising an internal portion located within the housing and connected to the light emitter, and an exposed connection end exposed from the housing for connection to a printed circuit board (PCB), the exposed connection end being configured to form a frictional fit with a corresponding hole in the PCB and be sufficiently rigid to withstand a compressive insertion force into the hole. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
