<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07642008-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07642008</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11282558</doc-number>
<date>20051118</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2004-0099304</doc-number>
<date>20041130</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>447</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>02</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>M</subclass>
<main-group>2</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429181</main-classification>
<further-classification>429174</further-classification>
<further-classification>429180</further-classification>
<further-classification>429183</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Rechargeable battery</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4598466</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Arenas et al.</name>
<date>19860700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification> 296232</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0118501</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Hashimoto et al.</name>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>429180</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>3214225</doc-number>
<date>19831000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>1020060000520</doc-number>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>17</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>8</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429181</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429183</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429174</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>429180</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>7</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060115727</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060601</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Yong-Sam</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoo</last-name>
<first-name>Seok-Yoon</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kim</last-name>
<first-name>Hyun-Seok</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Christie, Parker &#x26; Hale, LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Samsung SDI Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ryan</last-name>
<first-name>Patrick</first-name>
<department>1795</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Parsons</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas H.</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A rechargeable battery includes an electrode assembly including a positive electrode, a negative electrode, and a separator interposed between the two electrodes, a container for receiving the electrode assembly inside, and a cap assembly fixed to the container. The cap assembly includes a cap plate fixed to the container, an external terminal disposed in the cap plate to electrically be coupled with the electrode assembly, and a tubular body that surrounds the external terminal to fix the external terminal to the cap plate. The external terminal includes at least one groove formed toward inside of the external terminal for fastening the external terminal to the tubular body.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="115.74mm" wi="98.72mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="147.49mm" wi="145.12mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="138.01mm" wi="103.72mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="143.59mm" wi="142.75mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="214.71mm" wi="95.76mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="213.11mm" wi="87.97mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="165.35mm" wi="114.05mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="79.42mm" wi="76.28mm" file="US07642008-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority to and the benefit of Korean Patent Application No. 10-2004-0099304, filed on Nov. 30, 2004, the entire content of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an assembly structure of an external terminal for a rechargeable battery.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Unlike non-rechargeable batteries, rechargeable batteries may be recharged. Non-aqueous electrolyte rechargeable batteries with high energy density have recently been developed as high power rechargeable batteries. Lower power batteries in which battery cells are made into a battery pack are used as the power source for various portable electronic devices such as cellular phones, laptop computers, and camcorders. Larger battery packs which are formed by connecting several to tens of the rechargeable battery cells may be suitable for motor driven devices such as the electric vehicles.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Rechargeable batteries may be classified into different categories based on external shape, for example, rectangular box and cylindrical shapes. Rechargeable batteries include an electrode assembly in which a long rectangular-shaped positive plate, a long rectangular-shaped negative plate, and a separator that is interposed between the plates are spiral-wound together. Alternatively, a positive plate, a negative plate, and a separator may be stacked in a multiple layer structure. The electrode assembly is inserted into a container, and a cap assembly is mounted on the container to form the battery.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The cap assembly of such rechargeable batteries has an external terminal that is coupled to the electrode assembly. The cap assembly is fixed to the container by welding, etc. to seal the container.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Generally, the external terminal of the cap assembly is inserted into a hole that is formed on the cap plate of the cap assembly. Then, a packing and an O-ring are disposed between the hole and the external terminal to provide electrical insulation and a tight fit.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The external terminal is coupled with the cap plate by a nut that is fastened to a screw thread formed on the outer circumferential surface of the external terminal. The packing and O-ring are pressed against the nut to seal the hole.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">However, the above sealing structure and installation of the external terminal is problematic because it requires many parts which raise the manufacturing cost, and complicates the manufacturing process which decreases the manufacturing efficiency.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention provides a rechargeable battery in which the assembly structure of the cap plate and the external terminal are improved to simplify the assembly process and to reduce assembly time.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">According to one embodiment of the present invention, a rechargeable battery includes an electrode assembly having a positive electrode, a negative electrode, and a separator interposed between the two electrodes, a container for receiving the electrode assembly inside, and a cap assembly that is fixed to the container. The cap assembly includes a cap plate that is fixed to the container, an external terminal that is disposed in the cap plate and electrically coupled with the electrode assembly, and a tubular body that surrounds the external terminal to fix the external terminal to the cap plate. The external terminal includes at least one groove that is formed toward the inside of the external terminal and is fastened to the tubular body.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The external terminal may include at least one groove having a preformed shape on its circumferential surface. The groove may have a continuous or non-continuous shape.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The external terminal may be inserted into a through hole formed on the cap plate and the tubular body may be arranged around the through hole to be in close contact with the external terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The tubular body may include flanges that extend to the interior surface of the cap plate. The tubular body may be integrally formed with the cap plate and it may have a cylindrical shape. The tubular body may be fastened to the external terminal by a press.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The planar cross section of the external terminal and the planar cross section of the inner space of the tubular body may have the same shape.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A sealing member may be interposed between the tubular body and the external terminal, and the sealing member may include a gasket of a cylindrical shape to closely contact the inner circumferential surface of the tubular body. The sealing member may be made of a resin that is injected and cured between the tubular body and the external terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Flanges may be formed at both ends of the sealing member and the flanges may extend to the upper end of the tubular body and the interior surface of the cap plate.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">According to another embodiment of the present invention, a method for manufacturing a battery includes inserting a tubular body into a through hole of a cap plate of a cap assembly to be assembled with an external terminal, inserting the external terminal into the tubular body, and press molding the tubular body from the outside of the tubular body whereby the tubular body closely contacts the external terminal and at least one groove is formed toward inside of the external terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">According to another embodiment of the present invention, a method for manufacturing a battery includes inserting a sealing member into a through hole of a cap plate of a cap assembly to be assembled with an external terminal, inserting the external terminal into the through hole in which the sealing member is inserted, inserting a tubular body to surround the external terminal, and press molding the tubular body from the outside of the tubular body whereby the tubular body closely contacts the external terminal and at least one groove is formed toward inside of the external terminal.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross sectional view of a rechargeable battery according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross sectional view of a cap assembly assembled with an external terminal of the rechargeable battery according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic cross sectional view of a rechargeable battery according to another embodiment of the-present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref> is an exploded partial cross sectional view of a cap assembly assembled with an external terminal of the rechargeable battery of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref> is a cross sectional view of the cap assembly after the cap assembly has been assembled with the external terminal of the rechargeable battery according to yet another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross sectional view of a cap assembly assembled with an external terminal of a rechargeable battery according to still another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref> are cross sectional views showing a sealing member assembled with a cap plate according to still other embodiments of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic block diagram showing a rechargeable battery driving a motor according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The following description refers to a hexahedronal rechargeable battery with a positive terminal and a negative terminal that are formed on a cap plate as external terminals. However, the present invention is not limited to the structure described below and other shapes battery such as a cylinder may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the rechargeable battery of first embodiment includes an electrode assembly <b>10</b> having a positive electrode <b>11</b>, a negative electrode <b>12</b>, and a separator <b>13</b> interposed between the two electrodes, a container <b>20</b> having a space to receive the electrode assembly <b>10</b> inside the container, and a cap assembly <b>30</b> that is mounted on an opening <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the container <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The cap assembly <b>30</b> includes a cap plate <b>31</b> mounted on the opening <b>20</b><i>a </i>of the container <b>20</b> to seal it. The cap assembly also includes a positive terminal <b>16</b> and a negative terminal <b>17</b> coupled with the positive electrode <b>11</b> and the negative electrode <b>12</b>, respectively, through lead elements <b>15</b>, <b>15</b>&#x2032; and are assembled with the cap plate <b>31</b> to expose a portion of the terminals outside the container <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The positive terminal <b>16</b> and the negative terminal <b>17</b> are inserted through holes <b>32</b>, <b>32</b>&#x2032; respectively, that are formed on the cap plate <b>31</b>. Tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; which surround the positive terminal <b>16</b> and the negative terminal <b>17</b> and fix the terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> to the cap plate <b>31</b> are formed around the through hole <b>32</b> in the cap plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The external terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> are tightly fixed to the cap plate <b>31</b> of the cap assembly <b>30</b> through the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032;. The tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; are pressed against the external terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> to make close contact with the cap assembly <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The container <b>20</b> may include, but is not limited to a conductive metal such as aluminum, an aluminum alloy, and steel plated with nickel. The container <b>20</b> may have a rectangular-box shape that has an inner space to receive the electrode assembly <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The electrode assembly <b>10</b> has a jellyroll structure such that the positive electrode <b>11</b> and the negative electrode <b>12</b> including collectors coated with a positive active material and a negative active material, respectively, and the separator <b>13</b> interposed between them are stacked in a multiple layer structure and then wound into a jellyroll configuration.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The positive electrode <b>11</b> and the negative electrode <b>12</b> have uncoated regions <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>a</i>, respectively, that are absent active materials along one edge.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The uncoated regions <b>11</b><i>a</i>, <b>12</b><i>a </i>are arranged to face each other when assembling the electrode assembly <b>10</b>. The positive uncoated region <b>11</b><i>a </i>is coupled with a lead element <b>15</b> that contacts the positive external terminal <b>16</b>. The negative uncoated region <b>12</b><i>a </i>is coupled with a lead element <b>15</b>&#x2032; that contacts the negative external terminal <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The positive terminal <b>16</b> and the negative terminal <b>17</b> have screw threads in portions which pass through the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; and are exposed to the exterior. The screw threads are formed to fasten connectors (not shown) that couple multiple rechargeable batteries by the screw connections to form a battery module.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> also have a flange <b>18</b>, <b>18</b>&#x2032; in their lower portion that is positioned on the interior of the cap plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; have opened ends into which the respective external terminals <b>16</b>,<b>17</b> are insertable.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The externally exposed positive external terminal <b>16</b> and negative external terminal <b>17</b> include at least one groove <b>53</b>, <b>53</b>&#x2032; that is formed toward the interior of the external terminals on the outer circumferential surface of the external terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> which contacts the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032;. The grooves <b>53</b>, <b>53</b>&#x2032; are formed after the external terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> are inserted into the tubular bodies while the terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> are fastened to the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032;. Specifically, the grooves <b>53</b>, <b>53</b>&#x2032; are formed after the outer circumferential surfaces of the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; and the outer circumferential surfaces of the external terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> which contact the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; are pressed together. The terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> may include at least one groove preformed on its circumferential surface, thereby ensuring a tight seal between the terminal and the tubular body. The grooves <b>53</b>, <b>53</b>&#x2032; may have a continuous or non-continuous shape.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The planar cross section of the external positive terminal <b>16</b> and external negative terminal <b>17</b> has the same shape as the planar cross section of the inner space of the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032;. The tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; include a flange <b>52</b>, <b>52</b>&#x2032; protruding toward the interior surface of the cap plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">In one exemplary embodiment, the inside diameter of the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; is sized for the terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> to be insertable thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The positive terminal <b>16</b> and the negative terminal <b>17</b> have screw threads which pass through the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032;, respectively, to be exposed to the exterior, and they have flanges <b>18</b>,<b>18</b>&#x2032; which are positioned inside the container <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The screw thread is a portion formed to fasten connectors (not shown) electrically connecting batteries by screw connection when plural secondary batteries are formed into a battery module.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The flanges <b>18</b>, <b>18</b>&#x2032; closely contact the lower surface of the cap plate <b>31</b> to prevent separation of the terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b> from the cap plate <b>31</b> to the outside, when the positive terminal <b>16</b> and the negative terminal <b>17</b> are inserted into the through hole <b>32</b> to be fastened with the cap plate <b>31</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Sealing members <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; may be interposed between the respective tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; and external terminals <b>16</b>, <b>17</b>. The sealing members <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; may include a gasket of a cylindrical shape to be in close contact with the inner circumferential surface of the tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Flanges <b>41</b>, <b>42</b> may be formed at both ends of the sealing members <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; to prevent separation of the sealing members and the tubular bodies. The sealing members <b>40</b>, <b>40</b>&#x2032; may be made using a polymer resin which is injected between the tubular bodies and the external terminals, and then cured. Examples of the polymer resin include polyphenylene sulfide (PPS), polyperfluoroalkoxyethylene (PFA), polypropylene (PP), and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the rechargeable battery includes an electrode assembly <b>100</b> having a positive electrode <b>110</b>, a negative electrode <b>120</b>, and a separator <b>130</b> interposed between the two electrodes, a container <b>200</b> having a space to receive the electrode assembly <b>100</b> inside the container, and a cap assembly <b>300</b> that is mounted on an opening <b>200</b><i>a </i>of the container <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The cap assembly <b>300</b> includes a cap plate <b>310</b> that is mounted on the opening <b>200</b><i>a </i>of the container <b>200</b> to seal it. The cap assembly also includes a positive terminal <b>160</b> and a negative terminal <b>170</b> that are coupled with a lead portion <b>110</b><i>a </i>of the positive electrode <b>110</b> and a lead portion <b>120</b><i>a </i>of the negative electrode <b>120</b>, respectively, through lead elements <b>150</b>, <b>150</b>&#x2032; and are assembled with the cap plate <b>310</b> to expose a portion thereof outside the container <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The positive terminal <b>160</b> and the negative terminal <b>170</b> are inserted into a through hole <b>320</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A</figref>) that is formed on the cap plate <b>310</b>. Sealing members <b>400</b>, <b>400</b>&#x2032; are mounted in the through hole <b>320</b> while they surround the positive terminal <b>160</b> and the negative terminal <b>170</b> and fix the terminals <b>160</b>, <b>170</b> to the cap plate <b>310</b>. Tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032; which surround the positive terminal <b>160</b> and the negative terminal <b>170</b> and fix the terminals <b>160</b>, <b>170</b> to the cap plate <b>310</b> are formed around the through hole <b>320</b> in the cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The external terminals <b>160</b>, <b>170</b> are tightly fixed to the cap plate <b>310</b> of the cap assembly <b>300</b> through the sealing member <b>400</b>, <b>400</b>&#x2032; and the tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4A and 4B</figref>, the tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032; have open ends into which the external terminals <b>160</b>,<b>170</b> are insertable.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The externally exposed positive external terminal <b>160</b> and negative external terminal <b>170</b> include at least one groove <b>530</b>, <b>530</b>&#x2032; that is formed toward the interior of the external terminals and is fastened to the tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032;. The grooves <b>530</b>, <b>530</b>&#x2032; are formed while the terminals <b>160</b>, <b>170</b> are fastened to the respective tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The terminals <b>160</b>, <b>170</b> may include at least one preformed groove to form a tight seal between the terminals and the tubular bodies. The grooves <b>530</b>, <b>530</b>&#x2032; may have a continuous or non-continuous shape.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">The planar cross section of the external positive terminal <b>160</b> and external negative terminal <b>170</b> has the same shape as the planar cross section of the inner space of the tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032;. The tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032; include flanges <b>520</b>, <b>520</b>&#x2032; that protrude to the interior surface of the cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The inside diameter of the tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032; may be sized such that the terminals <b>160</b>,<b>170</b> are insertable thereinto.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">In the present embodiment, the tubular body <b>500</b> is fixed to the external terminals <b>160</b> through pressing. As shown <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref>, when the external terminal <b>160</b> is inserted into the tubular body <b>500</b>, the external member is pressed down the sealing member <b>400</b>. The tubular body <b>500</b> is pressed on its circumferential surface, thereby fixing the tubular body <b>500</b> to the external terminal <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4B</figref>, at least one groove <b>530</b> is formed toward the interior of the circumferential surface of the external terminal which contacts the tubular body <b>500</b>. The groove <b>530</b> is formed by pressing the tubular body <b>500</b> and the external terminal <b>160</b>. Although <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref> show only one terminal <b>160</b>, it will be understood by a person of skill in the art that the above-described embodiment is also applicable to the second terminal <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The sealing member <b>400</b> inserted in the through hole <b>320</b> of the cap plate <b>310</b> is pressed by the flange <b>180</b> of the external terminal <b>160</b> on the interior surface of the cap plate <b>310</b> and is also pressed by the flange <b>520</b> of the tubular body <b>500</b> on the exterior surface of the cap plate <b>310</b>. Thereby, the sealing member <b>400</b> maintains a tight seal between the cap plate <b>310</b> and the external terminal <b>160</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">As shown <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref>, the sealing member <b>400</b> has a cylindrical shape adapted to receive external terminal <b>160</b> therein. The sealing member <b>400</b> also has a narrow center insertable in the through hole <b>320</b>, and flanged ends to contact the interior and exterior of the cap plate.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">A first end of the sealing member <b>400</b> is closely adjacent to the flange <b>180</b> of the external terminal <b>160</b> at the interior of the cap plate <b>310</b>. A second end of the sealing member <b>400</b> is closely adjacent to and pressed by the flange <b>520</b> of the tubular body <b>500</b> at the exterior of the cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The sealing members <b>400</b>, <b>400</b>&#x2032; may include a gasket and may be made using a polymer resin injected between the tubular bodies and the external terminals and cured. Examples of the polymer include polyphenylene sulfide (PPS), polyperfluoroalkoxyethylene (PFA), polypropylene (PP), and so on.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, an electrode assembly <b>100</b>, a case <b>200</b>, and external terminals <b>160</b> and <b>170</b> have the same structure as in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a tubular body <b>501</b> covers the external terminal <b>161</b>. The tubular body <b>501</b> has an inside diameter generally corresponding to the diameter of the external terminal <b>161</b>. The tubular body <b>501</b> has a closed end and open end to cover the external terminal <b>161</b>. The tubular body <b>501</b> also includes a flange <b>521</b> which extends from the open end. The flange <b>521</b> may press the sealing member <b>401</b> to contact the cap plate <b>311</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">The tubular body <b>501</b> covers the external terminal <b>161</b> and acts as an external terminal. The tubular body <b>501</b> may include screw threads <b>540</b> on the circumferential surface.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">The tubular body <b>501</b> is assembled with the external terminal <b>161</b> by a press. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, the external terminal <b>161</b> is inserted into the tubular bodies <b>501</b> and the tubular body <b>501</b> is squeezed on its circumferential surface to form a groove <b>531</b> while the tubular body is pressed down on the sealing member <b>401</b>. The external terminal <b>161</b> which contacts the tubular body <b>501</b> is also squeezed to fix the tubular body <b>501</b> to the external terminal <b>161</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, the sealing member <b>400</b> and/or cap plate <b>310</b> may include protrusions <b>410</b> which are formed at a junction between the sealing member <b>400</b> and the cap assembly <b>310</b> to improve sealing therebetween.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> shows protrusions <b>410</b> which are formed on interior and exterior surfaces of the cap plate <b>310</b>. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> shows protrusions on the upper and lower ends of the sealing member <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The protrusions have an arc-shaped cross section and may be formed in a circular shape on the sealing member <b>400</b> and/or cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">When the sealing member <b>400</b> closely contacts the cap plate <b>310</b> through the flanges <b>180</b> of the external terminal <b>160</b>, <b>170</b> and the tubular bodies <b>500</b>, the protrusions <b>410</b> allow the cap plate and the sealing member to be pressed to each other, thus enhancing the connection between the cap plate and the sealing member.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">The following will describe the assembly of the terminals with the tubular bodies referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> according to one embodiment of the present invention. In the present embodiment, the positive terminal <b>16</b> and the negative terminal <b>17</b> have the same shape, and they are inserted into the respective tubular bodies <b>50</b>, <b>50</b>&#x2032; of the same shape. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> shows only the structure of the positive terminal <b>16</b>, which is applied correspondingly to the negative terminal <b>17</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The terminal <b>16</b> is installed in the cap assembly <b>30</b> by the following process. The tubular body <b>50</b> is inserted into the through hole <b>32</b> of the cap plate <b>31</b> and then the terminal <b>16</b> is inserted to pass through the opening of the tubular body <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">After the terminal <b>16</b> is completely inserted into the tubular body <b>50</b> and the flange <b>18</b> formed on the lower end of the terminal <b>16</b> contacts the lower end flange <b>52</b> of the tubular body <b>50</b>, the tubular body <b>50</b> is press molded from the exterior toward the terminal <b>16</b> by operating a press (P), as indicated schematically, for example, in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">The following will describe how to assemble the terminals with the tubular bodies referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>4</b>A and <b>4</b>B according to alternate embodiments of the present invention. The positive terminal <b>160</b> and the negative terminal <b>170</b> have the same shape, and they are inserted into respective tubular bodies <b>500</b>, <b>500</b>&#x2032; of the same shape. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref> show only the structure of the positive terminal <b>160</b>, which is applied correspondingly to the negative terminal <b>170</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The terminal <b>160</b> is installed in the cap assembly <b>300</b> by the following process. The sealing member <b>400</b> is inserted into the through hole <b>320</b> of the cap plate <b>310</b> and is inserted to pass through the center of the sealing member <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">After the terminal <b>160</b> is completely inserted into the tubular body <b>500</b> and the flange <b>180</b> formed on the lower end of the terminal <b>160</b> contacts the lower end of the sealing member <b>400</b>, the tubular body <b>500</b> is installed on the terminal <b>160</b> externally exposed from the cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">When the terminal <b>160</b> is inserted into the tubular body <b>500</b>, the flange <b>520</b> of the tubular body <b>500</b> contacts the upper end of the sealing member <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">When the tubular body <b>500</b> and the terminal <b>160</b> are pressed to the sealing member <b>400</b>, the flange <b>520</b> of the tubular body <b>500</b> and the flange <b>180</b> of the terminal <b>160</b> press the sealing member <b>400</b> on the interior and the exterior of the cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In this way, the sealing member <b>400</b> is tightly sealed to the cap plate <b>310</b>. Additionally, the tubular body <b>500</b> is pressed toward the terminal <b>160</b> so that the tubular body <b>500</b> is tightly sealed to the terminal <b>160</b> and fixed to the cap plate <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">A plurality of the above-mentioned rechargeable batteries is arranged with and is connected to each other in series or in parallel to provide a battery module. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic block diagram of a battery module <b>1</b> which includes the rechargeable batteries as discussed in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 3</figref> driving a motor <b>50</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The rechargeable battery of the present invention may be used as the power source for motor driving devices requiring high power characteristics, such as the hybrid electric vehicles, electric vehicles, wireless vacuum cleaners, motorbikes, or motor scooters.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">According to the present embodiments, the external terminal may be easily mounted in a cap assembly to thereby save time and effort in the assembly of the external terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">In addition, the seal between the external terminal and the cap assembly is improved to enhance the battery performance.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Moreover, the number of parts necessary for assembling the external terminal and maintaining the tightness may be reduced to save the manufacturing cost of the secondary battery.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Although exemplary embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes may be made in this embodiment without departing from the principles and spirit of the invention, the scope of which is defined in the claims and their equivalents.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A rechargeable battery comprising:
<claim-text>an electrode assembly including a positive electrode, a negative electrode, and a separator between the positive electrode and the negative electrode;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a container adapted to receive the electrode assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap assembly fixed to the container, the cap assembly including a cap plate fixed to the container, an external terminal in the cap plate and electrically coupled to the electrode assembly, a tubular body surrounding the external terminal, the tubular body including a flange extending along an interior surface of the cap plate, and a sealing member between the tubular body and the external terminal, wherein the external terminal has at least one groove for fixing the external terminal to the cap plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one groove has a non-continuous shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the external terminal is insertable into a through hole on the cap plate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the tubular body is around the through hole to be in contact with the external terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tubular body is integral with the cap plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a planar cross section of the external terminal and a planar cross section of an interior space of the tubular body are the same shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the tubular body is cylindrical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the battery drives a motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A rechargeable battery comprising:
<claim-text>an electrode assembly including a positive electrode, a negative electrode, and a separator between the two electrodes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a container adapted to receive the electrode assembly;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cap assembly fixed to the container, the cap assembly including a cap plate fixed to the container, an external terminal in the cap plate and electrically coupled to the electrode assembly, a sealing member in a through hole of the cap assembly, the sealing member between the external terminal and the through hole, and a tubular body surrounding the external terminal, wherein the sealing member has a flange at either end to prevent separation of the sealing member and the tubular body; wherein the external terminal has at least one press-molded groove for fixing the external terminal to the cap plate.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one press-molded groove has a non-continuous shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>,
<claim-text>wherein the external terminal is insertable into a through hole on the cap plate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the tubular body is around the through hole to be in contact with the external terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the tubular body is integral with the cap plate.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein a planar cross section of the external terminal and a planar cross section of an inner space of the tubular body are the same shape.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the tubular body is cylindrical.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the sealing member and/or the cap assembly includes protrusions at a junction between the sealing member and the cap assembly.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The rechargeable battery of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the battery drives a motor.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. A method for manufacturing a rechargeable battery, the rechargeable battery having an electrode assembly, a container adapted to receive the electrode assembly, and a cap assembly fixed to the container, the cap assembly including a cap plate fixed to the container, an external terminal disposed through the cap plate and electrically coupleable to the electrode assembly, the method comprising:
<claim-text>inserting a tubular body into a through hole of the cap plate, the tubular body adapted to be assembled with the external terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting the external terminal into the tubular body; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>press molding the tubular body from an exterior of the tubular body whereby the tubular body closely contacts the external terminal and forms at least one groove on an interior of the external terminal.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. A method for manufacturing a rechargeable battery, the rechargeable battery having an electrode assembly, a container adapted to receive the electrode assembly, and a cap assembly fixed to the container, the cap assembly including a cap plate fixed to the container and an external terminal disposed through the cap plate and electrically coupleable to the electrode assembly, the method comprising:
<claim-text>inserting a sealing member into a through hole of the cap assembly such that the sealing member is between the external terminal and the through hole;</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting the external terminal into the sealing member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting a tubular body over the external terminal to surround the external terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>press molding the tubular body from an outside of the tubular body whereby the tubular body closely contacts the external terminal and at least one groove is formed toward an interior of the external terminal such that the sealing member penetrates a circumferential surface of the external terminal. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
