<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641532-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641532</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11804501</doc-number>
<date>20070518</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>256</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>J</subclass>
<main-group>9</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>445 26</main-classification>
<further-classification>445 22</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Method of manufacturing fluorescent lamps by securing leads within the lamp's eyelets without exerting external tension to the leads</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4855634</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Gagnon et al.</name>
<date>19890800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>31331811</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5010272</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Eckhardt et al.</name>
<date>19910400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>31331807</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313242</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313352</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313 49- 51</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313238</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>313623-625</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>31331801-31811</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>445 22</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>445 26</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>445 27</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>2</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>3</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>10720355</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20031124</date>
</document-id>
<parent-grant-document>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7227308</doc-number>
<kind>A </kind>
<date>20070705</date>
</document-id>
</parent-grant-document>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11804501</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20070224906</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20070927</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Rense</last-name>
<first-name>Mark S.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Lyndhurst</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Fay Sharpe LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>General Electric Company</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Schenectady</city>
<state>NY</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Santiago</last-name>
<first-name>Mariceli</first-name>
<department>2879</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A lamp includes a reflector including a reflective portion, a heel, and a nose, wherein the nose includes an opening. A light source is disposed in the reflector. A pair of leads connects to the light source. An eyelet protrudes through the opening in the nose and receives one of the leads. A positioning member is disposed in the heel portion of the reflector. The positioning member includes an opening to receive the light source.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="146.13mm" wi="185.59mm" file="US07641532-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="185.76mm" wi="146.56mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641532-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="154.52mm" wi="128.78mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641532-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a divisional application of U.S. application Ser. No. 10/720,355, filed on Nov. 24, 2003 now U.S. Pat. No. 7,227,308, issued Jul. 5, 2007, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to electric lamps. More particularly the invention relates to electric lamps where a filament of the lamp is aligned with a focal point of a reflector.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">PAR type lamps operate most efficiently when a filament coil of a light source is in a known position relative to the focal point of the reflector of the lamp. Known methods to fix the location of the light source and thus the filament relative to the reflector (or reflector housing) include using an insulating spacer and ceramic adhesives. This assembly technique is process intensive and results in filament tube reliability issues due to cement transfer onto a pinched end of the light source and mislocation of a heat shield, which can cause thermal cycle oxidation failures. Quality issues such as deviation from desired beam pattern, center beam intensity, and lumen output can also be prevalent with this type of fixing system.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">An alternative method of fixing the location of the light source uses a metal disc in conjunction with metal eyelets. In this method, to assemble the lamp, a light source is inserted into an opening of a positioning member that is placed in engagement with a ledge of a protrusion. Thereafter, a force is applied to positioning member so as to deform it slightly rearwardly. After the force is applied to the positioning member a pair of eyelets are then mechanically fastened to the leads that will retain the deformation of the positioning member. After a period of time the assembly will &#x201c;relax&#x201d; so that a force remains on the positioning member.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Another alternative uses two metal eyelets crimped tightly to the base of the reflector housing. This alternative is highly dependent upon small variations and the conditions of openings in the base of the glass reflector. Furthermore, no positioning member is provided to facilitate positioning the light source in the reflector housing. Consequently, fixing the filament coil of the light source in a known position relative to the focal point of the reflector is difficult.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A lamp includes a reflector, a light source, a positioning member, and first and second eyelets. The reflector includes a reflective portion, a heel portion, and a nose where the nose includes an opening extending therethrough. The light source and positioning member are disposed at a desired location in the reflector. The positioning member includes an opening that receives the light source. A pair of leads extend from the light source where they are received in respective eyelets. The eyelets protrude through the opening in the nose of the reflector.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">A method of manufacturing a lamp comprising a reflector, a light source disposed in the reflector, a pair of leads connected to the light source, an eyelet protruding through an opening in a nose of the reflector and a positioning member disposed in the heel portion of the reflector is provided. The method includes the steps of positioning a portion of the light source inside an opening in the positioning member. The method further includes inserting the eyelet into the opening in the nose such that a portion of the eyelet extends from each side of the nose. The method further includes deforming the eyelet such that the eyelet is fixed in the opening of the nose. The method also includes inserting the light source into the reflector such that at least one lead protrudes through the eyelet.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic cross-sectional view of a lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view of a positioning member of the lamp of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a side elevation view of the positioning member of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a lamp or electric lamp <b>10</b> includes a reflector housing <b>12</b>, a light source <b>14</b>, and a positioning member <b>16</b>. The lamp in the preferred arrangement comprises a conventional halogen PAR type lamp. The lamp can alternatively be a conventional incandescent lamp, as well as other conventional lamps.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The reflector housing <b>12</b> is made of glass and provides an enclosure for the light source <b>14</b>. The reflector housing is coated with a reflective coating. The reflector housing includes a reflective portion <b>18</b>, along at least an inner surface thereof and is preferably a highly reflective material such as an aluminum layer, although other reflective surfaces such as a dichroic material can be used without departing from the scope and intent of the present invention. The reflective portion <b>18</b> typically has a concave or parabolic shape, although it is contemplated that the reflector housing could adopt a different contour or shape such as an elliptical or other known shape or combination of shapes. The reflector housing further includes a heel portion <b>22</b> and a nose <b>24</b>. The heel portion <b>22</b> depends axially outwardly from a central portion of the reflective portion <b>18</b> and has a substantially cylindrical configuration. The nose <b>24</b> is circular and extends from and closes off the heel portion <b>22</b>. A lens cover <b>26</b> encloses the reflector housing <b>12</b> along the outer circumference of the housing.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The heel portion <b>22</b> attaches to a lamp base (not shown) such as an Edison base, as just one example. Details of such arrangements are well known in the art so that further discussion herein is unnecessary. The heel portion <b>22</b> includes a plurality of radial shoulders <b>28</b> positioned on the inside of the heel portion <b>22</b>. Four shoulders are provided at 90&#xb0; apart from one another; however, a fewer or greater number of shoulders can be provided. The shoulders <b>28</b> support the positioning member <b>16</b> above the nose <b>24</b>. The shoulders extend a predetermined height above the nose to position a filament <b>30</b> of the light source <b>14</b> in proper vertical relation to the focal point of the reflective portion <b>18</b> of the reflector housing <b>12</b>. The shoulders <b>28</b>, in conjunction with the positioning member <b>16</b>, position the filament axially and diametrically with respect to the focal point of the reflective portion.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The nose <b>24</b> includes axially extending openings <b>32</b>. The openings <b>32</b> proceed from an inner surface of the nose where the openings communicate with an inner cavity of the lamp toward a stepped region or a countersunk region <b>34</b> on an outer surface of the nose <b>24</b>. In another embodiment, the openings <b>32</b> can be tapered. The light source <b>14</b> includes the filament <b>30</b>, a light transmissive envelope or bulb <b>36</b> and a crimped end <b>38</b>. The light source can be a conventional incandescent light source, but could also be a tungsten halogen light source or arc discharge light source. Leads <b>40</b> extend from the light source <b>14</b> to attach to the Edison or other type base (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">As mentioned earlier, the positioning member <b>16</b> rests on the radial shoulder(s) <b>28</b>. The shoulder dimension and the outer dimension (diameter) of the positioning member are closely matched to accurately locate the positioning member inside of heel portion <b>22</b> and thus relative to the reflector housing. This in turn, assures accurate location of the light source relative to the focal point of the reflector housing as will become more apparent below. The positioning member is preferably made of aluminum, however in an alternative embodiment the positioning member can be made from another suitable material, usually a metal. Since the positioning member <b>16</b> need not be placed in tension when inserted in the reflector housing the positioning member <b>16</b> can be made of aluminum. The aluminum positioning member <b>16</b> prevents tarnishing and facilitates the reflection of radiant energy, thus providing an additional heat shielding function as well as maximizing light output from the lamp.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The positioning member <b>16</b> includes an opening <b>42</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>). The opening <b>42</b> is positioned in the positioning member <b>16</b> to axially, diametrically and vertically align the filament <b>30</b> of the light source <b>14</b> with the focal point of the reflective portion <b>18</b> of the reflector housing <b>12</b>. The positioning member includes two central tabs <b>44</b> preferably disposed on opposite sides of the opening and four additional, smaller tabs <b>46</b> spaced outwardly from the central tabs. Particularly, two outer tabs <b>46</b> are located on one side of the opening <b>42</b> on opposite sides of the central tab <b>44</b>. Two additional tabs <b>46</b> are located across from the first two outer tabs on an opposite side of the opening <b>42</b> and on an opposite side of the other central tab <b>44</b>. In the embodiment depicted, the central tabs <b>44</b> depend axially outward (downwardly) from the positioning member <b>16</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) and the outer tabs <b>46</b> project axially outward in the opposite direction (upwardly) from the positioning member. The opening <b>42</b> receives the crimped end <b>38</b> of the light source <b>14</b>. The central tabs <b>42</b> engage, through spring action, the crimped end <b>38</b> of the light source <b>14</b> when the light source is received by the opening <b>42</b>. The outer tabs <b>46</b> cradle the bulb <b>36</b> of the light source <b>14</b> spacing and accurately locate the bulb <b>36</b> in relation to the positioning member <b>16</b>. In this manner, the light source is precisely positioned relative to the focal point of the reflector housing.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Eyelets <b>50</b> are positioned in the openings <b>32</b> of the nose <b>24</b>. The eyelets in the preferred embodiment are made of 70/30 brass; however, the eyelets can be made of any other suitable material. The eyelets include a tubular portion <b>52</b> and a flanged portion <b>54</b>. In a preferred embodiment, the tubular portion <b>52</b> has a generally constant thickness and homogenous strength characteristic throughout the tubular portion for ease of manufacture. The flanged portion <b>54</b> is, for example, a rolled over portion of the tubular portion <b>52</b>. The eyelets <b>50</b> are received in the openings <b>32</b> from the inside of the heel portion <b>22</b> and a segment of the tubular portion <b>52</b> of each eyelet extends a distance from the outside surface of nose <b>24</b>. The flanged portion <b>52</b> seats on the inner surface of nose <b>24</b>. As best illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the flanged portion <b>54</b> is dimensioned from abutting engagement with the inner surface of the nose <b>24</b> at the inner end of opening <b>32</b> by inserting the eyelets from within the reflector housing, through the heel portion, and into respective openings in the nose. In an alternative embodiment, the flanged portion can be received in a countersunk region or shoulder at the inner end of the opening <b>32</b>. Upon insertion into the openings <b>32</b> the tubular portion <b>52</b> of the eyelet extending from the outer surface of nose <b>24</b> is deformed, i.e. swaged, to form a radial shoulder or upset portion <b>56</b> to mechanically fasten the eyelet <b>50</b> to the outer surface of the nose <b>24</b>. The upset portion <b>56</b> engages the countersunk region <b>34</b> to keep the eyelet stable before and after the lead is inserted into the eyelet. The upset portion <b>56</b> sitting in the countersunk region aligns the eyelet in the two perpendicular axes of the nose <b>24</b> and axially limits any movement of the eyelet in the opening <b>32</b>. In other words, the eyelet after being swaged is locked in three mutually perpendicular axes. The upset portion <b>56</b> of the eyelet also provides a larger surface area engaging the nose <b>24</b>, lessening any likelihood that the eyelet <b>50</b> might come loose due to thermal cycling. The flanged portion <b>54</b> can also be deformed to further mechanically fasten the eyelet <b>50</b> to the nose <b>24</b> if desired. Preferably deformation of the eyelet does not affect the inside diameter of the opening extending axially through the eyelet.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">To assemble the lamp <b>10</b>, the eyelets <b>50</b> are inserted into the openings <b>32</b> in the nose <b>24</b> from inside the reflector housing <b>12</b>. The eyelets are received such that the flanged portion <b>54</b> rests on the inner surface of the nose <b>24</b> that faces the reflective portion <b>12</b> of the lamp <b>10</b>. A portion of the tubular portion <b>52</b> of the eyelets <b>50</b> protrudes outwardly from the openings <b>32</b> on an opposite side of the nose <b>24</b> from the reflective portion <b>18</b> of the reflector housing <b>12</b>. The eyelet flanged portion <b>54</b> engages the nose <b>24</b> of the reflector housing <b>12</b>. Deforming the tubular portion <b>52</b> forms a swaged portion <b>56</b> that engages a side of the opening <b>32</b> in the nose <b>24</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The light source <b>14</b> is inserted through the positioning member <b>42</b> by pressing the crimped seal region <b>38</b> of the bulb <b>36</b> into tight, biased engagement with the positioning member. Specifically, the crimped region <b>38</b> of the light source is suitable and advantageously cradled by outer tabs <b>46</b> extending from one side of the positioning member <b>42</b> and by central tabs <b>44</b> extending from the other side. This subassembly comprising the light source <b>14</b> and the positioning member <b>42</b> is then inserted into the reflector <b>12</b> such that each of the leads <b>40</b> protrude through a respective one of the eyelets <b>50</b>. The positioning member <b>16</b> rests on the shoulders <b>28</b> in the heel portion <b>22</b> of the housing <b>12</b>. The positioning member <b>16</b> need not be placed in tension and rests on the shoulder with no greater force than the weight of the positioning member and the light source. The eyelets <b>50</b> are then crimped to mechanically fasten the leads <b>40</b> within the eyelets <b>50</b>. The eyelets are then preferably brazed to further mechanically fasten the eyelets <b>50</b> to the leads <b>40</b>. Other conventional techniques can be used to attach the leads to the eyelets. Such a method properly positions the light source <b>14</b> in relation to the focal center of the reflector <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">By providing a countersink <b>34</b> in the nose <b>24</b>, and deforming/swaging the eyelets to provide a secure engagement therewith, a more compact arrangement is achieved. The swaged shoulder <b>56</b> locks the eyelets to the reflector housing without placing the assembly in tension. Subsequently crimping and brazing the eyelets to the leads <b>38</b> provides a secure connection during assembly and that is resistant to issues associated with thermal cycling.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">While the lamp has been described with respect to specific embodiments by way of illustration, many modifications and changes will occur to those skilled in the art. It is, therefore, to be understood that the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications and changes as fall within the scope and spirit of the claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of manufacturing a lamp comprising a reflector including a heel portion and a nose, the lamp further comprising a light source disposed in the reflector, a pair of leads connected to the light source, a pair of eyelets each having a flanged portion protruding through an opening in the nose and a positioning member disposed in the heel portion of the reflector, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>positioning the light source inside an opening in the positioning member</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting the eyelet into the opening in the nose such that a portion of the eyelet extends from the outside surface of the nose;</claim-text>
<claim-text>deforming the eyelet such that the eyelet is fixed in the opening of the nose;</claim-text>
<claim-text>inserting the light source and positioning member into the reflector such that at least one lead protrudes through the eyelet; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>crimping the eyelet to mechanically fasten the lead to the outlet without putting the lead in tension.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the positioning step further comprises the step of positioning the light source such that tabs located on opposite sides of the opening engage the light source.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the step of inserting the eyelet further comprises inserting the eyelet into the opening of the nose from inside the reflector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the eyelet deforming step further comprises the step of swaging the eyelet such that the eyelet engages the opening in the nose.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the eyelet deforming step further comprises deforming the eyelet such that the eyelet is fixed in three mutually perpendicular axes.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, further comprising inserting the heel into a lamp base and brazing at least one of the leads to the lamp base. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
