<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641511-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641511</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11998934</doc-number>
<date>20071203</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>60</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439527</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Jack cable assembly with support tray and method of making same</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4806112</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Roberts et al.</name>
<date>19890200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439144</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5649838</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sung</name>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6142799</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Marcel</name>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6527581</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Wang</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439445</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6894219</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Culbertson</name>
<date>20050500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6935903</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Gaidosch</name>
<date>20050800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>9</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439527</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439529</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439533</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>8</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090142957</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090604</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>DeMonica</last-name>
<first-name>Michael J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cortland</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Francis</last-name>
<first-name>Michael E.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beaver Falls</city>
<state>PA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yurtin</last-name>
<first-name>John A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Cortland</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Twomey</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas N.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Delphi Technologies, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Leon</last-name>
<first-name>Edwin A.</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Girardi</last-name>
<first-name>Vanessa</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An electrical jack cable assembly includes a jack cable connector and an adaptor coupling for attaching the connector to a support. The adaptor coupling has a face plate and a tray that extends to a rear wall. The connector body is retained in the tray behind the abutment wall so that the rear wall resists any movement of the connector body with respect to the adaptor coupling in the plug-in direction. The jack cable assembly is made by providing a jack cable connector providing an adaptor coupling having a tray that extends rearwardly to a rear wall and assembling the connector body to the tray by slanting the connector body and inserting the slanted connector body into the tray until it passes over the rear wall of the tray. The rear end of the connector body is then pushed down for retaining the connector body firmly and positively in the tray.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="160.19mm" wi="262.38mm" file="US07641511-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="258.40mm" wi="170.10mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641511-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="256.96mm" wi="155.96mm" file="US07641511-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="269.07mm" wi="176.61mm" file="US07641511-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This invention relates generally to a jack cable assembly comprising an electrical jack cable connector and an adaptor coupling for mounting the electrical jack cable connector on a support for receiving an electrical plug-in connector and to a method for making the jack cable assembly.</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">It is already known to provide a jack cable assembly comprising an electrical jack cable connector and an adaptor coupling for mounting the electrical jack cable connector on a support for receiving an electrical plug-in connector. In the known assembly, an annular adaptor is pushed into a smaller hole in a support panel from one side, usually the outside of the support panel and retained by flexible lock arms engaging an opposite side, usually the inside of the support panel adjacent the hole. The electrical jack cable connector is then plugged into the adaptor from the opposite or inside of the support panel and retained by flexible lock arms of the electrical jack cable connector that engage the adaptor. Thus, the electrical jack cable connector is mounted on the support panel for receiving an electrical plug-in connector that is plugged into the electrical jack cable connector from the one side or outside of the panel through the smaller hole in the support panel.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A potential problem exists when the electrical cable jack connector is retained in the plug-in direction of the electrical plug-in connector by flexible lock arms and the electrical plug-in connector is plugged into and pulled out of the electrical jack cable connector often. Repeated plugging and unplugging tends to weaken the flexible lock arms so that electrical cable jack connector can be pushed back away from the support in the plug-in direction when the electrical plug-in connector is plugged into the cable jack connector in the plug-in direction resulting in failure to make an electrical connection.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">The jack cable assembly of the invention provides a cable jack assembly having an adaptor coupling that resists the plug-in forces in a positive manner so that an electrical connection is made between the jack cable connector and a plug-in connector even after repeated plugging and unplugging of the plug-in connector in the plug-in direction.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The adaptor coupling preferably includes a tray for holding a connector body of the jack cable assembly so that a rear wall of the tray resists movement of connector body in the plug-in direction.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The adaptor coupling preferably includes a face plate and a socket that extends rearwardly from an opening in the face plate for receiving an electrical plug-in connector in the plug-in direction.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In another aspect, the jack cable assembly of the invention is made by providing a jack cable connector having a connector body, providing an adaptor coupling and assembling the jack cable connector to the adaptor coupling so that the connector body is held against a rear wall of the adaptor connector to resist movement of the connector body in the plug-in direction.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The adaptor coupling preferably includes a tray that is shaped to receive the connector body snugly.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The tray of the adaptor coupling may have a reduced height to facilitate assembly of the connector body into the tray.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of an electrical jack cable assembly illustrating an embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is another exploded perspective view of the electrical jack cable assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3</figref>, <b>4</b> and <b>5</b> are perspective views of the process of assembling the electrical jack cable assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a longitudinal section of the electrical jack cable assembly of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a rear perspective view of another electrical jack cable assembly illustrating a second embodiment of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a rear perspective view of still another electrical jack cable assembly illustrating a third embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring now to the drawings, the electrical jack cable assembly <b>10</b> comprises a jack cable connector <b>12</b> and an adaptor coupling <b>14</b> for attaching the connector <b>12</b> to a support (not shown). The adaptor coupling <b>14</b> can be attached to the support in any suitable manner, such by pushing the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> into a smaller hole of a support panel from one side and retaining the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> by flexible arms engaging the opposite side of the support panel as in the case of the prior art assembly discussed above. Alternatively, the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> may form an integral part of the support itself, such as being an integral part of a molded plastic panel in an automobile. In either event, the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> is preferably of one-piece construction that may result from molding the adaptor coupling in one piece.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Jack cable jack connector <b>12</b> comprises a plurality of electric cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> and a plurality of grounded electric terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> that are attached to the ends of the electric cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> respectively. Each of the electric cables comprises a signal cable and a ground cable that are attached to an inner signal contact and an outer ground shell respectively. More particularly as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the typical electric cable <b>22</b> comprises a signal cable <b>22</b><i>a </i>that is attached to an inner signal contact <b>28</b><i>a </i>and a ground cable <b>22</b><i>b </i>that is attached to the outer ground shell <b>28</b><i>b</i>. The typical signal cable <b>22</b><i>a </i>and ground cable <b>22</b><i>b </i>can be attached to the respective inner signal contact <b>28</b><i>a </i>and outer ground shell <b>28</b><i>b </i>in any suitable manner such as by soldering the cable cores to attachment tabs at the inner ends of the signal contact <b>28</b><i>a </i>and ground cable <b>28</b><i>b </i>as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The ends of the electric cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b>, signal cables as well as ground cables, and the attached electric terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> are all spaced apart and insert molded in a molded connector body <b>32</b> of a suitable plastic electrically insulating material. When the molded connector body <b>32</b> is cured, three juxtaposed electric cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> enter the rear end of the connector body <b>32</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>) while the attached electric terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> protrude from the front end of the connector body <b>32</b> in a spaced apart relationship (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>).</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Adaptor coupling <b>14</b> has a face plate <b>34</b> and a tray <b>36</b> that has side walls <b>38</b> and a rear wall <b>40</b> of reduced height. Adaptor coupling <b>14</b> preferably includes a socket <b>42</b> at the forward end that extends rearwardly from an opening <b>44</b> in the face plate <b>34</b> to an abutment wall <b>46</b> that is intermediate the face plate <b>34</b> and the rear wall <b>40</b>. Abutment wall <b>46</b> has a plurality of through holes <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> and <b>52</b> for receiving the respective electric terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> so as to protrude into the socket <b>42</b> from the portion of the tray <b>36</b> behind the abutment wall <b>46</b>. Adaptor coupling <b>14</b> also preferably includes a hold-down tab <b>54</b> that projects rearwardly from abutment wall <b>46</b> and the rear wall <b>40</b> of reduced height preferably includes a central cable channel <b>56</b> for receiving the juxtaposed cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> that project from the rear end of the molded connector body <b>32</b> as best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The molded connector body <b>32</b> is retained in the tray <b>36</b> behind the abutment wall <b>46</b> by lock projections <b>58</b> that snap into place beneath lock bars <b>60</b> that are formed by slots in the lower portions of the rear wall <b>40</b> which is also best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The jack cable assembly <b>10</b> is assembled in the following manner. The cable jack connector <b>12</b> is formed in a conventional and well known manner by attaching the female terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> to the ends of the respective cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> and then insert molding the rearward portions of the female terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> in the molded connector body <b>32</b>. The adaptor coupling <b>14</b> is also fabricated in any suitable manner such by a conventional injection molding technique. The cable jack connector <b>12</b> and adaptor coupling <b>14</b> are formed so that the connector body <b>32</b> fits snugly into the tray <b>36</b> between the abutment wall <b>46</b> and the rear wall <b>40</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> so that the jack cable connector <b>12</b> is positively retained in the plug-in direction (shown by the arrow <b>62</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>) by the rear wall <b>40</b> of the tray <b>36</b>. In this regard it should be noted that the rear wall <b>40</b> preferably includes the channel <b>56</b> for cables <b>20</b>, <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> to increase the height of the rear wall <b>40</b> on either side of the cables.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The jack cable connector <b>12</b> is assembled to the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> by slanting the connector body <b>32</b> at an angle of about 15 degrees with respect to the bottom of the tray <b>36</b> (or about 75 degrees with respect to the face plate <b>34</b>) so that the connector body <b>32</b> can be inserted into the tray <b>36</b> behind the abutment wall <b>46</b> as best shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The projecting ends of the female terminals <b>26</b>, <b>28</b> and <b>30</b> of the slanted connector body <b>32</b> are then aligned with the holes <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> and <b>52</b> in the abutment wall <b>46</b> and inserted through the holes <b>48</b>, <b>50</b> and <b>52</b> in the abutment wall <b>46</b> until connector body <b>32</b> engages the abutment wall <b>48</b> passes over the rear wall <b>40</b> of the tray <b>36</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The rear end of the connector body <b>32</b> is then pushed down against the floor of the tray <b>36</b> so that the lock projections <b>56</b> projecting from the rear end of the connector body <b>32</b> snap down under the lock bars <b>60</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. The forward end of the connector body <b>32</b> is held down by the tab <b>54</b> and the jack cable connector <b>12</b> is held firmly and positively in the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> with the rear wall, <b>40</b> resisting any movement of the connector body <b>32</b> with respect to the adaptor coupling <b>14</b> in the plug-in direction indicated by the arrow <b>62</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A mating connector with male pins and an outer canister such as that shown in U.S. Pat. No. 5,649,838 granted Jul. 22, 1997 or the like (not shown) can be plugged into the cable jack <b>12</b> repeatedly without any danger of pushing the connector body <b>32</b> out of the adapter coupling <b>14</b> because the plug-in forces are transmitted to the rear wall <b>40</b> of the tray <b>36</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a rear perspective view of another electrical jack cable assembly <b>100</b> illustrating a second embodiment of the invention. This embodiment has a modified connector body <b>132</b> for the jack cable connector <b>112</b> that includes a lock shoulder <b>158</b> at each side and a modified adaptor coupling <b>114</b> that has a flexible lock arm <b>160</b> in each side wall <b>138</b> of the tray <b>136</b>. The jack cable connector <b>112</b> and adaptor coupling <b>114</b> are otherwise the same as the jack cable connector <b>12</b> and adaptor coupling <b>14</b> and assembled in the same manner. However, when the rear end of the connector body <b>132</b> is pushed down against the floor of the tray <b>136</b>, the lock arms <b>160</b> now snap over the lock shoulders <b>158</b> on the rear end of the connector body <b>132</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> to hold the jack cable connector <b>112</b> firmly and positively in the adaptor coupling <b>114</b> with the rear wall <b>140</b> resisting any movement of the connector body <b>132</b> with respect to the adaptor coupling <b>114</b> in the plug-in direction indicated by the arrow <b>162</b>, even though the forward end of the connector body is not held down by a tab as in the case of the earlier embodiment discussed above.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a rear perspective view of still another electrical jack cable assembly <b>200</b> illustrating a third embodiment of the invention. This embodiment also has a modified connector body <b>232</b> for the jack cable connector <b>212</b> that includes an elongate cantilevered tongue <b>254</b> (in place of the short tab <b>54</b>) that is reinforced by gussets <b>255</b> and a modified adaptor coupling <b>214</b> that does not have any lock projections or shoulders. The jack cable connector <b>212</b> and adaptor coupling <b>214</b> are otherwise the same as the jack cable connector <b>12</b> and adaptor coupling <b>14</b> and assembled in a similar manner. However, when the connector body <b>232</b> is then pushed into the tray <b>236</b> behind the abutment wall <b>240</b>, the end of the elongate cantilevered tongue <b>254</b> is raised and bowing the tongue <b>254</b> upwardly resiliently until the rear end of the connector body <b>232</b> passes over the rear wall <b>240</b> whereupon the tongue <b>254</b> recovers and pushes the rear end of the connector body down <b>232</b> against the floor of the tray <b>236</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. The jack cable connector <b>212</b> is held firmly and positively in the adaptor coupling <b>214</b> with the rear wall <b>240</b> resisting any movement of the connector body <b>32</b> with respect to the adaptor coupling <b>214</b> in the plug-in direction indicated by the arrow <b>262</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">In all of the embodiments discussed above, there is a positive two-way retention of the connector body <b>32</b>, <b>132</b> or <b>232</b> in the respective tray <b>36</b>, <b>136</b> or <b>236</b> with the rear wall <b>40</b>, <b>140</b> or <b>240</b> resisting movement in the plug-in direction and the intermediate wall <b>46</b>, <b>146</b> or <b>246</b> at the front of the tray resisting movement in the pull-out direction.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">It will be readily understood by those persons skilled in the art that the present invention is susceptible of broad utility and application. Many embodiments and adaptations of the present invention other than those described above, as well as many variations, modifications and equivalent arrangements, will be apparent from or reasonably suggested by the present invention and the foregoing description, without departing from the substance or scope of the present invention. Accordingly, while the present invention has been described herein in detail in relation to its preferred embodiment, it is to be understood that this disclosure is only illustrative and exemplary of the present invention and is made merely for purposes of providing a full and enabling disclosure of the invention. The foregoing disclosure is not intended or to be construed to limit the present invention or otherwise to exclude any such other embodiments, adaptations, variations, modifications and equivalent arrangements, the present invention being limited only by the following claims and the equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An electrical jack cable assembly comprising a jack cable connector and an adaptor coupling for attaching the jack cable connector to a support of which the adaptor coupling may be an integral part,
<claim-text>the jack cable connector having an electric cable and an electric terminal that is attached to an end of the electric cable,</claim-text>
<claim-text>an end of the electric cable and the attached electric terminal being disposed in a connector body so that the electric cable enters a rear end of the connector body with the electrical terminal facing forward to be able to receive an electric plug-in connector when moved in a plug-in direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the adaptor coupling having a tray that has side walls and a rear wall,</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for retaining the connector body in the tray so that the rear wall resists any movement of the connector body with respect to the adaptor coupling in the plug-in direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the adaptor coupling has a face plate and a socket at a forward end that extends rearwardly from an opening in the face plate to an abutment wall that is intermediate the face plate and the rear wall of reduced height, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the abutment wall having a through hole for receiving the electric terminal so as to protrude into the socket from a portion of the tray behind the abutment wall.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The electrical jack assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the means for retaining the connector body in the tray behind the abutment wall comprises a lock shoulder at each side of the connector body and a flexible lock arm in each side wall of the tray.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The electrical jack assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the means for retaining the connector body in the tray behind the abutment wall comprises a hold-down tab that projects rearwardly from the abutment wall and projections of the connector body that snap into place beneath lock bars that are formed by slots in the lower portions of the rear wall of the adaptor coupling.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The electrical jack assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the means for retaining the connector body in the tray behind the abutment wall comprises an elongate cantilevered tongue of the adaptor coupling that is reinforced by gussets, the elongate cantilevered tongue pushing the rear end of the connector body down against the floor of the tray to hold the jack cable connector firmly and positively in the adaptor coupling with the rear wall resisting any movement of the connector body with respect to the adaptor coupling in the plug-in direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An electrical jack cable assembly comprising a jack cable connector and an adaptor coupling for attaching the jack cable connector to a support of which the adaptor coupling may be an integral part,
<claim-text>the jack cable connector having a plurality of electric cables and a plurality of grounded electric terminals that are attached to the ends of the electric cables respectively,</claim-text>
<claim-text>each one of the plurality of electric cables comprising a signal cable and a ground cable that are attached to an inner signal contact and an outer ground shell of one of the plurality of grounded electric terminals respectively,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the plurality of electric cables, signal cables as well as ground cables, and the attached plurality of grounded electric terminals attached thereto being insert molded in a molded connector body of a suitable plastic electrically insulating material so that the plurality of electric cables enter a rear end of the connector body while the attached plurality of electric terminals protrude from a front end of the connector body in a spaced apart relationship to be able to receive respective electric plug-in connectors when moved in a plug-in direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the adaptor coupling having a face plate and a tray that has side walls and a rear wall of reduced height,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the adaptor coupling further including a socket at a forward end that extends rearwardly from an opening in the face plate to an abutment wall that is intermediate the face plate and the rear wall of reduced height,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the abutment wall having a plurality of through holes for receiving the plurality of electric terminals respectively so as to protrude into the socket from a portion of the tray behind the abutment wall,</claim-text>
<claim-text>the rear wall of reduced height including a central cable channel for receiving the plurality of cables that project from the rear end of the molded connector body, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for retaining the molded connector body in the tray behind the abutment wall so that the rear wall resists any movement of the connector body with respect to the adaptor coupling in the plug-in direction.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The electrical jack assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the means for retaining the molded connector body in the tray comprises a hold-down tab that projects rearwardly from the abutment wall and projections of the connector body that snap into place beneath lock bars that are formed by slots in the lower portions of the rear wall of the adaptor coupling.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The electrical jack assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the means for retaining the molded connector body in the tray comprises a lock shoulder at each side of the connector body and a flexible lock arm in each side wall of the tray.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The electrical jack assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the means for retaining the molded connector body in the tray comprises an elongate cantilevered tongue of the adaptor coupling that is reinforced by gussets, the elongate cantilevered tongue pushing the rear end of the connector body down against the floor of the tray to hold the jack cable connector firmly and positively in the adaptor coupling with the rear wall resisting any movement of the connector body with respect to the adaptor coupling in the plug-in direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method of making a jack cable assembly comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>providing a jack cable connector having an electric terminal attached to an end of a cable with a rearward portion of the electric terminal disposed in a connector body so that the cable enters a rearward end of the connector body with the electric terminal facing forward to be able to receive an electric plug-in connector when moved in a plug-in direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing an adaptor coupling having a tray that extends rearwardly to a rear wall, the tray being shaped so that the connector body fits snugly in the tray against the rear wall,</claim-text>
<claim-text>assembling the connector body to the adaptor coupling so that the connector body is retained in the tray against the rear wall of the tray to resist any movement of the connector body with respect to the adaptor coupling in the plug-in direction, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the electric terminal has a protruding end, the adaptor coupling has a face plate and an abutment wall between the face plate and the rear wall, the abutment wall has a hole extending therethrough, and the tray is shaped so that the connector body fits snugly in the tray between the abutment wall and the rear wall, and the adaptor coupling has a socket that extends rearwardly from an opening in the face plate to the abutment wall, and wherein the protruding end of the electric terminal is inserted through the hole of the abutment wall into the socket when the slanted connector body is inserted into the tray. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
