<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641481-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641481</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11870064</doc-number>
<date>20071010</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>258</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>12</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 70</main-classification>
<further-classification>439 66</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Non-intrusive interposer for accessing integrated circuit package signals</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4076357</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cistola</name>
<date>19780200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 65</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5934914</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fjelstad et al.</name>
<date>19990800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 82</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6015301</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Brodsky et al.</name>
<date>20000100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 73</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6712621</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Li et al.</name>
<date>20040300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 65</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6746255</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20040600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439108</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7029288</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Li</name>
<date>20060400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 66</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7048549</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Swain</name>
<date>20060500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439 66</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7539027</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Callahan et al.</name>
<date>20090500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361803</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>16</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 70- 73</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439 66</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090197436</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090806</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Trobough</last-name>
<first-name>Mark</first-name>
<address>
<city>Olympia</city>
<state>WA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Grossman, Tucker, Perreault &#x26; Pfleger, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Intel Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Santa Clara</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Truc T</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed is an interposer for accessing one or more signals from an Integrated Circuit (IC) package. The interposer is disposed between the IC package and a socket body. The interposer comprises a plurality of clearance holes and at least one connecting element. The plurality of clearance holes allows an array of contacts on a first surface of the socket body to pass through the interposer and make electrical contact with a first set of contacts of a plurality of contacts of the IC package. The at least one connecting element is configured to make electrical contact with a second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package. The electrical contact between the at least one connecting element and the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package provides access to the one or more signals from the IC package.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="190.42mm" wi="164.93mm" file="US07641481-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.60mm" wi="150.54mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641481-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="243.33mm" wi="170.69mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641481-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="214.46mm" wi="165.44mm" file="US07641481-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="246.97mm" wi="119.04mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641481-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="251.71mm" wi="165.69mm" file="US07641481-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure generally relates to validation and debug-operations in Integrated Circuit (IC) packages, and more particularly, to an interposer disposed between an IC package and a socket body for accessing selective IC package signals.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The advantages and features of the present disclosure will become better understood with reference to the following detailed description and claims taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein like elements are identified with like symbols, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an arrangement of a stacked-socket interposer assembly disposed between a first land grid array socket body and an Integrated Circuit (IC) package;</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded isometric view depicting an arrangement of an interposer disposed between a socket body and an Integrated Circuit (IC) package, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an isometric view depicting the interposer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disposed on the socket body, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure;</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an arrangement of the IC package on the socket body with the interposer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disposed in between the IC package and the socket body, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure; and</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> illustrate a loading mechanism mounted over an IC package and an actuation of socket load on the IC package respectively, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the description of several views of the drawings.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">For a thorough understanding of the present disclosure, reference is to be made to the following detailed description, including the appended claims, in connection with the above-described drawings. Although the present disclosure is described in connection with exemplary embodiments, the present disclosure is not intended to be limited to the specific forms set forth herein. It is understood that various omissions and substitutions of equivalents are contemplated as circumstances may suggest or render expedient, but these are intended to cover the application or implementation without departing from the spirit or scope of the claims of the present disclosure. Also, it is to be understood that the phraseology and terminology used herein is for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting. The terms &#x201c;first,&#x201d; &#x201c;second,&#x201d; and the like, herein do not denote any order, quantity, or importance, but rather are used to distinguish one element from another, and the terms &#x201c;a&#x201d; and &#x201c;an&#x201d; herein do not denote a limitation of quantity, but rather denote the presence of at least one of the referenced item.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The present disclosure provides an interposer for accessing one or more signals from an Integrated Circuit (IC) package. The interposer is disposed between the IC package and a socket body. The interposer comprises a plurality of clearance holes and at least one connecting element. The plurality of clearance holes allows an array of contacts on a first surface of the socket body to pass through the interposer and make electrical contact with a first set of contacts of a plurality of contacts of the IC package. The at least one connecting element is configured to make electrical contact with a second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package. The electrical contact between the at least one connecting element and the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package provides access to the one or more signals from the IC package. Further, the interposer is designed to be non-intrusive and has minimal impact on the typical operations of the IC package.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an arrangement of a stacked-socket interposer assembly <b>100</b> disposed between a first land grid array socket body <b>102</b> and an Integrated Circuit package <b>104</b>. The first land grid array socket body <b>102</b> is surface mounted on a motherboard <b>106</b> using typical surface mounting techniques. For example, a matrix of soldered balls such as soldered ball <b>106</b><i>a </i>may be used to surface mount the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b> on the motherboard <b>106</b>. The stacked-socket interposer assembly <b>100</b> includes a second land grid array socket body <b>108</b>, a spacer <b>110</b> and a probe base board <b>112</b>. The IC package <b>104</b> has a top surface <b>114</b> and a bottom surface <b>116</b>. The top surface <b>114</b> faces away from the motherboard <b>106</b> and the bottom surface <b>116</b> faces towards the motherboard <b>106</b>. The bottom surface <b>116</b> includes a plurality of contacts such as a first set of contacts and a second set of contacts (not shown).</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The first set of contacts and the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts together serve as access points for accessing a plurality of signals associated with processes performed by the IC package <b>104</b>. For example, the plurality of signals may correspond to program execution, software error testing and such other processes of IC package <b>104</b>. The plurality of signals are accessed when the plurality of contacts make electrical contact with contacts (not shown) provided on the second land grid array socket body <b>108</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The second land grid array socket body <b>108</b> is mounted on the probe base board <b>112</b> in a manner similar to the mounting of the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b> on the motherboard <b>106</b> (using a matrix of soldered balls such as a soldered ball <b>106</b><i>a</i>). The probe base board <b>112</b> includes electrical elements which serve to perform functions such as power delivery, signal termination, power supply bypassing and the like. The probe base board <b>112</b> may allow one or more signals of the plurality of signals accessed by the second land grid array socket body <b>108</b> to be interrupted (hereinafter referred to as interrupted signals). The interrupted signals may be routed over etched traces provided on the probe base board <b>112</b> to connectors (not shown) which may further be connected to validation equipment such as In-Target Probe (ITP) hardware (not shown) and the like.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">The probe base board <b>112</b> may also allow non-interrupted signals (hereinafter referred to as passed-through signals) to pass through the probe base board <b>112</b> into the spacer <b>110</b>. The spacer <b>110</b> serves to provide the necessary separation for mounting the probe base board <b>112</b> onto the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b>. The spacer <b>110</b> further allows the passed-through signals to pass through the spacer <b>110</b> to the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b>. The passed-through signals are then passed on to the motherboard <b>106</b> by the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b> for routing to elements (not shown) such as memory modules and the like, mounted on the motherboard <b>106</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Though the stacked-socket interposer assembly <b>100</b> provides access to the plurality of signals from the IC package <b>104</b>, mechanical modifications may be required to be made to a retention mechanism (not shown) of the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b>. The retention mechanism of the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b> is typically designed to accommodate only the IC package <b>104</b>. The introduction of the stacked-socket interposer assembly <b>100</b> results in significant addition to thickness and as such mechanical modifications may be required to be made to the retention mechanism of the first land grid array socket body <b>102</b>. Further, it will be evident to those skilled in the art that the introduction of the stacked-socket interposer assembly <b>100</b> results in significant signaling challenges and limitations, especially for high speed signals such as single-ended Double Data Rate (DDR), Front Side Bus (FSB), and even differential buses such as Peripheral Component Interconnect Express (PCIE), which can render these types of signals inoperable when the stacked socket interposer is installed into the system via the LGA socket.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded isometric view depicting an arrangement of an interposer <b>300</b> disposed between a socket body <b>200</b> and an Integrated Circuit (IC) package <b>400</b>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. The socket body <b>200</b> includes an array of contacts (not shown) on a first surface <b>202</b>. The array of contacts are configured to make electrical contact with a plurality of contact pads (not shown) on the IC package <b>400</b>. The IC package <b>400</b> includes a top surface <b>402</b> and a bottom surface (not shown). The bottom surface of the IC package <b>400</b> is configured with the plurality of pads or lands and may be placed on the array of contacts provided on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The socket body <b>200</b> includes two side walls <b>204</b> opposite and spaced apart and two end walls <b>206</b> connecting the two side walls <b>204</b> in a manner such that the first surface <b>202</b>, the two side walls <b>204</b> and the two end walls <b>206</b> configure a receiving space therebetween. Such an arrangement of the socket body <b>200</b>, for example, configures a rectangular structure capable of accommodating the Integrated Circuit (IC) package <b>400</b> therein. The socket body <b>200</b> may be surface mounted on a printed circuit board (not shown) with the first surface <b>202</b> facing away from the printed circuit board (PCB).</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The first surface <b>202</b> includes an array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> configured to make electrical contact with the plurality of contacting pads on the IC package <b>400</b>. The array of contacts may be of any suitable material such as gold-plated copper and the like. The array of contacts may be arranged in a fashion facilitating electrical connectivity with the contact pads of the IC Package <b>400</b>. For example, the array of contacts may be arranged in a grid array fashion. Further, each of the two end walls <b>206</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> defines a groove <b>208</b> (hereinafter referred together as grooves <b>208</b>). Once the IC package <b>400</b> is accommodated into the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b>, the grooves <b>208</b> provide space for grabbing the IC package <b>400</b> using human fingers for removing the IC package <b>400</b> from the socket body <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">It will be evident to those skilled in the art that peripheral edges of the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b> may include engagement features such as a cylindrical protrusion <b>210</b> for coupling the IC package <b>400</b> to the socket body <b>200</b>. The IC package <b>400</b> may have complimentary engagement features on peripheral edges, such as cut-out portions <b>404</b>, to couple the IC package <b>400</b> with the socket body <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The interposer <b>300</b> disposed between the socket body <b>200</b> and the IC package <b>400</b> may be in the form of a flexible circuit board. The interposer <b>300</b> (hereinafter referred to as flexible circuit board <b>300</b>) includes a main portion <b>302</b> and two extending portions <b>304</b> extending away from the main portion <b>302</b>. The main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> may be dimensioned to fit in the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b> and as such the peripheral edges of the main portion <b>302</b> may configure a rectangular structure. The main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> is disposed between the socket body <b>200</b> and the IC package <b>400</b>. The two extending portions <b>304</b> extend away from peripheral edges of the main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>. The width of each of the two extending portions <b>304</b> may be designed to fit the width of the grooves <b>208</b>, and as such the two extending portions <b>304</b> extend out of the socket body <b>200</b> through the grooves <b>208</b> provided in the two end walls <b>206</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>. The main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> includes a plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> and at least one connecting element such as connecting element <b>308</b> disposed between the plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b>. Further, the main portion <b>302</b> includes a central cavity <b>310</b> which aligns with central cavity <b>212</b> defined in the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b>. The plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> are disposed around the central cavity <b>310</b> of the main portion <b>302</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> are designed in shapes that allow the array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> to pass through the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> and make electrical contact with the first set of contacts (not shown) of the plurality of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b>. Program instructions for execution of the operations of the IC package <b>400</b> may be communicated through the electrical contact between the first set of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b> and the array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>. A second set of contacts (not shown) of the plurality of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b> may be electrically shunted from contacting the array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> by the at least one connecting element such as the connecting element <b>308</b> disposed between the second set of contacts of the IC package and the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b>. Further, the at least one connecting element is configured with requisite conducting surface (explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>) to make electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">The first set of contacts and the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b> correspond to program signals of the IC package <b>400</b>. The plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> are designed to mechanically and electrically correspond to specific signals of the IC package <b>400</b>, such as those signals (hereinafter referred to as passed-through signals) which correspond to normal operations of the IC package <b>400</b>. The plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> allow the array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> to make the typical connection with the first set of contacting pads of the IC package to access the passed-through signals.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b> may correspond to one or more signals (hereinafter referred to as interrupted signals) of the plurality of signals. The second set of contacts makes electrical contact with the at least one connecting element thereby providing access to the interrupted signals, such as the debug signals. The interrupted signals are routed from the at least one connecting element to the peripheral edges of the main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> using etched traces on the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>. The interrupted signals may then be routed out of the socket body <b>200</b> using the two extending portions <b>304</b> which extend out through the grooves <b>208</b> provided in the two end walls <b>206</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>. It will be evident to those skilled in the art that the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> may extend out of other relieved sections provided in peripheral walls of the socket body <b>200</b>. The two extending portions <b>304</b> include debug interfaces <b>312</b> at respective ends of the two extending portions <b>304</b>. The debug interfaces <b>312</b> may be interfaced with hardware (not shown) used for debug operations. An example of the debug interfaces <b>312</b> may be an In-Target Probe (ITP) debug connector.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">An example of the IC package <b>400</b> may include a Central Processing Unit (CPU) processor. An example of the socket body <b>200</b> may include but is not limited to a Land Grid Array (LGA) socket body. The arrangement of the interposer <b>300</b> disposed on the socket body <b>200</b> will be explained in further detail in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is an isometric view depicting the interposer <b>300</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disposed on the socket body <b>200</b>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. As explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, peripheral edges of the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b> may include engagement features for coupling the IC package <b>400</b> to the socket body <b>200</b>. The interposer <b>300</b> (flexible circuit board <b>300</b>) has complimentary engagement features at the peripheral edges of the main portion <b>302</b>, similar to those on peripheral edges of the IC package <b>400</b>, enabling the main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> to align and fit snugly in the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> may be typically cantilever-shaped metal springs and may require a working/deflection range of typically 15 mils. The flexible circuit board <b>300</b> may be designed to have minimal thickness to be non-intrusive and produce little effect on the relatively large working deflection of the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b>, when the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> is disposed between the IC package <b>400</b> and the socket body <b>200</b>. The minimal thickness of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> ensures that the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> is non-intrusive and that the electrical connection between the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b> (passing through the plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b>) and the first set of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b> is unaffected. In accordance with one embodiment of the present disclosure, the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> may be designed with two copper layers to have a total thickness of 2-3 mils. Copper layers may further be added to increment the thickness of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> by 1-1.5 mils.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Further, as explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the at least one connecting element of the interposer <b>300</b> makes electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b>, thereby electrically shunting the second set of contacts from contacting the array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>. The contacts of the array of contacts below the at least one connecting element may over-deflect thereby causing damage to those contacts of the array of contacts. The at least one connecting element such as the connecting element <b>308</b> on the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> may further be designed to have thickness less than rest of flexible board <b>300</b>. For instance, techniques such as partial laser ablation, polymer etching, or voiding solder mask behind the at least one connecting element may be used to selectively thin down the at least one connecting element.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">In accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure, the at least one connecting element includes a flexible portion capable of being raised to make electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b>. In accordance with another embodiment of the present disclosure, the flexible portion of each of the at least one connecting element such as connecting element <b>308</b> may be in the form of a cantilever structure <b>314</b> hinged at one end of a cut-out <b>316</b> and extending into the cut-out <b>316</b> on the main portion <b>302</b> of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>. The cut-out <b>316</b> may be designed as a through-hole in the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>. The cantilever structure <b>314</b> may resemble a protrusion (of the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>) extending from one peripheral edge of the cut-out <b>316</b> into the through-hole and terminating at a pre-determined distance from the opposite peripheral edge of the cut-out <b>316</b>. The flexible portion of the at least one connecting element is suitably designed in the form of the cantilever structure <b>314</b> to ensure compliance when the at least one connecting element makes electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b>. Further, the cantilever structure <b>314</b> has an exposed conducting surface <b>318</b> on a top surface contacting the second set of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b> to facilitate electrical connection. The hinging of the cantilever structure <b>314</b> at one end further adds flexibility to the at least one connecting element. When the flexible circuit board <b>300</b> is disposed on the socket body <b>200</b>, the large deflection of the array of contacts on the first surface <b>202</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> raises the hinged cantilever structure <b>314</b>, thereby facilitating the electrical connection of the exposed conducting surface <b>318</b> with the second set of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Further, as explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, connecting elements such as the connecting element <b>308</b> of the at least one connecting element are disposed at pre-determined locations between the plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> on the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>. The pre-determined locations may correspond to locations for making electrical contact with second set of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b>. Manufacturing techniques such as laser ablation and plasma etching, typically used for flexible circuit boards and organic substrates, may be used to selectively form the at least one connecting element on the flexible circuit board <b>300</b>. During socket actuation, considerable force is exerted by the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b> on the at least one connecting element. The flexible portion, such as the cantilever structure <b>314</b>, of the at least one connecting element may be designed to deflect the exposed conducting surface <b>318</b> of the at least one connecting element towards the corresponding second set of contacts of the plurality of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b>. The arrangement of the IC package <b>400</b> on the socket body <b>200</b> is illustrated in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an arrangement of the IC package <b>400</b> on the socket body <b>200</b> with the interposer <b>300</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> disposed in between the IC package <b>400</b> and the socket body <b>200</b>, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. As explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b> is configured to receive the IC package <b>400</b>. The peripheral edges of the receiving space has engagement features which engage with complimentary engagement features provided on peripheral edges of the IC package <b>400</b> to couple the IC package <b>400</b> to the socket body <b>200</b>. The interposer <b>300</b> is disposed in between the IC package <b>400</b> and the socket body <b>200</b>, with the main portion <b>302</b> being accommodated in the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b>. The two extending portions <b>304</b> of the interposer <b>300</b> extend out of the socket body <b>200</b> through the grooves <b>208</b> provided in the two end walls <b>206</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">When the socket actuation forces are applied by means of a loading mechanism (depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>), the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b> pass through the plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> provided on the main portion <b>302</b> of the interposer <b>300</b> to make electrical contact with the first set of contacts of the plurality of contacting pads of the IC package <b>400</b>. The contacts of the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b> below the at least one connecting element of the interposer <b>300</b> exert an upward force on the at least one connecting element, raising the flexible portion, such as the cantilever structure <b>314</b>, of the at least one connecting element. The raising of the flexible portion of the at least one connecting element, brings the exposed conducting surface <b>318</b> on the top surface of the flexible portion to make electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b>. The electrical connections are magnified and depicted (inset) in a simplified cross-sectional view of the arrangement of the IC package <b>400</b> mounted on the socket body <b>200</b> with the interposer <b>300</b> disposed there between.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The cross sectional view of the arrangement illustrates cross sections of the IC package <b>400</b>, the interposer <b>300</b> and the socket body <b>200</b>. As illustrated, the interposer <b>300</b> is disposed between the IC package <b>400</b> and the socket body <b>200</b>. Array of contacts <b>214</b> of the socket body <b>200</b> passing through the plurality of clearance holes <b>306</b> make electrical contact with the first set of contacts <b>406</b> of the plurality of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b>. The contacts of the array of contacts <b>214</b> blocked by the at least one connecting element such as the connecting element <b>308</b> of the at least one connecting element raises the flexible portion of the connecting element <b>308</b> to make electrical contact with second set of contacts <b>408</b> of the plurality of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b>. As explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the electrical contact between the at least one connecting element of the interposer <b>300</b> and the second set of contacts <b>408</b> of the IC package <b>400</b> provides access to one or more signals from the IC package <b>400</b>. The one or more signals may be routed to the peripheral edges of the main portion <b>302</b> of the interposer <b>300</b> using etched traces and may then be routed out of the socket body <b>200</b> using the two extending portions <b>304</b> to connectors such as debug connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> illustrate a loading mechanism mounted over an IC package <b>400</b> and an actuation of socket load on the IC package <b>400</b> respectively, in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, the IC package <b>400</b> is accommodated into the receiving space of the socket body <b>200</b> with the interposer <b>300</b> disposed in between the IC package <b>400</b> and the socket body <b>200</b>, as explained in conjunction with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. A socket body frame <b>500</b> coupled with a loading mechanism (not shown) is mounted on the IC package <b>400</b> enclosing the socket body <b>200</b>. The loading mechanism includes a loading plate <b>602</b> and a lever <b>604</b>. The loading plate <b>602</b> is hinged at one end of the socket body frame <b>500</b> using nuts such as nut <b>502</b>. The loading plate <b>602</b> may rotate about the hinge to assume one of an open and a closed position using the lever <b>604</b>. A driving shaft <b>606</b> of the lever <b>604</b> may be rotated to lift a raised portion <b>608</b> of a closing shaft <b>610</b> of the lever <b>604</b>. The lifting of the raised portion <b>608</b> of the closing shaft <b>610</b> releases a trapped extended portion <b>612</b> of the loading plate <b>602</b>. The loading plate <b>602</b> may then be raised to assume an open position. The loading plate is depicted in open position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The loading plate <b>602</b> is depicted in closed position in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>. In the closed position, two protruding portions <b>614</b> supported on arms of the loading plate <b>602</b> exert a socket actuation force on the IC package <b>400</b>. When the loading plate <b>602</b> assumes an open position (depicted in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>), the socket actuation force on the IC package <b>400</b> is released. The IC package <b>400</b> may then be removed using clearance provided by the grooves <b>208</b> in the two end walls <b>206</b> of the socket body <b>200</b>. The loading plate <b>602</b> assumes a closed position to exert a socket actuation force on the IC package <b>400</b> to facilitate proper electrical contact between the first set of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b> and the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b>. The socket actuation force applied by the loading plate <b>602</b> further results in the array of contacts of the socket body <b>200</b> exerting a force on the at least one connecting element of the interposer <b>300</b> to raise the flexible portion of the at least one connecting element. The raised flexible portion of the at least one connecting element makes electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the IC package <b>400</b> to provide access to one or more signals from the IC package <b>400</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The interposer, such as the interposer <b>300</b>, disposed between an IC package and a socket body may provide access to specific desired signals from the IC package, such as debug signals. Moreover, the interposer is designed to be non-intrusive and has minimal signaling impact on the typical operations of the IC package. Further, the interposer in the form of a flexible circuit board may bend under or around any supporting mechanical structure around the socket body without affecting its functionality.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The foregoing descriptions of specific embodiments of the present disclosure have been presented for purposes of illustration and description. They are not intended to be exhaustive or to limit the present disclosure to the precise forms disclosed, and obviously many modifications and variations are possible in light of the above teaching. The embodiments were chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the present disclosure and its practical application, to thereby enable others skilled in the art to best utilize the disclosure and various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated. It is understood that various omission and substitutions of equivalents are contemplated as circumstance may suggest or render expedient, but such are intended to cover the application or implementation without departing from the spirit or scope of the claims of the present disclosure.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An interposer for accessing one or more signals of a plurality of signals from an Integrated Circuit (IC) package, the interposer disposed between the IC package and a socket body, the socket body configured to receive the IC package, the interposer comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of clearance holes for allowing an array of contacts on a first surface of the socket body to pass through the interposer to make electrical contact with a first set of contacts of a plurality of contacts of the IC package; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one connecting element disposed between the plurality of clearance holes, the at least one connecting element configured to make electrical contact with a second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the electrical contact between the at least one connecting element and the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package provides access to the one or more signals of the plurality of signals from the IC package.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the interposer is a flexible circuit board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one connecting element comprises a flexible portion capable of being raised to make electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more signals of the plurality of signals of the IC package are signals for debugging the IC package.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the interposer further comprises extending portions extending out of the socket body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref>, wherein the extending portion routes the one or more signals accessed by the at least one connecting element out of the socket body to a debugging connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, wherein the debugging connector is an In-Target Probe (ITP) connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The interposer of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the socket body is a Land Grid Array (LGA) socket body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A method for accessing one or more signals of a plurality of signals from an Integrated Circuit (IC) package, said method comprising:
<claim-text>forming an interposer by:
<claim-text>forming a plurality of clearance holes for allowing an array of contacts on a first surface of a socket body to pass through the interposer to make electrical contact with a first set of contacts of a plurality of contacts of the IC package; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing at least one connecting element between the plurality of clearance holes, the at least one connecting element configured to make electrical contact with a second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing access to the one or more signals of the plurality of signals from the IC package by forming electrical contact between the at least one connecting element and the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>disposing the interposer between the IC package and a socket body, the socket body configured to receive the IC package.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the interposer is a flexible circuit board.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the at least one connecting element comprises a flexible portion capable of being raised to make electrical contact with the second set of contacts of the plurality of contacts of the IC package.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the one or more signals of the plurality of signals of the IC package are signals for debugging the IC package.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the interposer further comprises extending portions extending out of the socket body.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the extending portion routes the one or more signals accessed by the at least one connecting element out of the socket body to a debugging connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the debugging connector is an In-Target Probe (ITP) connector.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the socket body is a Land Grid Array (LGA) socket body. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
