<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07642102-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07642102</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11668572</doc-number>
<date>20070130</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>235</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>L</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>66</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>438 14</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Real-time parameter tuning using wafer thickness</invention-title>
<number-of-claims>39</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>None</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>6</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>6</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080183412</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080731</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Funk</last-name>
<first-name>Merritt</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Deshpande</last-name>
<first-name>Sachin</first-name>
<address>
<city>San Jose</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lally</last-name>
<first-name>Kevin</first-name>
<address>
<city>Austin</city>
<state>TX</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Oblon, Spivak, McClelland, Maier &#x26; Neustadt, L.L.P.</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tokyo Electron Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Garber</last-name>
<first-name>Charles D.</first-name>
<department>2812</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Stevenson</last-name>
<first-name>Andre&#x2032;  C</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The invention can provide a method of processing a wafer using a Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure to receive an input message that can include a pass-through message, a real-time feedforward message, or a real-time optimization message, or any combination thereof. The RTPT procedures can use real-time wafer thickness data to create, modify, and/or use measurement recipe data, measurement profile data, and/or measurement model data. In addition, RTPT procedures can use real-time wafer thickness data to create, modify, and/or use process recipe data, process profile data, and/or process model data.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="228.26mm" wi="154.18mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="207.01mm" wi="145.46mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="188.72mm" wi="151.89mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="163.15mm" wi="138.68mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="209.30mm" wi="154.94mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="227.84mm" wi="173.23mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="230.63mm" wi="158.33mm" file="US07642102-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is related to co-pending Ser. No. 11/668,537 entitled &#x201c;Real-Time Parameter Tuning For Etch Processes&#x201d;; Ser. No. 11/668,553, entitled &#x201c;Real-Time Parameter Tuning Using Wafer Temperature&#x201d;; Ser. No. 11/668,654, entitled &#x201c;Method for Using a Wafer Temperature Dependent Profile Library&#x201d;; and Ser. No. 11/668,690, entitled &#x201c;Method for Using a Wafer Thickness Dependent Profile Library&#x201d;, each filed on even date herewith. The contents of each of these applications are herein incorporated by reference in their entireties.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to process modeling, and more particularly to improving the modeling accuracy using real-time parameter tuning.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One example of optical metrology involves directing an incident beam at a structure, measuring the resulting diffracted beam, and analyzing the diffracted beam to determine various characteristics, such as the profile of the structure. In semiconductor manufacturing, optical metrology of periodic gratings is typically used for quality assurance.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For example, a periodic grating may be formed near an operating structure of a semiconductor chip. The periodic grating is then illuminated with an electromagnetic radiation, and the electromagnetic radiation that deflects off the periodic grating can be collected as a diffraction signal. The diffraction signal can then be analyzed to determine whether the periodic grating, and by extension whether the operating structure of the semiconductor chip, has been fabricated according to specifications.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In one conventional system, the diffraction signal collected from illuminating the periodic grating (the measured-diffraction signal) is compared to a library of simulated-diffraction signals. Each simulated-diffraction signal in the library is associated with a hypothetical profile. When a match is made between the measured-diffraction signal and one of the simulated-diffraction signals in the library, the hypothetical profile associated with the simulated-diffraction signal is presumed to represent the actual profile of the periodic grating, thus providing information about the operating structure which can be used for further processing, control etc.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Material variations can occur across a wafer, from wafer to wafer and from lot to lot. This variation, for example, can be due to CVD or spin on films not being uniform across the wafer, chamber to chamber variations and chamber drift in processing over time. Further, film properties can change across a wafer and/or wafer to wafer during a process, such as the etch process, due to the nature of using end pointing and sacrificial films to control a bottom CD. Etching of a film, for example, can change the optical properties and physical properties of a film. Such changes in material properties, film properties or other properties that occur during processing of the wafer can also cause variation in optical properties of the material, film, etc. Thus, optical metrology of a semiconductor wafer (by using a grating, for example) can produce measurement results that vary in accordance with the variations in the optical properties, rather than on the parameter intended to be measured.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">One object of the invention is to address the above and/or other problems with optical metrology methods.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Another object of the invention is to provide a mechanism for considering prior process effects on optical metrology measurements in order to provide accurate measurement data.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The invention can provide a method of processing a wafer in real-time using Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedures. In addition, a Real-Time Optimizer (RTO) can be used to perform RTPT procedures using real-time RTPT parameters from one or more Transparent Coupling Devices (TCDs).</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The method of processing a wafer can include receiving the wafer and wafer data and the wafer data includes historical and/or real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data. The wafer can be received by a measurement subsystem. A wafer state is established for the wafer. An RTO can receive one or more input messages that can include pass-through messages, or real-time feedforward messages, or any combination thereof. The pass-through message can include historical wafer data and the real-time feedforward message can include real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data. One or more TCDs can create real-time feedforward data using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message. The real-time feedforward data is created when input message includes a real-time feedforward message, and is not created when the input message include a real-time feedforward message. The real-time feedforward data can includes real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data. The RTO can feed forward the real-time feedforward data to a controller in the measurement subsystem when the feedforward state is a first value, and does not feed forward the real-time feedforward data when the feedforward state is a second value. The feedforward state is the first value when the real-time feedforward data can be fed forward before a measurement process is performed for the wafer, and the feedforward state is the second value when the real-time feedforward data cannot be fed forward before the measurement process is performed for the wafer. Then either a tuned measurement recipe, a tuned measurement profile, or a tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof can be created using a RTPT procedure that uses the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data as tuning data when a RTPT state is a first value; or the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof is not created when the RTPT state is a second value. In addition, the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof can be created when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message, and the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof cannot be created when the input message does not include a real-time feedforward message.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The method can further include measuring the wafer in the measurement subsystem using the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the first value; identifying the measured wafer as a tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and storing measured data associated with the tuned wafer as tuned measurement data. A RTO can be used to receive an input message that can include a pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Another aspect of the invention includes a method of performing optical measurements on a wafer, including processing an input signal to obtain non-tuning data including a measurement recipe for use in the optical measurement system, and performing an optical measurement based on the measurement recipe at optical measurement hardware of the measurement system to obtain an optical diffraction signal from a measurement site on the wafer. Also included is obtaining tuning data an optical analysis system of the measurement system, and calculating a measurement result based on the optical diffraction signal and the tuning data.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Other aspects of the invention will be made apparent from the description that follows and from the drawings appended hereto.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Embodiments of the invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the accompanying schematic drawings in which corresponding reference symbols indicate corresponding parts, and in which:</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an exemplary block diagram of a processing system in accordance with embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary block diagram of an optimized system in accordance with embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a schematic representation of a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD) in accordance with embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary flow diagram of a procedure for processing a wafer in accordance with embodiments of the invention;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an exemplary flow diagram of a procedure for using a thickness-dependent profile library that was created using real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data; and</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart showing a method for determining a tuned ODP measurement result based on tuning data in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The invention provides a system and methods for using real-time parameter tuning during wafer processing. One or more Transparent Coupling Devices (TCDs) can be used to feed forward messages and/or data in real-time to update models and/or recipes. TCDs can be installed and integrated into a factory system, a processing subsystem, and/or a measurement subsystem without large changes in factory automation and/or tool software.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows an exemplary block diagram of a processing system in accordance with embodiments of the invention. In the illustrated embodiment, wafer-processing system <b>100</b> comprises a lithography subsystem <b>110</b>, an etching subsystem <b>120</b>, a deposition subsystem <b>130</b>, and a measurement subsystem <b>140</b>. The lithography subsystem <b>110</b>, etching subsystem <b>120</b>, deposition subsystem <b>130</b>, and measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can be coupled to each other using transfer system <b>160</b>. For example, transfer system <b>160</b> can be used to receive wafers, transfer wafers, align wafers, store wafers exchange process-related information, and exchange wafer-related information.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">A manufacturing execution system (MES) <b>180</b> can be coupled <b>182</b> to the transfer system <b>160</b> and can be coupled <b>181</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>. As used herein, the term &#x201c;coupled&#x201d; followed by a reference designator can indicate a physical or non-physical coupling of two systems to achieve data transfer and/or physical transfer of an object such as a wafer. Alternatively a factory level and/or host system may be used and other coupling techniques may be used. In alternate embodiments, one or more additional subsystems may be required. For example, wafer-processing system <b>100</b> may be coupled <b>161</b> to another processing system.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">The wafer-processing system <b>100</b> can include a system controller <b>105</b> and storage devices <b>107</b>. Alternatively, the system controller <b>105</b> and/or storage devices <b>107</b> may not be required. System controller <b>105</b> can be coupled <b>102</b> to the transfer system <b>160</b> and can be coupled <b>106</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>. Alternatively other configurations may be used and other coupling techniques may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The lithography subsystem <b>110</b> can include a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD) <b>118</b> that can be coupled <b>119</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>, the etching subsystem <b>120</b> can include a TCD <b>128</b> that can be coupled <b>129</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>, the deposition subsystem <b>130</b> can include a TCD <b>138</b> that can be coupled <b>139</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>, and the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can include TCD <b>148</b> that can be coupled <b>149</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>. Alternatively, one or more of the TCDs <b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, and <b>148</b> may not be required. Single TCDs are shown for each subsystem, but this is not required for the invention. In other embodiments, any number of TCDs can be used in a subsystem. The TCDs can be coupled in series and/or in parallel and can have one or more input ports and/or one or more output ports. TCDs can be coupled to each other and to other devices using a network such as an intranet, internet, and/or wireless connections. TCDs can be connected to one or more input devices and/or output devices in a subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">The lithography subsystem <b>110</b> can include a controller <b>115</b> that can include a Real-Time Optimizer (RTO) <b>117</b>, the etching subsystem <b>120</b> can include a controller <b>125</b> that can include a RTO <b>127</b>, the deposition subsystem <b>130</b> can include a controller <b>135</b> that can include a RTO <b>137</b>, and the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can include a controller <b>145</b> that can include a RTO <b>127</b>. The controllers (<b>105</b>,<b>115</b>, <b>125</b>,<b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>) can be coupled to each other as required. For example, controller <b>115</b> can be coupled <b>116</b> to a data transfer system <b>190</b>, controller <b>125</b> can be coupled <b>126</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>, controller <b>135</b> can be coupled <b>136</b> to the data transfer system <b>190</b>, and controller <b>145</b> can be coupled <b>146</b> to a data transfer system <b>190</b>. Alternatively, other coupling configurations may be used. In addition, a scanner <b>150</b> can be coupled to the lithography subsystem <b>110</b>, or alternatively, the lithography subsystem <b>110</b> may include a scanning system.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">One or more of the RTOs (<b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, and <b>147</b>) and/or one or more of the TCDs (<b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, and <b>148</b>) can be used when performing Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedures. A RTO can receive real-time data, such as real-time RTPT parameters from one or more TCDs to tune and/or optimize a recipe, profile, and/or model. In some embodiments, a tuning procedure can be performed in which fine adjustments are made to the optical measurement based on feedforward data, and an optimization procedure can then be performed in which the &#x201c;tuned&#x201d; data is then used to calculate an optimized recipe for processing or updating a process model. One or more of the RTOs (<b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, and <b>147</b>) can perform real-time RTPT procedures using real-time tuning data and provide real-time tuned data as described herein. In some embodiments, one or more RTOs can be used to intercept one or more SECS (semiconductor equipment communication standard) messages from a MES <b>180</b>, read and/or remove tuning information, feed forward the tuning information, and pass-through the remaining information as an SECS message. One or more of the RTOs (<b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, and <b>147</b>) can perform real-time optimization procedures using real-time optimization data and provide real-time optimized data as described herein. For example, a TCD can be used to process the messages. In addition, one or more RTOs can be used to intercept one or more SECS messages from another subsystem, read and/or remove optimization information, feed forward the optimization information, and pass-through the remaining information as an SECS message. For example, a message can be passed-through to a MES <b>180</b> or another subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In addition, one or more of the controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>) can be used to perform RTPT procedures. The controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>,<b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>) can include procedures and/or memory (not shown) as required. For example, a memory (not shown) can be used for storing information and instructions to be executed by the controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>), and may be used for storing temporary variables or other intermediate information during the execution of instructions by the various computers/processors in the wafer-processing system <b>100</b>. One or more controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>), or other system components can comprise the means for reading data and/or instructions from a computer readable medium and can comprise the means for writing data and/or instructions to a computer readable medium.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The wafer-processing system <b>100</b> can perform a portion of or all of the processing steps of the invention in response to the computers/processors in the wafer-processing system executing one or more sequences of one or more instructions contained in a memory. Such instructions may be received from another computer, a computer readable medium, or a network connection.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Stored on any one or on any combination of computer readable media, the present invention includes software for controlling the wafer-processing system, for driving a device or devices for implementing the invention, and for enabling the wafer-processing system <b>100</b> to interact with a human user. Such software may include, but is not limited to, device drivers, operating systems, development tools, and applications software. Such computer readable media further includes the computer program product of the present invention for performing all or a portion (if processing is distributed) of the processing performed in implementing the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The term &#x201c;computer readable medium&#x201d; as used herein refers to any medium that participates in providing instructions to a processor of the system <b>100</b> for execution. A computer readable medium may take many forms, including but not limited to, non-volatile media, volatile media, and transmission media.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In some embodiments, an integrated system can be configured using system components manufactured by Tokyo Electron Limited (TEL). For example, an integrated metrology module (IMM) from TEL may be used. In other embodiments, different subsystems and/or tools may be included.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The processing tools can include one or more etch tools, deposition tools, ALD tools, measurement tools, ionizations tools, polishing tools, coating tools, developing tools, cleaning tools, exposure tools, and thermal treatment tools. In addition, the metrology tools can include a CD-Scanning Electron Microscopy (CDSEM) tool, a Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) tool, a focused ion beam (FIB) tool, an ODP tool, an Atomic Force Microscope (AFM) tool, or other optical metrology tools. The processing tools and/or metrology tools can have different interface requirements. TCDs can be configured to satisfy these different interface requirements and can be used to &#x201c;transparently&#x201d; couple a number of different processing tools and/or metrology tools to an existing processing system. As will be discussed below, &#x201c;collected data&#x201d; can include historical and real-time wafer data and/or process data. For example, real-time wafer thickness data and/or real time wafer temperature data can be extracted from the collected data.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">One or more of the subsystems of the wafer-processing system <b>100</b> can comprise a control component, a GUI component, and/or a database component (not shown). For example, GUI components (not shown) can provide easy to use interfaces that enable users to: view status; create/view/edit TCDs, RTOs, RTPT procedures, strategies, plans, errors, faults, databases, rules, recipes, modeling applications, simulation/spreadsheet applications, email messages, and diagnostics screens. As should be apparent to those skilled in the art, the GUI components need not provide interfaces for all functions, and may provide interfaces for any subset of these functions or others not listed here.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">TCDs <b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, and <b>148</b> can be coupled to data transfer system <b>190</b> for exchanging information with the MES <b>180</b> and other subsystems. The data transfer system <b>190</b> can comprise hardwire and/or wireless components.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The system controller <b>105</b> can include Advanced Process Control (APC) applications, Fault Detection and Classification (FDC), and/or Run-to-Run (R2R) applications, and can be coupled to subsystem <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, and/or <b>140</b> using a bidirectional link <b>102</b> to the transfer system <b>160</b>. Alternatively, the system controller may be coupled differently. In alternate embodiments, one or more TCDs (not shown) may be included in a system controller <b>105</b> and may exchange information with the MES and/or subsystems.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">In some embodiments, a TCD, such as <b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, or <b>148</b>, can extract a recipe, profile, and/or a model tuning parameter message from a host message and can route the tuning parameter message to a controller, such as controller <b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, or <b>145</b>. Other messages from the host message can be passed through to a subsystem associated with the message without any changes. In many cases, the TCD can be installed and operated with little or no changes required to the subsystem and/or tool software.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In other embodiments, a TCD, such as TCD <b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, or <b>148</b>, can extract a recipe, profile, and/or a model tuning parameter message from a host message and can route the tuning parameter message to a RTO, such as RTO <b>107</b>, <b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, or <b>147</b>. Other messages from the host message can be passed through to a subsystem associated with the message without any changes. In still other embodiments, a TCD, such as <b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, or <b>148</b>, can extract a recipe, profile, and/or a model tuning parameter message from an internal message and can route the tuning parameter message internally within a subsystem and/or externally.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">One or more of the RTOs (<b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, and <b>147</b>) and/or one or more of the controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>) can comprise process tuning and/or optimization procedures, model tuning and/or optimization procedures, or profile tuning and/or optimization procedures, or any combination thereof. For example, process (recipe) tuning and/or optimization procedures can include update procedures that can be performed just before a process (recipe) is executed. Process (recipe) tuning and/or optimization procedures can get update data that can be used to update a process recipe just before a process (recipe) is executed. Process (recipe) tuning and/or optimization procedures determine when a wafer gets processed by an updated recipe and when there is not enough time to change the recipe before processing the current wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">By using real-time tuning and/or optimization data, processes recipes, profiles, and/or models can be updated in real-time, can be performed with more precision, and more accurate process results can be achieved. In smaller geometry technologies below the 65 nm node, more accurate results are required. The real-time update data can include recipe/profile/model tuning parameters, and the optimization/update data can be fed forward in real-time by a TCD in a RTO, for example.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Material and/or process variations that can affect process recipes, profiles, models, and/or process results can change within a wafer, from wafer-to-wafer, and from lot-to-lot. These variations can be caused by changes and/or problems in the lithography subsystem <b>110</b>, the etching subsystem <b>120</b>, the deposition subsystem <b>130</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>140</b>, and/or the transfer system <b>160</b>. Non-uniform films and/or non-uniform processes can cause problems. In addition, tool-to-tool variations, chamber-to-chamber variations, and chamber drift can lead to problems over time. For example, thicknesses and/or uniformities can change within a wafer, from wafer to wafer, and from lot to lot during the etch process due to the nature of using end pointing and sacrificial films to control a bottom critical dimension (CD). In addition, thickness and/or temperature variations can cause changes in the optical properties and other physical properties.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The latest information from material processing procedures and/or measurement procedures obtained just prior to the etching process can be fed forward and can be used at the time of etching calculations to optimize the etching process accuracy and precision. The information can be passed to an etching and/or metrology tool calculation procedures in real-time as real-time variable parameters, overriding current model default values and narrowing the search space for resolving accurate results. Information can be used with a library-based system or in real-time regression or any combination of both library and real-time regression to optimize part of the measurement procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">A measurement subsystem, such as measurement subsystem <b>140</b>, can include an integrated Optical Digital Profiling (iODP) system (not shown). Alternatively, other metrology systems may be used. An iODP tool is available from Timbre Technologies Inc. (a TEL company). For example, ODP techniques can be used to obtain critical dimension (CD) information, structure profile information, or via profile information, and the wavelength ranges for an iODP system can range from less than approximately 200 nm to greater than approximately 900 nm. An exemplary ODP system can include an ODP Profiler Library, a Profiler Application Server (PAS), and ODP Profiler Software. The ODP Profiler Library can comprise an application specific database of optical spectra and its corresponding semiconductor profiles, CDs, and film thicknesses. The PAS can comprise at least one computer that connects with optical hardware and computer network. The PAS handles the data communication, ODP library operation, measurement process, results generation, results analysis, and results output. The ODP Profiler Software includes the software installed on PAS to manage measurement recipe, ODP Profiler library, ODP Profiler data, ODP Profiler results search/match, ODP Profiler results calculation/analysis, data communication, and PAS interface to various metrology tools and computer networks.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">A metrology subsystem, such as measurement subsystem <b>140</b>, can use polarizing reflectometry, spectroscopic ellipsometry, reflectometry, or other optical measurement techniques to measure accurate device profiles, accurate critical dimensions (CD), and multiple layer film thickness of a wafer. The integrated metrology process can be executed in-line, which eliminates the need to break the wafer for performing the analyses or waiting for long periods for data from external tools. ODP techniques can be used with the existing thin film metrology tools for inline profile and CD measurement, and can be integrated with TEL processing tools and/or lithography systems to provide real-time process monitoring and control. An exemplary optical metrology system is described in U.S. Pat. No. 6,943,900, entitled GENERATION OF A LIBRARY OF PERIODIC GRATING DIFFRACTION SIGNAL, by Niu, et al., issued on Sep. 13, 2005, and is incorporated in its entirety herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">An alternative procedure for generating a library of simulated-diffraction signals can include using a machine learning system (MLS). Prior to generating the library of simulated-diffraction signals, the MLS is trained using known input and output data. In one exemplary embodiment, simulated diffraction signals can be generated using a machine learning system (MLS) employing a machine learning algorithm, such as back-propagation, radial basis function, support vector, kernel regression, and the like. For a more detailed description of machine learning systems and algorithms, see &#x201c;Neural Networks&#x201d; by Simon Haykin, Prentice Hall, 1999, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. See also U.S. Patent Publication No. 2004/0017574, titled OPTICAL METROLOGY OF STRUCTURES FORMED ON SEMICONDUCTOR WAFERS USING MACHINE LEARNING SYSTEMS, filed on Jun. 27, 2003, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">For detailed description of metrology model optimization, refer to U.S. Patent Publication No. 2004/0017574, OPTIMIZED MODEL AND PARAMETER SELECTION FOR OPTICAL METROLOGY, by Vuong, et al., filed Jun. 27, 2002; U.S. Patent Publication No. 2006/0064280, OPTICAL METROLOGY MODEL OPTIMIZATION BASED ON GOALS, by Vuong, et al., filed Sep. 21, 2004; and U.S. Patent Publication No. 2005/0209816, OPTICAL METROLOGY OPTIMIZATION FOR REPETITIVE STRUCTURES, by Vuong, et al., filed on Apr. 27, 2004, all of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entireties.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">When a regression process is used, a measured diffraction signal measured off the patterned structure can be compared to simulated diffraction signals. The simulated diffraction signals can be iteratively generated based on sets of profile parameters, to get a convergence value for the set of profile parameters that generates the closest match simulated diffraction signal compared to the measured diffraction signal. For a more detailed description of a regression-based process, see U.S. Pat. No. 6,785,638, titled METHOD AND SYSTEM OF DYNAMIC LEARNING THROUGH A REGRESSION-BASED LIBRARY GENERATION PROCESS, issued on Aug. 31, 2004, which is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">When a library-based process is used, an optical metrology data library can be generated and/or enhanced using tuned and/or optimized recipes, profiles, and/or models. The optical metrology data library can comprise pairs of simulated diffraction signals and corresponding set of profile parameters. A detailed description of generating optical metrology data such as a library of simulated diffraction signals and a corresponding set of profile parameters is described in U.S. Pat. No. 6,943,900 which is incorporated herein by reference.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Controllers, such as <b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, or <b>145</b>, can include APC, R2R, FDC, and/or RTPT procedures that can operate as control strategies, control plans, control models, and/or recipe managers to provide run-to-run (R2R) processing. For example, wafer level context matching at runtime allows for custom configuration by wafer (state, slot, waferID, lotID, etc.). In addition, feedforward and/or feedback control can be implemented by installing TCDs, and configuring control strategies, control plans, and control models to use the TCDs. A control strategy can be executed for each system process where feedforward and/or feedback control is implemented. When a system process executes, one or more of the control plans within the control strategy can be executed. Each control plan can be used to modify the recipe based on feed-forward and/or feedback information.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">Control and/or analysis strategies/plans can cover multiple process steps within a wafer processing sequence, and can be used to analyze the time real-time and/or collected data, and establish error conditions. A procedure can be executed when a context is matched. During the execution of an analysis procedure, one or more analysis plans can be executed. A plan can create an error when a data failure occurs, an execution problem occurs, or a control problem occurs. When an error occurs, the plan can generate an alarm message; the parent strategy status can be changed to a failed status; the plan status can be changed to a failed status; and one or more messages can be sent to the alarm log and the FDC system. When a feedforward plan or a feedback plan fails, one or more of the plans in the parent strategy may be terminated, and their status can be changed to a failed status. In one case, when a defective incoming wafer, or a faulty RTO, or a defective TCD is detected, a control plan can detect and/or identify this as a fault. A data collection plan and/or analysis plan can reject the data at one or more of the measurement sites for this wafer or reject the data because a RTPT, a RTO-related and/or a TCD-related procedure fails.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">In one embodiment, a feedforward and/or feedback plan failure may not terminate the strategy or other plans, and an etching and/or a measurement procedure failure may not terminate the strategy or other plans. For example, a feedforward plan can indicate a failure when a RTO and/or TCD fail. Successful plans, strategies, etching procedures, and/or measurement procedures do not create any error/alarm messages. Pre-specified failure actions for strategy and/or plan errors can be stored in a database, and can be retrieved from the database when an error occurs. Failure actions can use the nominal process recipe for this wafer or use a null process recipe for this wafer. A null recipe can be a control recipe that can be used by a processing tool and/or processing chamber to allow a wafer to pass through and/or remain in a processing chamber without processing. For example, a null recipe can be used when a process is paused or when a wafer does not require processing. When a RTO and/or TCD fail, the previous data can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In some embodiments, the RTO <b>127</b> can use feedforward data received via the data transfer system <b>190</b> to tune and/or optimize an etching process. When a wafer lot is being processed by an etching subsystem <b>120</b> after being processed by a lithography subsystem <b>110</b>, one or more of the wafers can be sent to a measurement subsystem <b>140</b>. For example, new real-time measurement data can be created when a wafer is being measured in the measurement subsystem <b>140</b>, and newly created measurement data can be fed forward in real-time from the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> to the etching subsystem <b>120</b> using formatted messages. One or more of the formatted messages from the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can be exchanged between TCD <b>148</b> and TCD <b>128</b>. The TCD <b>128</b> can process the formatted message and extract new data for the RTO <b>127</b>. When new data is available, the RTO <b>127</b> in the etching subsystem <b>120</b> can either use the new data to tune and/or optimize an etching recipe, profile, and/or model currently being used for the wafer lot or RTO <b>127</b> can use the new data to tune and/or optimize an etching recipe, profile, and/or model for the next wafer lot. When the RTO <b>127</b> uses the new data to tune and/or optimize an etching recipe, an etching profile, and/or an etching model for the wafer lot currently being processed, the RTO <b>127</b> can determine if an etching recipe, an etching profile, and/or an etching model can be updated before the current wafer is processed. The current wafer is processed using the tuned and/or optimized etching recipe, profile, and/or model when the etching recipe, profile, and/or model can be updated before the current wafer is processed. The current wafer can be processed using a non-tuned and/or non-optimized etching recipe, profile, and/or model when the etching recipe cannot be updated before the current wafer is processed. When a newly tuned and/or optimized etching recipe, profile, and/or model are available, an etching subsystem and/or etching controller <b>125</b> may determine when to use the newly tuned and/or optimized etching recipe, profile, and/or model. For example, RTO <b>127</b> can use CD data, thermal data, thickness data, uniformity data, timing data, delay data, or optical properties data, or any combination thereof to tune and/or optimize an etching recipe, an etching profile, and/or an etching model.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">In other embodiments, the RTO <b>147</b> can use feedforward data received via the data transfer system <b>190</b> to tune and/or optimize a measurement process. When a wafer lot is being measured by a measurement subsystem <b>140</b> after being processed by an etching subsystem <b>120</b>, one or more of the wafers can be sent to a measurement subsystem <b>140</b>. For example, new real-time etch processing data can be created when a wafer is being etched in the etching subsystem <b>120</b>, and newly created etch processing data can be fed forward in real-time from the etching subsystem <b>120</b> to the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> using formatted messages. One or more of the formatted messages from the etching subsystem <b>120</b> can be sent from TCD <b>128</b> to TCD <b>148</b>. The TCD <b>148</b> in the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can process the formatted message and extract new data for the RTO <b>147</b>. When new data is available, the RTO <b>147</b> can either use the new data to tune and/or optimize a measurement recipe, profile, and/or model currently being used for the wafer lot or RTO <b>147</b> can use the new data to tune and/or optimize a measurement recipe, profile, and/or model for the next wafer lot.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">When the RTO <b>147</b> uses the new data to tune and/or optimize a measurement recipe, profile, and/or model for the wafer lot currently being processed, the RTO <b>147</b> can determine if the measurement recipe, profile, and/or model can be updated before the current wafer is measured. The current wafer can be measured using the tuned and/or optimized measurement recipe, profile, and/or model when the measurement recipe, profile, and/or model can be updated before the current wafer is measured. The current wafer can be measured using a non-tuned and/or non-optimized measurement recipe, profile, and/or model when the measurement recipe cannot be updated before the current wafer is measured. When a newly tuned and/or optimized measurement recipe, profile, and/or model are available, a measurement subsystem <b>140</b> and/or associated controller <b>145</b> may determine when to use the newly tuned and/or optimized measurement recipe, profile, and/or model. For example, RTO <b>147</b> can use CD data, thermal data, thickness data, uniformity data, or optical properties data, or any combination thereof to tune and/or optimize a measurement recipe, profile, and/or model.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can measure isolated and/or nested structures at different times, and the etching subsystem <b>120</b> and/or RTO <b>127</b> can use new measurement data for isolated and/or nested structures to tune and/or optimize a process chemistry and/or process time. For example, wafer thickness or temperature can be different near isolated and/or nested structures. In addition, wafer thickness or temperature can be different near open areas and/or trench array areas.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can provide measurement data for damaged layers, features, and/or structures for different wafers and/or lots, and the etching subsystem <b>120</b> and/or RTO <b>127</b> can use the measurement data for damaged layers, features, and/or structures to update, tune, and/or optimize an etching chemistry and/or etching time.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can measure mask and/or photoresist features, structures, and/or thicknesses, and the etching subsystem <b>120</b> and/or RTO <b>127</b> can use new measurement data for the mask and/or the photoresist features, structures, and/or thicknesses to update, tune, and/or optimize a process recipe, a process chemistry, and/or process time. The measurement subsystem <b>140</b> can measure the etched features and use new process data from the etch process to update, tune, and/or optimize a measurement recipe.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The etching subsystem <b>120</b> can feed forward the end-point detection (EPD) times to the measurement subsystem <b>140</b> to improve the wafer film thickness computation. EPD times can also be used by RTO <b>127</b> to update, tune, and/or optimize an etching recipe, by the RTO <b>147</b> to update, tune, and/or optimize a measurement recipe and/or library selection, and RTO <b>127</b> to update, tune, and/or optimize a mask and/or photoresist model, an etching process model, and/or etching tool model.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">While a wafer and/or lot is being processed, additional calculated data, simulated data, and/or measured data can be generated, and this data can be fed forward and/or fed back in real time by the processing system to update process, measurement, and/or simulation recipes before the current wafer is processes or before additional wafers in the wafer lot are processed.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">When a wafer is measured before an etching process, the pre-etch measurement data can be used to narrow the search range of the post-etch measurements, and this can increase the accuracy and reduce the measurement calculation times. An expected measurement value can be fed forward based on pre-etch measurements and etch trim amount. The subsystem <b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, and <b>140</b> can use the most up-to-date pre-processing information obtained from previously performed processes to perform new calculations.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Measurement data from subsystem <b>140</b> can include measured diffraction signals associated with patterned structures or un-patterned structures, and the diffraction signals can be stored using processing state data, and wafer, lot, recipe, site, or wafer location data. RTO data can include variables associated with patterned structure profile, metrology device type and associated variables, and ranges used for the variables floated in the modeling and values of variables that were fixed in the modeling. The library profile data, the feedforward messages, and/or data may include fixed profile parameters (such as pitch), the N and K parameters, and/or metrology device parameters (such as angle of incidence and/or azimuth angle).</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">In some embodiments, RTPT procedures can use measured diffraction signals, and the RTPT parameters can include recipe input information, historical data, tuning data, optimization data, library profile data, feedforward data, feedback data, and measured diffraction signal data to create, tune and/or optimize an optical metrology recipe, structure, and/or model. Feedback data can include correction data. Recipe data can include materials in the layers of the patterned and un-patterned structures in the stack. Tuning and/or optimization data can include profile parameters, material refraction parameters, and metrology device parameters that can be used to tune and/or optimize the optical metrology recipe, profile, and/or model. RTPT procedures may utilize context/identification information such as wafer ID, slot ID, lot ID, recipe, state, and patterned structure ID as a means for organizing and indexing data. Library data can include measured diffraction signals associated with devices, wafers, lots, recipes, site or wafer location, patterned and/or un-patterned structures. Metrology data can include variables associated with patterned structure profile, metrology device type and associated variables, and ranges used for the variables floated in the modeling and values of variables that were fixed in the modeling. RTPT procedures can use feedforward data and/or feedback data to determine the patterned structure profile, critical dimension, and underlying thicknesses in real time. RTPT output data can be selectively transmitted, stored, displayed, and/or transmitted to another system and/or subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Feedforward messages and/or data may include an underlying film thicknesses, CD, and/or values of one or more profile parameters of the patterned structure. The underlying film thicknesses, CD, and/or values of one or more profile parameters of the patterned structure may be used by the RTPT procedures to make real-time updates and/or corrections. The feedforward messages and/or data may include one or more CDs for a patterned structure that may be used to alter an etching recipe and/or a deposition recipe. The data transmitted to the etching subsystem can comprise underlying film thicknesses, CD, and/or values of the profile parameters of the patterned structure together with identification information such as wafer identification (ID), slot ID, lot ID, recipe, and patterned structure ID to facilitate retrieval for other applications.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In addition, the RTPT procedures may create, tune, and/or optimize a library of simulated diffraction signals and the corresponding set of profile parameters. The RTPT procedures may create, tune, and/or optimize a second data set from a trained machine learning system (MLS), and the MLS may be trained with a subset of the library data. For example, values for the metrology device parameters, such as angle of incidence, may be obtained from the vendor specifications of the metrology device, and the values for azimuth angle can be obtained from the setup used in the diffraction measurement. Changed and/or updated values can be fed forward using a TCD to improve performance.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">Intervention and/or judgment rules can be defined at a strategy level, a plan level, a model level, or a procedure level. Intervention and/or judgment rules can be assigned to execute whenever a matching context is encountered. When a matching context is encountered at a higher level as well as a lower level, the intervention and/or judgment rules associated with the higher level can be executed. GUI screens (not shown) can be used for defining and maintaining the intervention and/or judgment rules. Intervention and/or judgment rule definition and assignment can be controlled by the MES <b>180</b>. The intervention and/or judgment rules can be for TCDs, RTOs, and/or RTPT procedures and can be maintained in a database. Documentation and help screens can be provided for the intervention and/or judgment rules.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The MES <b>180</b> can be configured to monitor some system processes, and factory level intervention and/or judgment rules can be used to determine which processes are monitored and which data can be used. In addition, factory level intervention and/or judgment rules can be used to determine how to manage the data when a process can be changed, paused, and/or stopped. In addition, the MES <b>180</b> can provide run-time configuration information and real-time update information. Data can be exchanged using GEM SECS communications protocol.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In general, rules allow system and/or tool operation to change based on the dynamic state of a semiconductor processing system and/or the processing state of a product. Some setup and/or configuration information can be determined by the processing system subsystems when they are initially configured. In addition, rules can be used to establish a control hierarchy at the system/tool level. Rules can be used to determine when a process can be paused and/or stopped, and what can be done when a process is paused and/or stopped. In addition, rules can be used to determine what corrective actions are to be performed, such as when to change a process, how to change the process, and how to manage the data.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">Exemplary methods of processing a wafer can include receiving one or more wafers and associated wafer data, and establishing a processing sequence and/or a wafer state for each wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The wafer state can include a sequencing state (SQ<sub>n,m</sub>) variable that can be determined from the processing sequence, where n is the wafer number and m is the processing sequence number. For example, n and m can be integers. In some embodiments, the processing sequence may be obtained from a MES and cannot be modified. In other embodiments, a virtual (modifiable) processing sequence may be established, and the sequencing state and/or process start time can be changed by a subsystem computer and/or an operator. For example, additional sequence states altered start times may be used to establish additional etching steps, to hold wafers while etching steps are being performed, to hold wafers while calculations are being performed, to route wafers to different tools when a tool goes off-line, and/or to correct and/or analyze fault conditions. In addition, additional sequence states altered start times may be used to hold and/or re-route wafers while feedforward data and/or messages are created, processed, sent, and/or received, to hold and/or re-route wafers while tuning data and/or tuned data and/or messages are created, processed, sent, and/or received, and/or to hold and/or re-route wafers while optimization and/or optimized data and/or messages are created, processed, sent, and/or received.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">For example, a wafer can be sent to a lithography subsystem <b>110</b> when the sequencing state is a first value (SQ<b>1</b>); a wafer can be sent to an etch subsystem <b>120</b> when the sequencing state is a second value (SQ<b>2</b>); a wafer can be sent to a deposition subsystem <b>130</b> when the sequencing state is a third value (SQ<b>3</b>); a wafer can be sent to a measurement subsystem <b>140</b> when the sequencing state is a fourth value (SQ<b>4</b>); a wafer can be sent to an external measurement system <b>150</b> when the sequencing state is a fifth value (SQ<b>5</b>); and a wafer can be sent to a transfer subsystem <b>160</b> when the sequencing state is a sixth value (SQ<b>6</b>). Alternatively, other configurations may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">In addition, the wafer state can include a tuned variable (TV<sub>n,m</sub>), an optimized variable (OV<sub>n,m</sub>), an updated variable (UV<sub>n,m</sub>) a measured variable (MV<sub>n,m</sub>), a processed variable (PV<sub>n,m</sub>), and a delay time variable (DTV<sub>n,m</sub>), where n is the wafer number and m is a processing sequence number. The tuned variable (TV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d; when the wafer has been tuned and is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d; when the wafer has not been tuned, the optimized variable (OV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d; when the wafer has been optimized and is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d; when the wafer has not been optimized, the updated variable (UV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d; when the wafer has been updated and is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d; when the wafer has not been updated, the measured variable (MV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d; when the wafer has been measured and is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d; when the wafer has not been measured, and the processed variable (PV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d; when the wafer has been processed and is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d; when the wafer has not been processed. A delay time variable (DTV<sub>n,m</sub>) can be used to delay wafer sequencing, calculations, processes, and/or measurements. Alternatively, the wafer state may be characterized using different and/or additional variables.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">When a feed-forward state is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, the feedforward data and/or messages can be fed forward, and when the feedforward state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, the feedforward data and/or messages are not fed forward. When a pass-through state is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, pass-through data and/or messages can be passed through, and when the pass-through state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, pass-through data and/or messages are not passed through.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">When a RTPT state is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, a RTPT procedure can be performed, and when the RTPT state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, a RTPT procedure is not performed. When an optimization state is a first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, an optimization procedure can be performed, and when the optimization state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, an optimization procedure is not performed.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">When the update state is the first value, a process can be updated using the tuned data and/or optimized data before the current wafer is processed, the current wafer can be processed using the updated process, and updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer. When the update state is the second value, a process cannot be updated using the tuned data and/or optimized data before the current wafer is processed, the current wafer is processed using a non-updated process, and non-updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Input and output messages can include fault messages, response messages, error messages, feedforward messages, feedback messages, pass-through messages, internal messages, external messages, tuning messages, optimization messages, status messages, timing messages, process results messages, and/or other messages.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">In various embodiments, one or more input messages can be received and/or processed by one or more subsystems (<b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, <b>140</b>, and <b>160</b>), by one or more controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>), by one or more RTOs (<b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, and <b>147</b>), or by one or more TCDs (<b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, and <b>148</b>), or any combination thereof. In addition, one or more output messages can be created and/or sent by one or more subsystems (<b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, <b>140</b>, and <b>160</b>), by one or more controllers (<b>105</b>, <b>115</b>, <b>125</b>, <b>135</b>, and <b>145</b>), by one or more RTOs (<b>117</b>, <b>127</b>, <b>137</b>, and <b>147</b>), or by one or more TCDs (<b>118</b>, <b>128</b>, <b>138</b>, and <b>148</b>), or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079">In addition, messages can include real-time command, calculation, and/or override information. Real-time processing and/or measurement data obtained just prior to the next process step can be fed forward and can be used before the next process is performed to delay the process, to calculate new process parameters, and to improve the process accuracy and precision. The real-time data can be passed to a processing tool as RTPT procedure variables/parameters, can be used to override current recipe data, profile, and/or model default values, to override current sequencing state data, to override current start times, and can be used to narrow the search space for determining recipes, profiles, and/or models and their associated accuracy limits.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an exemplary block diagram of system in accordance with embodiments of the invention. In the illustrated embodiment, system <b>200</b> is shown comprising a Real-Time Optimizer (RTO) <b>210</b> that can include a real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, a real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, and a real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>. Alternatively, a real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, a real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, or a real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, or any combination thereof may not be required, and/or the RTO <b>210</b> may be configured differently. One or more RTOs can be established when a system is configured and/or changed. For example, RTOs may be controlled by a MES (host) computer, by a processing system computer, and/or by a processing subsystem computer.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can be coupled <b>222</b> to a data transfer system <b>290</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can be coupled <b>232</b> to a data transfer system <b>290</b>, and the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can be coupled <b>242</b> to the data transfer system <b>290</b>. Alternatively, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, and the data transfer system <b>290</b> may be configured and/or coupled differently. The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, and/or the data transfer system <b>290</b> can comprise hardware, firmware, or software, or any combination thereof. The data transfer system <b>290</b> can be coupled to other devices (not shown) using a link <b>291</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">The RTO <b>210</b> can include a first TCD <b>225</b> that can be coupled to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>228</b>, can be coupled to the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> using a link <b>227</b>, and can be coupled <b>224</b> to the data transfer system <b>290</b>. RTO <b>210</b> can include a second TCD <b>235</b> that can be coupled to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>238</b>, can be coupled to the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> using a link <b>237</b>, and can be coupled <b>234</b> to the data transfer system <b>290</b>. RTO <b>210</b> can include a third TCD <b>245</b> that can be coupled to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>248</b>, can be coupled to the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> using a link <b>247</b>, and can be coupled <b>244</b> to the data transfer system <b>290</b>. The first TCD <b>225</b>, the second TCD <b>235</b>, and/or the third TCD <b>245</b> can comprise hardware, firmware, or software, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">In various embodiments, one or more input messages can be received and/or processed by the RTO <b>210</b>, and one or more output messages can be created and/or sent by the RTO <b>210</b>. The RTO <b>210</b> can create internal messages that can include real-time feedforward messages and/or data. The RTO <b>210</b> can send internal messages and receive responses to the internal messages in real-time, and can send output messages, and receive responses to the output messages in real time, and can create, process, send and/or receive other messages in real time. For example, one or more real-time optimizers (<b>220</b>, <b>230</b>, and <b>240</b>) and/or one or more TCDs (<b>225</b>, <b>235</b>, and <b>245</b>) may use internal messages. In addition, internal messages can include real-time feedforward data, historical data, input data, output data, priority data, delay data, fault data, response data, error data, feedforward data, feedback data, pass-through data, internal data, external data, tuning and/or tuned data, optimization and/or optimized data, status data, timing data, process results data, and/or measured data.</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">The first TCD <b>225</b>, the second TCD <b>235</b>, and/or the third TCD <b>245</b> can receive in real-time input messages that can include real-time feedforward messages and/or real-time pass-through messages from the MES <b>280</b> and/or other devices using data transfer system <b>290</b>. The first TCD <b>225</b> can process a first input message in real time and can feed forward a first real-time feedforward message to the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> using a link <b>227</b> when the first input message includes a first real-time feedforward message. In addition, the first TCD <b>225</b> can process the first input message in real time and can pass-through a first real-time pass-through message to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>224</b> when the first input message includes a first real-time pass-through message. The second TCD <b>235</b> can process a second input message in real time and can feedforward a second real-time feedforward message to the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> using a link <b>237</b> when the second input messages includes a second real-time feedforward message. In addition, the second TCD <b>235</b> can process the second input message in real time and can pass-through a second real-time pass-through message to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>234</b> when the second input message includes a second real-time pass-through message. The third TCD <b>245</b> can process a third input message in real time and can feedforward a third real-time feedforward message to the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> using a link <b>247</b> when the third input messages includes a third real-time feedforward message. In addition, the third TCD <b>245</b> can process the third input message in real time and can pass-through a third real-time pass-through message to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>244</b> when the third input message includes a third real-time pass-through message.</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">In other embodiments, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, or the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, or any combination thereof can receive in real-time input messages that can include real-time feedforward messages and/or real-time pass-through messages from the MES <b>280</b> and/or other devices using data transfer system <b>290</b>. The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can process a first input message in real time and can feedforward a first real-time feedforward message to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b> when the first input messages includes a first real-time feedforward message. In addition, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can process the first input message in real time and can pass-through a first real-time pass-through message to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>222</b> when the first input message includes a first real-time pass-through message. The real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can process a second input message in real time and can feedforward a second real-time feedforward message to the second TCD <b>235</b> using a link <b>237</b> when the second input message includes a second real-time feedforward message. In addition, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can process the second input message in real time and can pass-through a second real-time pass-through message to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>232</b> when the second input message includes a second real-time pass-through message. The real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can process a third input message in real time and can feedforward a third real-time feedforward message to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b> when the third input messages includes a third real-time feedforward message. In addition, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can process the third input message in real time and can pass-through a third real-time pass-through message to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>242</b> when the third input message includes a third real-time pass-through message. Furthermore, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, or the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, or any combination thereof can generate and send output messages in response to the input messages.</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">In other embodiments, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, and/or the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can receive, process, and/or send non-optimized and/or un-tuned data in real time.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can process one or more input messages in real time and can use the tuning and/or optimization data from the one or more input messages in a tuning and/or optimization procedure thereby creating tuned and/or optimized process recipes. The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can feedforward one or more real-time feedforward messages to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>, and the one or more real-time feedforward messages can include real-time tuned and/or optimized process recipes. In addition, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can process one or more input messages in real time, can pass-through other messages to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>, and/or can pass-through other messages (other than feed forward messages) to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>222</b>, when an input message includes other messages. Furthermore, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can generate and send output messages in response to the input messages.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In some embodiments, the tuning and/or optimization data can include layer fabrication information. For example, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can process one or more input messages in real time and can use real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real time wafer temperature data from the one or more input messages in a RTPT procedure to tune and/or optimize etching recipe data. The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can feedforward one or more real-time feedforward messages to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>, and the one or more real-time feedforward messages can include the real-time tuned and/or optimized etching recipe data, and/or can pass-through other messages to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>. For example, other messages may include historical, setup and/or configuration data. When the first TCD <b>225</b> receives the feedforward messages and/or other messages from the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the first TCD <b>225</b> can process in real time the feedforward messages and/or the other messages into feedforward messages and pass-through messages that can be sent to the MES <b>280</b> and/or other subsystems using data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">Alternatively, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can feed forward the tuned and/or optimized etching recipe data to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>, and/or can pass-through other messages to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>. When the first TCD <b>225</b> receives the tuned and/or optimized etching recipe data from the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the first TCD <b>225</b> can process the tuned and/or optimized etching recipe data into feedforward messages and pass-through messages that can be sent in real time to the MES <b>280</b> and/or other subsystems using data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">The real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can process one or more input messages in real time and can use the tuning and/or optimization data from the one or more input messages in a tuning and/or optimization procedure thereby creating tuned and/or optimized profile data. The real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can feedforward one or more real-time feedforward messages to the first TCD <b>225</b> using a link <b>227</b>, and the one or more real-time feedforward messages can include real-time tuned and/or optimized profile data. In addition, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can process one or more input messages in real time, can pass-through other messages (messages not required by the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>) to the second TCD <b>235</b> using a link <b>237</b>, and/or can pass-through other messages to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>232</b>, when an input message includes other messages. Furthermore, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can generate and send output messages in response to the input messages.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">For example, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can process one or more input messages in real time and can use real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature data from the one or more input messages in a RTPT procedure to create tuned and/or optimized profile data. The real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can feedforward one or more real-time feedforward messages to the second TCD <b>235</b> using a link <b>237</b>, and the one or more real-time feedforward messages can include the real-time tuned and/or optimized profile data, and/or can pass-through other messages (messages not required by the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>) to the second TCD <b>235</b> using a link <b>237</b>. When the second TCD <b>235</b> receives the feedforward messages and/or other messages from the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the second TCD <b>235</b> can process in real time the feedforward messages and/or the other messages into feedforward messages and pass-through messages that can be sent to the MES <b>280</b> and/or other subsystems using data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">Alternatively, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can feed forward tuned and/or optimized profile data to the second TCD <b>235</b> using a link <b>237</b>, and/or can pass-through other messages to the second TCD <b>235</b> using a link <b>237</b>. When the second TCD <b>235</b> receives the tuned and/or optimized profile data from the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, the second TCD <b>235</b> can process the tuned and/or optimized profile data into feedforward messages and pass-through messages that can be sent in real time to the MES <b>280</b> and/or other subsystems using data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">The real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can process one or more input messages in real time and can use the tuning and/or optimization data from the one or more input messages in a tuning and/or optimization procedure thereby creating tuned and/or optimized modeling data. The real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can feedforward one or more real-time feedforward messages to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b>, and the one or more real-time feedforward messages can include the tuned and/or optimized modeling data. In addition, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can process one or more input messages in real time, can pass-through other messages (messages not required by the real-time profile optimizer <b>240</b>) to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b>, and/or can pass-through other messages to the data transfer system <b>290</b> using a link <b>232</b>, when an input message includes other messages. Furthermore, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can generate and send output messages in response to the input messages.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">For example, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can process one or more input messages in real time and can use real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature data from the one or more input messages in a RTPT procedure to create tuned and/or modeling data. The real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can feedforward one or more real-time feedforward messages to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b>, and the one or more real-time feedforward messages can include the real-time tuned and/or optimized modeling data, and/or can pass-through other messages (messages not required by the real-time profile optimizer <b>240</b>) to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b>. When the third TCD <b>245</b> receives the feedforward messages and/or other messages from the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, the third TCD <b>245</b> can process in real time the feedforward messages and/or the other messages into feedforward messages and pass-through messages that can be sent to the MES <b>280</b> and/or other subsystems using data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">Alternatively, the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can feed forward tuned and/or optimized modeling data to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b>, and/or can pass-through other messages to the third TCD <b>245</b> using a link <b>247</b>. When the third TCD <b>245</b> receives tuned and/or optimized modeling data from the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b>, the third TCD <b>245</b> can process the tuned and/or optimized modeling data into feedforward messages and pass-through messages that can be sent in real time to the MES <b>280</b> and/or other subsystems using data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0097" num="0096">Single TCDs <b>225</b>, <b>235</b>, <b>245</b> are shown, and single links <b>227</b>, <b>237</b>, <b>247</b>, <b>228</b>, <b>238</b>, and <b>248</b> are shown, but this is not required for the invention. In other embodiments, any number of TCDs can be used, and any number of links can be used. Alternatively, an RTO may not include any TCDs, or TCDs can be configured outside of the RTO. Links <b>222</b>, <b>224</b>, <b>227</b>, <b>228</b>, <b>232</b>, <b>234</b>, <b>237</b>, <b>238</b>, <b>242</b>, <b>244</b>, <b>247</b>, and <b>248</b> can be high-speed links that can be used to exchange data and/or formatted messages.</p>
<p id="p-0098" num="0097">In addition, the system <b>200</b> can include another TCD <b>250</b> that can be coupled to a data transfer system <b>290</b> using a first link <b>252</b> and a second link <b>254</b>. For example, the first link <b>252</b> and/or the second link <b>254</b> can be a high-speed link configured to feed forward real-time data. A single TCD <b>250</b> is shown, and single links <b>252</b>, <b>254</b> are shown, but this is not required for the invention. In other embodiments, any number of TCDs can be used, and any number of links can be used. The TCDs can be coupled in series and/or in parallel and can have one or more input ports and/or one or more output ports. TCDs can be coupled to each other and to other devices using intranet, internet, and/or wireless connections. TCDs can be connected to one or more input devices and/or output devices in one or more subsystems using the data transfer system <b>290</b>. Alternatively, TCDs can be coupled directly to subsystems and/or be part of a subsystem as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. As also seen in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a MES <b>280</b> can be coupled <b>282</b> to a data transfer system <b>290</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0099" num="0098">The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, the real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, and/or the real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can utilize context information such as time, wafer ID, slot ID, lot ID, recipe, and patterned structure ID as a means for organizing and indexing real-time and/or historical data.</p>
<p id="p-0100" num="0099">The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can use wafer data, models, recipes, and profile data to tune and/or optimize a process, such as an etching process, a deposition process, a measurement process, an exposure process, a development process, a thermal process, a cleaning process, or a transfer process, or any combination thereof. The real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can use a wafer model, an accuracy model, a recipe model, an optical properties model, a structure model, a FDC model, a prediction model, a confidence model, a measurement model, an etching model, a deposition model, a first wafer effect model, a chamber model, a tool model, a drift model, a delay time model, an electrical performance model, or a device model, or any combination thereof. In addition, the real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> can use historical data, wafer data, accuracy data, process data, optical properties data, structure data, FDC data, prediction data, confidence data, measurement data, etching data, chamber data, tool data, drift data, electrical performance data, or device data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0101" num="0100">The real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> can use wafer data, accuracy data, process data, optical properties data, structure data, FDC data, prediction data, confidence data, measurement data, etching data, chamber data, tool data, or drift data, or any combination thereof to estimate, enhance, tune, and/or optimize a profile, feature, structure, a pattern, a target, or a layer, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0102" num="0101">The real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can be used to create, enhance, tune, and/or optimize a wafer model, an accuracy model, a recipe model, an optical properties model, a structure model, a FDC model, a prediction model, a confidence model, a measurement model, an etching model, a chamber model, a tool model, or a drift model, an electrical performance model, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0103" num="0102">A real-time process optimizer <b>220</b>, a real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b>, and/or a real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> can perform RTPT procedures using feedforward messages and/or data. The feedforward data can be updated on a within-wafer basis, on a wafer-to-wafer basis, and/or on a lot-to-lot basis. One or more RTPT parameters can be used in real time to create, enhance, tune, and/or optimize a recipe, a profile estimate, and/or model. Processing and/or material variations affecting the optical properties can change across a wafer, wafer-to-wafer, process-to-process, lot-to-lot.</p>
<p id="p-0104" num="0103">The RTPT parameters can include layer information that can include layer thickness data. For example, thickness data may be provided after a deposition process, and many current factory systems do not include procedures for communicating such information to the measurement subsystem. By feed forwarding real-time wafer temperature, layer thickness and/or other wafer characteristics data to a measurement and/or processing subsystem, improved wafer processing is provided. Material variations and/or process variations that affect the water temperature and/or layer thicknesses can change across a wafer, from wafer to wafer, and from lot to lot. For example, thickness variation can be due to a deposition process not being uniform across the wafer, and this can include chamber-to-chamber variations and chamber drift in processing over time. Thickness variations can cause optical property variations and/or thermal variations to occur.</p>
<p id="p-0105" num="0104">In some examples, thickness variation can be due to a Chemical Vapor Deposition (CVD) or spin on process. New thickness data can be obtained after a CVD process, and the new thickness data can be obtained from a measurement process or a simulation process. In addition, thickness variation can be due to a Chemical Mechanical Polishing (CMP) or other polishing process. New thickness data can be obtained after a CMP process, and the new thickness data can be obtained from a measurement process or a simulation process.</p>
<p id="p-0106" num="0105">In other examples, thickness and/or thermal variation can occur because of an etching and/or ashing process. New thickness and/or thermal data can be obtained after an etching and/or ashing process, and the new thickness and/or thermal data can be obtained from a measurement process or a simulation process. Film properties can change across a wafer and from wafer to wafer during the etch process when EPD (end point detection) and/or sacrificial films are used to control a bottom CD (critical dimension). The deposition and/or etching of a film can change the optical properties, thermal properties and/or physical properties.</p>
<p id="p-0107" num="0106">The RTO <b>210</b> can use real-time wafer thickness and/or temperature data to create tuned lithography data when the RTPT state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the first value (SQ<b>1</b>); can use real-time wafer thickness and/or temperature data to create optimized lithography data when the optimization state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the first value (SQ<b>1</b>); can feed forward the tuned lithography data and/or the optimized lithography data when the feedforward state is the first value; and/or can pass-through the tuned lithography data and/or the optimized lithography data when the pass-through state is the first value. The tuned lithography data can include tuned recipe data, tuned profile data, or tuned modeling data, or any combination thereof. The optimized lithography data can include optimized recipe data, optimized profile data, or optimized modeling data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0108" num="0107">When the wafer is sent to the lithography subsystem, the wafer can be processed by the lithography subsystem using the tuned lithography data and/or optimized lithography data when the update state is the first value, and updated lithography process result data can be established for the processed wafer. The wafer can be processed using non-updated procedures when the update state is the second value, and non-updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer. For example, when the update state is the first value, the tuned lithography data and/or the optimized lithography data can be used by the lithography subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed and the current wafer can be processed by the lithography subsystem using the updated procedure, and when the update state is the second value, the tuned lithography data and/or the optimized lithography data cannot be used by the lithography subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed by the lithography subsystem and the wafer can be processed using a non-updated procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0109" num="0108">The RTO <b>210</b> can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create tuned etching data when the RTPT state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the second value (SQ<b>2</b>); can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create optimized etching data when the optimization state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the second value (SQ<b>2</b>); can feed forward the tuned etching data and/or the optimized etching data when the feedforward state is the first value; and/or can pass-through the tuned etching data and/or the optimized etching data when the pass-through state is the first value. The tuned etching data can include tuned recipe data, tuned profile data, or tuned modeling data, or any combination thereof. The optimized etching data can include optimized recipe data, optimized profile data, or optimized modeling data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0110" num="0109">When the wafer is sent to the etching subsystem, the wafer can be processed by the etching subsystem using the tuned etching data and/or optimized etching data when the update state is the first value, and updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer. The wafer can be processed using non-updated procedures when the update state is the second value, and non-updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer. For example, when the update state is the first value, the tuned etching data and/or the optimized etching data can be used by the etching subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed and the current wafer can be processed by the etching subsystem using the updated procedure, and when the update state is the second value, the tuned etching data and/or the optimized etching data cannot be used by the etching subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed by the etching subsystem and the wafer can be processed using a non-updated procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0111" num="0110">The RTO <b>210</b> can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create tuned deposition data when the RTPT state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the third value (SQ<b>3</b>); can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create optimized deposition data when the optimization state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the third value (SQ<b>3</b>); can feed forward the tuned deposition data and/or the optimized deposition data when the feedforward state is the first value; and/or can pass-through the tuned deposition data and/or the optimized deposition data when the pass-through state is the first value. The tuned deposition data can include tuned recipe data, tuned profile data, or tuned modeling data, or any combination thereof. The optimized deposition data can include optimized recipe data, optimized profile data, or optimized modeling data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0112" num="0111">When the wafer is sent to the deposition subsystem, the wafer can be processed by the deposition subsystem using the tuned deposition data and/or optimized deposition data when the update state is the first value, and updated deposition data can be established for the processed wafer. The wafer can be processed using non-updated procedures when the update state is the second value, and non-updated measurement data can be established for the measured wafer. For example, when the update state is the first value, the tuned deposition data and/or the optimized deposition data can be used by the deposition subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed and the current wafer can be processed by the deposition subsystem using the updated procedure, and when the update state is the second value, the tuned deposition data and/or the optimized deposition data cannot be used by the deposition subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed by the deposition subsystem and the wafer can be processed using a non-updated procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0113" num="0112">The RTO <b>210</b> can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create tuned measurement data when the RTPT state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the fourth value (SQ<b>4</b>); can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create optimized measurement data when the optimization state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the fourth value (SQ<b>4</b>); can feed forward the tuned measurement data and/or the optimized measurement data when the feedforward state is the first value; and/or can pass-through the tuned measurement data and/or the optimized measurement data when the pass-through state is the first value. The tuned measurement data can include tuned recipe data, tuned profile data, or tuned modeling data, or any combination thereof. The optimized measurement data can include optimized recipe data, optimized profile data, or optimized modeling data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0114" num="0113">When the wafer is sent to the measurement subsystem, the wafer can be measured by the measurement subsystem using the tuned measurement data and/or optimized measurement data when the update state is the first value, and updated measurement data can be established for the measured wafer. The wafer can be measured using non-updated procedures when the update state is the second value, and non-updated measurement data can be established for the measured wafer. For example, when the update state is the first value, the tuned measurement data and/or the optimized measurement data can be used by the measurement subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is measured and the current wafer can be measured by the measurement subsystem using the updated procedure, and when the update state is the second value, the tuned measurement data and/or the optimized measurement data cannot be used by the measurement subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is measured by the measurement subsystem and the wafer can be measured using a non-updated procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0115" num="0114">The RTO <b>210</b> can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create tuned external measurement data when the RTPT state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the fifth value (SQ<b>5</b>); can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create optimized external measurement data when the optimization state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the fifth value (SQ<b>5</b>); can feedforward the tuned external measurement data and/or the optimized external measurement data when the feedforward state is the first value; and/or can pass-through the tuned external measurement data and/or the optimized external measurement data when the pass-through state is the first value. The tuned external measurement data can include tuned recipe data, tuned profile data, or tuned modeling data, or any combination thereof. The optimized external measurement data can include optimized recipe data, optimized profile data, or optimized modeling data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0116" num="0115">When the wafer is sent to the external measurement subsystem, the wafer can be measured by the external measurement subsystem using the tuned external measurement data and/or optimized external measurement data when the update state is the first value, and updated external measurement data can be established for the measured wafer. The wafer can be measured using non-updated procedures when the update state is the second value, and non-updated external measurement data can be established for the measured wafer. For example, when the update state is the first value, the tuned external measurement data and/or the optimized external measurement data can be used by the external measurement subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is measured and the current wafer can be measured by the external measurement subsystem using the updated procedure, and when the update state is the second value, the tuned external measurement data and/or the optimized external measurement data cannot be used by the external measurement subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is measured by the external measurement subsystem and the wafer can be measured using a non-updated procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0117" num="0116">The RTO <b>210</b> can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create tuned alignment data when the RTPT state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the sixth value (SQ<b>6</b>); can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to create optimized alignment data when the optimization state is the first value, and the sequencing state is the sixth value (SQ<b>6</b>); can feedforward the tuned alignment data and/or the optimized alignment data when the feedforward state is the first value; and/or can pass-through the tuned alignment data and/or the optimized alignment data when the pass-through state is the first value. The tuned alignment data can include tuned recipe data, tuned profile data, or tuned modeling data, or any combination thereof. The optimized alignment data can include optimized recipe data, optimized profile data, or optimized modeling data, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0118" num="0117">Alternatively, a wafer can be stored temporally in the transfer subsystem <b>160</b> when the sequencing state is the sixth value (SQ<b>6</b>) and when delay time is required or an error has occurred. In addition, a wafer can be stored temporally in another subsystem when delay time is required or an error has occurred. For example, short delay times may be used to allow more time for feedforward messages and/or data to be created, processed, sent, and/or received.</p>
<p id="p-0119" num="0118">When the wafer is sent to the transfer subsystem, the wafer can be processed by the transfer subsystem using the tuned alignment data and/or optimized alignment data when the update state is the first value, and updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer. The wafer can be processed using non-updated procedures when the update state is the second value, and non-updated process result data can be established for the processed wafer. For example, when the update state is the first value, the tuned alignment data and/or the optimized alignment data can be used by the transfer subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed and the current wafer can be processed by the transfer subsystem using the updated procedure, and when the update state is the second value, the tuned alignment data and/or the optimized alignment data cannot be used by the transfer subsystem to update a procedure before the wafer is processed by the transfer subsystem and the wafer can be processed using a non-updated procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0120" num="0119">The MES can collect data including measured, processing, historical, and real-time data, can establish the wafer state, and can create and send output messages that can include real-time feedforward messages and/or data. Alternatively, a subsystem can collect data including set-up data, configuration data, historical data, input data, output data, priority data, delay data, fault data, response data, error data, feedforward data, feedback data, pass-through data, internal data, external data, tuning and/or tuned data, optimization and/or optimized data, status data, timing data, process results data, and/or measured data, can change the wafer state, and can create real-time feedforward messages and/or data.</p>
<p id="p-0121" num="0120">A transfer subsystem (<b>160</b> <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>) can be used to receive and/or store a plurality of wafers. A controller can be used to select a wafer from the plurality of wafers, and the controller can use wafer state data and the processing sequence data from the MES.</p>
<p id="p-0122" num="0121">Formatted messages can be parsed to create the output messages, the internal messages, or the real-time feedforward messages. For example, a TCD can parse the formatted message, can remove data targeted for the etching subsystem, and can reconstruct a message compatible with the processing system.</p>
<p id="p-0123" num="0122">The real-time wafer data and/or process data can include bottom CD data, middle CD data, top CD data, or angle data, or any combination thereof and the processing system can comprise an etching tool and the etching tool uses the real-time wafer state and/or process state data to determine an etching time to use when etching a deep trench on the wafer, to determine an etching time to use when etching a dual damascene structure on the wafer, to determine an etching time to use when etching a gate structure on the wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0124" num="0123">A RTO and/or TCD can be coupled to another TCD, to another RTO, an external processing tool, or an external measurement tool, or any combination thereof. A RTO and/or TCD can be used to translate from XML to SML, or from SML to XML, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0125" num="0124">Furthermore, one or more of the TCDs (<b>225</b>, <b>235</b>, and <b>245</b>) in the RTO <b>210</b> can generate and send output messages in response to the input messages.</p>
<p id="p-0126" num="0125">The RTPT parameters can include layer information. In some embodiments, the RTPT parameters can include real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data. In one example, real-time wafer thickness and uniformity data may be provided to a measurement subsystem after a developing process. Material variations and/or process variations that occur during and/or after the development process can affect the layer properties and can change across a wafer, wafer-to-wafer, process-to-process, lot-to-lot. In a second example, real-time wafer thickness and uniformity data may be provided to a measurement subsystem after an etching process. Material variations and/or process variations that occur during and/or after the etching process can affect the physical properties and can change across a wafer, wafer-to-wafer, process-to-process, lot-to-lot. In another example, real-time wafer thickness and uniformity data may be provided to a measurement subsystem after a deposition process. Material variations and/or process variations that occur during and/or after the deposition process can affect the wafer thickness and/or uniformity and can change across a wafer, wafer-to-wafer, process-to-process, lot-to-lot.</p>
<p id="p-0127" num="0126">For example, many current factory systems do not include procedures for communicating wafer layer information to the measurement subsystem after the wafer is processed. Layer variations caused by a wafer process may not be uniform across the wafer, due to, for example, chamber-to-chamber variations, processing times, processing chemistries, and chamber drift over time.</p>
<p id="p-0128" num="0127">The new thickness data may be used by a real-time process optimizer <b>220</b> to update, tune, and/or optimize an etching recipe by using the thickness variations to establish new etching times and/or re-prioritize the end-point timing. The new thickness data may be used by a real-time profile optimizer <b>230</b> to reduce a search range associated with profile specific etching recipes and improve the accuracy of the etching process. The new thickness data may be used by a real-time model optimizer <b>240</b> to update an etching and/or chamber model by over-riding the current and/or default model values.</p>
<p id="p-0129" num="0128">Real-time data from material processing procedures obtained just prior to the next process step can be fed forward and can be used before the next process is performed to calculate new process parameters to improve the process accuracy and precision. The real-time data can be passed to a processing tool as RTPT procedure variables/parameters, can be used to override current recipe, profile, and/or model default values, and can be used to narrow the search space for determining recipes, profiles, and/or models and their associated accuracy limits.</p>
<p id="p-0130" num="0129">When the sequencing state is the first value (SQ<b>1</b>), a wafer can be sent to a lithography subsystem <b>110</b>, and process data that can include real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be obtained when a wafer is being processed. Some of the process data from the lithography subsystem can be fed forward to one or more other subsystems that will perform subsequent processes.</p>
<p id="p-0131" num="0130">RTO <b>210</b> can be used to prevent the feedforward messages and/or data from being sent until the recipient is ready to use the feedforward messages and/or data. In one example, before messages and/or data are sent, the recipient can be sent test messages, and the recipient can send back response messages that can include status data. In other examples, the RTO can wait a pre-determined length of time, or can obtain delay time data from a response message.</p>
<p id="p-0132" num="0131">Delay time variables can be used to delay wafers, calculations, processes, and/or measurements. For example, delay times can be used to prevent feedforward data from arriving before it can be used by calculations, processes, and/or measurements for the current wafer. Delay times can be determined by a wafer state, a sequencing state, a MES, a controller, and/or a subsystem. Delay time variables can be used by one or more of the real-time optimizers (<b>220</b>, <b>230</b>, and/or <b>240</b>), and/or one or more of the TCDs (<b>225</b>, <b>235</b>, and <b>245</b>) in the RTO <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0133" num="0132">One or more RTOs can be configured inside or outside the measurement subsystem and/or the processing subsystem. For example, when a RTO is separated from a subsystem, a feedforward state value can be used to control the inputs to the RTO and an update state value can be used to control the outputs from the RTO to the subsystem. For example, when the feedforward state is the first value, a RTPT and/or optimized procedure can be created before the wafer is processed, and when the feedforward state is the second value, the processing procedure cannot be tuned and/or optimized before the wafer is processed. When the feedforward state is the first value, tuning data and/or optimization data can be fed forward to the RTO before the wafer is processed, and when the feedforward state is the second value, the tuning and/or optimization data cannot be fed forward to the RTO before the wafer is processed. When the update state is the first value, the tuned and/or optimized data created by the RTO can be fed forward from the RTO to the subsystem and can be used to process the wafer, and when update state is the second value the tuned and/or optimized data cannot be used to process the wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0134" num="0133">Some procedures can include processing the wafer using an optimized processing when the optimization state is the first value; identifying the processed wafer as an optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and identifying processing data associated with the optimized wafer as optimized processing data. In addition, the wafer can be processed using a non-optimized processing procedure when the optimization state is a second value; the processed wafer can be identified as a non-optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the processing data associated with the non-optimized wafer can be identified as non-optimized processing data.</p>
<p id="p-0135" num="0134">The wafer can be processed using a tuned processing procedure when the RTPT state is the first value; the processed wafer can be identified as a tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the processing data associated with the tuned wafer can be identified as tuned processing data. The wafer can be processed using an un-tuned processing procedure when the RTPT state is the second value; the processed wafer can be identified as an un-tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the processing data associated with the un-tuned wafer can be identified as un-tuned processing data.</p>
<p id="p-0136" num="0135">In some examples, an input message can be a formatted message comprising recipe data and feedforward data. A TCD can process the formatted message and create a separate recipe message for the processing tool and a separate feedforward message for the measurement tool. For example, the TCD can parse the formatted message. When the TCD is operating in a &#x201c;Feed Forward&#x201d; mode, a separate recipe message may or may not be sent to the processing tool, and a separate feedforward message can be sent to a measurement tool. The feedforward message can include real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data that can be used to determine in real-time which profile library to use when analyzing information from the measurement tool. When real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data is provided to a metrology tool, the calculation errors can be reduced and the accuracy is improved. In some cases, a smaller profile space within a library space can be identified using the feedforward data. For example, the feedforward thickness data allows the ODP procedure to determine profiles from the profile library in real-time, thereby decreasing measurement time and increasing throughput.</p>
<p id="p-0137" num="0136"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a schematic representation of a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD) in accordance with embodiments of the invention. In the illustrated embodiment, a semiconductor processing system <b>300</b> is shown that includes a data transfer system <b>390</b>, a MES system <b>380</b>, a processing subsystem <b>320</b>, a measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, and a TCD <b>310</b>. In addition, multiple devices and/or systems can be included. Alternatively, other systems, other devices, other elements, and/or other systems may be included.</p>
<p id="p-0138" num="0137">The data transfer system <b>390</b> can be coupled to one or more processing subsystems <b>320</b> and can exchange information with the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using one or more bidirectional links <b>396</b> and one or more ports (<b>395</b>, <b>325</b>). Alternatively, a port and/or a bi-directional link may not be required. For example, link <b>396</b> can support XML and/or SECS-GEM messages and data transfers. In addition, other transfer protocols can be supported. A processing subsystem <b>320</b> can be part of an integrated semiconductor processing system <b>300</b> or be external to a semiconductor processing system.</p>
<p id="p-0139" num="0138">The data transfer system <b>390</b> can be coupled to one or more measurement subsystems <b>340</b> and can exchange information with the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using one or more bidirectional links <b>394</b> and one or more ports (<b>397</b>, <b>346</b>). Alternatively, a port and/or a bidirectional link may not be required. For example, link <b>394</b> can support XML and/or SECS-GEM messages and data transfers. In addition, other transfer protocols can be supported. A measurement subsystem <b>340</b> can be part of an integrated semiconductor processing system <b>300</b> or be external to the semiconductor processing system <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0140" num="0139">The MES <b>380</b> can be coupled to the data transfer system <b>390</b> using one or more bidirectional links <b>382</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0141" num="0140">The one or more processing subsystems <b>320</b> can be coupled to one or more measurement subsystems <b>340</b> and these subsystems can exchange information with each other using one or more bi-directional links <b>324</b> and one or more ports (<b>327</b>, <b>345</b>). Alternatively, a port and/or a bi-directional link may not be required. For example, link <b>324</b> can support XML and/or SECS-GEM messages and data transfers. In addition, other transfer protocols can be supported. For example, a processing system <b>320</b> can include one or more subsystems such as subsystems (<b>110</b>, <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>, <b>140</b>, and <b>150</b>, <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>). Alternatively, other configurations may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0142" num="0141">The data transfer system <b>390</b> can be coupled to one or more TCDs <b>310</b> and can exchange information with the TCD <b>310</b> using one or more bi-directional links <b>391</b> and one or more ports (<b>311</b>, <b>393</b>). Alternatively, a port and/or a bi-directional link may not be required. For example, link <b>391</b> can support XML and/or SECS-GEM messages and data transfers. In addition, other transfer protocols can be supported. A TCD <b>310</b> can be integrated into a semiconductor processing system <b>300</b> in a variety of ways or can be external to the semiconductor processing system <b>300</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0143" num="0142">One or more TCDs <b>310</b> can be coupled to one or more processing subsystems <b>320</b> can exchange information with the one or more processing subsystems <b>320</b> using one or more bidirectional links <b>322</b> and one or more ports (<b>312</b>, <b>323</b>). Alternatively, a port and/or a bidirectional link may not be required. For example, link <b>322</b> can support XML and/or SECS-GEM messages and data transfers. In addition, other transfer protocols can be supported.</p>
<p id="p-0144" num="0143">In addition, one or more TCDs <b>310</b> can be coupled to one or more measurement subsystems <b>340</b>, and can exchange information with the one or more measurement subsystems <b>340</b> using one or more bidirectional links <b>342</b> and one or more ports (<b>313</b>, <b>347</b>). Alternatively, a port and/or a bi-directional link may not be required. For example, link <b>342</b> can support XML and/or SCS-GEM messages and data transfers. In addition, other transfer protocols can be supported.</p>
<p id="p-0145" num="0144">TCD <b>310</b> can comprise a controller <b>318</b> and a message handler <b>319</b> that can perform message-processing procedures for receiving, building, parsing, sending, splitting, combining, and/or routing messages and other data items. The message handler <b>319</b> can comprise a first port <b>311</b>, a second port <b>312</b>, and a third port <b>313</b>. Alternatively, a different number of ports may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0146" num="0145">In one embodiment, a first path <b>315</b> can be established between the first port <b>311</b> and the second port <b>312</b>, and a second path <b>316</b> can be established between the first port <b>341</b> and the third port <b>343</b>, and one or more input messages can be received at port <b>311</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0147" num="0146">In some embodiments, TCD <b>311</b> can receive one or more input messages that can include one or more feedforward messages and one or more pass-through messages. Alternatively, the input messages can include other messages and/or data. TCD <b>311</b> can process the input messages, and can send one or more output messages. The output messages include feedforward messages and/or pass-through messages. Alternatively, the output messages can include other messages and/or data. TCD <b>311</b> can feed forward one or more feedforward messages when the input message includes a feedforward message, and/or can pass through a pass-through message when the input message includes a pass-through message.</p>
<p id="p-0148" num="0147">In some examples, the first path <b>315</b> can be used for transferring messages and/or data between the MES <b>380</b> and the processing system <b>320</b>. The second path <b>316</b> can be used for transferring messages and/or data between the MES <b>380</b> and the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>. For example, the first path <b>315</b> is established when a first TCD enablement parameter is a first value (&#x201c;true&#x201d;), and the first path <b>315</b> is not established when the first TCD enablement parameter is a second value (&#x201c;false&#x201d;). In addition, the second path <b>316</b> is established when a second TCD enablement parameter is a first value (&#x201c;true&#x201d;), and the second path <b>316</b> is not established when the second TCD enablement parameter is a second value (&#x201c;false&#x201d;). Alternatively, other logic may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0149" num="0148">In a first mode, a first TCD enablement parameter can be the first value (&#x201c;true&#x201d;), a first path <b>315</b> can be established through the TCD, the TCD can send one or more output messages to the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>, and can receive one or more input (response) messages from the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>. The second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value (&#x201c;true&#x201d;), a second path <b>316</b> can be established through the TCD, the TCD can send one or more output messages to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>, and can receive one or more input (response) messages from the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0150" num="0149">In some examples, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the pass-through state is the first value (&#x201c;pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the first path <b>315</b> to pass through the pass-through message to the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b> and can receive one or more response messages from the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the feed-forward state is the first value (&#x201c;feed-forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a feed-forward message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the second path <b>316</b> to feed forward the feed-forward message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b> and can receive one or more response messages from the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0151" num="0150">In other examples, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the feed-forward state is the first value (&#x201c;feed-forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a feed-forward message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the first path <b>315</b> to feed forward the feed-forward message to the processing subsystem using link <b>322</b>, and can receive one or more response messages from the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the pass-through state is the first value (&#x201c;pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the second path <b>316</b> to pass through the pass-through message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>, and can receive one or more response messages from the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0152" num="0151">Alternatively, the first TCD enablement parameter and the second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the feed-forward state is the first value (&#x201c;feed-forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a feed-forward message. TCD <b>311</b> can feed forward the feed-forward message to processing subsystem <b>320</b> and/or the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> and can receive one or more input (response) messages from processing subsystem <b>320</b> and/or the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>. In addition, the first TCD enablement parameter and the second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the pass-through state is the first value (&#x201c;pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> can pass through the pass-through message to processing subsystem <b>320</b> and/or the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> and can receive one or more input (response) messages from processing subsystem <b>320</b> and/or the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0153" num="0152">In other cases, a first TCD enablement parameter can be the first value (&#x201c;true&#x201d;), a first path <b>315</b> can be established through the TCD, and the TCD can send one or more output messages to the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>, and receive one or more input (response) messages from the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>. The second TCD enablement parameter can be the second value (&#x201c;false&#x201d;), a second path <b>316</b> is not established through the TCD, and the TCD does not send one or more output messages to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> via port <b>313</b>. For example, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the pass-through state is the first value, and/or when the input message includes a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the first path <b>315</b> to pass through the pass-through message to the processing subsystem using link <b>322</b>, and can receive one or more response messages from the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the feedforward state is the second value (&#x201c;do not feed forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a feedforward message. TCD <b>311</b> does not feed forward a feedforward message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0154" num="0153">Alternatively, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the feedforward state is the first value (&#x201c;feedforward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a feedforward message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the first path <b>315</b> to feed forward the feedforward message to the processing subsystem using link <b>322</b>, and can receive one or more response messages from the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using link <b>322</b>. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the pass-through state is the second value (&#x201c;do not pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> does not pass through a pass-through message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0155" num="0154">In additional cases, a first TCD enablement parameter can be the second value (&#x201c;false&#x201d;), a first path <b>315</b> is not established through the TCD, and the TCD does not send one or more output messages to the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using port <b>312</b>. The second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value (&#x201c;true&#x201d;), a second path <b>316</b> can be established through the TCD, and the TCD can send one or more output messages to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>, and receive one or more response messages from the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>. For example, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the pass-through state is the second value (&#x201c;do not pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> does not pass through a pass-through message to the processing subsystem via port <b>312</b>. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the feedforward state is a first value (&#x201c;feed forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a feedforward message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the second path <b>316</b> to feed forward the feedforward message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>, and can receive one or more response messages from the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0156" num="0155">Alternatively, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the feedforward state is the second value (&#x201c;do not feed forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a feedforward message. TCD <b>311</b> does not feed forward a feedforward message to the processing subsystem. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the first value when the pass-through state is the first value (&#x201c;pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message includes a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> can use the second path <b>316</b> to pass through the pass-through message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>343</b>, and can receive one or more response messages from the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> using link <b>342</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0157" num="0156">In still other cases, a first TCD enablement parameter can be the second value (&#x201c;false&#x201d;), the first path <b>315</b> is not established through the TCD, and the TCD does not send one or more output messages to the processing subsystem <b>320</b> using port <b>312</b>. The second TCD enablement parameter can be the second value (&#x201c;false&#x201d;), the second path <b>316</b> is not established through the TCD, and the TCD does not send one or more output messages to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> via port <b>313</b>. For example, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the pass-through state is the second value (&#x201c;do not pass-thru&#x201d;, and/or when the input message does not include a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> does not use the first path <b>315</b> to pass through the pass-through message to the processing subsystem. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the feedforward state is the second value (&#x201c;do not feed forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a feedforward message. TCD <b>311</b> does not use the second path <b>316</b> to feed forward the feedforward message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b> via port <b>313</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0158" num="0157">Alternatively, the first TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the feedforward state is the second value (&#x201c;do not feed forward&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a feedforward message. TCD <b>311</b> does not use the first path <b>315</b> to feed forward the feedforward message to the processing subsystem. In addition, the second TCD enablement parameter can be the second value when the pass-through state is the second value (&#x201c;do not pass-thru&#x201d;), and/or when the input message does not include a pass-through message. TCD <b>311</b> does not use the second path <b>316</b> to pass through the pass-through message to the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0159" num="0158">In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, single subsystems are shown, and alternatively, a different number of processing subsystems having any number of controllers associated with them in addition to other types of processing tools and modules may be used. The processing subsystem <b>320</b> can include one or more etch tools, deposition tools, ALD tools, measurement tools, ionizations tools, polishing tools, coating tools, developing tools, cleaning tools, exposure tools, and thermal treatment tools.</p>
<p id="p-0160" num="0159">The processing subsystem <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b> can include GUI components (not shown) and can include memory components (not shown) that can include one or more computer-readable storage media. In addition, the processing subsystem <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b> can exchange information using one or more computer-readable storage media. Operational data, process data, library data, historical data, and/or computer executable code can be stored and/or used.</p>
<p id="p-0161" num="0160">In addition, before, during, and/or after data collection, an analysis strategy can be executed, and FDC (fault detection and classification), judgment, and/or intervention plans can be executed. When an analysis strategy is executed, wafer data, process data, module data, TCD-related data, RTO-related data, and/or RTPT-related data can be analyzed, and alarm/fault conditions can be identified. In addition, when judgment and/or intervention rules are associated with TCD-related procedures, RTO-related procedures, and/or RTPT-related procedures, they can be executed. For example, after TCD-related data, RTO-related data, and/or RTPT-related data have been created, the data can be analyzed using intervention and/or judgment rule evaluation techniques. Intervention and/or judgment rule evaluation procedures and/or limits can be performed based on historical data, on the customer's experience, or process knowledge, or obtained from a host computer.</p>
<p id="p-0162" num="0161">As feature sizes decrease below the 65 nm node accurate measurement data becomes more important and more difficult to obtain. RTPT procedures can be used to more accurately etch and measure these ultra-small features. The TCD-related data can be compared with the warning and/or control limits, and when a run-rule is violated, an alarm can be generated, indicating a processing problem.</p>
<p id="p-0163" num="0162">When an alarm is generated, a controller can perform notification procedures and/or intervention procedures. Notification can be via e-mail or by an e-mail activated pager. An intervention procedure can be used to pause and/or stop a process at the end of the current lot, or after the current wafer. A controller can identify the processing module and/or procedure that caused the alarm to be generated. An intervention procedure can cause a wafer and/or process to proceed using non-updated recipes and/or data.</p>
<p id="p-0164" num="0163">The processing subsystem <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b> can include FDC procedures, and they can exchange FDC information with each other and/or the MES <b>380</b>. Rules can be used in FDC procedures to determine how to respond to alarm conditions, error conditions, fault conditions, and/or warning conditions. In addition, the MES <b>380</b> can send command and/or override information to the processing system <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b>, or any combination thereof. One or more FDC procedures can be running at the same time and can send and/or receive information concerning an alarm/error/fault condition. FDC information can be exchanged via a network, e-mail, or personal communication devices. For example, an alarm/error/fault condition can be established, and a message can be sent to pause the current process or to stop the current process when a limit is reached or exceeded, or when a product requirement is not met, or when a corrective action is required. The FDC procedures can prioritize and/or classify faults, predict system performance, predict preventative maintenance schedules, decrease maintenance downtime, and extend the service life of consumable parts in the system. The interfaces to the RTPT and/or FDC procedures can be web-enabled, can provide a real-time status display, and can be used for real-time intervention.</p>
<p id="p-0165" num="0164">The processing subsystem <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b> can control multiple processing procedures and/or models that are executed at the same time and are subject to different sets of process constraints. For example, a controller can run in three different modes: simulation mode, test mode, and standard mode. A controller can operate in simulation mode in parallel with the other modes. RTPT procedures can be run in real-time and produce real-time data, and FDC procedures can be run in real-time and produce real-time faults and/or errors. In addition, RTPT procedures can be run in a simulation mode and produce real-time simulation data, and FDC procedures can be run in a simulation mode and produce real-time predicted faults and/or errors.</p>
<p id="p-0166" num="0165">The processing subsystem <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b> can take various actions in response to an alarm/fault, depending on the nature of the alarm/fault. The actions taken on the alarm/fault can be context-based, and the context can be specified by a rule, a system/process recipe, a module type, module identification number, load port number, cassette number, lot number, control job ID, process job ID, slot number and/or the type of data.</p>
<p id="p-0167" num="0166">The processing subsystem <b>320</b>, the measurement subsystem <b>340</b>, or the TCD <b>310</b> can exchange information with each other and/or with the MES <b>380</b>. The information can include measurement data, process data, historical data, feed-forward data, and/or feedback data. Furthermore, the MES <b>380</b> and/or the data transfer system <b>390</b> can be used to provide external measurement data, such as external CD SEM (critical dimension scanning electron microscope) information, TEM (transmission electron microscope) information, or FIB (focused ion beam) information. External information can include adjustment factors and timestamp data that can be used to adjust for any offset between the system measurement tools and the external measurement tools. In addition, the TCD can feed forward external measurement data as soon as the data is provided by the MES <b>380</b>, or another optical metrology tool to the TCD <b>310</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0168" num="0167">One or more simulation applications can be used to compute predicted data for the wafer based on the input state, the process characteristics, and a process model. Tuned and/or optimized metrology models can be used to predict and/or calculate the smaller structures and/or features associated with the design nodes below <b>65</b> nm. An etch rate model can be used along with a processing time to compute an etch depth, and a deposition rate model can be used along with a processing time to compute a deposition thickness. For example, models can include process chemistry models, chamber models, EM models, SPC charts, PLS models, PCA models, FDC models, and Multivariate Analysis (MVA) models. For example, a TCD, a RTO, and/or a RTPT procedure can operate in a simulation mode, a test mode, and a standard mode.</p>
<p id="p-0169" num="0168">The MES <b>380</b> can create and provide wafer sampling sequences, and the wafer slot selection can be determined using a (PJ Create) function. The R2R control configuration can include, among other variables, feedforward control plan variables, feedback control plan variables, metrology calibration parameters, control limits, and SEMI Standard variable parameters. Metrology data reports can include wafer, site, structure, and composition data, among others, and the tool can report actual settings for the wafer</p>
<p id="p-0170" num="0169">The measurement subsystem <b>340</b> can include one or more iODP systems (not shown). For example, ODP techniques can be used to obtain critical dimension (CD) information, structure profile information, or via profile information, and the wavelength ranges for an ODP system can range from less than 200 nm to more than 900 nm.</p>
<p id="p-0171" num="0170">Recipes can be organized in a tree structure that can comprise recipe sets, classes, and recipes that can be displayed as objects. Recipes can include process recipe data, system recipe data, and IM recipe data. IM recipes can contain pattern recognition information, can be used to identify the sites and/or chips to sample on each wafer, and can be used to determine which ODP recipe to use. ODP recipes can be used to determine which ODP library to use, and to define the measurement metrics to report, such as top CD, bottom CD, side wall angle (SWA), layer thickness, trench width, trench depth, and goodness of fit (GOF) data.</p>
<p id="p-0172" num="0171">As the physical dimensions of the structures decrease, real-time processing using feedforward data may be required for a large percentage of the wafers to obtain more accurate etching and/or measurement data. In addition, some wafers may be used to verify a new process and/or to assess an existing process. One or more measurement procedures can be performed. When a new process is being developed and/or verified, the process results can be varying, and an assessment or verification procedure can be performed on a larger percentage of the wafers. When an assessment or verification procedure is performed a TCD can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0173" num="0172">A measurement strategy can be executed and used to establish when and how to use a measurement site. A strategy can be specified by a semiconductor manufacturer based on data stored in a historical database. For example, a semiconductor manufacturer may have historically chosen a number of sites on the wafer when making SEM measurements and would like to correlate the metrology data to the data measured using a SEM tool. In this case, the TCD could be used to feedforward data for those sites. Other manufacturers can use TEM and/or FIB data. In addition, the number of measurement sites used can be reduced as the manufacturer becomes more confident that the process is and will continue to produce high quality devices. Alternatively, other measurement procedures and/or other measurement sites may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0174" num="0173">When new and/or additional metrology data is required, optical metrology measurements can be made at one or more sites on the wafer. In one embodiment, the feedforward data can include measured data from an un-patterned area adjacent to the patterned structure, measured data from an un-patterned area that is not adjacent to the patterned structure, measured data from a test area of the same wafer, or in an area of a test wafer. In some embodiments, the feedforward data can be used for all of the sites on the wafer, or can be used for the whole lot of wafers, or can be used for a whole process run. For example, previous layer thickness data may be used for calculations until new feedforward data is obtained from the TCD.</p>
<p id="p-0175" num="0174">Measurement structures and/or features can include periodic gratings, periodic arrays, and/or other periodic structures on a wafer and can be measured at one or more of the measurement sites on a wafer. Measurement structures and/or features on a wafer may be in a resist layer, or in an ARC layer, or in any combination thereof. In addition, the measurement structures and/or features on a wafer may be created using a resist layer, or an ARC layer, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0176" num="0175">A measurement procedure can be time consuming and can affect the throughput of a processing system. During process runs, a manufacturer may wish to minimize the amount of time used to measure a wafer. The measurement procedure can be context driven and different RTPT and/or optimization procedures may be performed based on the context of the wafer. For example, one or more wafers may not be measured, tuned, and/or optimized, and procedures may be performed using a subset of measurement sites included in a measurement plan.</p>
<p id="p-0177" num="0176">During a development portion of the semiconductor process, historical data can be created and stored for later use. The historical data can include measured data at a number of measurement sites. Before, during, and/or after a procedure is performed, prediction data can be created and/or modified. The new prediction data can be fed forward by a TCD to update the calculations, models, and/or results. Before, during, and/or after a procedure is performed, confidence data can be created and/or modified. The new confidence data can be fed forward by a TCD to update the calculations, models, and/or results. The confidence data can include confidence values for the measured data, the predicted data, the modeling data, and/or the process data.</p>
<p id="p-0178" num="0177">The historical data can include GOF data, thermal data, thickness data, via-related data, CD data, CD profile data, material related data, trench-related data, sidewall angle data, differential width data, or any combination thereof. The measurement data can also include site result data, site number data, CD measurement flag data, number of measurement sites data, coordinate X data, and coordinate Y data, among others.</p>
<p id="p-0179" num="0178">RTPT procedures can be used by an etching subsystem to adjust etching recipes and/or models in real-time to etch three-dimensional structures, such as dual-damascene structures, contacts, vias, and gates. In addition, RTPT procedures can be used by measurement subsystems to adjust process and/or measurement recipes and/or models in real-time to measure three-dimensional structures, such as contacts, vias, and gates. The three-dimensional structures can increase the sensitivity of thickness variations and require structure modeling and/or measurements in multiple directions. Measurement subsystems can cause through-put problems and higher measurement throughput can be obtained by adjusting the sampling locations, and structures dynamically.</p>
<p id="p-0180" num="0179">In a semiconductor processing system, multiple processing and/or measurement tools can be present and tool matching can be a critical issue. In some cases, data from integrated metrology tools must be matched with data from external and/or reference metrology tools. RTPT procedures can be used for metrology data matching between tools and can be used to create the calibration adjustments needed by a measurement subsystem. These adjustments can be made as R2R calculations, and can be reported to the host.</p>
<p id="p-0181" num="0180">RTPT procedures can update an etching recipe, profile, and/or model using data for different thickness, different temperatures, different sites, different wafers, different tools, and/or different processes. The data can include average values, limit values, tolerance values, within-wafer variation values, wafer-to-wafer variation values, and/or lot-to-lot variation values. For example, the data can include a wafer thickness variation from center to edge after an etching process, after a deposition process, development process, or a thermal process.</p>
<p id="p-0182" num="0181">In addition, variations in etch EPD times can cause wafer thickness variations that can be fed forward to a measurement subsystem. The measurement subsystem can use X&#x26;Y measurement maps for dynamic measurements. In some instances, a gate etch process can damage the high K material and nitride layer causing a change in the wafer thickness and film optical properties.</p>
<p id="p-0183" num="0182">RTPT procedures can use single or multiple tuning variables. When multiple variables are used a classification system can be used to establish which tuning variable should be calculated first.</p>
<p id="p-0184" num="0183">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="28pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>External (&#x3bc;m)</entry>
<entry>External (&#x3bc;m)</entry>
<entry>Internal (&#x3bc;m)</entry>
<entry>Internal (&#x3bc;m)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Site #</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
<entry>X</entry>
<entry>Y</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="28pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="49pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="42pt" align="char" char="."/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="49pt" align="char" char="."/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>1</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2650</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;41550</entry>
<entry>26093</entry>
<entry>131721</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>2</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;2650</entry>
<entry>2130</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;105484</entry>
<entry>66149</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>3</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;68450</entry>
<entry>2130</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;39693</entry>
<entry>88017</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>4</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;35550</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;107070</entry>
<entry>59023</entry>
<entry>66212</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>5</entry>
<entry>63150</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;85230</entry>
<entry>124821</entry>
<entry>66235</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>6</entry>
<entry>63150</entry>
<entry>67650</entry>
<entry>59045</entry>
<entry>687</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>7</entry>
<entry>30250</entry>
<entry>133170</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6759</entry>
<entry>668</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>8</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;85205</entry>
<entry>13160</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;72561</entry>
<entry>642</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>9</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;68450</entry>
<entry>13160</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;138341</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;43014</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>10</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;52855</entry>
<entry>13160</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;6745</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;43014</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>11</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;52855</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;7920</entry>
<entry>91956</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;42986</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>12</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;68450</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;7920</entry>
<entry>59069</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;86675</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>13</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;85205</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;7920</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;39625</entry>
<entry>&#x2212;108545</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0185" num="0184">Table 1 shows the X&#x26;Y coordinates for 13 exemplary measurement sites used by an external metrology tool (second and third column), and the X&#x26;Y coordinates for 13 measurement sites used by an internal metrology tool (fourth and fifth column). In some examples, the RTPT procedures can use the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data that is fed forward after a process as a tuning variable. Wafer thickness differences can occur when measurements are made using internal tools and external tools, and the differences can change over time. RTPT procedures can use the data from an internal and/or external metrology tool, and can be used to relate the data from one tool to another tool.</p>
<p id="p-0186" num="0185">For example, RTPT procedures may be used to tune and/or optimize downloaded metrology information or default data in an iODP application, to set or fix ODP model parameters such as wafer thickness, material properties, and/or optical properties that change with thickness and/or time, to tune and/or optimize recipes, profiles, and/or models with minimal impact to the host software, to extend the current variable parameter adjust message to include a list of parameter names and values by site and by wafer, and use an open-ended list to allow for flexibility of adding new parameters.</p>
<p id="p-0187" num="0186">During RTPT procedures, calculated data and/or predicted data can be fed forward to narrow search ranges, to increase the accuracy of processes and/or measurements, and to reduce process and/or measurement times.</p>
<p id="p-0188" num="0187">RTPT procedures can be used with systems, subsystems, tools, and/or sensors. RTPT parameters can be structured as system level objects, tool level objects, lot level objects, wafer level objects, site level objects, optimization objects, and/or tuning objects.</p>
<p id="p-0189" num="0188">When TCDs are created, one or more message types can be used, such as Connect messages, Return messages, setMeasurementParameters messages. onTuningStatusChangeRequest Event messages, tuningStatusChanged messages, SECS-GEM messages, and XML messages.</p>
<p id="p-0190" num="0189">The TCD can support a connect message that can be used to initiate communications between a server interface and a client. The TCD can support a Return message to the primary message. The primary message can be initiated by the client and the Return made by the server. For example, if the server does not recognize the client version number or the client's version is incompatible with server, the version can be deemed incompatible. If an incompatible version is provided, an error will be returned in the HResult.</p>
<p id="p-0191" num="0190">The TCD can support a setMeasurementParameters message that can be used to allow the client to send Tuning parameters to the controller at any point in time. The TCD can support a Return message to the primary message. The primary message shall be initiated by the client and the Return made by the server. The setMeasurementParameters message can be used to allow the client to send tuning parameter values for a particular wafer that may be used later for grating measurements on that wafer. For example, the message can contain a list of the tuning parameter values for multiple sites in the wafer. Each site can be identified by the site co-ordinates.</p>
<p id="p-0192" num="0191">The TCD can support a message and/or event sent from a controller to a TCD. The TCD can support an onTuningStatusChangeRequest event that can be sent by the controller. When the tuningEnabledStatus parameter is false, the tuning mechanism can be disabled. When the tuningEnabledStatus parameter is true, the tuning mechanism can be enabled.</p>
<p id="p-0193" num="0192">The TCD can support a message and/or event sent from TCD to an iODP application. For example, the TCD can support a tuningStatusChanged message that can be called by a TCD procedure, and this message can be sent whenever the tuning mechanism status in the TCD is changed.</p>
<p id="p-0194" num="0193">The TCD can support XML translations, and SECS-GEM&#x2014;XML Mapping. For example, an ODP parameter extracted out of the Host SECS Message can be converted &#x2018;as is&#x2019; into the correct XML representation. The XML interface may have its own exception handling.</p>
<p id="p-0195" num="0194">The TCD can support process job and control job creation. Multiple jobs can be executed in parallel, and a job can have multiple states, such as &#x201c;queued&#x201d;, &#x201c;selected&#x201d;, and &#x201c;executing&#x201d;.</p>
<p id="p-0196" num="0195">For some SECS messages between the host and the tool, standard SECS exception handling and timeouts can apply. The normal case is that both systems sent its reply message in time to the TCD. Possible exceptions are the following:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0196">The metrology tool and/or controller are responding late.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0197">The metrology tool and/or controller are not responding at all.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0198">The metrology subsystem and/or controller are responding late.</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0199">The metrology subsystem and/or controller are not responding at all.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0197" num="0200">When messages do not arrive at the correct time from the metrology tool and/or controller, a TCD procedure can assign a unique error code, such as &#x201c;No Reply from metrology tool&#x201d; or &#x201c;No Reply from metrology controller&#x201d;. When a tool is not replying, the TCD can be programmed not to take any action, and allow the host to perform the recovery operation. Alternatively, the TCD may send a return code (non-response) message to the host, and allow the host to perform the recovery operation.</p>
<p id="p-0198" num="0201">The TCD can support multiple measurement sites, multiple layers, and X &#x26; Y values for multiple sites. For example, a TCD can pass film thickness data for three layers from a factory host to the metrology tool for pre and post DTMO (deep trench mask open) measurements.</p>
<p id="p-0199" num="0202">In various embodiments, windows sockets can be used to send data. During startup, a Create Socket procedure can be performed to create a socket object; a Connect Socket procedure can be performed to connect to the socket using the created socket object; and a XML Logical Connect procedure can be performed to send the XML connect message.</p>
<p id="p-0200" num="0203">A Send XML Tuning Message Data procedure can be performed to send the XML tuning message, [e.g. send(sock, . . . , TuningMessage)]. An XML Receive Acknowledgment procedure can be performed to receive the acknowledgement from a controller [e.g. bytesRcvd=recv(sock, . . . ,recdata)].</p>
<p id="p-0201" num="0204">The TCD can support many unique structures that can be defined in SML or XML, can support substantially large structures, can support nested recursive structures, can enable automatic translation from SML to XML and XML back to SML, and can support a large number of parameters. The parameters can be related to wafer state information and can include passing location information, measurement information, design information, chip layout information, library limits, and ranges for searching. A measurement subsystem can have one or more connection ports that can be used to allow the host to communicate directly or through a TCD using XML or SML.</p>
<p id="p-0202" num="0205">An XML message can be unique to the device or a SEMI standard such as the PCS standard that enables APC applications to communicate with each other can be used to transform standard SML to XML/PCS messages. The TCD procedures can provide an automatic translation from SML to XML and XML back to SML for reply messages. Alternatively, other combinations of SML and XML may be included.</p>
<p id="p-0203" num="0206">Additional communication protocols can include an Ethernet based message structure such as SML or XML and hardware based message structures such as RS232, RS422 and Analog signal.</p>
<p id="p-0204" num="0207">The TCD software and hardware can be used to provide a substantially transparent addition of a device to a process tool or measurement tool&#x2014;enabling the factory to adjust the device recipe settings. The device can be a sensor, measurement device, or an analysis device. The parsing of the variable parameter message&#x2014;such as a S6F11 message is transparent to the tool. The feedforward information targeted for the metrology tool is removed, and the message can be reconstructed to be compatible to the target tool.</p>
<p id="p-0205" num="0208">Multiple TCDs can be cascaded together, and this can allow one TCD to be used for parsing information being downloaded to the tool while another TCD is used to merge data for reporting to the host from multiple devices.</p>
<p id="p-0206" num="0209">The TCD can provide and manage exception handling with messages that are being split or parsed for multiple devices. The confirmation replies from multiple devices can be consolidated. For example, one success message can be sent if all are successful, and one failure message can be sent if any fails. In other cases, when multiple devices have a failure, a return error can be sent for the device with the highest priority. Alternatively, a report with multiple failures may include merged the error text and priority information from all failed devices into one error text string.</p>
<p id="p-0207" num="0210">One or more TCD procedures can be used to enable two way communications for downloading parameters or recipes, for uploading data or recipes, and for handshaking. Host can query the tools, controllers, and/or TCD procedures for current status and configuration. TCD procedures can be used to communicate with multiple devices on the tool by separating the unique parameters for each device and by distributing the information to each device. For example, parameters can be sent to the controllers, processing tools, metrology tools, OES tools, RF sensors, endpoint detectors, temperature sensors, and depth sensors.</p>
<p id="p-0208" num="0211">One or more TCD procedures can be used to split downloaded message content one to many; can be used to route downloaded feedforward messages and recipe messages to different devices; can be used with multiple messages by sending one to many and merging many back to one; can be used to create a new message or event from any device and insert this message into the common data steam back to the host.</p>
<p id="p-0209" num="0212">In addition, a TCD procedure can be part of a host procedure, an additional hardware adapter between a host computer and a tool computer, part of the tool host interface, or part of one of the devices added to the tool. The TCD can be physical or virtual&#x2014;part of software module and routing the messages to different devices on the common Ethernet network.</p>
<p id="p-0210" num="0213"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an exemplary flow diagram of a procedure for processing a wafer in accordance with embodiments of the invention. In the illustrated embodiment, an exemplary procedure <b>400</b> is shown for using a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD) to process a wafer. Alternatively, other procedures and subsystems may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0211" num="0214">In <b>410</b>, wafer data such as wafer thickness and/or temperature can be collected. Data collection procedures can be performed before and/or while wafers are being etched by an etching subsystem processed by a deposition subsystem, measuring system or any other system. Data can be collected using a processing subsystem, a (MES), and/or host system. The collected data can include wafer data relating to a characteristic of the wafer or process data relating to a process associated with the wafer. The collected data can be real-time data from one or more processing tools and one or more metrology tools, for example. Data can also be collected using a database and/or library coupled to one or more processing tools and/or one or more metrology tools. In one example, data collected in step <b>410</b> includes layer or film thickness data collected from an etch subsystem. The thickness data may be thickness of an etched film that is calculated in the etch system based on etch rate, etch time, end point detection or other raw data available from the etch process. Alternatively, the collected data may be the raw etch data that can be sent to other subsystems for processing.</p>
<p id="p-0212" num="0215">In <b>415</b>, one or more input messages can be created and/or sent by a host (MES), subsystem, or system controller based on the collected data. The input message can include one or more pass-through messages and/or one or more real-time feedforward messages. A host (MES) system and/or a subsystem can process the collected data to create the input message, and can send the input message to a measurement subsystem and/or a processing subsystem. An input message may also be created, modified, and/or sent by a subsystem and/or system controller. In a preferred embodiment data collection step <b>410</b> is continuously performed for all subsystems and the collected data is continuously processed to create input messages that are sent to any or all subsystems to provide the most current information available (real-time data) to facilitate efficient and accurate performance of processing in the subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0213" num="0216">In <b>420</b>, one or more wafers can be received in a subsystem. Wafer data relating to the wafer may be received at the subsystem prior to or after receipt of the wafer. For example, a wafer lot can be received and a processing sequence can be established, a current wafer can be identified and can be sent to the etching subsystem, and a wafer state can be established for the current wafer. The wafer data can include historical and/or real-time wafer thickness or wafer temperature data. In one embodiment, the wafers are received at a measurement subsystem such as that described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0214" num="0217">In <b>425</b>, a TCD in or associated with the subsystem that received the current wafer can receive one or more input messages created and sent in step <b>415</b>. Continuing with the example above, the input message is received by a TCD associated with the measurement subsystem. An input message can include a pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof. The pass-through message can include set-up data, configuration data, historical data, input data, output data, priority data, delay data, fault data, response data, error data, feedforward data, feedback data, pass-through data, internal data, external data, tuning and/or tuned data, optimization and/or optimized data, status data, timing data, process results data, and/or measured data. The real-time feedforward message can include real-time process data, measured data or wafer data such as real-time temperature data, thickness data, n&#x26;k data, and/or uniformity data.</p>
<p id="p-0215" num="0218">In <b>430</b>, the TCD associated with the subsystem that received the wafer and input message can process one or more input messages and can obtain real-time wafer data such as wafer temperature and/or thickness data from the real-time feedforward message when at least one input message includes a real-time feedforward message. For example, the TCD can process the one or more input messages in real time into one or more pass-through messages and one or more real-time feedforward messages. The TCD can parse the real-time feedforward message to obtain the real-time wafer temperature and/or thickness data. The TCD can examine the input message to determine when the input message includes the real-time feedforward message, and/or the TCD can determine how to extract the real-time feedforward message. Continuing with the example given above, in step <b>430</b> the TCD associated with the measurement subsystem can receive an input message and process the message to obtain the thickness data collected from the etch subsystem and provided as part of a feedforward message.</p>
<p id="p-0216" num="0219">In addition, one or more TCDs associated with the subsystem that received the wafer and input message can process the one or more input messages and can obtain real-time and/or historical data from the pass-through message when at least one input message includes a pass-through message. Where the subsystem is the measurement subsystem, the pass-through data may include a measurement recipe. In some instances, real-time data associated with a current wafer being processed by a particular subsystem will be included in a pass-through message. For example, delayed data from a previous process and/or another subsystem may be used as real-time pass-through data. The TCD can parse the pass-through message to obtain the real-time data and/or historical data. The TCD can examine the input message to determine when the input message includes the real-time and/or historical data, and/or the TCD can determine how to extract the real-time and/or historical data. For example, when the pass-through state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, the pass-through the messages, the real-time data, and/or the historical data can be passed through, and when the pass-through state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, the pass-through messages, the real-time data, and/or the historical data may not be passed through.</p>
<p id="p-0217" num="0220">In <b>435</b>, a query can be performed to determine when to feed forward the feedforward message and/or data to the subsystem associated with the TCD. Continuing with the example given above, the TCD associated with the measurement subsystem can determine whether the feedforward message/data including the thickness data from the etch tool can be sent to the measurement subsystem. The TCD can use the feedforward state value to determine when to feed forward the feedforward message and/or data present in the input message. When the feedforward state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, procedure <b>400</b> can branch to <b>440</b>, and the feedforward messages and/or data can be fed forward. When the feedforward state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, procedure <b>400</b> can branch to <b>480</b>, and the feedforward messages and/or data are not fed forward to the subsystem such as the measurement subsystem, as will be further described below.</p>
<p id="p-0218" num="0221">In <b>440</b>, the feedforward messages and/or data can be fed forward to the intended subsystem such as the measurement subsystem. When the feedforward state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, the feedforward messages and/or data can be fed forward, and when the feedforward state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, the feedforward messages and/or data are not fed forward. In addition, the feedforward messages and/or data can be fed forward when the input message includes feedforward messages and/or data, and the feedforward data and/or messages are not fed forward when the input message does not include feedforward messages and/or data. For example, real-time wafer thickness, temperature, and/or n&#x26;k data from the etch subsystem can be fed forward to the measurement subsystem when the feedforward state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d; (and there is a feedforwad message/data to forward), and the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data is not fed forward when the feedforward state is the second value &#x201c;false.</p>
<p id="p-0219" num="0222">In some embodiments, the feedforward state can be determined using timing data related to a process performed in the subsystem that the feedforward message/data will be sent to. In the measurement subsystem example, the feedforward state can be the first value when the feedforward message and/or data can be fed forward before the current wafer is measured, and the feedforward state can be the second value when the feedforward message and/or data cannot be fed forward before the current wafer is measured. In addition, the feed-forward state can be the first value when the measurement procedure and/or calculation is delayed until the feed-forward message and/or data is received, and the feed-forward state can be the second value when the measurement procedure and/or calculation cannot be delayed.</p>
<p id="p-0220" num="0223">In <b>445</b>, the feedforward messages and/or data are not fed forward when the feedforward state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, or when the input message does not include a feedforward message/data. Where the feedforward data is intended for the measurement subsystem, for example, the feedforward state can be the second value when the feedforward message and/or data cannot be fed forward before the current wafer is measured. Where feedforward data is not sent to the intended subsystem, the subsystem (or a processor related thereto) cannot create a tuned or optimization procedure for use in the subsystem. Thus, the process <b>400</b> branches from <b>445</b> to <b>490</b>, where the wafer is processed in the subsystem without tuned or optimized procedures.</p>
<p id="p-0221" num="0224">Where feedforward message/data is obtained from the input message and fed forward to the intended subsystem, then the feedforward data can be used to tune or optimize a process performed in the subsystem as shown in steps <b>450</b>-<b>475</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, described below. For example, thickness data from the etch tool can be used to tune or optimize a measurement process in the measurement subsystem. For example, the tuning and optimizing procedure can be performed in a processor of the TCD and sent to the measurement subsystem, performed in an RTO and then sent to the measurement subsystem, or performed in the measurement subsystem itself based on feedforward messages/data received in the measurement subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0222" num="0225">In <b>450</b>, a query can be performed to determine when to perform a RTPT procedure using the feedforward message and/or data. When a RTPT state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, procedure <b>400</b> can branch to <b>455</b>, and when the RTPT state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, procedure <b>400</b> can branch to <b>460</b>. In one example, a controller in the measurement subsystem can use a RTPT state value to determine when to perform a RTPT procedure using the feedforward message and/or data present in the input message. When a RTPT state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, one or more RTPT procedures can be performed, and when the RTPT state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, a RTPT procedure is not performed,</p>
<p id="p-0223" num="0226">In <b>455</b>, tuned data can be created using one or more RTPT procedures. One or more RTPT procedures can be performed when the input message includes feedforward messages and/or tuning data. Continuing with the etch and measurement example above, thickness data from the etch subsystem can be used in an RTPT procedure to create tuned data such as a tuned measurement procedure that can be used to improve measurements in the measurement subsystem. As another example, real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data obtained from a previous deposition process can be fed forward and can be used as tuning parameter data in one or more RTPT procedures for an etch process. In some embodiments, a tuned etching recipe, a tuned etching profile, or a tuned etching model, or any combination thereof can be created using the RTPT procedures that use the real-time feedforward data (e.g., wafer thickness data) as tuning data when feedforward data is available before the wafer is etched. The tuned etching recipe, the tuned etching profile, or the tuned etching model, or any combination thereof can be created when the RTPT state is the first value. The tuned etching recipe, the tuned etching profile, or the tuned etching model, or any combination thereof is not created when the RTPT state is the second value. In some examples, an un-tuned etching recipe, an un-tuned etching profile, or an un-tuned etching model, or any combination thereof can be created when the RTPT state is the second value. Tuned etching recipe data, tuned etching profile data, or tuned etching model data, or any combination thereof can be sent to the etching subsystem when it is created elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0224" num="0227">In some embodiments, the RTPT state can be determined using timing data. Where the RTPT result will be sent to the measurement subsystem, for example, the RTPT state can be the first value when the RTPT procedure can be performed before the current wafer is measured, and the RTPT state can be the second value when the RTPT procedure cannot be performed before the current wafer is measured.</p>
<p id="p-0225" num="0228">In <b>460</b>, tuned processing data is not created. For example, un-tuned processing data can be created using one or more un-tuned procedures. One or more un-tuned procedures can be performed when the input message does not include feedforward messages and/or tuning data. In the measurement example developed above, an un-tuned measurement recipe, an un-tuned measurement profile, or a un-tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof can be created when the RTPT state is the second value. As another example, un-tuned etching recipe data, un-tuned etching profile data, or un-tuned etching model data, or any combination thereof can be created and/or stored when the RPTP state is the second value. The un-tuned etching recipe data, the un-tuned etching profile data, or the un-tuned etching model data, or any combination thereof can be sent to the etching subsystem if it is created elsewhere. In one embodiment, rather than creating an un-tuned procedure, step <b>460</b> may simply allow the subsystem to perform a process using a process recipe obtained from a pass through message, without any tuning thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0226" num="0229">If the RTPT procedure is not performed, then the procedure <b>400</b> continues to step <b>460</b> where it is determined whether to optimize the procedure based on the feedforward message/data. This allows the optimization procedure to be performed when feedforward data is present, but the RTPT procedure is not performed. Thus, when feedforward data is present, one or both of an RTPT procedure and an optimization procedure can be performed based on such data.</p>
<p id="p-0227" num="0230">In <b>470</b>, a query can be performed to determine when to perform an optimization procedure using the feedforward message and/or data. When the optimization state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, procedure <b>400</b> can branch to <b>475</b>, and when the RTPT state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, procedure <b>400</b> can branch to <b>480</b>. A controller in the subsystem such as the measurement subsystem can use the optimization state value to determine when to perform an optimization procedure using the feedforward message and/or optimization data present in the input message. When the optimization state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, one or more optimization procedures can be performed, and when the optimization state is a second value &#x201c;false&#x201d;, an optimization procedure is not performed.</p>
<p id="p-0228" num="0231">In <b>470</b>, optimized data can be created using one or more optimization procedures. One or more optimization procedures can be performed when the input message includes feedforward messages and/or optimization data, and an optimization procedure may not be performed when the input message does not include feedforward messages and/or optimization data. For example, real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be fed forward and can be used as tuning parameter data in one or more optimization procedures. When the feedforward state is the first value &#x201c;true&#x201d;, the real time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data is fed forward to the intended subsystem, and the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data is not fed forward when the feedforward state is the second value &#x201c;false.</p>
<p id="p-0229" num="0232">Continuing with the etch and measurement example above, thickness data from the etch subsystem can be used in an optimization procedure to create optimized data such as an optimized measurement procedure that can be used to improve measurements in the measurement subsystem. As another example, an optimized etching recipe, an optimized etching profile, or an optimized etching model, or any combination thereof can be created using the optimization procedures that use the real-time feedforward data (wafer thickness data from a previous deposition process, for example) as tuning data when feedforward data is available before the wafer is etched. The optimized etching recipe, the optimized etching profile, or the optimized etching model, or any combination thereof can be created when the optimization state is the first value. The optimized etching recipe, the optimized etching profile, or the optimized etching model, or any combination thereof is not created when the optimization state is the second value. In addition, the optimized etching recipe, the optimized etching profile, or the optimized etching model, or any combination thereof is not created when the optimization state is the second value.</p>
<p id="p-0230" num="0233">In some embodiments, the optimization state can be determined using timing data. Where the RTPT result will be sent to the measurement subsystem, for example, the optimization state can be the first value when the optimization procedure can be performed before the current wafer is measured, and the optimization state can be the second value when the optimization procedure cannot be performed before the current wafer is measured. An optimized etching recipe data, an optimized etching profile data, or an optimized etching model data, or any combination thereof can be sent to the etching subsystem when it is created elsewhere.</p>
<p id="p-0231" num="0234">In <b>480</b>, optimized data is not created. For example, non-optimized data can be created using one or more non-optimized procedures. One or more non-optimized procedures can be performed when the input message does not include feedforward messages and/or optimization data. In the measurement example developed above, non-optimized measurement recipe, a non-optimized measurement profile, or a non-optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof can be created when the optimization state is the second value. As another example, a non-optimized etching recipe, a non-optimized etching profile, or a non-optimized etching model, or any combination thereof can be created when the optimization state is the second value. A non-optimized etching recipe data, a non-optimized etching profile data, or a non-optimized etching model data, or any combination thereof can be sent to the etching subsystem when it is created elsewhere. In one embodiment, rather than creating a non-optimized procedure, step <b>465</b> may simply allow the subsystem to perform a process using a process recipe obtained from a pass through message, without any optimization thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0232" num="0235">In <b>490</b>, the current wafer can be processed by the subsystem that received the wafer and the input message, using up-dated data or non-updated data. For example, updated data can include feed-forward data, tuned data, or optimized data, or any combination thereof, and non-updated data can include historical data, un-tuned data, or non-optimized data, or any combination thereof. When the wafer is processed in the subsystem using the updated, tuned, and/or optimized data, the processed wafer and the associated processing data can be identified accordingly by changing the wafer state for the wafer. When the wafer is processed in the subsystem using the non-updated, un-tuned, and/or non-optimized data, the processed wafer and the associated processing data can be identified accordingly by changing the wafer state for the wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0233" num="0236">Continuing with the measurement example above, the measurement subsystem can perform a measurement of the wafer using an optimized and/or measurement process that was created based on the thickness data collected from a etch subsystem. Alternatively, the etching subsystem can perform an etching process based on thickness data collected from a deposition subsystem. In a preferred embodiment, an etching process can be performed using updated data including improved measurement data provided from an optimized or tuned measurement process as described above.</p>
<p id="p-0234" num="0237">Further, when a wafer is processed using updated data, the wafer and/or data associated therewith can be identified as updated. For example, when the wafer is etched in the etching subsystem using the updated recipe data, the etched wafer can be identified as an updated wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the etching (process result) data associated with the updated wafer can be identified and/or stored as updated process result (etching) data. For example, the updated etching (process result) data may include the updated recipe data and/or EPD data. When the wafer is etched in the etching subsystem using the non-updated data, the etched wafer can be identified as a non-updated wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the etching data associated with the non-updated wafer can be identified and/or stored as non-updated etching data. When the wafer is etched in the etching subsystem using the tuned data, the etched wafer can be identified as a tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the etching data associated with the tuned wafer can be identified and/or stored as tuned etching data. When the wafer is etched in the etching subsystem using the un-tuned data, the etched wafer can be identified as an un-tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the etching data associated with the un-tuned wafer can be identified and/or stored as un-tuned etching data. When the wafer is etched in the etching subsystem using the optimized data, the etched wafer can be identified as an optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the etching data associated with the optimized wafer can be identified and/or stored as optimized etching data. When the wafer is etched in the etching subsystem using the non-optimized data, the etched wafer can be identified as a non-optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the wafer; and the etching data associated with the non-optimized wafer can be identified and/or stored as non-optimized etching data.</p>
<p id="p-0235" num="0238">The etching data can also be identified as real-time feedforward data, real-time tuning data, and/or real-time optimization data for subsequent processes. Some parts of the etching data can be formatted and sent as feedforward messages and/or data, and other parts of the etching data can be formatted and sent as pass-through messages and/or data.</p>
<p id="p-0236" num="0239">In addition, profile data for the etched features and/or structures of the current wafer and/or lot can be created, enhanced, and/or modified in the etching subsystem. When updated data is used, a new profile shape and associated profile parameters can be identified and stored as updated data elements. When tuned data is used, the profile shape and associated profile parameters can be identified and stored as tuned data elements. When optimized data is used, the profile shape and associated profile parameters can be identified and stored as optimized data elements. When non-updated data is used, the profile shape and associated profile parameters can be identified and stored as non-updated data elements. When un-tuned data is used, the profile shape and associated profile parameters can be identified and stored as un-tuned data elements. When non-optimized data is used, the profile shape and associated profile parameters can be identified and stored as non-optimized data elements.</p>
<p id="p-0237" num="0240">Furthermore, modeling data for the current wafer and/or lot can be created, enhanced, and/or modified in the etching subsystem. When updated data is used, a new etching model can be identified and stored as updated modeling data. When tuned data is used, a new etching model can be identified and stored as tuned modeling data. When optimized data is used, a new etching model can be identified and stored as optimized modeling data. When non-updated data is used, a new etching model can be identified and stored as non-updated modeling data. When un-tuned data is used, a new etching model can be identified and stored as un-tuned modeling data. When non-optimized data is used, a new etching model can be identified and stored as non-optimized modeling data.</p>
<p id="p-0238" num="0241">When a simulation is performed using updated, tuned, or optimized data, the simulation model and/or simulation data can be identified and/or stored accordingly.</p>
<p id="p-0239" num="0242">A tuning procedure can be performed in real-time to create, modify, and/or use tuned etching recipe data, tuned etching profile data, or tuned etching model data, or any combination thereof. During a tuning procedure one or more RTPT procedures can be performed. An optimization procedure can be performed in real-time to create, modify, and/or use optimized etching recipe data, optimized etching profile data, or optimized etching model data, or any combination thereof. During an optimization procedure one or more RTPT procedures can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0240" num="0243">When an etch-related RTPT procedure is performed, the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature data can be used to determine an etching chemistry, or an etching time, a processing gas ratio, an expected endpoint time, heater power, and/or RF power required.</p>
<p id="p-0241" num="0244">When an RTPT procedure is performed, the real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine a wafer radius for an alignment procedure and/or a measurement procedure. For example, edge cleanliness can affect the radius. In addition, as dimensions get smaller real-time wafer temperature can have a greater impact during aligning, measuring, and/or processing. The real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature data can also be used to determine wafer curvature. Furthermore, the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine the actual wafer thickness when the aligning, measuring, and/or processing occur.</p>
<p id="p-0242" num="0245">In other RTPT procedures, the real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine a contaminant level, a contamination probability, and/or an out-gassing rate.</p>
<p id="p-0243" num="0246">When other RTPT procedures are performed, the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine a nozzle position during a deposition procedure, and/or a probe position during an alignment and/or measurement procedure. In addition, the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine the amount of energy radiated by the wafer in an alignment and/or measurement chamber. For example, the optical system, nozzle, and/or probe used may be position-sensitive and/or temperature-sensitive.</p>
<p id="p-0244" num="0247">In some RTPT procedures, the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine the optical properties for the wafer and/or used to determine a calibration factor for the optical properties.</p>
<p id="p-0245" num="0248">In some other RTPT procedures, the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26; k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine the characteristics of a mask and/or photoresist layer. For example, wafer thickness may affect CDs and/or sidewall angles. The real-time wafer thickness data, n&#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be altered by a thermal, an etching, ashing, and/or cleaning process.</p>
<p id="p-0246" num="0249">In some additional RTPT procedures, the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data and/or real-time wafer temperature can be used to determine the correct location for a measurement site on the wafer. In addition, the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be used to determine the actual wafer thickness when the measurement occurs. For example, cooling rates and/or delay times may be used. Delay times and/or cooling rates can be dependent on the process sequence being used.</p>
<p id="p-0247" num="0250">A RTO or a controller can create real-time wafer thickness data, real time n &#x26;k data, real-time wafer temperature data, real-time tuning data, and/or real-time optimization data using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message. The real-time message can include feedforward data, set-up data, configuration data, historical data, input data, output data, priority data, delay data, fault data, response data, error data, feedback data, pass-through data, internal data, external data, tuning and/or tuned data, optimization and/or optimized data, status data, timing data, process results data, and/or measured data.</p>
<p id="p-0248" num="0251">A RTO or a controller can feed forward real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data, real-time wafer temperature data, real-time tuning data, and/or real-time optimization data when the feedforward state is the first value, and does not feed forward the real-time wafer thickness data, n &#x26;k data, real-time tuning data, and/or real-time optimization data when the feedforward state is a second value. For example, one or more TCDs associated with the RTO may be used to feed forward the real-time wafer thickness data, real-time tuning data, and/or real-time optimization data to the measurement subsystem and/or other subsystems.</p>
<p id="p-0249" num="0252">The procedure can also include collecting data using a MES, a RTO, a TCD, or a controller, the collected data including historical and real-time wafer layer data; creating real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data; creating a formatted message comprising the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data; and sending the formatted message using a RTO, a TCD, or a controller.</p>
<p id="p-0250" num="0253">The TCD can be coupled to another TCD, an external processing tool, or an external measurement tool, or any combination thereof. In addition, the TCD can be coupled to a plurality of subsystems, and the TCD can process the formatted message to create separate messages for one or more of the subsystems.</p>
<p id="p-0251" num="0254">The TCD can process, separate, and/or combine error messages from one or more of the subsystems to create one or more error messages.</p>
<p id="p-0252" num="0255">The feedforward data can comprises wafer state information, location information, measurement information, vendor information, design information, chip layout information, library information, tool information, or searching information, or any combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0253" num="0256">In still other embodiments, the method of processing a wafer can include receiving a plurality of wafers and wafer data. A current wafer can be identified, a wafer state can be established for each wafer, and the wafer data can include real-time wafer data. An input message can be received by a controller, and the input message can include the pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof. The procedure can include sending the current wafer to an internal etching tool when the sequencing state is the first value, and sending the wafer to an external etching tool when the sequencing state is a second value. Other wafers in a wafer lot can be sent to other subsystems or other integrated metrology (IM) tools. The feed-forward messages and/or pass-through messages can be sent to the correct tool when the input message includes feed-forward messages and/or pass-through messages. One or more TCDs can receive, process, modify, and/or send feed-forward messages and/or pass-through messages.</p>
<p id="p-0254" num="0257"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an exemplary flow diagram of a procedure for processing a wafer in accordance with embodiments of the invention. In the illustrated embodiment, an exemplary procedure <b>500</b> is shown for using one or more TCDs to process a wafer in real time. Alternatively, other procedures may be used.</p>
<p id="p-0255" num="0258">In <b>505</b>, data is collected by the wafer processing system and messages can be created, processed, modified, sent, and/or received throughout a processing system in real time. Messages can include feed-forward data and/or pass-through data. A host (MES) system can collect the data and process the collected data to create the feed-forward data and/or pass through data. Alternatively, feed-forward data may be created and/or modified by a subsystem and/or system controller. Data collection procedures can be performed before and/or while wafers are being processed by a processing system. Preferably, data is continuously collected and messages are continuously generated and sent throughout the processing system to ensure that the most current information is available to facilitate operations in each subsystem of the wafer processing system. Data can be collected using a host (MES) system, and the collected data can include semiconductor processing data from two or more processing tools and two or more metrology tools. The processing tools can include one or more etch tools, deposition tools, ALD tools, measurement tools, ionizations tools, polishing tools, coating tools, developing tools, cleaning tools, exposure tools, and thermal treatment tools. In addition, the metrology tools can include a CD-Scanning Electron Microscopy (CDSEM) tool, a Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) tool, a focused ion beam (FIB) tool, an ODP tool, or another optical metrology tool. The processing tools and/or metrology tools can have different interface requirements. TCDs can be configured to satisfy these different interface requirements and can be used to &#x201c;transparently&#x201d; couple a number of different processing tools and/or metrology tools to an existing processing system. The collected data can include historical and real-time wafer data and/or process data. Alternatively, additional data may be created and/or modified by a subsystem and/or system controller.</p>
<p id="p-0256" num="0259">In <b>510</b>, a wafer and messages are received by a subsystem of the wafer processing system. The wafer may arrive at the subsystem either before or after the message. For example, a processing sequence can be established for the wafer by the host (MES) system, and the processing sequence can be sent in a message to the subsystem so that the a subsystem in the sequence can prepare for receiving the wafer. For example, wafer and/or process state data can be used before and/or when a wafer is received to establish a processing sequence. The processing subsystem can be a deposition subsystem, etching subsystem, lithography subsystem, or any other subsystem for performing a process on the wafer. Alternatively, a wafer can be received by a different subsystem. Further, messages may be received by the processing subsystem itself, or a TCD or RTO associated with the processing subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0257" num="0260">In one example, one or more messages can be processed in real time by one or more TCDs. A TCD can process one or more formatted messages and create one or more messages that include pass-through data and/or one or more messages that can include feed-forward data. In addition, one or more of the messages can include recipe data, profile data, modeling data, tuning data, and/or optimization data that can be created, by a host (MES) system. Alternatively, the data may be created and/or modified by a subsystem and/or system controller. For example, a formatted message comprising pass-through data and/or feed-forward data can be sent to a TCD that can be coupled to a processing tool, a measurement tool, and the MES, and the TCD can parse the formatted message.</p>
<p id="p-0258" num="0261">In <b>515</b>, a query can be performed to determine when feed-forward data is available for use in the processing subsystem that received the wafer. When feed-forward data is not available, procedure <b>500</b> can branch to <b>520</b>, and when feed-forward data is available, procedure <b>500</b> can branch to <b>525</b>. The feed-forward data can include real-time wafer data, real-time measured data, and/or real-time process data. For example, one or more of the TCDs associated with the processing subsystem can be operating in a &#x201c;Feed-Forward&#x201d; mode when feed-forward data is available and/or when the feed-forward state is a first value, and the feed-forward data can include real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data. In addition, one or more of the TCDs associated with the processing subsystem can be operating in a &#x201c;Non-Feed-Forward&#x201d; mode when feed-forward data is not available and/or when the feed-forward state is a second value.</p>
<p id="p-0259" num="0262">In <b>520</b>, a procedure is not updated in the first processing subsystem. In some embodiments, a feed-forward message and/or data may not be available because of timing issues. When the feed-forward data is not available, the feed-forward message and/or data are not used to create updated data that can be used to optimize and/or tune the process performed in the subsystem. For example, when the wafer has been transferred to a deposition subsystem, a non-updated deposition process can be created, and non-updated deposition data can be generated. When the wafer has been transferred to an etching subsystem, a non-updated etch process can be created, and non-updated etch data can be generated. When the wafer has been transferred to a lithography subsystem, a non-updated lithography process can be created and non-updated lithography data can be generated. Alternatively, in step <b>520</b>, updated process or data may not created, but rather the subsystem is caused to perform its process using an old process previously stored in the subsystem and/or provided as part of a passthrough message.</p>
<p id="p-0260" num="0263">In <b>525</b>, an updated procedure can be created for the processing subsystem and updated data can be generated. For example, a process recipe for the first process tool can be tuned and/or optimized based on the feedforward data, and the tuned and/or optimized recipe can be used to perform the process in the subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0261" num="0264">For example, when the wafer has been transferred to a deposition subsystem, an updated deposition process can be created using the feed-forward data, and updated deposition data can be created. The updated deposition data can include new and/or old real-time wafer thickness and/or uniformity data. When the wafer has been transferred to an etching subsystem, an updated etching process can be created using the feed-forward data, and updated etch data can be created. The updated etch data can include new and/or old real-time wafer thickness and/or uniformity data. The updated measurement data can include new and/or old real-time wafer thickness and/or uniformity data. When the wafer has been transferred to a lithography subsystem, an updated lithography process can be created using the feed-forward data, and updated lithography data can be created. The updated lithography data can include new and/or old real-time wafer thickness and/or uniformity data.</p>
<p id="p-0262" num="0265">A pass-through message can be sent to the subsystem by a processing tool, and a real-time feed-forward message may or may not be sent by the processing tool. One or more of the messages can be sent by a controller/computer coupled to the processing tool. The pass-through message can include recipe data that is not required immediately, and the real-time feed-forward message can include recipe data that can be used immediately. For example, feed-forward message can include real-time layer thickness data from a deposition subsystem that can be used in real-time by an etching subsystem to determine in real-time which etching recipe to use when etching the current wafer. When real-time layer thickness data is provided to an etching tool, the calculation time is reduced and the accuracy is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0263" num="0266">In step <b>530</b>, the process is performed in the processing subsystem. As noted above, the process performed in <b>530</b> can be an updated process where feedforward data is available, or a non-updated process where feedforward data is not available. Further, in <b>530</b> data resulting from the process is made available for collection so that new messages can be generated and sent throughout the processing system. Thus, updated or non-updated processing (process result) data can be generated. The updated data can be identified as real-time feed-forward data, pass-through data, and/or historical data. In addition, other data can be identified. One or more real-time feed-forward messages can be created and sent to the MES, and/or other subsystems. One or more pass-through messages can be created and sent to the MES, and/or other subsystems. In addition, the historical data can be stored. Processing sequence and/or wafer state data can be used to create and/or send the messages.</p>
<p id="p-0264" num="0267">In <b>535</b>, a query is performed to determine whether to perform a measurement procedure on the wafer after the process has been performed on the current wafer. The measurement procedure is preferably an optical measurement such as an ODP measurement process for measuring 2D and/or 3D structures on the wafer. The query in step <b>535</b> may be resolved based on a processing sequence established by the host for the wafer, for example. When the current wafer does not require measurement, procedure <b>500</b> can branch to <b>540</b>, and when the current wafer requires measurement, procedure <b>500</b> can branch to <b>560</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0265" num="0268">In <b>540</b>, a query can be performed to determine when another process sequence is required for the current wafer. Where another process is to be performed on the current wafer, the procedure <b>500</b> loops back to step <b>510</b> where a processing subsystem (the same or different from the previous processing system) receives the current wafer and processes the wafer as discussed above. In this regard, the additional process includes another query for current feedforward data that may have been received in a message to the processing subsystem. For example, a deposition procedure may have previously been performed and the new feed-forward data may include real-time wafer thickness and/or uniformity data.</p>
<p id="p-0266" num="0269">Further, the new feedforward data may be received directly from the processing subsystem that performed the previous process on the wafer. For example, a wafer can be processed by a deposition subsystem using an updated deposition procedure, and real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be generated by the deposition subsystem. Then the wafer can be transferred to an etching subsystem. The deposition subsystem can send feed-forward messages to the etching subsystem. The etching subsystem can receive and process the feed-forward messages and can extract the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data. The etching system can use the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to establish tuned etching data that can include an etching recipe, an etching time, and/or an etching chemistry. Next, the etching subsystem can etch the wafer using the tuned etching data. In addition, when real-time layer thickness data is provided to an etching tool, the calculation time is reduced and the accuracy is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0267" num="0270">Where another process is not performed on the current wafer, the current wafer is removed from the processing system is step <b>543</b>, and a determination is made in step <b>545</b> whether another wafer is to be processed by the processing system. Where another wafer is to be processed, then the procedure <b>500</b> loops back to step <b>510</b> where the another wafer is received in a processing subsystem and processing is performed in the subsystem as discussed above. Processing for the additional wafer may be tuned or optimized based on data obtained from a previous process on the additional wafer and/or data obtained for other wafers. Where no additional wafer is available for processing, the procedure ends in step <b>550</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0268" num="0271">Returning to step <b>535</b>, where a measurement procedure is to be performed on a wafer, the wafer and messages are received by a measurement subsystem of the wafer processing system in step <b>555</b>. The measurement subsystem can be any optical measurement system, but is preferably an ODP system that performs <b>2</b>D and <b>3</b>d measurements on the wafer using scatterometry. Further, messages may be received by the measurement subsystem itself, or a TCD or RTO associated with the processing subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0269" num="0272">In <b>560</b>, a query can be performed to determine when feed-forward data is available for use in the measurement subsystem that received the wafer. When feed-forward data is not available, procedure <b>500</b> can branch to <b>565</b>, and when additional feed-forward data is available, procedure <b>500</b> can branch to <b>570</b>. For example, a deposition procedure and an etching procedure may have previously been performed and the additional feed-forward data may include real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data from a deposition process and/or real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data from an etching process.</p>
<p id="p-0270" num="0273">In <b>565</b>, a procedure is not updated in the measurement subsystem. For example, a feedforward messages/data may not be available to the measurement subsystem due to timing issues. When the feed-forward data is not available, the feed-forward message and/or data are not used to create updated data that can be used to optimize and/or tune the measurement process performed in the measurement subsystem. For example, non-updated measurement recipe data, non-updated measurement profile data, and/or non-updated measurement modeling data can be created in <b>565</b> using pass-through and/or historic data. Alternatively, in step <b>565</b> an updated process or data may not be created, but rather the measurement subsystem is caused to perform its process using an old measurement process previously stored in the subsystem and/or provided as part of a pass-through message.</p>
<p id="p-0271" num="0274">In <b>570</b>, updated measurement data can be created. Updated measurement recipe data, updated measurement profile data, and/or updated measurement modeling data can be created using real-time feed-forward data. For example, the updated measurement recipe data, the updated measurement profile data, and/or the updated measurement modeling data can be created using real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or uniformity data. The real-time data can be passed to a measurement tool as RTPT procedure variables/parameters, can be used to override current recipe data, profile, and/or model default values, to override current sequencing state data, to override current start times, and can be used to narrow the search space for determining recipes, profiles, and/or models and their associated accuracy limits.</p>
<p id="p-0272" num="0275">In step <b>575</b>, the measurement process is performed in the processing subsystem. As noted above, the measurement process performed in <b>575</b> can be an updated process where feedforward data is available, or a non-updated process where feedforward data is not available. Further, in <b>575</b> measurement data resulting from the process is made available for collection so that new messages can be generated and sent throughout the processing system. Thus, the measurement process (updated or non-updated) can also result in updated data such as measurement results. The updated data can be identified as real-time feed-forward data, pass-through data, and/or historical data. In addition, other data can be identified. One or more real-time feed-forward messages can be created and sent to the MES, and/or other subsystems. One or more pass-through messages can be created and sent to the MES, and/or other subsystems. In addition, the historical data can be stored. Processing sequence and/or wafer state data can be used to create and/or send the messages.</p>
<p id="p-0273" num="0276">Once a measurement process has been performed, the procedure <b>500</b> continues to <b>540</b> where a query is made whether to perform an additional process on the current wafer after the measurement process. Where another process is to be performed on the current wafer, the procedure <b>500</b> loops back to step <b>510</b>, where a processing subsystem receives the current wafer and processes the wafer as discussed above. Where another process is not performed on the current wafer, the current wafer is removed from the processing system is step <b>543</b>, and a determination is made in step <b>545</b> whether another wafer is to be processed by the processing system as also discussed above. Where no additional wafer is available for processing, the procedure ends in step <b>550</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0274" num="0277">Thus, procedure <b>500</b> provides a flexible procedure whereby data is continuously collected by a processing system and the most current information can be used to tune and/or optimize procedures in processing and/or measurement subsystems. One or more processes can be performed on a the current wafer prior to measuring the wafer. For example, a measurement can be performed by the measurement subsystem after each process performed on the wafer. Alternatively, a measurement process may never be performed on a current wafer, such as where the current wafer is not a selected wafer in a lot sampling procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0275" num="0278">In one embodiment, the procedure of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> can be used to perform DTMO measurements in connection with an etch process. In this embodiment, a first CVD deposition process is performed to deposit a USG film on a substrate. Film thickness data from the USG deposition process can be sent to a host computer. The thickness measurements can be obtained by a measurement device on the CVD system, or by calculation based on deposition rates and times, for example. Further, the film thickness information may be provided for different measurement sites across the wafer. Once the USG layer is deposited, a second CVD process can be used to deposit a SiN layer on the USG layer. The SiN layer may be deposited with or without an updated procedure created based on the thickness measurements from the USG deposition process. Film thickness data from the SiN deposition process can be sent to the host computer. The thickness measurements (for one or more measurement sites) can be obtained by a measurement system of the CVD system, or by calculation based on deposition rates and times, for example. A DTMO etch is then performed to etch a feature in the USG and SiN layers. Again the USG and SiN thickness data may be used to provide an updated etch process, and the etch system can send new data to the host about etch rates, times etc. After etching, the wafer can be measured in an ODP measurement process to determine a structure of the etched feature. The ODP measurement system can use thickness data from the any or all of the previously performed processes to update a measurement procedure to ensure accurate measurement.</p>
<p id="p-0276" num="0279">A processing sequence and/or wafer state can be used to determine how to process and/or when to receive messages. One or more pass-through messages can be received by the measurement and/or processing tool, and a real-time feed-forward message may or may not be received by the measurement and/or processing tool. One or more of the messages can be received and/or processed by a TCD and/or controller coupled to the measurement and/or processing tool. The pass-through message can include data that is not required immediately, and the real-time feed-forward message can include data that can be used immediately. For example, feed-forward message can include real-time layer thickness data from a deposition subsystem that can be used in real-time by an etching subsystem to determine in real-time which etching recipe to use when etching the current wafer. When real-time thickness and/or thermal data can be provided to an etching tool, the calculation time can be reduced and the accuracy can be improved.</p>
<p id="p-0277" num="0280">Accuracy values can be determined for the updated and/or non-updated procedures and/or results, the accuracy values can be compared to accuracy limits, and refinement and/or optimization procedures can be performed if the accuracy values do not meet the accuracy limits. Alternatively, other procedures can be performed, other sites can be used, or other wafers can be used.</p>
<p id="p-0278" num="0281">When a refinement procedure is used, the refinement procedure can utilize bilinear refinement, Lagrange refinement, Cubic Spline refinement, Aitken refinement, weighted average refinement, multi-quadratic refinement, bi-cubic refinement, Turran refinement, wavelet refinement, Bessel's refinement, Everett refinement, finite-difference refinement, Gauss refinement, Hermite refinement, Newton's divided difference refinement, osculating refinement, or Thiele's refinement algorithm, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0279" num="0282">When measurements are made using optical techniques, the measured signals can include layer-dependent and/or wafer-thickness-dependent signals and/or spectra, and can include intensity, transmission, reflection, diffraction, and/or refraction signals and/or spectra, or any combination thereof. Alternatively, a measured signal can depend upon the wafer thickness uniformity data and/or other wafer thickness-related data.</p>
<p id="p-0280" num="0283">In some embodiments, a completion time and/or execution time can determined for the RTPT procedures. The completion time and/or execution time to a measurement and/or processing start time to determine if there is enough time to establish the updated recipe. The wafer can be measured and/or processed using the updated measurement recipe if the completion time and/or execution time are less than the processing start time, or the wafer can be measured using a non-updated measurement recipe if the completion time and/or execution time are not less than the processing start time.</p>
<p id="p-0281" num="0284">Processing sequences can change with time. When a process sequence is being developed, the through-put can be less than desired because the confidence values are lower and the risk factors are higher for new processes and additional measurement steps are required to raise the confidence values and lower the risk factors. When wafers are measured using separate and/or external measurement tools, additional time is required.</p>
<p id="p-0282" num="0285">Before, during, and/or after each process step in the processing sequence, real-time data can be created, processed, received, and/or sent, and the real-time data can include real-time measured, tuned, and/or optimized data. When real-time data is created, the real-time data and the creation time can be stored and can be examined to determine when the real-time data can be used. When real-time data is processed, the real-time data and the time stamp can be examined to determine what part of the real-time data can be used and how it can be used. When real-time data is received, the real-time data and the reception time can be stored and can be examined to determine when the real-time data can be used. Received messages can include time stamped data. When real-time data is sent, the real-time data and the transmission time can be stored and can be examined to determine when the real-time data can be used. Sent messages can include time stamped data. For example, the real-time data can be received and/or sent as real-time feedforward, pass-through, RTPT, and/or optimization data. Alternatively, other data may be created, received, and/or sent. Intervention and/or judgment rules may be established and used to determine when and how to process the real-time data, and the intervention and/or judgment rules can be process, device, product, and/or customer dependent.</p>
<p id="p-0283" num="0286">In some embodiments, a real-time process optimizer can receive and/or use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to tune and/or optimize a deposition process recipe in real-time; a real-time profile optimizer can receive and/or use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to tune and/or optimize a layer profile; and/or a real-time model optimizer can receive and/or use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to tune and/or optimize a model for the deposition process. During and/or after the mask layer deposition, process result data can be obtained and can be used in RTPT procedures. For example, the new real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data may be obtained that can be fed forward to tune and/or optimize the next process before the next process is performed.</p>
<p id="p-0284" num="0287">When new real-time data is established for the current wafer by a procedure associated with a deposition tool, and when the new real-time data from the deposition process can be fed forward to an exposure tool before the current wafer is exposed a more accurate exposure process can be performed on the current wafer. For example, layer thickness and thickness uniformity data can be fed forward from the deposition tool to an exposure tool. When the new real-time data from the deposition process cannot be fed forward to the exposure tool before the current wafer is exposed, a less accurate exposure process may be performed on the current wafer because the newest real-time data is not being used.</p>
<p id="p-0285" num="0288">When new real-time data is established for the current wafer by a procedure associated with an exposure tool, and when the real-time data from the exposure process can be fed forward to a developing tool before the current wafer is developed, an updated (more accurate) developing process can be performed on the current wafer. For example, exposure times, exposure doses, and/or uniformity data can be fed forward from an exposure tool to a developing tool. When the real-time optimization data from the exposure process cannot be fed forward to a developing tool before the current wafer is developed, a less accurate developing process may be performed on the current wafer because the newest real-time data is not being used.</p>
<p id="p-0286" num="0289">When new real-time data is established for the current wafer by a procedure associated with a developing tool, and when the new real-time data from the developing process can be fed forward to an etching tool before the current wafer is etched, an updated (more accurate) etching process can be performed on the current wafer. For example, processing times and thickness can be fed forward from a developing tool to an etching tool. When the new real-time data from a developing process cannot be fed forward to an etching tool before the current wafer is etched, a less accurate etching process may be performed on the current wafer because newest real-time data is not being used.</p>
<p id="p-0287" num="0290">When new real-time data is established for the current wafer by a procedure associated with an etching tool, and when the new real-time data from the etching process can be fed forward to a measurement tool before the current wafer is measured an updated (more accurate) measurement process can be performed on the current wafer. For example, etching rates and etching times can be fed forward from an etching tool to tune a recipe, a profile estimate, or a model, or a combination thereof in a measurement tool. When the new real-time data from an etching process cannot be fed forward to a measurement tool before the current wafer is measured, a less accurate measurement process may be performed on the current wafer because the newest real-time data is not being used.</p>
<p id="p-0288" num="0291">In addition, real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be provided to a real-time process optimizer associated with the metrology tool, and the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be used to determine when a library-based recipe can be used, or when a regression-based recipe can be used, or when a machine-learning recipe can be used. Alternatively, other feedforward data may be used. A real-time model optimizer associated with the metrology tool can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to determine when a one-dimensional model can be used, or when a two-dimensional model can be used, or when a three-dimensional model can be used. Alternatively, other feedforward data may be used. A real-time profile optimizer associated with the metrology tool can use real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data to determine a profile shape, or a unit cell shape, or a number of unit cells.</p>
<p id="p-0289" num="0292">When EPD is used to stop an etching process, the EPD time and the etch rate can be used to calculate an estimated film thickness. During processing etch rate monitor wafers can be run periodically, and a measurement tool can be used to measure the film thicknesses before and after a blanket wafer etch. The etching tool can calculate an etch rate without external metrology. For example, EPD data from a first pattered wafer can be used to tune (update) a film thickness model.</p>
<p id="p-0290" num="0293">During process development, stable processes are first developed and then the stable processes can be tuned and/or optimized. RTPT procedures can be used during process stabilization, process enhancement, and process optimization.</p>
<p id="p-0291" num="0294">During a process stabilization sequence, one or more additional measurement steps can be used to raise confidence values and/or decrease risk factors before a process optimization sequence is established. Delay times can be used to wait for tuning and/or optimization data before performing a process, and delay times can be used to wait for tuned and/or optimized data before performing a process. A measurement step can be performed before the etching process is performed to obtain data for a patterned mask layer that can be used to compare with the patterned etched layer. In addition, measurements can be made after a deposition process, and these measurements can provide thickness data, uniformity data, and/or optical properties data that can be fed forward as real-time data or historical data. Wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be obtained from processing tools, measurement tools, alignment tools, transfer tools, inspection tools, and/or pattern recognition tools.</p>
<p id="p-0292" num="0295">Some measurement sites can be non-measurable due to interference from underlying layers and or structures. Interference-based maps can be created and used to determine site location for measurements. In addition, interference profiles and/or models can be created.</p>
<p id="p-0293" num="0296">In some fabrication environments, RTPT procedures and integrated metrology tools can provide measurement data that was previously unavailable; can provide measurement data faster; can provide a more complete understanding of a process, can replace destructive methods; can provide more accurate checking of chamber performance, can provide a faster sampling rate, can improve within-wafer uniformity, can reduce the number of wafers at risk, and can provide shorter reaction times to process and/or tool excursions.</p>
<p id="p-0294" num="0297">In some embodiments, a deep trench process can be performed. For example, a multi-step deposition process can produce a photoresist layer on top of an un-patterned BARC layer and one or more underlying mask layers, and real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be obtained during and/or after each step in the deposition process. The real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data from the deposition process can be used in subsequent processes. A multi-step etch process can be performed after the multi-step deposition process and the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be fed forward to one or more etching tools.</p>
<p id="p-0295" num="0298">A first etch process step can produce a first layer consisting of patterned holes in the photoresist on top of the un-patterned BARC layer and the one or more underlying mask layers. For example, the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can include thickness and/or uniformity data for the photoresist layer that can be used to determine an etching time and/or chemistry. When a first measurement process is performed after the first etch step, the real-time wafer thickness, temperature and/or n&#x26;k data can be fed forward to the metrology tool and can be used to select the proper library and/or process space in a library. The first measurement process can be performed using an integrated metrology and/or reference metrology tool. A CD-SEM can be used as the reference metrology tool, and an iODP tool can be used as the integrated metrology tool. When an iODP tool is used, a profile model can be created that represents the structure to be measured. A good profile model must generate a simulated spectrum that closely matches a measured spectrum from a wafer. The GOF values can be used to determine the quality of a fit between the measured and simulated signals and/or feature/structures. Measurements can be made after one or more of the four process steps.</p>
<p id="p-0296" num="0299">Next, a second etch process (first mask open) can be performed, the photoresist and BARC layers can be removed, and one or more of the mask layers can be patterned. Then, a third etch process (second mask open) can be performed, one or more mask layers can be removed, and the pattern can be etch through one or more additional mask layers. Finally, a recess etch step can be performed, a deep trench can be formed in the wafer material and a portion of one or more masking layers may remain. Historically, deep trenches have been measured using the FIB technique.</p>
<p id="p-0297" num="0300">Before, during, and/or after measurements are made profile parameters and/or priorities can be established and/or changed. After the first etch process, the highest priority parameter can be the bottom CD of the printed holes in the photoresist. High priority data can include photoresist thickness and uniformity. For example, iODP data and/or historical (CD-SEM) data can be obtained for bottom CD for one or more dies on a measured wafer. In some fabrication environments, a small offset may occur between the newly measured (iODP) data and the historical (CD-SEM) data, but this can be corrected using a calibration procedure. In addition, there can be die-to-die variation in the newly measured (iODP) data and/or the historical (CD-SEM) data. Averaging can be used to minimize the effect of the variations, and averaging can be advantageous when within-wafer process data and trends are being analyzed.</p>
<p id="p-0298" num="0301">For the second and third etch processes, the high priority parameters can include bottom CD, and/or the thickness of the remaining mask layer, and lower priority parameters can include middle CD, top CD, and/or BARC thickness. For example, real-time iODP data and/or historical (FIB) data can be obtained for bottom CD for one or more dies on a measured wafer. The second and/or third etch process can be updated (tuned) using the real-time iODP data obtained after the first etch process. In addition, the third etch process can be updated (tuned) using the real-time iODP data obtained after the second etch process.</p>
<p id="p-0299" num="0302">Historically, some of these features have been measured using the FIB technique, and this can present a problem because the FIB technique has a destructive nature and low throughput. When integrated metrology tools are used, real-time iODP data can be obtained, and a more accurate measurement technique can be provided for these features. When offsets occur between the real-time iODP data and historical (FIB) data, these offsets can be corrected using a calibration procedure. An offset may occur due to the different methods used for the thickness measurements. Feed forward data may be used to reduce the offset and improve the accuracy of the calibration process.</p>
<p id="p-0300" num="0303">For the recess etch process, the high priority parameters can include bottom CD, and/or the thickness of the remaining mask layer, and lower priority parameters can include middle CD, top CD, and/or BARC thickness. The recess etch process can be updated (tuned) using the real-time iODP data obtained after the first etch process, the second etch process, and/or the third etch process. In addition, when layer features have high aspect ratios, the shape of the feature can vary with the depth of the features. For example, the shape in the XY plane may be rhomboidal at the upper surface, and elliptical at lower depths.</p>
<p id="p-0301" num="0304">In some deep trench procedures, the first three processes can be performed as a first sequence and the recess etch process can be performed as a second sequence. The recess etch process can be updated (tuned) using the real-time iODP data obtained after the first three processes are performed. Measurements can be made before and/or after the first sequence, and a first set of measurement data can include bottom CD data and/or thickness data. In addition, measurements can be made before and/or after the second sequence, and a second set of measurement data can include bottom CD data and/or thickness data. Thickness data can be provided for a photoresist layer, a BARC layer, one or more masking layers, and one or more substrate layers RTPT procedures can be used to reduce within-wafer CD variation, wafer-to-wafer CD variation, to compensate for chamber-to-chamber variation, to compensate for tool-to-tool variations, and to allow a given lot to be processed across multiple chambers, thereby maximizing throughput.</p>
<p id="p-0302" num="0305"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a flow chart showing a method for determining a tuned ODP measurement result based on tuning data in accordance with one embodiment of the present invention. The process of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is performed by a wafer processing system including a processing subsystem, an ODP subsystem and a TCD. The processing subsystem may be implemented as an etch subsystem a lithography subsystem or any of the wafer processing subsystems described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> above. Similarly, the ODP measurement subsystem may be implemented as any of the ODP measurement subsystems described with respect to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-5</figref> above. Thus, the ODP subsystem includes measurement hardware (such as a light source and detector) for obtaining a diffraction signal from the wafer, and a signal analyzer (such as the PAS described above) for determining a measurement result from the diffraction signal. The TCD may be external to the processing and ODP subsystems as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, or the TCD can be integral with the processing subsystem and/or the ODP subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0303" num="0306">In step <b>605</b> the TCD receives an input message. The input message may include tuning data and/or non-tuning data. The tuning data can be generated based on various information collected by a processor (such as the host computer) from any subsystem of a wafer processing system. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, tuning data is any data that can be used to modify or &#x201c;tune&#x201d; an ODP measurement process that was previously established for a wafer or lot, and non-tuning data is data that cannot be used to modify or tune the ODP measurement process. Tuning data can include feedforward data as described herein, and non-tuning data may include pass-through data as described herein. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the tuning data is sent to the ODP signal analyzer for use in tuning the ODP measurement process, while non-tuning data is sent to the processing subsystem for use in a process performed by the processing subsystem and/or a measurement performed by the ODP measurement hardware.</p>
<p id="p-0304" num="0307">In step <b>610</b>, the TCD determines whether the input message includes tuning data. For example, a controller of the TCD may search or parse the input message for tuning data that can be used to tune the ODP measurement process. Where the TCD determines in step <b>610</b> that the input message includes tuning data, the process proceeds to step <b>615</b> where the tuning data is obtained from the input message and sent to the ODP signal analyzer. For example, a controller of the TCD may be used to extract the tuning data from the input message, and send the tuning data to the ODP signal analyzer. In one embodiment, the tuning data is sent directly to the ODP signal analyzer, however, other routing may be used. The tuning data is stored in the ODP signal analyzer until it is needed to tune an ODP measurement process, as will be discussed further below.</p>
<p id="p-0305" num="0308">The tuning data obtained in <b>615</b> can be wafer characteristic data such as layer thickness, wafer temperature, wafer layer porosity, reflectivity, refractivity, n &#x26; k values and/or any other characteristic of the wafer that can affect optical measurement of the wafer. As would be understood by one of ordinary skill in the art, the n&#x26;k value of a film indicates a reflectivity/refractivity property of a film based on known characteristics such as material composition, doping, porosity etc. Wafer characteristic data can be directly measured during a previous process, or determined based on raw process data collected during the previous process. For example, the tuning data can be a deposited film thickness measured by an integrated metrology tool on a CVD subsystem or determined based on a deposition rate and time recorded by the CVD subsystem. In one embodiment, the tuning data obtained in step <b>615</b> is raw process data used by the processing and/or ODP subsystem to calculate wafer characteristic data, that in turn is used to tune an ODP measurement process. The tuning data can also be non-characteristic data that can be used to modify the measurement result in some way. For example, the tuning data can be instructions generated by a host for offsetting a measurement result obtained during the ODP process. Alternatively, the tuning data can be a new recipe generated by the host and sent to the ODP subsystem to replace an existing measurement recipe.</p>
<p id="p-0306" num="0309">In step <b>620</b>, non-tuning data is sent to the processing subsystem. As noted above, in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, non-tuning data is data that cannot be used to tune an ODP measurement process. For example, non-tuning data can include measurement setup data, processing setup data, initial measurement recipes, processing recipes, wafer identification data, or other data that can be used by the ODP measurement hardware to obtain a diffraction signal from a wafer and/or by the processing subsystem to perform a process on a wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0307" num="0310">The non-tuning data sent to the processing subsystem in step <b>620</b> can be data remaining after tuning data is extracted in step <b>615</b>. That is, where an input message includes both tuning data and non-tuning data, the tuning data is extracted and sent to the ODP signal analyzer in step <b>615</b>, and the remaining non-tuning data is sent to the processing subsystem in step <b>620</b>. Further, in the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, if the input message does not include tuning data (for tuning the ODP measurement process), then the input message includes only non-tuning data. Thus, where step <b>610</b> determines that tuning data is not included in the input message, then the process continues to step <b>620</b> where the non-tuning data is sent to the processing subsystem. In this regard, the input message containing only non-tuning data is preferably sent to the processing subsystem &#x201c;as is&#x201d; without modification by the TCD.</p>
<p id="p-0308" num="0311">In one embodiment, where the TCD receives an input message including both tuning and non-tuning data, the TCD can first obtain and send the tuning data to the ODP signal analyzer as described in step <b>615</b>. The TCD will then wait for the ODP signal analyzer to send a verification reply to the TCD indicating that the tuning data was received and did not generate any errors in the ODP subsystem. If such a verification is received, the TCD will then send the non-tuning data to the processing tool, but if the verification signal is not received due to an error, the non-tuning data will not be sent to the processing tool until the error is cleared. In an alternative embodiment, the TCD will send the tuning data to the ODP signal analyzer and also send the non-tuning data to the processing tool, and the ODP signal analyzer and processing tool will independently deal with exceptions for the respective data</p>
<p id="p-0309" num="0312">In step <b>625</b>, the TCD determines whether more input messages exist to be processed by the TCD. In one embodiment, input messages for an entire lot of wafers are sent from a host to the TCD, and the TCD processes all messages for the lot to obtain tuning and non-tuning data for all wafers in the lot. All tuning data for the lot is sent to the signal analyzer of the ODP subsystem where it is stored for later use in tuning a measurement result, and all non-tuning data for the lot is sent to the processing subsystem to control processing and measurement for the lot. Alternatively, input messages can be sent from the host or any subsystem to the TCD on a wafer to wafer basis. Where additional input messages exist, the process returns to step <b>605</b>, where the additional messages are processed by the TCD. Where no additional input messages exist, the process continues to step <b>630</b> where a wafer processing sequence is started. Thus, steps <b>605</b>-<b>625</b> provide a setup sequence whereby data is obtained from an input message(s) and routed to the processing subsystem or ODP subsystem as necessary prior to performing any processing of a wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0310" num="0313">Once the setup sequence is completed, a processing sequence of the wafer(s) begins in step <b>630</b>. In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the wafer processing sequence is controlled by the processing subsystem according to non-tuning data provided to the processing subsystem in step <b>620</b>. The passthough data can include instructions for processing a wafer in the processing subsystem, and/or instructions for performing an ODP measurement process in the ODP subsystem. The ODP measurement process can be performed on each wafer in a lot, or only on sample wafers of the lot. Further, the ODP measurement process can be performed on a wafer before and/or after processing of the wafer in the processing subsystem. Thus, in step <b>635</b>, the processing subsystem determines whether an ODP measurement process is required for a wafer. Where no measurement is required, a process such as etching, deposition etc. is performed on the wafer in step <b>640</b>, and the procedure returns to step <b>630</b> where the processing sequence continues. Thus, steps <b>630</b>-<b>640</b> are performed until an ODP measurement is required.</p>
<p id="p-0311" num="0314">When an ODP measurement is required, the procedure proceeds to step <b>645</b> where an optical measurement is performed on the wafer using ODP measurement hardware. In one embodiment, the processing subsystem determines when an optical measurement is needed and sends to the ODP measurement hardware only the data necessary for performing that measurement. For example, where a setup sequence was performed for an entire lot of wafers and the processing subsystem stores all non-tuning data for the lot, the processing subsystem can send only non-tuning data needed to perform that measurement (e.g. measurement setup and recipes) to the ODP measurement hardware. The ODP measurement hardware will then load the wafer and make measurements according to the data provided by the processing subsystem. Specifically, the ODP measurement hardware provides light incident on the wafer and detects a diffraction signal from a measurement site on the wafer. The diffraction signal may be spectral data, for example. In a preferred embodiment, a diffraction signal is detected for multiple sites on a wafer, such as the 13 x&#x26;y locations listed in Table 1 above.</p>
<p id="p-0312" num="0315">In one embodiment of the invention, the ODP measurement hardware can include additional sensors for providing internal tuning data (internal to the ODP subsystem) that can also be used to tune an OPD measurement process. For example, a light source and/or detector component of the ODP measurement hardware can include a temperature sensor for providing temperature data associated with each of the diffraction signals detected in step <b>645</b>. Alternatively, the hardware can be modified to measure thickness, porosity, reflectivity and/or collect any other wafer characteristic data that can be obtained during the measurement process in step <b>645</b>. This &#x201c;internal&#x201d; tuning data can be stored in the ODP subsystem's signal analyzer along with &#x201c;external&#x201d; tuning data sent in step <b>615</b>. All tuning data can then be used to tune the ODP measurement process.</p>
<p id="p-0313" num="0316">Once the measurement process is performed by the measurement hardware, in step <b>650</b> the ODP measurement subsystem determines whether tuning data is available for a diffraction signal obtained in step <b>645</b>. The available tuning data may be external tuning data or internal tuning data, as noted above. In one embodiment, the ODP signal analyzer receives a preliminary message that prompts the ODP subsystem to retrieve the tuning data for storage.</p>
<p id="p-0314" num="0317">Where step <b>650</b> determines that no tuning data exists, the process proceeds to step <b>655</b> where the ODP signal analyzer determines a measurement result without tuning the ODP process. Step <b>655</b> includes matching a diffraction signal obtained in step <b>645</b> with a simulated diffraction signal, and obtaining a measurement result associated with the simulated diffraction signal. A measurement result can be a CD measurement, a structure profile, a trench or via profile, a depth, a multilayer thickness measurement, and/or any other measurement result that can be obtained by use of ODP techniques. Determination of the measurement result can be based on a library system or regression system for identifying a simulated diffraction signal and associated measurement result. As step <b>655</b> is performed without using tuning data, the ODP measurement result is an un-tuned measurement result, as with conventional methods discussed in the background section above.</p>
<p id="p-0315" num="0318">However, where step <b>650</b> determines that tuning data (external or internal) is available, the process proceeds to step <b>660</b> where the ODP signal analyzer determines a measurement result by tuning the ODP measurement process. In one embodiment, the ODP signal analyzer can check and validate the tuning data. For example, where the tuning data is an invalid range or an invalid format, the OPD signal analyzer can send an error signal or alarm back to the processing tool (or any other source of the tuning date).</p>
<p id="p-0316" num="0319">The ODP signal analyzer determines the measurement result based on the diffraction signal obtained in step <b>645</b> and any tuning data obtained in step <b>615</b> and/or step <b>645</b>. For example, the tuning data, and in particular wafer characteristic data such as temperature, thickness and n&#x26;k values, can be used as variable parameters to override default values for these parameters in the ODP measurement process. With a library based measurement process, this tuning data can be used to pinpoint a small range of possible matches in the library for consideration, thereby reducing the time to achieve the measurement result. Similarly, with the regression based measurement process, the tuning data and/or wafer characteristic data can be used to provide an initial matching possibility that is close to the actual match, thereby reducing the regression iterations and the time to achieve a measurement result. Thus, the tuned measurement result obtained in step <b>660</b> can be a measurement result that is obtained more efficiently with the use of tuning data.</p>
<p id="p-0317" num="0320">Alternatively, the tuning data may be used to improve the accuracy of the measurement result. In one embodiment, the tuning data may be used to tune the measured diffraction signal obtained in step <b>645</b> prior to matching this measured signal with a simulated diffraction signal as part of step <b>660</b>. For example, wafer n&#x26;k values provided from the external tuning data in step <b>620</b>, or calculated in the optical analysis system can be used to modify the diffraction spectrum obtained in step <b>645</b> to have a spectral signature consistent with the n&#x26;k value. This tuned diffraction spectrum is then used to obtain a matching simulated diffraction signal.</p>
<p id="p-0318" num="0321">However, the above-described tuning of the diffraction signal itself can involve complex and time consuming computations. Thus, in an alternative embodiment, the tuning data can be used to tune a preliminary measurement result obtained by the ODP analyzer. For example, wafer temperature data provided in step <b>620</b> and/or step <b>645</b> may be used by the ODP analyzer to determine a CD shift of +2 nm, for example. Alternatively, this offset value can be determined outside the ODP subsystem and forwarded to the ODP subsystem as part of the external tuning data. Once the ODP signal analyzer determines a preliminary CD measurement result using conventional methods, the CD shift value of +2 nm is simply added to the preliminary measurement to provide a tuned measurement result. Such offset tuning of the measurement result can be achieved more efficiently than the above example of tuning by recalculating the measured diffraction signal itself. In one example, the ODP measurement subsystem can receive a standard tool calibration procedure that is broadcast by the host computer to all similar tools in the factory, and also receive specific tuning data used to offset measurement results of the specific tool. The offset value can be based on known variation in measurement results for the specific tool, known variation in processing subsystems in line with the specific tool etc.</p>
<p id="p-0319" num="0322">Once a measurement result is determined (either untuned in step <b>655</b>, or tuned in step <b>660</b>), the measurement result is sent to the processing subsystem (preferably in real time) for use in a control strategy for optimizing a process, as shown in step <b>665</b>. The processing subsystem may use the measurement result as part of a &#x201c;tuning&#x201d; or &#x201c;feedback&#x201d; control strategy for optimizing a process. For example, where the ODP measurement is performed on a wafer prior to processing the wafer in the processing subsystem, the measurement result can be used in a tuning control strategy for optimizing the subsequent process to be performed on the measured wafer in the processing subsystem. Where the measurement is performed on a wafer after processing the wafer in the processing subsystem, the measurement result can be used in a feedback control strategy for optimizing a process to be performed on the next wafer in the processing subsystem.</p>
<p id="p-0320" num="0323">In the embodiment of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, &#x201c;optimization&#x201d; of a process means using a measurement result to optimize a process recipe, a process model and/or a process profile. As described above, an RTO associated with a processing subsystem (such as an etch tool, deposition tool etc.) can obtain the measurement result and optimize the process performed by the subsystem. Whether the optimized process is available for a particular wafer can be determined based on timing requirements as described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0321" num="0324">Once the ODP measurement result is provided for use in a control strategy, the process in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> may end or loop back to step <b>630</b> where further wafer processing is performed.</p>
<p id="p-0322" num="0325">In some embodiments, when the message does not include tuning data, the message can be sent in its present form to a process tool or measurement tool as setup data. When the message does include tuning data, a TCD can remove the tuning data from the message and sends the tuning data to the optical measurement hardware, and any remaining part of the message can be sent to another subsystem and/or tool. The process tool can then send a message to the measurement hardware system at the appropriate time(when a wafer is ready to be measurement). For example, setup sequences and/or run-time sequence may be performed. During a setup sequence, a TCD can receive one or more messages and can look for PAS tuning data in each wafer or lot setup message. When the TCD finds a tuning parameter, the TCD can forward just this part of the message to the PAS and the PAS can store this data in a database for later use. In addition, standard setup information can be sent to the process tool. After the process tool accepts the setup messages successfully, then the lot of wafer can start processing. If the first wafer is a pre measurement wafer, then the process tool can send just the setup information for the given wafer to the metrology hardware (wafer <b>1</b>). The metrology hardware will load the wafer and start making measurements at one or more sites. During each measurement the measurement hardware can send a spectral data set to the PAS. When the PAS receives the spectral data, it then looks for tuning data in the database (e.g,. if it was expecting tuning data). The PAS then uses this data with the spectral data to calculate data for the given site. The calculated data can then be sent back to the measurement hardware and/or to the process tool in real-time site by site.</p>
<p id="p-0323" num="0326">Although certain embodiments of this invention have been described in detail above, those skilled in the art will readily appreciate that many modifications are possible in the embodiments without materially departing from the novel teachings and advantages of this invention. Accordingly, all such modifications are intended to be included within the scope of this invention. Thus, the description is not intended to limit the invention and the configuration, operation, and behavior of the present invention has been described with the understanding that modifications and variations of the embodiments are possible, given the level of detail present herein. Accordingly, the preceding detailed description is not mean or intended to, in any way, limit the invention&#x2014;rather the scope of the invention is defined by the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method of processing a wafer comprising:
<claim-text>receiving the wafer and wafer data, wherein the wafer is received by a measurement subsystem, a wafer state is established for the wafer, and the wafer data includes historical and/or real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving an input message including a pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof, wherein the pass-through message includes historical wafer data and the real-time feedforward message includes real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating, by a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD), real-time feedforward data using the real-time feedforward message, wherein the real-time feedforward data is created when input message includes a real-time feedforward message, and is not created when the input message does not include a real-time feedforward message, wherein the real-time feedforward data includes real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>feed-forwarding the real-time feedforward data to a controller in the measurement subsystem when a feedforward state is a first value, and not feed-forwarding the real-time feedforward data when the feedforward state is a second value, wherein the feedforward state is the first value when the real-time feedforward data can be fed-forward before a measuring process is performed for the wafer, and wherein the feedforward state is the second value when the real-time feedforward data cannot be fed forward before the measuring process is performed for the wafer; and either
<claim-text>creating a tuned measurement recipe, a tuned measurement profile, or a tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof using a Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure that uses the real-time wafer thickness data as tuning data when a RTPT state is a first value and the input message includes a real-time feedforward message; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>not creating the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is a second value and/or the input message does not include a real-time feedforward message.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>measuring the wafer in the measurement subsystem using the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as a tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing measurement data associated with the tuned wafer as tuned measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating by the measurement subsystem an un-tuned measurement recipe an un-tuned measurement profile, or an un-tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the feedforward state is the second value, and/or the RTPT state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the wafer in the measurement subsystem using the un-tuned measurement recipe, the un-tuned measurement profile, or the un-tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as an un-tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing measurement data associated with the un-tuned wafer as un-tuned measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>modeling the wafer or modeling a measurement procedure for the wafer or modeling both of these in the measurement subsystem using the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the first value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein when the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof is created, the real-time wafer thickness data is used to determine one or more of:
<claim-text>a wafer radius for alignment procedure and/or an measurement procedure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wafer curvature;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a contaminant level, a contamination probability, and/or an out-gassing rate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an actual wafer thickness when the measurement occurs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the amount of energy radiated by the wafer in an alignment and/or measurement chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>optical properties for the wafer and a calibration factor for the optical properties; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>properties of a photoresist layer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating by a Real-Time Optimizer (RTO) real-time feedforward data and optimization data using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message, wherein the real-time feedforward data and optimization data is created when the feedforward state is the first value, and is not created data when the feedforward state is a second value, wherein the optimization data includes wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>feed-forwarding the real-time feedforward data and optimization data to a controller in the measurement subsystem when the feedforward state is the first value, and not feed-forwarding the real-time feedforward data and optimization data when the feedforward state is the second value, wherein the feedforward state is the first value when the real-time feedforward data and/or optimization data can be fed-forward before a measurement process is performed for the wafer, and wherein the feedforward state is the second value when the real-time feedforward data and/or optimization data cannot be fed-forward before the measurement process is performed for the wafer; and either</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating an optimized measurement recipe, an optimized measurement profile, or an optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof using a RTPT procedure that uses the real-time feedforward data and optimization data when the optimization state is the first value and the input message includes a feedforward message, or not creating, by a controller coupled to the RTO, the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when the optimization state is the second value and/or the input message does not include a feedforward message.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>measuring the wafer in the measurement subsystem using the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as an optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing measurement data associated with the optimized wafer as optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating by the measurement subsystem a non-optimized measurement recipe, a non-optimized measurement profile, or a non-optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when the feedforward state is the first value, and the optimization state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the wafer in the measurement subsystem using the non-optimized measurement recipe, the non-optimized measurement profile, or the non-optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as a non-optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing measurement data associated with the non-optimized wafer as non-optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>modeling the wafer or modeling a measurement procedure or modeling both of these in the measurement subsystem using the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when the optimization state is the first value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the measurement subsystem comprises a CD-Scanning Electron Microscopy (CDSEM) tool, a Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) tool, a focused ion beam (FIB) tool, an ODP tool, an Atomic Force Microscope (AFM) tool, or another optical metrology tool.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wafer is received by an integrated metrology (IM) tool in the measurement subsystem.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>collecting data using a Manufacturing Execution System (MES), the collected data including the historical and real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating additional real-time wafer thickness data, wherein the MES processes the collected data to create the additional real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating a formatted message comprising the additional real-time wafer thickness data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the formatted message using the MES.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the wafer state comprises a tuned variable (TV<sub>n,m</sub>), an optimized variable (OV<sub>n,m</sub>), a measured variable (MV<sub>n,m</sub>), and a processed variable (PV<sub>n,m</sub>), where n is the wafer number and m is a processing sequence number, the tuned variable (TV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value when the wafer has been tuned and is a second value when the wafer has not been tuned, the optimized variable (OV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value when the wafer has been optimized and is a second value when the wafer has not been optimized, the measured variable (MV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value when the wafer has been measured and is a second value when the wafer has not been measured, and the processed variable (PV<sub>n,m</sub>) is a first value when the wafer has been processed and is a second value when the wafer has not been processed.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. A method of processing a wafer comprising:
<claim-text>receiving the wafer and wafer data, wherein a wafer state is established for the wafer, and the wafer data includes thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, by a controller, an input message including a pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating feedforward recipe data, feedforward profile data, or feedforward model data, or any combination thereof using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message, wherein the feedforward recipe data, feedforward profile data, or feedforward model data, or any combination thereof is created when a feedforward state is a first value, and the feedforward recipe data, feedforward profile data, or feedforward model data, or any combination thereof is not created when the feedforward state is a second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the wafer to an integrated metrology (IM) tool when the sequencing state is a predetermined value corresponding to the IM tool;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the pass-through message to the IM tool when the input message includes the pass-through message and the sequencing state is said predetermined value, wherein the pass-through message is sent using a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD); and either</claim-text>
<claim-text>feed-forwarding the feedforward recipe data, the feedforward profile data, or the feedforward model data, or any combination thereof using one or more TCDs coupled to the IM tool when a feedforward state is the first value and a sequencing state is the predetermined value, or not feed-forwarding the feedforward recipe data, the feedforward profile data, or the feedforward model data, or any combination thereof when the feedforward state is a second value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating a tuned wafer model using a first Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure that uses the wafer thickness data, wherein the tuned wafer model is created when a RTPT state is the first value, and the tuned wafer model is not created when the RTPT state is a second value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the tuned wafer model.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating tuned wafer profile data using a second RTPT procedure that uses the wafer thickness data and/or the tuned wafer model, wherein the tuned wafer profile data is created when the RTPT state is the first value, and the tuned wafer profile data is not created when the RTPT state is the second value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the tuned wafer profile data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating a tuned measurement recipe using a third RTPT procedure that uses the tuned wafer model, the tuned wafer profile data, or the wafer thickness data, or any combination thereof, wherein the tuned measurement recipe is created when the RTPT state is the first value, and the optimized recipe data is not created when the RTPT state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the wafer using the tuned measurement recipe when the RTPT state is the first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as an tuned wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing measurement data associated with the tuned wafer as tuned measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating an optimized wafer model using a first Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure that uses the wafer thickness data and the pass-through message, wherein the optimized wafer model is created when an optimization state is a first value, and the optimized wafer model is not created when the optimization state is a second value, wherein the pass-through message includes optimization data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the optimized wafer model.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating optimized wafer profile data using a second RTPT procedure that uses the optimization data, the wafer thickness data and/or the optimized wafer model, wherein the optimized wafer profile data is created when the optimization state is the first value, and the optimized wafer profile data is not created when the optimization state is the second value; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing the optimized wafer profile data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating an optimized measurement recipe using a third RTPT procedure that uses the optimized wafer model, the optimized wafer profile data, or the real-time wafer thickness data, or any combination thereof, wherein the optimized measurement recipe is created when the optimization state is the first value, and the optimized recipe data is not created when the optimization state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring the wafer using the optimized measurement recipe when the optimization state is the first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as an optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>storing measurement data associated with the optimized wafer as optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text>21. A method of processing a wafer comprising:
<claim-text>receiving the wafer and wafer data, wherein a wafer state is established for the wafer, and the wafer data includes historical and/or real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, by a Real-Time Optimizer (RTO) an input message including a pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>creating, by the RTO, optimized data using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message, wherein the optimized data is created when an optimization state is a first value, and the optimized data is not created when the optimization state is a second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the wafer to an internal measurement subsystem when a sequencing state is a predetermined value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the pass-through message to the internal measurement subsystem when the input message includes the pass-through message and/or when a pass-through state is a first value and the sequencing state is the predetermined value, and not sending the pass-through message to the internal measurement subsystem when the input message does not include the pass-through message, wherein the pass-through message is sent using a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD); and either</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the optimized data to the internal measurement subsystem when the feedforward state is the first value and the sequencing state is the predetermined value, or not sending the optimized data to the internal measurement subsystem when the feedforward state is the second value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text>22. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating an optimized measurement recipe, an optimized measurement profile, or an optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof using a Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof to the internal measurement subsystem with the optimized data wherein the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof is created using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message and the optimization state is the first value, and the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof is not created when the optimization state is the second value, wherein the real-time feedforward message includes real-time wafer thickness data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text>23. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>measuring by the internal measurement subsystem the wafer using the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when an update state is a first value and the optimization state is the first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as an optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying measurement data associated with the optimized wafer as optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00024" num="00024">
<claim-text>24. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00023">claim 23</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>measuring by the internal measurement subsystem the wafer using a non-optimized measurement recipe when the update state is the second value, and the optimization state is the second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as a non-optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying measurement data associated with the non-optimized wafer as non-optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00025" num="00025">
<claim-text>25. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>creating an optimized measurement recipe, an optimized measurement profile, or an optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof using a Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure that uses the optimized data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring by the internal measurement subsystem the wafer using the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof when an update state is a first value, and the optimization state is the first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as an optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying measurement data associated with the optimized wafer as optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00026" num="00026">
<claim-text>26. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00025">claim 25</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>measuring by the internal measurement subsystem, the wafer using a non-optimized measurement recipe when the update state is a second value, and/or the optimization state is a second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying the measured wafer as a non-optimized wafer by changing the wafer state for the measured wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>identifying measurement data associated with the non-optimized wafer as non-optimized measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00027" num="00027">
<claim-text>27. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00022">claim 22</claim-ref>, wherein when the optimized measurement recipe, the optimized measurement profile, or the optimized measurement model, or any combination thereof is created, the real-time wafer thickness data is used to determine one or more of:
<claim-text>a wafer radius for alignment procedure and/or a measurement procedure;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wafer curvature;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a contaminant level, a contamination probability, and/or an out-gassing rate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>actual wafer thickness when the measurement occurs;</claim-text>
<claim-text>amount of energy radiated by the wafer in an alignment and/or measurement chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>optical properties for the wafer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a calibration factor for the optical properties the characteristics of a photoresist layer; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>the correct location for a measurement site on the wafer.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00028" num="00028">
<claim-text>28. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00021">claim 21</claim-ref>, wherein said predetermined value is a fourth value, the method further comprising:
<claim-text>sending the wafer to a lithography subsystem when the sequencing state is a first value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the wafer to an etch subsystem when the sequencing state is a second value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the wafer to a deposition subsystem when the sequencing state is a third value;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the wafer to an external measurement tool when the sequencing state is a fifth value, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the wafer to a transfer subsystem when the sequencing state is a sixth value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00029" num="00029">
<claim-text>29. A system for processing a wafer comprising:
<claim-text>a measurement subsystem configured to receive the wafer and wafer data, wherein a wafer state is established for the wafer, and the wafer data includes historical and/or real-time wafer thickness data, and to receive an input message including a pass-through message, or a real-time feedforward message, or any combination thereof, wherein the pass-through message includes historical wafer data and the real-time feedforward message includes real-time wafer thickness data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a Transparent Coupling Device (TCD) coupled to the measurement subsystem, and configured to create real-time feedforward data using the real-time feedforward message when the input message includes a real-time feedforward message, wherein the real-time feedforward data is created when a feedforward state is a first value, and is not created when the feedforward state is a second value, wherein the real-time feedforward data includes real-time wafer thickness data; feed-forward the real-time feedforward data to the measurement subsystem when the feedforward state is the first value, and not feed-forward the real-time feedforward data when the feedforward state is a second value, wherein the feedforward state is the first value when the real-time feedforward data can be fed-forward before an measurement process is performed for the wafer, and wherein the feedforward state is the second value when the real-time feedforward data cannot be fed-forward before the measurement process is performed for the wafer; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller that creates a tuned measurement recipe, a tuned measurement profile, or a tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof using a Real-Time Parameter Tuning (RTPT) procedure that uses the real-time feedforward data when a RTPT state is a first value, and does not create the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is a second value.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00030" num="00030">
<claim-text>30. The system as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00029">claim 29</claim-ref>, wherein the measurement subsystem comprises means for measuring the wafer using the tuned measurement recipe, the tuned measurement profile, or the tuned measurement model, or any combination thereof when the RTPT state is the first value, and for identifying the measured wafer as a tuned wafer by changing a wafer state for the wafer, and for storing measurement data associated with the tuned wafer as tuned measurement data.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00031" num="00031">
<claim-text>31. A computer readable medium containing program instructions for execution on a computer system coupled to a semiconductor processing system, which when executed by the computer system, cause the semiconductor processing system to perform a process, comprising the steps of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00032" num="00032">
<claim-text>32. A method of performing optical measurements on a wafer comprising:
<claim-text>processing an input signal to obtain non-tuning data including a measurement recipe for use in the optical measurement system;</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing an optical measurement based on the measurement recipe at optical measurement hardware of the measurement system to obtain an optical diffraction signal from a measurement site on said wafer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining tuning data an optical analysis system of the measurement system; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating a measurement result based on said optical diffraction signal and said tuning data.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00033" num="00033">
<claim-text>33. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein said processing is performed by a processor of the optical measurement system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00034" num="00034">
<claim-text>34. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein said processing is performed by a TCD associated with the optical measurement system, said TCD being either external to the optical measurement system or an integral part of the optical measurement system.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00035" num="00035">
<claim-text>35. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein said performing comprises performing an optical measurement based on a measurement recipe including measurements for a plurality of measurement sites on the semiconductor wafer, wherein a plurality of diffraction signals corresponding to said plurality of measurement sites are obtained as a result of performance of the recipe.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00036" num="00036">
<claim-text>36. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein said obtaining comprises obtaining external tuning data including wafer characteristic data from said input message.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00037" num="00037">
<claim-text>37. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00036">claim 36</claim-ref>, wherein said wafer characteristic data of the external tuning data comprises end data measured and/or calculated by a subsystem external to the optical measurement tool.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00038" num="00038">
<claim-text>38. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein said obtaining comprises obtaining internal tuning data including wafer characteristic data created during said measurement in the optical measurement hardware.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00039" num="00039">
<claim-text>39. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00032">claim 32</claim-ref>, wherein said tuning data comprises n&#x26;k values determined by either the optical measurement system or a system other than the optical measurement system or both.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
