<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641492-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641492</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11987736</doc-number>
<date>20071204</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-330428</doc-number>
<date>20061207</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439271</main-classification>
<further-classification>439272</further-classification>
<further-classification>439382</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Electrical connector having vibration-resisting structure</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4713021</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kobler</name>
<date>19871200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439272</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5252088</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Morello et al.</name>
<date>19931000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439271</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0059970</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Ichio et al.</name>
<date>20070300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439382</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-174813</doc-number>
<date>20050600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439271</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439275</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439382</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439383</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439385</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080139039</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080612</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Azuma</last-name>
<first-name>Keiko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Makinohara</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Torii</last-name>
<first-name>Chieko</first-name>
<address>
<city>Makinohara</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Katsuura</last-name>
<first-name>Tomomi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Makinohara</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Edwards Angell Palmer &#x26; Dodge LLP</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Yazaki Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Zarroli</last-name>
<first-name>Michael C</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A connector including: a first connector housing having a tube-shaped hood part; a second connector housing to be fitted to the first connector housing; and a groove part provided on the second connector housing, wherein a terminal receiving part of the second connector housing is positioned in the hood part so that the first and second connector housings are fitted to each other, wherein an end part of the hood part enters the groove part when the first and second connector housings are fitted to each other.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="157.06mm" wi="158.75mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="176.70mm" wi="171.96mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="175.85mm" wi="159.85mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="192.02mm" wi="177.38mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641492-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="172.38mm" wi="140.55mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="181.78mm" wi="173.31mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641492-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="192.45mm" wi="172.97mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641492-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="158.58mm" wi="154.60mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="154.60mm" wi="170.69mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="159.94mm" wi="156.29mm" file="US07641492-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">(1) Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a connector having a vibration-resisting structure.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">(2) Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A motor vehicle mounts various electronic instruments which are connected to the motor vehicle and other electronic instruments through a wiring harness. The electronic instruments are connected to the wiring harness when connectors of the electronic instruments are coupled with those of the wiring harness.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The connector includes a connector housing and a terminal fitting to be received in the connector housing. When the connectors are coupled with each other, the respective terminal fittings in the connector housing are electrically connected to each other. Then, the wiring harness transmits electric power, control signals and so on to the electronic instruments.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Such a connector may be often used under a severe condition of vibration such as a condition in an engine room. In such a case, the connector is shaken due to the vibration causing the connector to suffer from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of an electrical contact of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In order to solve the above problem, various connectors have been proposed (for example, see Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2005-174813). Such a connector includes a male connector housing (hereinafter, male housing) and a female connector housing (hereinafter, female housing) which fits to the male housing. The male housing includes: a body part receiving terminal fittings; a resilient member attached to the outside of the body part; and an outer housing formed outside the body part being spaced from the body part. The male housing includes the hood-shaped body part which receives the terminal fittings.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">After the body part of the female housing enters between the body part of the male housing and the outer housing, then the male and female housings fit to each other. The resilient member is positioned between the outside of the body part of the male housing and the inside of the body part of the female housing. Then, an end part of the female housing presses one end part of the resilient member near the male housing, while a projection formed on an inner surface at the base end part-side of the body part of the female housing presses an opposite end part of the resilient member.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In the connector described in Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. 2005-174813, the resilient member is positioned between the outside of the body part of the male housing and the inside of the body part of the female housing. Therefore, the outer housing of the male housing may be shaken due to vibration, causing the connector to suffer from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of an electrical contact of the terminal fitting. When things come to the worst, the terminal fitting may be damaged.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">It is therefore an objective of the present invention to solve the above problem and to provide a connector, by which the connector can be prevented from being shaken with a simple structure thereof so that the terminal fitting can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">In order to attain the above objective, the present invention is to provide a connector including:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">a first connector housing having a tube-shaped hood part;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">a second connector housing to be fitted to the first connector housing; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">a groove part provided on the second connector housing, wherein a terminal receiving part of the second connector housing is positioned in the hood part so that the first and second connector housings are fitted to each other,</p>
<p id="h-0003" num="0000">wherein an end part of the hood part enters the groove part when the first and second connector housings are fitted to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">With the construction described above, the second connector housing includes the groove part into which the end part of the hood part of the first connector housing enters. Therefore, the end part of the hood part enters the groove part so that the first and second connector housings are fixed to each other stably. Accordingly, the connector can be prevented from being shaken with a simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">A width of the groove part decreases from a hood part-entering side of the groove part to the depth side of the groove part.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">With the construction described above, the end part of the hood part comes in stable contact with the inner surface of the groove part, so that the first and second connector housings are further stably fixed to each other. Accordingly, the connector can be further prevented from being shaken with a simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">At least one of an inner surface of the groove part and the end part of the hood part includes a resilient member made of resilient material.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">With the construction described above, the inner surface of the groove part closely comes in contact with the end part of the hood part through the resilient member, so that the resilient member is resiliently deformed so as to absorb the shaking of the connector. Accordingly, the connector can be further prevented from being shaken with a simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting. Moreover, by composing the resilient member with heat resisting resilient material, the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector can be prevented from reducing due to heat deterioration.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The first connector housing includes an engaging part, the second connector housing includes a mating engaging part to be engaged with the engaging part, and at least one of the engaging part and the mating engaging part includes a resilient member made of resilient material.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">With the construction described above, the engaging part closely comes in contact with the mating engaging part through the resilient member and the resilient member is resiliently deformed so as to absorb the shaking of the connector. Accordingly, the connector can be further prevented from being shaken with a simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting. Moreover, by composing the resilient member with heat resisting resilient material, the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector can be prevented from reducing due to heat deterioration.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a connector according to the first preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along II-II line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of a female housing shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along IV-IV line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a front view of a female housing shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a perspective view of a male housing shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross sectional view taken along VII-VII line in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a front view of a male housing shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a cross sectional view illustrating a male housing of a connector according to the second preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">In the following, a connector according to the first preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1-8</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, a connector <b>1</b> according to the first preferred embodiment of the present invention includes a male connector housing <b>2</b> (hereinafter, male housing <b>2</b>) and a female connector housing <b>5</b> (hereinafter, female housing <b>5</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In the first preferred embodiment, the male housing <b>2</b> corresponds to the first connector housing described in the claims and the female housing <b>5</b> corresponds to the second connector housing described in the claims. An outer housing <b>7</b> (explained later) of the male housing <b>2</b> corresponds to the hood part described in the claims, a body part <b>32</b> (explained later) of the female housing <b>5</b> corresponds to the terminal receiving part described in the claims, and a groove <b>34</b> (explained later) of the female housing <b>5</b> corresponds to the groove part described in the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The male housing <b>2</b> is made of electrically insulating synthetic resin or the like. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, the male housing <b>2</b> includes a body part <b>6</b> and an outer housing <b>7</b>. The body part <b>6</b> is formed in a tube-shape. The body part <b>6</b> receives a terminal fitting (not shown in the figure) attached to an end of an electric wire therein. The terminal fitting is made of electrically conductive sheet metal or the like. This terminal fitting is electrically connected to a terminal fitting of the female housing <b>5</b> when the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b> are fitted to each other.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The outer housing <b>7</b> is formed in a tube-shape including an outer wall <b>7</b><i>a</i>. The outer housing <b>7</b> receives the body part <b>6</b> therein. The outer housing <b>7</b> is arranged spaced from the body part <b>6</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the outer housing <b>7</b> includes a hole <b>11</b>, notched part <b>12</b>, guide recess <b>13</b>, resilient member <b>20</b>, contact part <b>8</b>, and locking arm <b>9</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">The hole <b>11</b> is formed in a rectangular shape in a plan view. The hole <b>11</b> is formed penetrating through the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the outer housing <b>7</b> near the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted, to which the outer housing <b>7</b> fits. The hole <b>11</b> is formed penetrating through the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the housing <b>7</b>, the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>facing the locking arm <b>9</b>. The hole <b>11</b> exposes one end part <b>16</b> (explained later) of the locking arm <b>9</b>. The hole <b>11</b> permits the one end part <b>16</b> of the locking arm <b>9</b>, which is resiliently deformed, to pass therethrough.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The notched part <b>12</b> is formed by notching the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>in a direction approaching the female housing <b>5</b> from an end part of the outer housing <b>7</b>, which end part is situated away from the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted, to which the outer housing <b>7</b> fits. The notched part <b>12</b> and the hole <b>11</b> are arranged lined up along a fitting direction of the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a plurality of the guide recesses <b>13</b> are formed from an inner surface of the outer housing <b>7</b>. The guide recess <b>13</b> extends along the fitting direction of the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>. A guide rib <b>37</b> (explained later) of the female housing <b>5</b> enters the guide recess <b>13</b> so as to make the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b> be fitted to each other in a proper direction.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The resilient member <b>20</b> is provided on an end part (i.e. an end part near the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted) of the outer housing <b>7</b>. The resilient member <b>20</b> is provided by assembling, two-color molding or the like. The resilient member <b>20</b> is made of resilient material such as rubber. The resilient member <b>20</b> is made of heat resisting resilient material in order to prevent the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector from reducing due to heat deterioration. The resilient member <b>20</b> comes in contact with a groove <b>34</b> (explained later) of the female housing <b>5</b> so as to prevent the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> from being shaken within the groove <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the contact part <b>8</b> is formed in a prism-shape and continues to the outer housing <b>7</b> at both ends in the longitudinal direction of the contact part <b>8</b>. The contact part <b>8</b> is arranged in a direction crossing at right angles the longitudinal direction of the locking arm <b>9</b>. The contact part <b>8</b> is arranged between the hole <b>11</b> and the notched part <b>12</b>. The contact part <b>8</b> is arranged facing the locking arm <b>9</b> and being spaced from the locking arm <b>9</b>. The contact part <b>8</b> comes in contact with the locking arm <b>9</b> when the locking arm <b>9</b> engages with an engaging projection <b>33</b> of the female housing <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">The locking arm <b>9</b> is formed continuing to the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the outer housing <b>7</b>. The longitudinal direction of the locking arm <b>9</b> is parallel to the fitting direction of the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>. An end part <b>16</b> (situated left in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) of the locking arm <b>9</b> in the longitudinal direction thereof is arranged near the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted, while an opposite end part <b>17</b> (situated right in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>) of the locking arm <b>9</b> in the longitudinal direction thereof is arranged away from the female housing <b>5</b>. The locking arm <b>9</b> includes: a connecting part <b>14</b> for connecting to the outer housing <b>7</b>; and an arm body <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">A pair of the connecting parts <b>14</b> is provided, each extending in a direction leaving the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted from the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>of the outer housing <b>7</b>, which is notched to the notched part <b>12</b>. A contact part between the connecting part <b>14</b> and the outer wall <b>7</b><i>a </i>is positioned at the center of the locking arm <b>9</b> in the longitudinal direction thereof. The connecting parts <b>14</b> position the arm body <b>15</b> therebetween. A pair of the connecting parts <b>14</b> is connected to an opposite end part <b>17</b> of the arm body <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">The arm body <b>15</b> is formed in a band plate-shape. The arm body <b>15</b> is arranged between the body part <b>6</b> and an outer housing <b>7</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the arm body <b>15</b> includes an engaging hole <b>18</b> as the engaging part and an operation part <b>19</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">The engaging hole <b>18</b> penetrates through the arm body <b>15</b>. The engaging hole <b>18</b> is formed at the end part <b>16</b> of the arm body <b>15</b>. The engaging hole <b>18</b> is formed in a rectangular shape in a plan view. An engaging projection <b>33</b> (explained later) of the female housing <b>5</b> enters the engaging hole <b>18</b>. When the engaging projection <b>33</b> enters the engaging hole <b>18</b>, the locking arm <b>9</b> engages with the engaging projection <b>33</b> so as to maintain the fitting between the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>. An inner surface of the engaging hole <b>18</b> is provided with the resilient member <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The resilient member <b>21</b> is formed on the inner surface of the engaging hole <b>18</b> near the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted. The resilient member <b>21</b> is provided by assembling, two-color molding or the like. The resilient member <b>21</b> is made of resilient material such as rubber. The resilient member <b>21</b> is made of heat resisting resilient material in order to prevent the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector from reducing due to heat deterioration. The resilient member <b>21</b> comes in contact with the engaging projection <b>33</b> so as to prevent the engaging projection <b>33</b> from being shaken within the engaging hole <b>18</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The operation part <b>19</b> is provided on an outer surface of the arm body <b>15</b> situated away from the body part <b>6</b>. The operation part <b>19</b> is provided at the opposite end part <b>17</b> of the arm body <b>15</b>. When the operation part <b>19</b> is pushed down, the engagement between the locking arm <b>9</b> and the engaging projection <b>33</b> is removed.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, a gap <b>10</b> is formed between the body part <b>6</b> and the outer housing <b>7</b>. An outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the body part <b>32</b> enters the gap <b>10</b>. An end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the gap <b>10</b> situated away from the female housing <b>5</b> to be fitted is formed in a tapered shape so that the width of the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>decreases as approaching the depth side (i.e. right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>). The end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>may be formed in an arc-shape in section.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The female housing <b>5</b> is made of electrically insulating synthetic resin or the like. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>, the female housing <b>5</b> includes a cover part <b>31</b>, body part <b>32</b>, engaging projection <b>33</b> as the mating engaging part, and groove <b>34</b>. The cover part <b>31</b> is formed in a tube-shape having a bottom. The cover part <b>31</b> is provided on the female housing <b>5</b> at the side situated away from the male housing <b>2</b> to be fitted. The cover part <b>31</b> includes a bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a</i>, peripheral wall <b>31</b><i>b </i>continuing to a peripheral edge of the bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a</i>, and rising-up wall <b>31</b><i>c. </i></p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>is formed in a flat plate-shape. The bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>is arranged in a direction crossing at right angles the fitting direction between the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>includes a terminal hole part <b>36</b> through which a terminal fitting (not shown in the figure) passes. The terminal hole part <b>36</b> is formed in a tube-shape and formed projecting from an outer surface of the bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>situated away from the body part <b>32</b>. The inside of the terminal hole part <b>36</b> is provided with a terminal hole <b>36</b><i>a </i>through which the terminal fitting passes and projects toward the body part <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The peripheral wall <b>31</b><i>b </i>is formed from the peripheral edge of the bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>extending in a direction leaving the body part <b>32</b>. The rising-up wall <b>31</b><i>c </i>is formed rising up from an outer surface of the bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>near the body part <b>32</b>. The rising-up wall <b>31</b><i>c </i>is formed throughout the entire outer periphery of the body part <b>32</b> having a distance from the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the body part <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">The body part <b>32</b> is formed in a tube-shape by the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a</i>. The body part <b>32</b> continues to the bottom wall <b>31</b><i>a </i>of the cover part <b>31</b>. The inside of the body part <b>32</b> receives a terminal fitting (not shown in the figure) entered into the terminal hole <b>36</b>. The terminal fitting is made of an electrically conductive sheet metal or the like. The terminal fitting is attached to an end of an electric wire. When the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b> fit to each other, the terminal fitting is electrically connected to a terminal fitting of the male housing <b>2</b>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the body part <b>32</b> includes a guide rib <b>37</b> and a resilient member <b>35</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">A plurality of the guide ribs <b>37</b> are formed projecting from the outer surface of the body part <b>32</b>. The guide rib <b>37</b> extends along the fitting direction between the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b>. The guide rib <b>37</b> enters the guide recess <b>13</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> so as to fit the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b> to each other in a proper direction.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The resilient member <b>35</b> is provided at an end part (i.e. end part near the male housing <b>2</b> to be fitted) of the body part <b>32</b>. The resilient member <b>35</b> is provided by assembling, two-color molding or the like. The resilient member <b>35</b> is made of resilient material such as rubber. The resilient member <b>35</b> is made of heat resisting resilient material in order to prevent the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector from reducing due to heat deterioration. The resilient member <b>35</b> comes in contact with an end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of a gap <b>10</b> (explained later) of the male housing <b>2</b> so as to prevent the end part of the body part <b>32</b> from being shaken within the end part <b>10</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the engaging projection <b>33</b> is formed projecting from the outer surface of the body part <b>32</b>. The engaging projection <b>33</b> engages with the engaging hole <b>18</b> of the locking arm <b>9</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> so as to maintain the engagement between the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the groove <b>34</b> is formed between the rising-up wall <b>31</b><i>c </i>and the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the body part <b>32</b>. An end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> enters the groove <b>34</b>. The groove <b>34</b> is formed in a tapered shape so that the width of the groove <b>34</b> decreases as approaching the depth side (i.e. right side in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>). The groove <b>34</b> may be formed in an arc-shape in section.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">When the connector <b>1</b> having the structure described above is assembled, first, the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> is allowed to enter the gap <b>10</b> between the body part <b>6</b> and the outer housing <b>7</b> of the male housing <b>2</b>. Then, the engaging projection <b>33</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> comes in contact with the end part <b>16</b> of the locking arm <b>9</b> of the male housing <b>2</b>. The locking arm <b>9</b> is pushed up by the engaging projection <b>33</b> so as to be resiliently deformed, so that the locking arm <b>9</b> comes in contact with the contact part <b>8</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">When the male housing <b>2</b> is allowed to further approach the female housing <b>5</b>, the engaging projection <b>33</b> further pushes up a portion of the locking arm <b>9</b> ranging from the end part of the locking arm <b>9</b> to the contact part <b>8</b>. Then, the engaging projection <b>33</b> enters the engaging hole <b>18</b> of the locking arm <b>9</b>, so that the engaging hole <b>18</b> engages with the engaging projection <b>33</b>. The engaging projection <b>33</b> resiliently deforms the resilient member <b>21</b> of the engaging hole <b>18</b>, so that the engaging projection <b>33</b> is received in the engaging hole <b>18</b> without being shaken. As a result, the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b> fit to each other, thereby assembling the connector <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">When the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b> fit to each other, the outer housing <b>7</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> positions the body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> thereinside. Further, the body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> positions the body part <b>6</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> thereinside.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> enters the groove <b>34</b> of the female housing <b>5</b>. The resilient member <b>20</b> of the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> is resiliently deformed, closely comes in contact with the inner surface of the groove <b>34</b> formed in a tapered shape, and is received in the groove <b>34</b> without being shaken. Further, the end part of the body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> enters the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the gap <b>10</b> of the male housing <b>2</b>. The resilient member <b>35</b> of the end part of the body part <b>32</b> is resiliently deformed, closely comes in contact with the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the gap <b>10</b> formed in a tapered shape, and is received in the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>without being shaken.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">According to the preferred embodiment described above, the female housing <b>5</b> includes the groove <b>34</b>, into which the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> enters. Therefore, the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> enters the groove <b>34</b>, so that the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b> are stably fixed to each other. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The width of the groove <b>34</b> is formed to decrease as the groove <b>34</b> leaves the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b>. Therefore, the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> stably comes in contact with the inner surface of the groove <b>34</b>, so that the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b> are further stably fixed to each other. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">The end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> includes the resilient member <b>20</b>. Therefore, the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> closely comes in contact with the inner surface of the groove <b>34</b> through the resilient member <b>20</b>, and the resilient member <b>20</b> is resiliently deformed so as to absorb the shaking of the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting. Further, by composing the resilient member <b>20</b> with heat resisting resilient material, the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from reducing due to heat deterioration.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The male housing <b>2</b> includes the engaging hole <b>18</b>, the female housing <b>5</b> includes the engaging projection <b>33</b>, and the engaging hole <b>18</b> includes the resilient member <b>21</b>. Therefore, the engaging hole <b>18</b> closely comes in contact with the engaging projection <b>33</b> through the resilient member <b>21</b>, and the resilient member <b>21</b> is resiliently deformed so as to absorb the shaking of the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting. Further, by composing the resilient member <b>21</b> with heat resisting resilient material, the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from reducing due to heat deterioration.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">In the first preferred embodiment described above, the resilient member <b>20</b> is provided on the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b>. However, instead, the resilient member <b>20</b> may be provided on the inner surface of the groove <b>34</b>. Further, the resilient member <b>20</b> may be provided on both the end part of the outer housing <b>7</b> and the inner surface of the groove <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064">Further, in the first preferred embodiment described above, the resilient member <b>21</b> is provided on the inner surface of the engaging hole <b>18</b>. However, instead, the resilient member <b>21</b> may be provided on the outer surface of the engaging projection <b>33</b>. Further, the resilient member <b>21</b> may be provided on both the inner surface of the engaging hole <b>18</b> and the outer surface of the engaging projection <b>33</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">In the following, a connector according to the second preferred embodiment of the present invention will be explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066">In the second preferred embodiment, the female housing <b>5</b> corresponds to the first connector housing described in the claims and the male housing <b>2</b> corresponds to the second connector housing described in the claims. An outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of a body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> corresponds to the hood part described in the claims, a body part <b>6</b> of the male housing <b>2</b> corresponds to the terminal receiving part described in the claims, and an end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the male housing <b>2</b> corresponds to the groove part described in the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, the male housing <b>2</b> according to the second preferred embodiment includes a resilient member <b>22</b> on an end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of a gap <b>10</b> formed between a body part <b>6</b> and an outer housing <b>7</b>. The resilient member <b>22</b> is provided on an inner surface of the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>by assembling, two-color molding or the like. The resilient member <b>22</b> is made of resilient material such as rubber. The resilient member <b>22</b> is made of heat resisting resilient material in order to prevent the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector from reducing due to heat deterioration.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">The resilient member <b>22</b> comes in contact with an outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of a body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b>. The resilient member <b>22</b> is provided with a groove <b>22</b><i>a</i>, into which an end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>enters. Further, a surface of the resilient member <b>22</b> facing the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>is formed in a tapered shape so as to facilitate the entering of the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a</i>. The end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>is formed tapered to a point so as to facilitate the entering thereof into the end part <b>10</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">When the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b> fit to each other, the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> enters the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>of the gap <b>10</b>. The end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>enters the groove <b>22</b><i>a </i>of the resilient member <b>22</b> so as to resiliently deform the resilient member <b>22</b> and closely comes in contact with the resilient member <b>22</b> so as to be received in the groove <b>22</b><i>a</i>. The resilient member <b>22</b> absorbs the omnidirectional shaking of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a</i>, that is, the omnidirectional shaking of the female housing <b>5</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070">According to the preferred embodiment described above, the male housing <b>2</b> includes the end part <b>10</b><i>a</i>, into which the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>of the body part <b>32</b> of the female housing <b>5</b> enters. Therefore, the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>enters the end part <b>10</b><i>a</i>, so that the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b> are stably fixed to each other. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The width of the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>is formed to decrease as the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>leaves the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a</i>. Therefore, the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>stably comes in contact with the inner surface of the end part <b>10</b><i>a</i>, so that the female housing <b>5</b> and the male housing <b>2</b> are further stably fixed to each other. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">The inner surface of the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>includes the resilient member <b>22</b>. Therefore, the inner surface of the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>closely comes in contact with the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a </i>through the resilient member <b>22</b>, and the resilient member <b>22</b> is resiliently deformed so as to absorb the shaking of the male housing <b>2</b> and the female housing <b>5</b>. Accordingly, the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from being shaken with the simple structure thereof so that the connector can be prevented from suffering from failure in electrical continuity due to abrasion of the terminal fitting. Further, since the resilient member <b>22</b> is positioned so as to receive the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a</i>, therefore resilient member <b>22</b> effectively absorbs the omnidirectional shaking of the connector <b>1</b>. Furthermore, by composing the resilient member <b>22</b> with heat resisting resilient material, the effect for preventing the shaking of the connector <b>1</b> can be prevented from reducing due to heat deterioration.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">Further, in the second preferred embodiment described above, the resilient member <b>22</b> is provided on the inner surface of the end part <b>10</b><i>a</i>. However, instead, the resilient member <b>22</b> may be provided on the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a</i>. Further, the resilient member <b>22</b> may be provided on both the inner surface of the end part <b>10</b><i>a </i>and the end part of the outer wall <b>32</b><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">The aforementioned preferred embodiments are described to aid in understanding the present invention and variations may be made by one skilled in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connector comprising:
<claim-text>a first connector housing having a tube-shaped hood part;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second connector housing to be fitted to the first connector housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an annular-shaped groove part provided outside a terminal receiving part of the second connector housing,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the terminal receiving part of the second connector housing is positioned in the hood part so that the first and second connector housings are fitted to each other,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein an end part of the hood part abuts against a tapered portion of the groove part so that the end part of the hood part is received in the groove part when the first and second connector housings are fitted to each other, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a width of the groove part decreases from a hood part-entering side of the groove part to the depth side of the groove part.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein at least one of an inner surface of the groove part and the end part of the hood part includes a resilient member made of resilient material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The connector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first connector housing includes an engaging part, the second connector housing includes a mating engaging part to be engaged with the engaging part, and at least one of the engaging part and the mating engaging part includes a resilient member made of resilient material. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
