<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641493-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641493</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12208278</doc-number>
<date>20080910</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>52</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439271</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Waterproof tightening structure for a signal connector</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4173385</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Fenn et al.</name>
<date>19791100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439277</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4291932</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Cox</name>
<date>19810900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439271</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6386915</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Nelson</name>
<date>20020500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439584</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7354309</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Palinkas</name>
<date>20080400</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439588</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>3</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439271-275</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439277</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439587</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Chun-Te</first-name>
<address>
<street>No. 61, Taiping Rd., North District</street>
<city>Taichung</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chow</last-name>
<first-name>Ming</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sinorica, LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Prasad</last-name>
<first-name>Chandrika</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter includes a bolt sleeve bored with a through insert hole provided inside with an annular stop edge formed with an annular holding groove and a first engage surface. A tightening connecter is inserted in the insert hole, and has a flange resisting the stop edge of the bolt sleeve and its second engage surface loosely fixed with the first engage surface. A fixing outer sleeve is secured with the annular projection of the tightening connecter. An elastic waterproof washer is received in an annular recess between the annular projection and the second engage surface and resisted by both the annular holding groove of the bolt sleeve and the front end of the fixing outer sleeve. Thus, the waterproof washer is closely and elastically held by the bolt sleeve, the tightening connecter and the fixing outer sleeve, able to block off moisture.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="120.31mm" wi="321.48mm" file="US07641493-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="217.25mm" wi="137.08mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641493-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="179.32mm" wi="135.64mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641493-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="143.43mm" wi="139.02mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641493-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="224.87mm" wi="146.81mm" file="US07641493-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="297.01mm" wi="209.89mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641493-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">This invention relates to a waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Prior Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A conventional signal connecter, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, includes a bolt sleeve <b>1</b>, a tightening connecter <b>2</b> and a fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b> combined together. The tightening connecter <b>2</b> is inserted in the interior of the bolt sleeve <b>1</b>, having its front end formed with a projecting ring <b>4</b> to resist against the inner wall of a stop edge <b>5</b> which is annularly disposed around the lower outer circumference of the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> and protruding toward the hollow center of the bolt sleeve <b>1</b>. The fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b>, to be fitted around the outer circumference of the tightening connecter <b>2</b> has its front end axially bored with an inner hole <b>6</b> to be tightly fitted with the tightening connecter <b>2</b>. A slot way <b>7</b>, preset in width, is defined by the rear inner wall of the fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b> and the outer circumference of the tightening connecter <b>2</b> for receiving a signal wire <b>100</b> therein. The signal wire <b>100</b> consists of an insulating layer <b>101</b>, a wire gauze layer <b>102</b> wrapped in the insulating layer <b>101</b>, a foamed core <b>103</b> disposed in the center and a guide wire <b>104</b> extending out of the center of the foamed core <b>103</b>. Further, the tightening connecter <b>2</b> has an outer edge at its rear section provided with a plurality of ratchet rings <b>8</b> for tightly fixing the signal wire <b>100</b>. The fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b> has its rear outer edge disposed with a plurality of circular rings <b>9</b> spaced apart. In assembling, the signal wire <b>100</b> is first inserted in the slot way <b>7</b> of the signal connecter and firmly fitted on the ratchet rings <b>8</b> on the rear outer edge of the tightening connecter <b>2</b>, and then the circular rings <b>9</b> on the rear outer surface of the fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b> are clamped and compressed by the clamping head of pliers (not shown) to secure the signal wire <b>100</b> on the ratchet rings <b>8</b> of the tightening connecter <b>2</b>. At this time, the fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b> has its front end closely resisting the rear outer end of the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> and tightly fitted with the tightening connecter <b>2</b>. Thus, the conventional signal connecter is closely assembled to enable the front end of the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> connecting to a signal terminal, such as a TV terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">However, after the conventional signal connecter is assembled, the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> and the projecting ring of the tightening connecter <b>2</b> are fixed together only by resisting of the fixing outer sleeve <b>3</b>; therefore, the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> and the tightening connecter <b>2</b> are of a loose fit structure and hence a gap still remains between the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> and the tightening connecter <b>2</b>. Thus, when the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> is rotated for connecting to a signal terminal, moisture is easily to permeate into the signal connecter through the gap between the bolt sleeve <b>1</b> and the tightening connecter <b>2</b> to wet the wire gauze layer <b>102</b> in the signal wire <b>100</b>. This will result in signal loss and fading or cause noise interference. As commonly known, there may be thousands of signal connecters used in a network; therefore, so long as one minute part is designed imperfect, the overall situation of the network will be affected.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The objective of this invention is to provide a waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter so that, when combined with a signal terminal, the signal connecter can avoid producing any gap among the components to prevent moisture from permeating into the interior and wetting the signal connecter.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter in the present invention includes a bolt sleeve, a tightening connecter and a fixing outer sleeve. The bolt sleeve is axially bored with a through insert hole provided inside with a stop edge formed with an annular holding groove and a first engage surface. The tightening connecter to be inserted in the insert hole of the bolt sleeve is formed with a flange to resist the stop edge of the bolt sleeve and axially disposed with a gradually-contracted second engage surface to be loosely fixed with the first engage surface of the bolt sleeve. Further, the tightening connecter is formed with an annular projection to be tightly fixed with the fixing outer sleeve, a rear-sectional ratchet member and an annular recess disposed between the annular projection and the second engage surface. An elastic waterproof washer is received in the annular recess of the tightening connecter, having its outer side protruding out of the annular recess to be closely resisted by one end of the annular holding groove at the inner side of the stop edge of the bolt sleeve. The fixing outer sleeve is fitted around the outer circumference of the tightening connecter to push against an outer side of the waterproof washer, with a gap formed between the fixing outer sleeve and the rear end of the bolt sleeve.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">With the structure of the present invention, after assembled together, the bolt sleeve, the tightening connecter and the fixing outer sleeve can be closely jointed together by means of the waterproof washer to achieve multiple locking effect. When the bolt sleeve is rotated for connecting to a signal terminal, the stop edge of the bolt sleeve will closely resist the waterproof washer, which can always keep close contact with the stop edge by its expanding elasticity, and the gap kept between the bolt sleeve and the fixing outer sleeve can function to prevent them from interfering with each other. Thus, the signal connecter of this invention can prevent moisture from permeating into the interior through the gap produced among the components.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">This invention will be better understood by referring to the accompanying drawings, wherein:</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a conventional signal connecter;</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter in the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter in the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> includes a partial enlarged cross-sectional view of the waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter in the present invention, and a further enlarged sectional view showing the first engage surface; and</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter in the present invention, showing that a signal wire is inserted in the slot way of a tightening connecter.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A preferred embodiment of a waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter in the present invention, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, includes a bolt sleeve <b>10</b>, a tightening connecter <b>20</b> and a fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> combined together.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The bolt sleeve <b>10</b> has its center axially formed with a through insert hole <b>11</b> with female threads <b>12</b> to enable the front end of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> to be threadably connected with a signal terminal, and its rear inner circumference annularly provided with a stop edge <b>13</b> radially protruding toward the center. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the stop edge <b>13</b> is disposed with an annular holding groove <b>131</b> at the rear end of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and has its inner annular side formed with a first engage surface <b>132</b>, this can be seen in the further enlarged sectional view showing the first engage surface, that is gradually expanded toward the signal terminal to form a conical surface.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The tightening connecter <b>20</b> is a hollow cylinder to be inserted in the insert hole <b>11</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>, having its front end formed with a flange <b>21</b> for resisting the front side of the stop edge <b>13</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>. The flange <b>21</b> has one end extending outward radially toward the stop edge <b>13</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and orderly formed with a second engage surface <b>22</b> with a comparatively small diameter, an annular projection <b>23</b> smaller than the second engage surface <b>22</b> in diameter and a rear-sectional ratchet member <b>24</b> whose diameter is smaller than the second engage surface <b>22</b>. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, when the tightening connecter <b>20</b> is inserted in the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>, the outer circumference of the second engage surface <b>22</b> of the tightening connecter <b>20</b> will correspond with the first engage surface <b>132</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>, and the second engage surface <b>22</b> is restrictedly positioned and engaged on the first engage surface <b>132</b>, letting the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and the tightening connecter <b>20</b> loosely fixed together. Further, an annular recess <b>231</b> is formed at a location between the annular projection <b>23</b> and the second engage surface <b>22</b> of the tightening connecter <b>22</b> for receiving an elastically tightening waterproof washer <b>25</b>, which has its outer side protruding out of the annular recess <b>231</b> to be closely resisted by the annular holding groove <b>131</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>, with an accommodating chamber <b>26</b> defined by the waterproof washer <b>25</b> and the first engage surface <b>132</b> and the second engage surface <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> is a hollow cylinder to be fitted around the outer circumference of the tightening connecter <b>20</b>, having its front end bored with an inner hole <b>30</b> to be tightly fitted with the annular projection <b>23</b> of the tightening connecter <b>20</b>. The fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> has the outer side of its front end formed with an annular resisting surface <b>32</b> for resisting one outer side of the waterproof washer <b>25</b>, with a joint gap <b>33</b> kept between the front end of the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> and the rear end of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>. An annular slot way <b>34</b> with a proper width is formed between the rear inner circumference of the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> and the outer circumference of the rear ratchet member <b>24</b> of the tightening connecter <b>20</b> to enable the rear ends of the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> and the tightening connecter <b>20</b> to connect a signal wire <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">In assembling, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, firstly, the tightening connecter <b>20</b> is inserted through the insert hole <b>11</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> to have its projecting ring <b>21</b> resisting against the stop edge <b>13</b> in the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and its second engage surface <b>22</b> restrictedly engaged with the first engage surface <b>132</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>. Simultaneously, the inner circumference of the annular holding groove <b>131</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> will be tightly pressed on the waterproof washer <b>25</b> in the annular recess <b>231</b> of the tightening connecter <b>20</b>. Next, the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> is fitted around the outer circumference of the annular projection <b>23</b> of the tightening connecter <b>20</b>, letting the front outer side of its annular resisting surface <b>32</b> resist against the outer side of the waterproof washer <b>25</b> and maintaining the gap <b>33</b> between the front end of the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> and the rear end of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b>. After the inner hole <b>31</b> in the front end of the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> is tightly fitted with the annular projection <b>23</b> of the tightening connecter <b>20</b>, a signal wire <b>100</b> can be inserted in the slot way <b>34</b> of the signal connecter and fixed on the rear-sectional ratchet member <b>24</b> at the rear outer edge of the tightening connecter <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">By so designing, the signal connecter of this invention has the following advantages.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">1. The bolt sleeve <b>10</b> has its first engage surface <b>132</b> loosely fixed with the tightening connecter <b>20</b> so the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> can be turned around for threadably connecting a signal terminal, such as a TV connecting terminal.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">2. The annular holding groove <b>131</b> of the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> is diametrically pressed on one side of the waterproof washer <b>25</b> received in the annular recess <b>231</b> of the tightening connecter <b>22</b>, and the waterproof washer <b>25</b> can closely contact with both the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and the tightening connecter <b>20</b> by its expanding elasticity; therefore, no gap will be formed between the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and the tightening connecter <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">3. The joint gap <b>33</b> formed between the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> prevents them from interfering with each other, and the bolt sleeve <b>10</b> and the tightening connecter <b>20</b> together with the fixing outer sleeve <b>30</b> are closely connected with the waterproof washer <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">4. The accommodating chamber <b>26</b> defined by the waterproof washer <b>25</b> and the first engage surface <b>132</b> together with the second engage surface <b>22</b> functions as an expansion space for the waterproof washer <b>25</b> when the waterproof washer <b>25</b> is pressed.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">While the preferred embodiment of the invention has been described above, it will be recognized and understood that various modifications may be made therein and the appended claims are intended to cover all such modifications that may fall within the spirit and scope on the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>I claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter comprising,
<claim-text>a bolt sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tightening connecter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fixing outer sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said bolt sleeve axially bored with a through insert hole in the center;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said bolt sleeve having an inner circumference of one end annularly provided with a stop edge radially protruding toward its center with a first engage surface formed thereon;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said tightening connecter being inserted in said insert hole of said bolt sleeve and stopped and restrictedly positioned by said stop edge to be loosely fitted with said bolt sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said fixing outer sleeve having its front inner hole tightly fixed with said tightening connecter to let said fixing outer sleeve covering an outer circumference of said tightening connecter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said tightening connecter formed with a flange to resist against said stop edge of said bolt sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said tightening connecter extended axially with a gradually dwindling diameter and formed thereon with a second engage surface, an annular projection and a rear-sectional ratchet member;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said tightening connecter diametrically formed with an annular recess at a location abutting said annular projection and said second engage surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an elastically tightening waterproof washer received in said annular recess;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said waterproof washer resisting against both said stop edge of said bolt sleeve and a front end of said fixing outer sleeve;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said stop edge of said bolt sleeve being formed with an annular holding groove;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said annular holding groove resisting against said waterproof washer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first engage surface formed into a conical surface wherein said first engage surface strictedly fixed with said second engage surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said fixing outer sleeve having said inner hole at the rear end thereof being tightly fixed on an outer circumference of said annular projection of said tightening connector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said tightening connector having waterproof and tightening functions.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said waterproof washer is exposed out of said annular recess.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The waterproof tightening structure for a signal connecter as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein an accommodating chamber is defined by said waterproof washer and said first engage surface of said bolt sleeve together with said second engage surface of said tightening connecter. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
