<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641501-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641501</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12497883</doc-number>
<date>20090706</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-339850</doc-number>
<date>20051125</date>
</priority-claim>
<priority-claim sequence="02" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2006-323229</doc-number>
<date>20061130</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>627</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439362</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e79">Connector holding clamp and connector retaining structure</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3867672</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Pizzigoni</name>
<date>19750200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361774</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4091246</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Donofrio et al.</name>
<date>19780500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6478623</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Wu</name>
<date>20021100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>43960735</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6533612</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Lee et al.</name>
<date>20030300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7077698</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Matthys et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0008554</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Chang</name>
<date>20030100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>07-245147</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>19950900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2001-135413</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20010500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2005-259698</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<date>20050900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>2</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439362</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439373</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439426</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>16</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>28</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12094486</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20080521</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12497883</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<continuation>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>PCT/JP2006/323229</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20061121</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>PENDING</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12094486</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</continuation>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090269965</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20091029</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Uchikawa</last-name>
<first-name>Ryuji</first-name>
<address>
<city>Chiyoda-ku</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Aizawa</last-name>
<first-name>Katsunao</first-name>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sughrue Mion, PLLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Mitsubishi Electric Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tokyo</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Dinh</last-name>
<first-name>Phuong K</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An upper panel section includes an inserting hole into which a tip of a longitudinal-type equipment-side connector that is mounted on a PCB board of an electrical device at right angles and includes a spring section formed on its lateral surface is inserted. A foot section supports the upper panel section on the PCB. An inner circumference of the inserting hole has a shape surrounding substantially an entire circumference of the tip of the equipment-side connector. The foot section is provided at a position that opens up the lateral surface of the longitudinal-type equipment-side connector on which the spring section of the equipment-side connector is formed.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="233.43mm" wi="103.80mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="251.88mm" wi="107.02mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="242.15mm" wi="112.52mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="251.54mm" wi="102.45mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="234.44mm" wi="119.13mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="204.22mm" wi="104.82mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="261.62mm" wi="163.07mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="228.26mm" wi="118.45mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="171.11mm" wi="154.01mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="239.44mm" wi="155.70mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="250.11mm" wi="101.09mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00011" num="00011">
<img id="EMI-D00011" he="253.49mm" wi="113.96mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00011.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00012" num="00012">
<img id="EMI-D00012" he="193.38mm" wi="106.60mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00012.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00013" num="00013">
<img id="EMI-D00013" he="228.52mm" wi="108.37mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00013.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00014" num="00014">
<img id="EMI-D00014" he="220.22mm" wi="125.39mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00014.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00015" num="00015">
<img id="EMI-D00015" he="259.76mm" wi="149.52mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00015.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00016" num="00016">
<img id="EMI-D00016" he="124.46mm" wi="141.14mm" file="US07641501-20100105-D00016.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This is a divisional of application Ser. No. 12/094,486 filed May 21, 2008, which is a Continuation Application of PCT Application No. PCT/JP2006/323229 filed Nov. 25, 2005. The entire disclosure(s) of the prior application(s), application Ser. No. 12/094,486 is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to a structure for preventing a connector from being disconnected, and more particularly, to a structure for preventing a small-sized connector, such as a universal serial bus (USB) standard and the like, from being disconnected.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND ART</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Recently, a small-sized connector, such as a USB standard connector, has become widely used. A factory automation (FA) apparatus, which is an apparatus such as a sequencer, a human machine interface (HMI), or a printer installed in a factory, is no exception where the small-sized connectors are begun to be commonly used. Because the FA apparatus is installed in more severe environments than an office automation (OA) apparatus, the FA apparatus requires higher reliability, robustness, and durability. In such an FA apparatus, it is not desirable for a cable connector connected to the FA apparatus to be disconnected by accident, because such disconnection could cause malfunction of facility machinery or data loss. However, a commercially available USB-mini type cable connector, for example, can get disconnected from an equipment-side connector if approximately 1 kg of a pulling weight is applied.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">To solve this problem, it has been conventionally suggested to put on a resin holder onto the cable connector provided with a tab, and to engage the tab into an engaging hole provided on the apparatus, realizing a structure that can tolerate a heavy pulling weight (see, for example, Patent Document 1).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">[Patent Document 1] Japanese Patent Application Laid-open No. 2001-135413 (FIG. 1)</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">DISCLOSURE OF INVENTION</heading>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">Problem to be Solved by the Invention</heading>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, in the connector retaining holder disclosed in Patent Document 1, because the apparatus and the holder are engaged using the tab and the engaging hole, an enough supporting force for preventing the connector from being disconnected cannot be achieved. Therefore, the connector retaining holder cannot prevent the connector from being disconnected if a heavy pulling weight is applied. For the FA apparatus described above, it is preferable to be tolerable against a pulling weight of approximately 6 kg. Furthermore, in the structure of the connector retaining holder disclosed in Patent Document 1, the connector is disengaged by pushing both sides of the thin-walled holder to move positions of the tab inside. Therefore, the connector can get disconnected easily as mentioned above, and the holder still has other unsolved problems. For example, because the material of the holder is vulnerable to temporal degradation, the tab may be deformed or break off from a base easily.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In addition, it is preferable for the FA apparatus, especially a stationary HMI for example, to have a structure to enable a cable connector, often inserted and removed such as one of USB-mini type, to be connected to the rear side of the apparatus at right angle, and not to a lateral side of the apparatus. This is because, the connection can be checked easier with eyes, and better workability can be achieved upon inserting or removing. However, the structure of a so-called straight type equipment-side connector is more vulnerable to damage than a so-called right-angle type equipment-side connector. To realize a structure that connects a small-sized cable connector at right angle to the rear side of a thin apparatus, such as a liquid crystal display, the straight type equipment-side connector is required. The right-angle type equipment-side connector is used to connect the cable connector to a lateral side of the apparatus. Because such a straight type equipment-side connector can get damaged easily, it is not suitable for the FA apparatus.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">In addition, it has been a problem that, upon connecting or removing the USB connector, static electricity charged at an operator side can get discharged into electronic components of the apparatus via the USB connector, causing the apparatus to fail. In addition, it is also a problem that the USB connector generates an emission noise that affects other apparatuses.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The present invention has been achieved to solve the above problems, and it is an object of the present invention to realize a connector retaining holder and a connector retaining structure that can achieve an enough supporting force for a small-sized cable connector, and can reliably prevent disconnection of the connector upon application of a heavy pulling weight, and more particularly, to realize a connector holding clamp and a connector retaining structure that can reduce disconnection of a cable connector by preventing the connector from being damaged, for a structure that the cable connector can be connected to the rear side of a thin apparatus at right angle.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">Means for Solving Problem</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">To solve the above problems and to achieve the object, a connector retaining holder according to the present invention prevents a cable connector, which is connected to an equipment-side connector provided on an equipment in a direction perpendicular to a surface of the equipment, from being disconnected from the equipment-side connector. The connector retaining holder includes a holding section that supports at least a rear end of the cable connector, which includes a contacting surface that makes a contact with a rear end surface of the cable connector, and a fastening section that is formed in a flange-like shape and is fastened onto the equipment with a fastening screw.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Furthermore, a connector holding clamp according to the present invention includes an upper panel section including an inserting hole into which a tip of a longitudinal-type equipment-side connector, which is mounted on a printed-circuit board (PCB) of equipment at right angle, is inserted and a foot section that supports the upper panel section on the PCB.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Moreover, a connector retaining structure according to the present invention includes a connector retaining holder that prevents a cable connector, which is coupled to a longitudinal-type equipment-side connector provided on a PCB of an equipment at right angle, from being disconnected from the equipment-side connector, which includes a holding section that supports at least a rear end of the cable connector, the holding section including a contacting surface that makes a contact with a rear end surface of the cable connector, and a fastening section that is formed in a flange-like shape and is fastened onto the equipment with a fastening screw; and a mounting base that is provided on the equipment, on which the fastening section of the connector retaining holder is mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Furthermore, a reinforced equipment-side connector according to the present invention includes a longitudinal-type connector section provided on a PCB of equipment at right angle and a supporting member that supports a tip of the connector section on the PCB.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Moreover, an FA apparatus according to the present invention includes a PCB; a longitudinal-type equipment-side connector that is provided on the PCB at right angle; and a connector holding clamp including an upper panel section that is provided with an inserting hole into which a tip of the equipment-side connector is inserted and is arranged substantially in parallel to the PCB, and a foot section that supports the upper panel section on the PCB.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The term &#x201c;apparatus&#x201d; herein means an apparatus such as a HMI, and the term &#x201c;equipment&#x201d; herein includes the &#x201c;apparatus&#x201d; and other elements such as a control panel. &#x201c;Connector-inserted direction&#x201d; means a direction in which a cable connector is inserted and removed with respect to an equipment-side connector, which is a direction on which the center axis of the cable connector is laid. &#x201c;Flange-like&#x201d; describes how an element is extended from an end thereof to an approximately perpendicular direction.</p>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">EFFECT OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">According to a connector retaining holder of the present invention, the holder is fastened to an apparatus using a fastening screw. Therefore, a sufficient force can be obtained to prevent disconnection of the connector, so that the connector can be reliably prevented from being disconnected even when a heavy pulling weight is applied.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">Furthermore, according to a connector holding clamp of the present invention, a tip of an equipment-side connector is inserted into and supported in an inserting hole. Therefore, the connector can be prevented from being damaged, such as an opening thereof being opened up or the connector being folded over, and the disconnection of a cable connector can be suppressed.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Moreover, according to a connector retaining structure of the present invention, the holder is fastened to the apparatus using the fastening screw. Therefore, an enough supporting force can be obtained to prevent the disconnection of the connector, so that the connector can be reliably prevented from being disconnected even when a heavy pulling weight is applied. At the same time, because a mounting base supports the holder more securely, the cable connector can be prevented from being disconnected more reliably.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">Furthermore, according to a reinforced equipment-side connector of the invention, because a tip of a connector section is secured, damages can be reliably prevented, such as the connector section being folded over.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Moreover, according to an FA apparatus of the present invention, the tip of the equipment-side connector is inserted into and supported in the inserting hole. Therefore, the connector can be prevented from being damaged, such as the opening thereof being opened up or the connector being folded over, and the disconnection of the cable connector can be suppressed.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0007" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a connector retaining structure according to a first embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the connector retaining structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, viewed from a different direction.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is perspective view of a generally-available USB male cable connector.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of a vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top view of the vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector, showing details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side view of the vertical USB female equipment-side connector, showing details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view of a connector retaining holder, showing details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a perspective view of the connector retaining holder, seen from the side of a fastening section, showing details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic of the connector retaining holder, seen from the side from which a cable extends out.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a sectional view along the line C-C shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, seen from the direction of arrows.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a schematic of the connector retaining holder, seen from the side on which a contact portion protrudes from.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, showing details thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a top view of the connector holding clamp, explaining the relationship between an inserting hole thereof and a shell of an equipment-side connector.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a perspective view of showing an exemplary application of the first embodiment, where the cable connector is connected to the rear side of a thin apparatus at right angle.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a perspective view for explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a second embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a perspective view of a mounting base piece, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a third embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a vertical cross sectional view of a box-type control panel, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a perspective view of the box-type control panel, seen from a front side thereof, explaining another example of the disconnection preventing structure according to fourth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref> is a perspective view of the box-type control panel, seen from a rear side thereof, explaining still another example of the disconnection preventing structure according to fourth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a sixth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a seventh embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to an eighth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a ninth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</figref> is a perspective view of a reinforced equipment-side connector, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a tenth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</figref> is a top view of a reinforced equipment-side connector, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to an eleventh embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</figref> is a sectional view along the line D-D shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</figref>, seen from the direction of arrows.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</figref> is a perspective view of a reinforced equipment-side connector, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a twelfth embodiment of the present invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0008" level="1">EXPLANATIONS OF LETTERS OR NUMERALS</heading>
<p id="p-0050" num="0000">
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0049"><b>20</b> Holder (connector retaining holder)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0050"><b>21</b> Holding section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0051"><b>22</b> Fastening section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0004" num="0052"><b>23</b> Notch</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0005" num="0053"><b>29</b> Fastening screw</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0006" num="0054"><b>24</b> Screw inserting hole</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0007" num="0055"><b>24</b><i>a </i>Counterbore</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0008" num="0056"><b>25</b> C-shaped engaging section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0009" num="0057"><b>26</b> Rib</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0010" num="0058"><b>26</b><i>a </i>Ending point of slope on a rib</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0011" num="0059"><b>26</b><i>b </i>Starting point of slope on a rib</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0012" num="0060"><b>27</b> Chamfer with an arc-shaped cross-section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0013" num="0061"><b>30</b>, <b>130</b>, <b>230</b>, <b>330</b>, <b>430</b>, <b>530</b> Connector holding clamp</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0014" num="0062"><b>31</b>, <b>231</b> Upper panel section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0015" num="0063"><b>32</b>, <b>232</b> Foot section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0016" num="0064"><b>33</b> Inserting hole</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0017" num="0065"><b>33</b><i>a </i>Clearance</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0018" num="0066"><b>34</b> Soldering tab on foot section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0019" num="0067"><b>35</b> Mounting flange</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0020" num="0068"><b>36</b> Penetrating hole</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0021" num="0069"><b>37</b> Coupling section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0022" num="0070"><b>38</b> Linking screw hole</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0023" num="0071"><b>40</b>, <b>140</b> Mounting base</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0024" num="0072"><b>41</b> Rotation stopper</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0025" num="0073"><b>42</b> Female screw hole (penetrating hole)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0026" num="0074"><b>50</b> USB male cable connector (cable connector)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0027" num="0075"><b>51</b> Housing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0028" num="0076"><b>52</b> Contact portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0029" num="0077"><b>53</b> Flexible portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0030" num="0078"><b>54</b> Cable</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0031" num="0079"><b>60</b> Vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector (equipment-side connector)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0032" num="0080"><b>61</b> Shell</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0033" num="0081"><b>62</b> Soldering tab on shell</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0034" num="0082"><b>63</b> Leads</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0035" num="0083"><b>64</b> Terminal portion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0036" num="0084"><b>65</b> Retaining flat spring (spring section)</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0037" num="0085"><b>80</b>, <b>180</b> Apparatus</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0038" num="0086"><b>81</b> Case</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0039" num="0087"><b>82</b> PCB</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0040" num="0088"><b>82</b><i>a </i>Penetrating hole for fixing</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0041" num="0089"><b>82</b><i>b </i>Inserting hole</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0042" num="0090"><b>83</b> PCB fixing screw</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0043" num="0091"><b>84</b> Spacer</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0044" num="0092"><b>85</b> Base</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0045" num="0093"><b>90</b> HMI</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0046" num="0094"><b>91</b> USB extension cable</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0047" num="0095"><b>100</b> Box-type control panel</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0048" num="0096"><b>141</b> Surrounding wall</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0049" num="0097"><b>240</b> Mounting base piece</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0050" num="0098"><b>131</b> Upper panel section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0051" num="0099"><b>132</b> Foot section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0052" num="0100"><b>160</b>, <b>260</b>, <b>360</b> Connector section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0053" num="0101"><b>170</b>, <b>270</b>, <b>370</b> Reinforced equipment-side connector</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0054" num="0102"><b>261</b> Engaging section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0055" num="0103"><b>261</b><i>a </i>Upper protrusion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0056" num="0104"><b>261</b><i>b </i>Lower protrusion</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0057" num="0105"><b>331</b>A First upper panel section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0058" num="0106"><b>331</b>B Second upper panel section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0059" num="0107"><b>332</b>A First foot section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0060" num="0108"><b>332</b>B Second foot section</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0061" num="0109"><b>361</b> Shell</li>
</ul>
</p>
<heading id="h-0009" level="1">BEST MODE(S) FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0051" num="0110">Exemplary embodiments of a connector retaining holder, a connector holding clamp, and a connector retaining structure according to the present invention will be explained in detail below with reference to the accompanying drawings. It should be understood that the embodiments are not intended to limit the scope of the invention in any way.</p>
<heading id="h-0010" level="1">First Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0052" num="0111"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a connector retaining structure according to a first embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view, viewed from another direction, of the connector retaining structure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The connector retaining structure according to the first embodiment includes: a connector holding clamp <b>30</b> that prevents a vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector (USB-mini connector) <b>60</b> provided onto a PCB <b>82</b> at right angle, which is built into an apparatus <b>80</b>, from being folded over; a connector retaining holder <b>20</b> that prevents a USB male cable connector (USB-mini plug) <b>50</b>, connected with the vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, from being disconnected; and a mounting base <b>40</b>, formed on the external wall surface of a case <b>81</b> of the apparatus <b>80</b>, onto which the holder <b>20</b> is mounted.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0112"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the USB male cable connector (hereinafter, simply referred to as &#x201c;cable connector&#x201d;) <b>50</b> that is generally available. The connector retaining holder (hereinafter, simply referred to as &#x201c;holder&#x201d;) <b>20</b> according to the first embodiment prevents the cable connector <b>50</b>, having the shape shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, from being disconnected. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, the cable connector <b>50</b> includes: a housing <b>51</b>, made of resin, that is formed on one end of a cable <b>54</b> and having a approximate shape of an quadrangular prism; a contact portion <b>52</b>, made of metal, that is mounted at the tip of the housing <b>51</b> and are mechanically and electronically connected to the vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector <b>60</b>; and a flexible portion <b>53</b>, made of resin, that covers the cable <b>54</b> at the rear end of the housing <b>51</b> and has a high flexibility so as to prevent the cable <b>54</b> from being bent at a sharp angle. A terminal portion, not shown, is provided inside the contact portion <b>52</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0113"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic perspective view of the vertical-type USB female equipment-side connector (hereinafter, simply referred to as &#x201c;equipment-side connector) <b>60</b>. The equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, is the so-called straight-type equipment-side connector that realizes a structure connecting the cable connector to the rear side of the thin apparatus at right angle. The connector holding clamp <b>30</b> according to the first embodiment prevents this straight-type equipment-side connector from being folded over. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> has a shell <b>61</b> that is made from a thin plate metal formed in approximately tubular in shape. The shell <b>61</b> has a terminal portion, not shown, inside thereof. A soldering tab <b>62</b> is formed, with the lateral sides thereof extended, at the rear end of the shell <b>61</b>. The soldering tab <b>62</b> is used for fixing the shell <b>61</b> onto the PCB. Leads <b>63</b>, extending from the terminal portion located inside the shell <b>61</b> and connected electrically to a pattern on the PCB, are also provided at the rear end of the shell <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0114"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a top view of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, showing details thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side view also of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, showing details thereof. A terminal portion <b>64</b>, electrically connected to the terminal portion located inside the contact portion <b>52</b> of the cable connector <b>50</b>, is arranged inside the shell <b>61</b>. On a lateral side of the shell <b>61</b>, a flat disconnection-preventing spring <b>65</b> is formed to prevent the cable connector <b>50</b> from being disconnected with a small force (approximately 1 kilogram). A specific example of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> includes a connector manufactured by Nihon Molex K.K., a part number 500075-0517. The equipment-side connector <b>60</b> having the structure described above is placed on the PCB in a vertical direction with an opening of the shell <b>61</b> facing upward, and fixed onto the PCB by soldering the tab <b>62</b> to the PCB. Therefore, it is possible to realize a connector structure with the shell arranged at right angle with the PCB (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), without arranging a PCB vertically, in comparison with a so-called right-angled type equipment-side connector, in which the shell is arranged horizontally on the PCB. However, the straight-type shell <b>61</b> is made from a thin metal formed in an approximate tubular shape, and meeting edges of the thin metal are not especially connected, such as by welding. Therefore, the opening of the shell <b>61</b> can be opened up easily and get damaged, if the edge is twisted by the contact portion <b>52</b> of the cable connector <b>50</b> that is inserted inside thereof. Furthermore, because the shell <b>61</b> is supported at the bottom end thereof only on an area obtained by projecting the cross section of the shell <b>61</b> onto the PCB, the shell <b>61</b> can be easily folded over, thus be peeled off from the PCB or broken off from the base, if a force is applied from a lateral direction.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0115"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a perspective view of the holder <b>20</b> according to the first embodiment, showing details thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is another perspective view of the same holder <b>20</b>, seen from a fastening side thereof, showing details thereof. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic of the holder <b>20</b>, seen from the side from which the cable <b>54</b> extends out. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a sectional view along the line C-C shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, viewed from the direction of arrows shown therein. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 11</figref> is a schematic of the holder <b>20</b>, seen from the side on which the contact portion <b>52</b> protrudes from. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> shows, in phantom lines, how the cable connector <b>50</b> fits inside the holder <b>20</b>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 to 11</figref>, the holder <b>20</b> is made of resin, and formed as a single piece, for example, such as by injection molding. The holder <b>20</b> includes: a holding section <b>21</b>, formed approximately tubular in shape, for accepting the cable connector <b>50</b> inside thereof; and a fastening section <b>22</b> that is formed in a flange-like shape on the holding section <b>21</b>, on the side thereof facing to the apparatus <b>80</b>. The material of the holder <b>20</b> is not limited to resin, and materials such as metal can also used. In addition, the holder <b>20</b> is not limited to injection molding, and may also be manufactured by die casting or cutting.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0116">As can be seen well in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the holding section <b>21</b> has an approximate tubular shape inside thereof for accepting the cable connector <b>50</b>. The holding section <b>21</b> also has a notch <b>23</b>, whose width is slightly larger than the diameter of the cable <b>54</b>, over its entire longitudinal length. Therefore, the cable <b>54</b> can be inserted from the side of the holding section <b>21</b> (from the radial direction), that is, from a direction perpendicular to the axis of the holding section <b>21</b>. A size of the holding section <b>21</b> is determined so that a predetermined space is formed between the cable connector <b>50</b> and an internal wall surface thereof, allowing the cable connector <b>50</b> to be accepted even when the cable connector <b>50</b> is rotated by 90 degrees (actually, the rotation may be by any angle within 360 degrees,) around the axis thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0117">Moreover, as can be seen well in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 7 and 9</figref>, a C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b>, to be fit onto the cable <b>54</b> with some play remaining, is provided on the rear end side of the holding section <b>21</b>, that is, on the side thereof from which the cable <b>54</b> extends out. The inner diameter of the C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b> is set slightly larger than the outer diameter of the cable <b>54</b>. The opening of the C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b> is communicated with the notch <b>23</b>, so that the cable <b>54</b> can be inserted from the side direction. The opening of the C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b> may be made slightly smaller in width than the outer diameter of the cable <b>54</b>, so that the cable <b>54</b>, having an elastic cover, can pass therethrough by applying a force, achieving better supportability of the cable connector <b>50</b>. The external surface of the C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b>, that is, the rear end surface of the holding section <b>21</b>, has a chamfer <b>27</b> with an arc-shaped cross-section, so that the cable <b>54</b> is not prevented from being bent at the rear of the holding section <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0118">The inner surface of the C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b> comes in contact with the rear end surface of the cable connector <b>50</b> (rear end surface <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the flexible portion <b>53</b>), as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>. The holder <b>20</b> supports the contacting surface at a fixed position with respect to the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, limiting backward movements of the cable connector <b>50</b>, to prevent the cable connector <b>50</b> from being disconnected. The contacting surface according to the first embodiment comes in contact with the rear end surface of the <b>53</b><i>a </i>of the flexible portion <b>53</b>; however, a contacting surface, coming in contact with a rear end surface of the housing <b>51</b>, may be formed by providing a protrusion or a step on the internal wall surface of the holding section <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0119">Two pairs of ribs <b>26</b>, four in total, are formed on the internal wall of the holding section <b>21</b>. Each of the ribs has a tapered ridge, and these ridges, each one facing to another, are gradually made smaller in width, as the ridges extend toward the C-shaped engaging section <b>25</b>. The ribs <b>26</b> are formed so that, when the cable connector <b>50</b> is accepted, an ending point <b>26</b><i>a </i>of the slope does not interfere with the rear end surface <b>51</b><i>a </i>of the housing <b>51</b>, and a starting point <b>26</b><i>b </i>of the slope does not interfere with the flexible portion <b>53</b>. It would not be a problem for the flexible portion <b>53</b> to interfere with the ribs <b>26</b>, if the flexible portion <b>53</b> has enough flexibility, as long as the stress does not cause damage or failure.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0120">As will be mentioned later in description of an attachment procedure, the cable connector <b>50</b> is tightly nipped at the flexible rear end of the flexible portion <b>53</b> by these four ribs <b>26</b>. In other words, the four ribs <b>26</b> function as a nipping unit that nips the rear end of the cable connector <b>50</b>, because the upper surface of the ridge of the rib <b>26</b> (the surface facing to the center axis) has a tapered surface (nipping surface) in the height direction, becoming gradually higher toward the rear end side of the holding section <b>21</b>. The holder <b>20</b>, having the rib shape, holds the nipping unit at a fixed position with respect to the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, suppressing movements of the rear end of the cable connector <b>50</b> in a direction perpendicular to the axis thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0121">By nipping the cylindrical flexible portion <b>53</b> that has the same axis as the cable <b>54</b>, the nipping unit, having the four ribs <b>26</b>, realizes a structure that can support the cable connector <b>50</b> even when the cable connector <b>50</b> is rotated by 90 degrees (actually, the rotation may be by any angle within 360 degrees).</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0122">The nipping unit according to the first embodiment includes the four ribs <b>26</b>, as described above. However, the nipping unit may also include, for example, three ribs <b>26</b>. Furthermore, the nipping unit can be formed by providing at least one rib <b>26</b> and the internal wall surface facing thereto to nip the rear end of the cable connector <b>50</b>. This arrangement simplifies the shape, with some sacrifice of the supportability. Still furthermore, inside of the holder <b>20</b> may have a conical-trapezoidal shape that is obtained by rotating the tapered surface (the slope surface from the starting point <b>26</b><i>b </i>to the ending point <b>26</b><i>a </i>of the slope) of the rib <b>26</b> around the center axis, to be used as a nipping surface. This arrangement can also prevent the rear end of the cable connector <b>50</b> from moving in a direction perpendicular to the axis thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0123">As can be seen well in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>, a screw inserting hole <b>24</b>, provided with a deep counterbore <b>24</b><i>a</i>, is formed for a screw on the apparatus side of the external end surface of the fastening section <b>22</b>. The fastening section <b>22</b> extends approximately at right angle from the holding section <b>21</b> toward a predetermined direction. A large attaching surface that makes a contact with the mounting base <b>40</b>, is formed on the end surface of the fastening section <b>22</b> and that of the holding section <b>21</b>. The holder <b>20</b> is fastened onto the apparatus <b>80</b> (mounting base <b>40</b>) with a fastening screw, not shown, penetrating through the screw inserting hole <b>24</b> for the screw. The head of the fastening screw sinks into the counterbore <b>24</b><i>a</i>, thus, becoming no obstacle upon working therewith.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0124"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 12</figref> is a perspective view of the connector holding clamp <b>30</b>, for showing details thereof. The connector holding clamp <b>30</b> is made from a metal plate being cut out in a laser process or punched out in a pressing process, and being bent in a bending process to be formed into an approximate U-shaped cross-section connector holding clamp <b>30</b>. On the entire surface of the connector holding clamp <b>30</b>, nickel plating, for example, is provided to improve workability upon soldering.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0125">The connector holding clamp <b>30</b> is arranged approximately in parallel to the PCB <b>82</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), and includes an upper panel section <b>31</b>, provided with inserting holes <b>33</b> for inserting the tip of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, and a pair of foot sections <b>32</b> for supporting the upper panel section <b>31</b> on the PCB <b>82</b>. A coupling section <b>37</b>, extending from the upper panel section <b>31</b>, is provided on one of the sides of the upper panel section <b>31</b> not having the foot section <b>32</b>, to stabilize the connection with the holder <b>20</b>. A linking screw hole <b>38</b> is threaded on the coupling section <b>37</b>, and a fastening screw <b>29</b> penetrates through the fastening section <b>22</b> of the holder <b>20</b> to be screwed therein.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0126">One of the pair of the foot sections <b>32</b>, provided to each side of the upper panel section <b>31</b>, has two soldering tabs <b>34</b> at a bottom end thereof. The other foot section <b>32</b> has a single soldering tab <b>34</b> and a mounting flange <b>35</b> at a bottom end thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0127"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref> is a top view of the connector holding clamp <b>30</b>, provided to explain the relationship between the shape of the inserting hole <b>33</b>, provided on the connector holding clamp <b>30</b>, and that of the shell <b>61</b> of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>. Functions of the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> are explained with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>. As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>, the shape of the inserting hole <b>33</b>, formed on the upper panel section <b>31</b>, follows the external contour of the shell <b>61</b>. In other words, the inserting hole <b>33</b> has a shape that the tip of the shell <b>61</b> just fits into with a predetermined size tolerance, and forms a surrounding section that surrounds the tip of the shell <b>61</b>. The connector holding clamp <b>30</b> supports the inserting hole <b>33</b> (surrounding section) at a fixed position with respect to the PCB <b>82</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>), preventing the shell <b>61</b> from being folded over in all directions therearound, and from being damaged by the tip opening thereof being opened up.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0128">A clearance <b>33</b><i>a </i>is provided on a part of the inner surface edge of the inserting hole <b>33</b>, so that the movement of the retaining flat spring <b>65</b> of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, is not abstained. The inserting hole <b>33</b> according to the first embodiment aligns the shell <b>61</b> in width direction and prevents the opening of the shell <b>61</b> from being opened up by nipping the shell <b>61</b> between inner surfaces S<b>1</b> and S<b>2</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 13</figref>. At the same time, the inserting hole <b>33</b> aligns the shell <b>61</b> in a length direction and prevents the opening of the shell <b>61</b> from being opened up by nipping the shell <b>61</b> between inner surfaces S<b>3</b> and S<b>4</b>. As obvious it might be from the above, even if another shape is used for the inserting hole <b>33</b> (for example, a simple rectangle with the clearance <b>33</b><i>a </i>above), an approximately similar effect can be achieved, as long as the inserting hole <b>33</b> has at least two pairs of inner surfaces (limiting sides), four in total, although the supportability for the opening of the shell <b>61</b> might be somewhat sacrificed. Alternatively, the inserting hole <b>33</b> may touch the shell <b>61</b> at the points shown as S<b>1</b> to S<b>4</b>, further sacrificing the shape supportability.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0129">In addition, some improvement might be made to the inserting hole <b>33</b>, for example, by forming a part of the inner surface edge thereof in an accordion-like cross-section shape. In this arrangement, the inner surface edge of the inserting hole <b>33</b> has elasticity that generates resiliency in a direction that shrinks the size of the inserting hole <b>33</b>. By way of this resiliency, that part of the inserting hole <b>33</b> is constantly kept in contact with the shell <b>61</b>, to improve the supportability.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0130">According to the first embodiment, upon being manufactured by being punched out by a press, the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> is punched out from the PCB side of the upper panel section <b>31</b>. Generally speaking, if a hole is formed with a press, the edge of an opening becomes slacked and rounded out on a side that faces a male press. On the contrary, on the opposite side, burrs are formed on the edge of the opening. Therefore, if the metal plate is pressed in the direction described above, the edges of the opening of the inserting hole <b>33</b> becomes slacked and rounded out on the PCB side. Therefore, the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> can be inserted more easily, improving workability of an assembly process.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0131">Referring back to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> is fixed onto the PCB <b>82</b>, by the tabs <b>34</b> thereof being inserted into inserting holes <b>82</b><i>b </i>and being soldered onto the PCB <b>82</b>. The tabs <b>34</b> are soldered in the same soldering process as for other electric components provided onto the PCB <b>82</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0132">In addition to the soldered tab <b>34</b>, the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> is fastened onto a spacer <b>84</b> with a PCB fixing screw <b>89</b> passing through a penetrating hole <b>36</b> formed on the mounting flange <b>35</b>. In other words, the PCB fixing screw <b>89</b> is also used for fixing the connector holding clamp <b>30</b>. If there is a concern that external static electricity (from the operator) might cause damage or a failure of the apparatus or affect nearby apparatus, or the USB connector might generate an emission noise, the shell needs to be brought down to the signal ground. The connector holding clamp <b>30</b> according to the first embodiment establishes an electrical connection with the shell <b>61</b> and a base (signal ground) <b>85</b> through the spacer <b>84</b>. In this manner, the shell can be reliably brought down to the signal ground easily. The connector holding clamp <b>30</b> may be used to connect not only to the signal ground, but also to the frame ground.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0133">A method for attaching the holder <b>20</b> will be now explained. The holder <b>20</b> accepts the cable <b>54</b> from the side direction thereof by moving the holder <b>20</b> in the direction shown by an arrow A in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>. The cable connector <b>50</b> is then moved in a direction shown by an arrow B, to be accepted into the holding section <b>21</b>. At this time, the cable connector <b>50</b> is forcibly pushed into the holding section <b>21</b>, so that the cable connector <b>50</b> is seized by the four ribs <b>26</b> (<figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref>) described above. The holder <b>20</b>, with this arrangement, is settled onto the mounting base <b>40</b> to connect the cable connector <b>50</b> with the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>. The fastening screw <b>29</b>, penetrating through the fastening section <b>22</b>, is screwed into the linking screw hole <b>38</b> via a penetrating hole <b>42</b>. In this manner, the holder <b>20</b> is securely fixed onto the apparatus <b>80</b>. Because the holder <b>20</b> is fixed by the single fastening screw <b>29</b>, the holder <b>20</b> could attempt to rotate around the fastening screw <b>29</b>; however, this rotating movement is confined by rotation stoppers <b>41</b>. The linking screw hole <b>38</b> should be used for fastening the fastening screw <b>29</b>, as required. If the inner surface of the case <b>81</b> does not come in contact with the coupling section <b>37</b>, the penetrating hole <b>42</b> is used as a female screw hole <b>42</b>, and the fastening screw <b>29</b> is screwed only into the female screw hole <b>42</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0134"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 14</figref> is a perspective view of showing an application of the first embodiment, where the cable connector is connected to the rear side of a thin apparatus at right angle. A thin HMI <b>90</b> having a liquid crystal display includes a built-in PCB, not shown, arranged in parallel to the display unit. To connect the cable connector to the rear side of the thin apparatus, having the structure above, at right angle, it is effective to use the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> according to the first embodiment, which can be provided onto the PCB at right angle. It is preferable to use the disconnection preventing structure according to the first embodiment to prevent the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> from being damaged and the cable connector <b>50</b> from being disconnected from the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0135">As described above, in the disconnection preventing structure according to the first embodiment, the holder <b>20</b> is fastened to the apparatus <b>80</b> with the fastening screw <b>29</b>. Therefore, sufficient disconnection preventing force can be obtained, and the disconnection can be reliably prevented even if a heavy pulling weight (6 kilograms or greater) is applied. Furthermore, because the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> has a surrounding section (inserting hole <b>33</b>) that surrounds the tip of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b>, the connector damage, such as the opening of the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> being opened up or the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> being folded over, can be prevented, and the cable connector <b>50</b> can be prevented from being disconnected.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0136">The effects of the present invention can be best achieved by combining the holder <b>20</b> and the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> according to the first embodiment; however, sufficient effects can be also achieved, by using the holder <b>20</b> or the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> by itself. In other words, if the holder <b>20</b> is used by itself, sufficient disconnection preventing force can be obtained for the cable connector <b>50</b>, reliably preventing the cable connector <b>50</b> from being disconnected with a heavy pulling weight. If the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> is used by itself, connector damage can be prevented in a structure that the cable connector <b>50</b> is connected to the rear side of a thin apparatus at right angle, also to prevent the cable connector <b>50</b> from being disconnected.</p>
<heading id="h-0011" level="1">Second Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0078" num="0137"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref> is a perspective view for explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a second embodiment of the present invention. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 15</figref>, on one lateral side of a thin apparatus <b>180</b>, such as a notebook computer, a connector-connecting port is provided using a right-angle type equipment-side connector. A mounting base <b>140</b>, onto which the holder <b>20</b> is mounted, is formed around the connector-connecting port. In other words, according to the second embodiment, the holder <b>20</b> is used by itself.</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0138">The mounting base <b>140</b> according to the second embodiment includes a surrounding wall <b>141</b> that surrounds the surface where the holder <b>20</b> is mounted. Therefore, the holder <b>20</b> is supported reliably, and the cable connector <b>50</b> is reliably prevented from being disconnected. At the same time, dust and water resistance of the connector-connecting port can be improved.</p>
<heading id="h-0012" level="1">Third Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0080" num="0139"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref> is a perspective view of a mounting base piece, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a third embodiment of the present invention. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 16</figref>, a mounting base piece <b>240</b> according to the third embodiment has a shape achieved by cutting out the part, provided with the mounting base <b>140</b>, of the lateral side of the thin apparatus <b>180</b> according to the second embodiment. To enable the holder <b>20</b> to be used, the mounting base piece <b>240</b> is adhered around a connector-connecting port of a generally-available apparatus, using an adhesive agent or strong double-sided tape. The mounting base piece <b>240</b> can be manufactured from resin such as by injection molding. The female screw hole <b>42</b> may also be embedded with a metal nut, for example, to secure fastening.</p>
<heading id="h-0013" level="1">Fourth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0081" num="0140"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 17</figref> is a vertical cross-sectional view of a box-type control panel, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention. In the disconnection preventing structure according to the fourth embodiment, the mounting base piece <b>240</b> according to the third embodiment is fixed onto the rear side of a box-type control panel <b>100</b> that encloses, for example, the thin HMI <b>90</b> having a liquid crystal display. The equipment-side connector is provided on the inner surface, at a position facing the mounting base piece <b>240</b> on the rear side of the control panel, and connected to the HMI <b>90</b> using a USB extension cable <b>91</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0141"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a perspective view of the box-type control panel, seen from the front side thereof, for explaining another example of the disconnection preventing structure according to the fourth embodiment. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref> is a perspective view of the same box-type control panel, seen from the rear side thereof. The box-type control panel <b>100</b> includes a box-shaped main body <b>10</b><i>a</i>, and a door <b>100</b><i>b </i>that is provided to the main body <b>100</b><i>a </i>and can be freely opened and closed. The HMI <b>90</b> is arranged at the upper portion of the door <b>100</b><i>b</i>. The mounting base piece <b>240</b> is provided positions such as an upper section of the front side of the door <b>100</b><i>b </i>(P<b>1</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>), a lower section of the front side of the door <b>100</b><i>b </i>(P<b>2</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>), a lower section of the lateral side of the main body <b>100</b><i>a </i>(P<b>3</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 18</figref>, P<b>6</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>), an upper section of the rear side of the main body <b>100</b><i>a </i>(P<b>4</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>), or a lower section of the rear side of the main body <b>100</b><i>a </i>(P<b>5</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 19</figref>). This structure allows the cable connector to be inserted or removed without opening and closing the door <b>100</b><i>b. </i></p>
<heading id="h-0014" level="1">Fifth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0083" num="0142"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 20</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention. In comparison with the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> according to the first embodiment, a connector holding clamp <b>130</b> according to the fifth embodiment lacks the coupling section <b>37</b>. The connector holding clamp <b>130</b> is effective in using the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> by itself.</p>
<heading id="h-0015" level="1">Sixth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0084" num="0143"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 21</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a sixth embodiment of the present invention. In comparison with the connector holding clamp <b>130</b> according to the fifth embodiment, a connector holding clamp <b>230</b> according to the sixth embodiment lacks the mounting flange <b>35</b>, an upper panel section <b>231</b> and foot sections <b>232</b> have smaller widths, and the number of the soldering tabs <b>34</b> is reduced. The connector holding clamp <b>230</b> having such a structure is effective for those that do not need to be earthed to the signal ground, and especially effective for those needing to be reduced in size in some sacrifice of the supportability.</p>
<heading id="h-0016" level="1">Seventh Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0085" num="0144"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 22</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a seventh embodiment of the present invention. A connector holding clamp <b>330</b> according to the seventh embodiment has mounting flanges <b>334</b>, provided at the lower ends of the two foot sections <b>232</b> of the connector holding clamp <b>230</b> according to the sixth embodiment. The connector holding clamp <b>330</b> is fixed onto the PCB with the fixing screws <b>89</b>, penetrating through a penetrating hole provided on each of mounting flanges <b>334</b> to securely fix the foot sections <b>232</b> onto the PCB. In other words, both ends of the connector holding clamp <b>330</b> are screwed to and securely fixed onto the PCB.</p>
<heading id="h-0017" level="1">Eighth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0086" num="0145"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 23</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to an eighth embodiment of the present invention. A connector holding clamp <b>430</b> according to the eighth embodiment improves manufacturability and reduces a cost for the connector holding clamp <b>330</b> according to the seventh embodiment. The connector holding clamp <b>430</b> is fixed onto the PCB using rivets <b>436</b> penetrating through the penetrating holes formed on mounting flanges <b>434</b>, respectively provided at the lower ends of the foot section <b>232</b>. In other words, both ends of the connector holding clamp <b>430</b> are securely fixed onto the PCB by crimping the rivets.</p>
<heading id="h-0018" level="1">Ninth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0087" num="0146"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 24</figref> is a perspective view of a connector holding clamp, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a ninth embodiment of the present invention. A connector holding clamp <b>530</b> according to the ninth embodiment further improves the manufacturability and further reduces the cost of the connector holding clamp <b>430</b> according to the eighth embodiment. Folding tabs <b>534</b>, respectively provided at the lower ends of the foot sections <b>232</b>, are folded and crimped behind the PCB to fix the connector holding clamp <b>530</b> onto the PCB. In other words, the folding tabs <b>534</b>, respectively provided at each end of the connector holding clamp <b>530</b>, are crimped to fix the connector holding clamp <b>530</b> onto the PCB.</p>
<heading id="h-0019" level="1">Tenth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0088" num="0147"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 25</figref> is a perspective view of a reinforced equipment-side connector, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a tenth embodiment of the present invention. A reinforced equipment-side connector <b>170</b> according to the tenth embodiment has a structure in which the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> according to the first embodiment is integrated with the connector holding clamp <b>130</b> according to the fifth embodiment. The reinforced equipment-side connector <b>170</b> includes: a longitudinal-type connector section <b>160</b> provided onto the PCB of an apparatus, not shown, at right angle; an upper panel section <b>131</b> arranged approximately in parallel to the PCB and having the inserting hole <b>33</b> for inserting the tip of the connector section <b>160</b>; and a pair of foot sections <b>132</b> supporting the upper panel section <b>131</b> on the PCB. The upper panel section <b>131</b> and the foot sections <b>132</b> make up a supporting member that supports the tip of the connector section <b>160</b> on the PCB.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0148">The connector section <b>160</b> generally has the same structure as the equipment-side connector <b>60</b> according to the first embodiment. The inserting hole <b>33</b>, approximately the same in shape as the one provided to the upper panel section <b>31</b> of the connector holding clamp <b>30</b> according to the first embodiment, is provided on the upper panel section <b>131</b>. A tip of the connector section <b>160</b> is inserted into the inserting hole <b>33</b>, and soldered together to be integrated therewith. One of the foot sections <b>32</b>, provided to each side of the upper panel section <b>31</b>, has two of the soldering tabs <b>34</b> at a bottom end thereof. The other foot section <b>32</b> has the single soldering tab <b>34</b> and the mounting flange <b>35</b> at a bottom end thereof. The mounting flange <b>35</b> includes the penetrating hole <b>36</b> for fastening. The connection between the connector section <b>160</b> and the upper panel section <b>131</b> is not limited to soldering, but also may be adhered with an adhesive agent or welded together.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0149">The reinforced equipment-side connector having the structure above includes the connector section, the upper panel section having the inserting hole inserted with the tip of the connector section, and the foot sections for supporting the upper panel section on the PCB. Therefore, the equipment-side connector can be prevented from being damaged reliably, such as opening thereof being opened up, or being folded over.</p>
<heading id="h-0020" level="1">Eleventh Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0091" num="0150"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</figref> is a top view of a reinforced equipment-side connector, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to an eleventh embodiment of the present invention. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 27</figref> is a sectional view along the line D-D shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 26</figref>, seen from the direction of arrows. In a reinforced equipment-side connector <b>270</b>, a connector section <b>260</b> is connected to the upper panel section <b>131</b> by way of engaging sections <b>261</b> formed at two locations on the edge of the opening of the connector section <b>260</b>. The engaging section <b>261</b> includes an upper protrusion <b>261</b><i>a </i>provided on the edge of the opening at the tip, and a lower protrusion <b>261</b><i>b </i>arranged behind from the tip and facing to the upper protrusion <b>261</b><i>a</i>. An internal surface of the inserting hole <b>33</b> on the upper panel section <b>131</b> is nipped by and engages to these two protrusions <b>261</b><i>a</i>, <b>261</b><i>b</i>. In this manner, the connector section <b>160</b> is engaged into the upper panel section <b>131</b> to become connected. Remaining elements of the structure are the same as those according to the tenth embodiment.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0151">In the reinforced equipment-side connector having the structure described above, the connector section <b>160</b> is engaged into the upper panel section <b>131</b> to become connected. Therefore, the connecting process can be simplified.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0152">In the tenth and the eleventh embodiments, the upper panel section <b>131</b> may include the coupling section <b>37</b>, as required, threaded with the linking screw hole <b>38</b> through which the fastening screw <b>29</b> penetrates, passing through the fastening section <b>22</b> of the holder <b>20</b>, in the same manner as in the upper panel section <b>31</b> according to the first embodiment. The mounting flange <b>35</b> may be omitted as appropriate, if there is no need to earth to the signal ground.</p>
<heading id="h-0021" level="1">Twelfth Embodiment</heading>
<p id="p-0094" num="0153"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 28</figref> is a perspective of a reinforced equipment-side connector, explaining a disconnection preventing structure according to a twelfth embodiment of the present invention. A reinforced equipment-side connector <b>370</b> according to the twelfth embodiment includes: a longitudinal-type connector section <b>360</b> provided onto the PCB of an apparatus, not shown, at right angle; a first upper panel section <b>331</b>A and a second upper panel section <b>331</b>B, each of which extends from a connecting-side opening edge of the connector section <b>360</b> in parallel in opposing directions; and a first foot sections <b>332</b>A and a second foot sections <b>332</b>B, bending toward the PCB from one end of the upper panel sections <b>331</b>A, <b>331</b>B, respectively. The mounting flange <b>35</b>, having the penetrating hole <b>36</b> for fastening, is provided at a bottom end of the first foot section <b>332</b>A. The soldering tab <b>34</b> is provided at a bottom end of the second foot section <b>332</b>B. The upper panel sections <b>331</b>A, <b>331</b>B and the foot sections <b>332</b>A, <b>332</b>B make up a supporting member that supports the tip of the connector section <b>360</b> on the PCB.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0154">The upper panel sections <b>331</b>A, <b>331</b>B and the foot sections <b>332</b>A, <b>332</b>B are formed by extending a thin metal plate, forming a shell <b>361</b> of the connector section <b>360</b>, toward the connector-connecting side by a predetermined length, and by folding the extended section. Therefore, the number of components can be reduced, and a connecting process for the upper panel sections <b>331</b>A, <b>331</b>B and the connector section <b>360</b> can be omitted.</p>
<heading id="h-0022" level="1">INDUSTRIAL APPLICABILITY</heading>
<p id="p-0096" num="0155">As described above, the connector retaining holder, the connector holding clamp, and the connector retaining structure according to the present invention is suited for preventing disconnection of a small-sized connector, such as USB standard connector, connected to an FA apparatus, and especially most suited for preventing an equipment-side connector from being damaged, and a cable connector from being disconnected, in a structure where the cable connector is connected to the rear side of a thin apparatus at right angle.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A connector retaining structure comprising:
<claim-text>a connector retaining holder that prevents a cable connector that is coupled to a longitudinal-type equipment-side connector provided on a PCB of electrical equipment at a right angle from being disconnected from the equipment-side connector, the connector retaining holder including
<claim-text>a supporting section that supports at least a rear end of the cable connector, the supporting section including a contacting surface that makes a contact with a rear end surface of the cable connector, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fastening section that is formed in a flange-like shape and is fastened to the equipment with a fastening screw;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mounting base that is provided on the equipment and on which the fastening section of the connector retaining holder is mounted; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a connector supporting clamp including
<claim-text>an upper panel section that includes an inserting hole into which a tip of the equipment-side connector is inserted and a separate screw hole other than the inserting hole, and is arranged substantially in parallel to the PCB, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a foot section that supports the upper panel section on the PCB, wherein</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fastening screw is screwed and fixed into the screw hole in the upper panel section of the connector supporting clamp.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The connector retaining structure according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the mounting base includes a surrounding wall that surrounds the fastening section of the connector retaining holder.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
