<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641499-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641499</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12229938</doc-number>
<date>20080828</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>627</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439352</main-classification>
<further-classification>439595</further-classification>
<further-classification>439489</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">High voltage connector and interlocking loop connector assembly</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5236373</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kennedy</name>
<date>19930800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5692923</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Sawada</name>
<date>19971200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439350</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6119668</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Richards et al.</name>
<date>20000900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6491542</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Zerebilov</name>
<date>20021200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6572401</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Kurimoto et al.</name>
<date>20030600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439489</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7081193</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Dewey et al.</name>
<date>20060700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7084361</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Bowes et al.</name>
<date>20060800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7381084</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Horn et al.</name>
<date>20080600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00009">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7402068</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Tarchinski</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439357</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00010">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0032404</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Furuta et al.</name>
<date>20050200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439157</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00011">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2008/0220652</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tyler</name>
<date>20080900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439610</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439595</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439488-490</main-classification>
<additional-info>unstructured</additional-info>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>11</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>George</last-name>
<first-name>Terry A.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Salem</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Sudik, Jr.</last-name>
<first-name>Joseph</first-name>
<address>
<city>Niles</city>
<state>OH</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Twomey</last-name>
<first-name>Thomas N.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Delphi Technologies, Inc.</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Troy</city>
<state>MI</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Hammond</last-name>
<first-name>Briggitte R</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A high voltage and interlock loop assembly has first and second high voltage connector housings complementarily constructed for releasable engagement with each other and for having a high voltage circuit running therethrough. First and second connectors for an interlock loop circuit are complementarily constructed for releasable engagement with each other with one of the interlock loop connectors being mounted on one of the high voltage connector housings. The first and second interlock loop connectors have complementarily abutment shoulders with one abutment shoulder being on a flexible tab. The flexible tab is movable to misalign its abutment shoulder from the other abutment shoulder when the high voltage connector housings are properly engaged together to allow full engagement of the first and second interlock loop connectors.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="127.34mm" wi="225.81mm" file="US07641499-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="233.09mm" wi="134.20mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641499-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="204.89mm" wi="141.82mm" file="US07641499-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="205.74mm" wi="139.62mm" file="US07641499-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="213.53mm" wi="111.84mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641499-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="211.33mm" wi="105.66mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641499-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="217.09mm" wi="108.71mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641499-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="213.95mm" wi="102.79mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641499-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="205.74mm" wi="152.48mm" file="US07641499-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The field of this invention relates to a high voltage connector assembly and more particularly for a high voltage connector assembly that incorporates a high voltage interlock loop connector assembly for automotive applications.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">Vehicles that are propelled by internal combustion engines have low voltage circuits that are used to operate numerous devices for example, turn signals, headlights, brake lights, radios, and electronic instrument panels. Electric or hybrid vehicles on the other hand need to have a high voltage circuitry to provide the needed wattage to run the main electric motors and other devices that have typically been belt driven. It is foreseen that many more electric type vehicles will enter the commercial market that use high voltage (typically 300V or higher) to power these devices and will need high voltage connectors for the circuits.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In order to allow easy installation and disconnection of various electrical components for repair and replacement, the high voltage circuit for these electric and hybrid vehicles may have several conveniently placed high voltage connectors that may be connected together or disconnected from each other.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">Furthermore, due to the high voltage and large amperage involved, it is a prerequisite to shut down the high voltage circuit in question before an automotive technician or other individual disconnects any high voltage connector. To prevent premature physical contact with the high voltage circuit, interlock loop circuitry, often referred to as high voltage interlock loops (HVIL), have been devised which when triggered will activate a shut-off program to shut down the high voltage circuit. One such trigger is an interlock loop connector in the HVIL circuit that often is piggybacked onto the high voltage connectors to allow the high voltage electrical circuit to shut down and adequately discharge after the HVIL circuit becomes disconnected but before the connector housing of the high voltage connector assembly can become disconnected.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Present HVIL connectors system are costly, bulky and contain extra parts which are subject to grease and grime buildup that may eventually interfere in its operation.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">What is needed is a smaller and more reliable connector for an HVIL system. What is also needed is an HVIL connector that uses as part of its structure a connection position assurance device on the high voltage connector housing.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In accordance with one aspect of the invention, a high voltage and interlock loop connector assembly has first and second high voltage connector housings as part of a high voltage circuit running therethrough. The first and second high voltage connector housings are complementarily constructed for releasable engagement with each other. First and second connectors for an interlock loop circuit are also complementarily constructed for releasable engagement with each other. The first and second interlock loop connectors preferably are movable to disconnect and break an interlock loop circuit running therethrough. One of the first or second interlock loop connectors is mounted on one of the high voltage connector housings. The first and second interlock loop connectors each have complementarily abutment shoulders with one abutment shoulder being on a flexible tab. The abutment shoulders abut each other and prevent full engagement of the connectors when the first and second high voltage connector housings are not fully engaged with each other. The flexible tab is movable by one of the high voltage connector housings to misalign its abutment shoulder from the other abutment shoulder when the high voltage connector housings are properly engaged together to allow full engagement of the first and second interlock loop connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Preferably, the first and second high voltage connector housings have a latching handle mechanism constructed to be non-releasable when the first and second interlock connectors are engaged to each other. It is also preferred that the high voltage connector housings require engagement with a tool to complete disconnection of the high voltage circuit within the high voltage connector housings after disconnection of the interlock loop circuit within the interlock loop interlock loop connectors.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In one embodiment, one of the high voltage connector housings has a connector positioned assurance device. Preferably, the connector position assurance device has a slide member with a locking protrusion that extends into an opening in the first high voltage connector housing when in the engaged position. The locking protrusion is recessable out of the opening by a tool sized to enter the opening to allow the connector position assurance slide member to move to its disengaged position and to allow the latching handle mechanism to be releasable and to allow disconnection of the first and second high voltage connector housings. Furthermore, the locking protrusion may be positioned at a distal end of a resiliently flexible tongue section of the slide member. The tongue section is flexible to allow the locking protrusion to flex and descend out of the opening under a stop shoulder. It is desired that the opening and the locking protrusion are covered by the interlock loop connectors when the interlock connectors are engaged.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In one embodiment, the flexible tab is deflectable upward by a surface of the connector position assurance slide member when the high voltage connector housings are in the fully engaged position and the connector position assurance slide member is in the locked position. One of the interlock loop connectors and the high voltage connector housings have a groove to receive the flexible tab to let it resiliently bias back downward to a rest position when the interlock loop connectors are fully engaged.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">Reference now is made to the accompanying drawings in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective assembled view of a high voltage and HVIL connector assembly showing the first and second HVIL connectors assembled on top of the first and second high voltage connector housings;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a perspective view of the second HVIL connector shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the first high voltage connector housing shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3A</figref> is a top plan partially broken view of the first high voltage connector housing illustrating the connection position assurance slide member;</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of the first HVIL connector shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the assembly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> with the high voltage connector housing fully engaged and the HVIL connectors in position to be engaged;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> with the HVIL connectors fully engaged;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-sectional view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> with the HVIL first connector disengaged and the high voltage connector housing ready to be disengaged;</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> with the connector position assurance mechanism slid back to allow the main latching device to be operated to unlock the high voltage connector housings;</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a cross-sectional view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrating another improper installation attempt with the high voltage housing connected but the connection position assurance device not positioned in the installed position; and</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> is a cross-sectional view similar to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> illustrating an improper sequence of installation of the HVIL connectors.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, a high voltage and HVIL connector assembly <b>10</b> is shown with a male high voltage housing <b>12</b> connected to a female high voltage housing <b>14</b>. A latching device <b>16</b> and connection position assurance device <b>18</b> are housed on the female connector housing <b>14</b>. High voltage wires <b>20</b> extend from each housing <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> and connect together when the two housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> are connected as part of a high voltage circuit <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">A male HVIL connector <b>22</b> is piggy backed on top of the male housing <b>12</b>. The connector <b>22</b> may be integrally formed with the male housing <b>12</b>. A female HVIL connector <b>24</b> is removably mounted on top of the female housing <b>14</b>. <b>14</b>. Low voltage HVIL wires <b>26</b> are operably connected to the HVIL connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> that contact each other to form part of an HVIL circuit <b>27</b>. When the connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> become disconnected the HVIL circuit <b>27</b> becomes open and is programmed to open the high voltage circuit <b>21</b> by disconnecting from a high voltage source (not shown). A period of time, for example 5 seconds, is required to insure an adequate discharge of the voltage to less than 60 volts after the high voltage circuit <b>21</b> is disconnected from the high voltage source.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">In order to assure that the appropriate period of time occurs between the opening of the HVIL circuit <b>27</b> and the access to the high voltage circuit <b>21</b>, the high voltage connector housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> and the HVIL connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> are constructed to take time to disconnect. In particular, the period of time needs to be long enough from first disengagement of the HVIL circuit <b>27</b> and when the HVIL connector housings are disengaged to the time the high voltage connector housing <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> become accessible and are first pulled apart to open the high voltage circuit <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">It is desired that the latching device <b>16</b> is inoperable and/or inaccessible when the HVIL connectors <b>22</b>, <b>24</b> are engaged. Furthermore, once the HVIL low voltage circuit <b>27</b> is open by pulling apart the two connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b>, the needed use of a tool provides time when a person picks up the tool and uses it to access a mechanism before the full disconnection of the two high voltage housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> is possible.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A male low voltage connector <b>22</b> is housed or mounted on the male high voltage housing <b>12</b> as more clearly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>. The low voltage connector <b>22</b> may be integrally formed with the high voltage housing <b>12</b>. The low voltage connector <b>22</b> has a stop shoulder <b>30</b> formed near the male entry end <b>32</b> for the low voltage electric terminal connectors (not shown). A slot <b>34</b> is formed between the stop tab <b>30</b> and the end <b>32</b> that axially extends rearwardly.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 5</figref>, the female high voltage connector housing <b>14</b> has a first end <b>36</b> for receiving an end <b>38</b> of the male connector housing <b>12</b> and has high voltage terminals <b>40</b> that engage complementary high voltage terminals. (not shown) in male connector housing <b>12</b>. At a top surface, the latch device <b>16</b> has a latch handle <b>44</b> that operates locking latches <b>46</b> that releasably engage complementary recesses <b>48</b> in the male housing <b>12</b> to latch and lock the two high voltage housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> together.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The connector position assurance device <b>18</b> includes a slide member <b>50</b> that slides along a groove <b>54</b> in the female connector <b>14</b> under the latch handle <b>44</b>. The male connector <b>12</b> as more clearly shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</figref> has an abutment section <b>56</b> which receives and deflects the slide <b>50</b> upwardly within the groove <b>54</b> when pushed to the assured position. When the movable slide member <b>50</b> is fully engaged, its thicker handle end <b>55</b> prevents the latch handle <b>44</b> from being operably depressed to pivot the latches <b>46</b> upward. Therefore, the latches <b>46</b> cannot lift and disengage from the male connector housing <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, the connector <b>24</b> has a female end <b>58</b> with low voltage terminals <b>59</b> for the HVIL circuit <b>27</b>. A flexible tab <b>60</b> is formed with one abutment shoulder <b>61</b> at end <b>58</b> that can be radially flexed inwardly (upwardly as shown in the Figures) but resiliently biased to its rest position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, when the two low voltage connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> are engaged after the high voltage connector housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> are engaged, the flex tab <b>60</b> is flexed upwardly as it rides on top of the slide <b>50</b>. Slide <b>50</b> misaligns its abutment shoulder <b>61</b> to pass over the stop shoulder <b>30</b> and enter slot <b>34</b> to the engaged position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>. In the engaged position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, terminals <b>58</b> engage terminals <b>63</b> in housing <b>24</b>. The latch handle <b>44</b> even though exposed is not operational because of the lock out function of the CPA device <b>18</b>, particularly by the interposition of thicker section <b>55</b>. Once the low voltage connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> are fully engaged the flex tab <b>60</b> is allowed to resiliently flex back to a rest position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> by engaging a recess <b>65</b> within the slot <b>34</b>. This alleviates long term stress on the flex tab <b>60</b> during the installed position and increases it durability.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">Referring now to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 6 and 7</figref>, the flex tab <b>60</b> has a canted surface <b>72</b> to allow the female connector <b>24</b> to be axially pulled and disengaged from the male connector housing <b>22</b>. Once the female connector housing <b>24</b> is disengaged from the assembly <b>10</b>, the slide <b>50</b> member has a lock protrusion <b>64</b> extending into an opening <b>66</b> in the latch handle <b>44</b>. The opening <b>66</b> may be continuous with groove <b>54</b>. A lock shoulder <b>67</b> is at one end of opening <b>66</b>. The lock protrusion <b>64</b> is at a distal end of resilient tongue section <b>52</b>. A tool, for example a small screw example a small screw driver or a pick, needs to push the protrusion <b>64</b> downwardly as shown by arrow <b>75</b> to disengage it from the opening <b>66</b> to bypass shoulder <b>67</b> in order to allow the slide member <b>50</b> to slide back to the set position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>. Aperture <b>70</b> with stop shoulder <b>71</b> prevents the slide member <b>50</b> from undesirably disengaging from housing <b>14</b>. After the slide member <b>50</b> is moved back to the set position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the latch handle <b>44</b> becomes free to be depressed and release the latches <b>46</b> to unlock high voltage housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> from each other. The time it takes for an operator to pick up a tool, press it into opening <b>66</b> and slide the slide <b>50</b> seems to generally well exceed the preferred 5 second period of time to adequately lower the voltage below the 60 volt level.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">Furthermore, with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 9 and 10</figref>, the HVIL connectors <b>22</b> and <b>24</b> cannot be engaged without the high voltage connector housings <b>12</b> and <b>14</b> previously being engaged. If the slide member <b>50</b> is not in the engaged position as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 and 6</figref>, the flex tab <b>60</b> is in a lower position by flexing into groove <b>54</b> and its shoulder <b>61</b> abuts against the stop shoulder <b>30</b> and prevents full engagement. For example in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 10</figref> when the female high voltage connector <b>14</b> is not there, it can be seen that the tab <b>60</b> abuts the stop shoulder <b>30</b>. Even if the female connector housing <b>14</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is there and partially engages but the slide member is not properly engaged, the slide <b>50</b> does not fill groove <b>54</b> and the flex tab <b>60</b> is allowed to drop into the same groove <b>54</b> and abut the stop shoulder <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In this fashion, an HVIL connector system for a high voltage connector provides several advantages of a system that prevent unwanted and undesirable premature connection of the low voltage HVIL circuit while also preventing unwanted and undesirable premature disconnection of a high voltage circuit of an electrically driven motor vehicle before the low voltage circuit is disconnected.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">It will be readily understood by those persons skilled in the art that the present invention is susceptible of broad utility and application. Many embodiments and adaptations of the present invention other than those described above, as well as many variations, modifications and equivalent arrangements, will be apparent from or reasonably suggested by the present invention and the foregoing description, without departing from the substance or scope of the present present invention. Accordingly, while the present invention has been described herein in detail in relation to its preferred embodiment, it is to be understood that this disclosure is only illustrative and exemplary of the present invention and is made merely for purposes of providing a full and enabling disclosure of the invention. The foregoing disclosure is not intended or to be construed to limit the present invention or otherwise to exclude any such other embodiments, adaptations, variations, modifications and equivalent arrangements, the present invention being limited only by the following claims and the equivalents thereof.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The embodiments in which an exclusive property or privilege is claimed are defined as follows:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A high voltage and interlock loop assembly comprising:
<claim-text>first and second high voltage connector housings complementarily constructed for releasable engagement with each other for having a high voltage circuit running therethrough;</claim-text>
<claim-text>first and second connectors for an interlock loop circuit complementarily constructed for releasable engagement with each other;</claim-text>
<claim-text>one of said interlock loop connectors being mounted on one of said high voltage connector housings;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first and second interlock loop connectors having complementarily abutment shoulders, one abutment shoulder being a flexible tab;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said abutment shoulders abut each other and prevent full engagement when said first and second high voltage connector housings are not fully engaged with each other; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said flexible tab being movable by one of said high voltage connectors to misalign its abutment shoulder from said other abutment shoulder when said high voltage connector housings are properly engaged together to allow full engagement of said first and second interlock loop connectors.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. A high voltage and interlock loop assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>said first and second interlock loop connectors being movable to disconnect and break a interlock loop circuit running therethrough; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first and second high voltage connector having a latching handle mechanism constructed to be non-releasable when said first and second interlock connectors are engaged to each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. A high voltage and interlock loop assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>one of said interlock connectors and high voltage connector housings require engagement with a tool to complete disconnection of said high voltage circuit within said high voltage connector housings after disconnection of said interlock loop circuit within said interlock loop connectors.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. A high voltage and high voltage interlock loop assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>one of said high voltage connector housings having a connector positioned assurance device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>said flexible tab being deflectable upward by a surface of said connector positioned assurance device when said high voltage connector housings are in the fully engaged position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>one of said second interlock loop connectors and said high voltage connector housings having a groove to receive said flexible tab to let it resiliently bias back downward to a rest position when said interlock loop connectors are fully engaged.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. A high voltage and high voltage interlock loop assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>said connector position assurance device having a slide member with a locking protrusion that extends into an opening in the first high voltage connector housing when in the engaged position, said locking protrusion being recessable out of said opening by a tool sized to enter said opening to allow said connector position assurance slide member to move to its disengaged position and to allow said latching handle mechanism to be operable to unlock said first and second high voltage connector housings from each other.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. A high voltage and high voltage interlock loop assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>said connector position assurance slide member having a resiliently flexible tongue that is flexible to allow said locking protrusion to exit the opening the opening under a stop shoulder.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. A high voltage and high voltage interlock loop assembly as defined in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00006">claim 6</claim-ref> further comprising:
<claim-text>said opening and said locking protrusion being covered by the said interlock loop connectors when said interlock connectors are engaged. </claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
