<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641518-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641518</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11889528</doc-number>
<date>20070814</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>TW</country>
<doc-number>96207058 U</doc-number>
<date>20070503</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>24</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439660</main-classification>
<further-classification>439188</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">SATA data connector</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7393247</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Yu et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439638</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2006/0279885</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Sung et al.</name>
<date>20061200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>361 42</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439188</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>43962014</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439660</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>10</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>12</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080274631</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20081106</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Lee</last-name>
<first-name>Chung-Liang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Wu</last-name>
<first-name>Hsi-Hsi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Chang</last-name>
<first-name>Hung Yu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>TW</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Rosenberg, Klein &#x26; Lee</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Innodisk Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Taipei</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Leon</last-name>
<first-name>Edwin A.</first-name>
<department>2833</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Girardi</last-name>
<first-name>Vanessa</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A modified standard SATA data connector is provided with a power supply circuit. The connector includes male and female data connectors. A male signal interface has seven male data connection pins, consisting of four data, a power supply, and two ground pins, the power supply pin replacing one of three original ground pins and connecting with a power line of a circuit board. A corresponding female signal interface has seven female data connection pins consisting of four data, a power receiving, and two ground pins. While the female and male data connectors are engaged, power can be supplied from the power line of the circuit board to an applied device connected with the female data connector via the power supplying and receiving pins. Thus, the SATA data connector can work without an external SATA power cable, and the volume of the cable can be reduced.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="156.80mm" wi="242.32mm" file="US07641518-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="203.37mm" wi="177.29mm" file="US07641518-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="244.18mm" wi="172.55mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641518-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="180.76mm" wi="90.42mm" file="US07641518-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="239.61mm" wi="165.61mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641518-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="220.47mm" wi="187.03mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641518-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="221.83mm" wi="164.25mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641518-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="245.11mm" wi="174.92mm" orientation="landscape" file="US07641518-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="180.51mm" wi="94.49mm" file="US07641518-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="208.45mm" wi="106.51mm" file="US07641518-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00010" num="00010">
<img id="EMI-D00010" he="186.10mm" wi="161.46mm" file="US07641518-20100105-D00010.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to a SATA data connector, and more particular to a SATA data connector with a power supply circuit.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">In accordance with the progressing of the computer development, the storage device plays a most important role. A hard disk is used to be the storage device provided within the computer, having with the communication interface, which was conformed to the specification of the Parallel Advanced Technology Attachment (PATA), and further, the recent communication interface thereof has been advanced to conform to the specification of the Serial Advanced Technology Attachment (SATA). The recent data transmission speed is getting higher substantially through the SATA communication interface, such as more than 150 Mb/s, the volume of the transmission line fitted in with the SATA communication interface is getting smaller, and the length thereof is getting longer, such as 100 cm.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">Referring to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of the prior art SATA transmission interface. The SATA data connector <b>12</b> comprises a male data connector <b>11</b> and a female data connector <b>13</b>, wherein the male connector <b>11</b> is set on a computer system, a motherboard, or a circuit board <b>10</b> to connect with other devices on the circuit board <b>10</b>. The female data connector <b>13</b> is set on the end of the SATA data cable <b>135</b>, and another end of the SATA data cable <b>135</b> can be connected with an external device <b>15</b>, such as the hard disk, the DVD ROM, the memory device, or other devices. Regarding to the external device <b>15</b> cannot have the operating power through the SATA data cable <b>135</b>, the external device <b>15</b> has to be connected to a power supply <b>17</b> through the SATA power connector <b>18</b> or a SATA power cable <b>175</b> for being supplied by the operating power.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">According to the demand of various voltages for supplying the SATA external device <b>15</b>, the specification of the SATA defines the operating voltages, including 12V, 5V, 3.3V, 0.7V, and 250 mV. Due to the consideration of that, the volume of the SATA power cable <b>175</b> has to be larger.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">In general, the conventional SATA data connector <b>12</b> has seven connection pins (S<b>1</b>-S<b>7</b>) that consist of three ground pins (GND), and four data pins, and the SATA power connector <b>18</b> has fifteen connection pins (P<b>1</b>-P<b>15</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">However, there are many problems of the SATA communication interface still, although many advantages have mentioned previously.
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0007">1. Due to there is nothing relative to the power line designed internally within the SATA data connector, a SATA power cable is used to connect with a power supply externally, however, once a device simply requires to be supplied power by 5V or 3.3V only, such as a Solid State Disk (SSD), the SATA power cable will be used inconveniently due to the structure of which is too complex because that supports a lot of operating powers.</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0002" num="0008">2. The connection between the male data connector and the female data connector within the SATA data connector is very unstable. Once an external force is applied on the male data connector or the female data connector, the link thereof should be failure, therefore, the hardware should be damaged or the data should be lost.</li>
    <li id="ul0001-0003" num="0009">3. The conventional SATA male data connector and the SATA female data connector are connected each other with single contact mode, and the data transmission speed is about 3.0 Gb/s. As the connection between the SATA male data connector and the SATA female data connector is loose by an external force, the transmission data must be damaged.</li>
</ul>
</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0010">It is a primary object of the present invention to provide a SATA data connector, wherein one of three ground pins of the SATA data connector can be used to be a power supplying pin, such that the SATA data connector can work without the external SATA power cable, and the amount and volume of the cable can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0011">It is a secondary object of the present invention to provide a SATA data connector, wherein the connection between the female data connector and the male data connector will not be loosened easily by an external force, since the female data connector and the male data connector can be respectively a female header and a pin header to ensure the stability and correction during data transmission.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0012">It is another object of the present invention to provide a SATA data connector, wherein the male data connector on the circuit board comprises a male signal interface and a power supplying line, and the female data connector of the SATA data connector comprises a female signal interface and a power receiving line, such that the male data connector can supply operating power and transmit data to the female data connector, and the SATA data connector can work without the external SATA power cable.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0013">It is another object of the present invention to provide a SATA data connector, wherein a power supply circuit can be provided between the circuit board and the female data connector according to the layout of the power supplying line and the power receiving line, and the connection between the male data connector and the female data connector can be tighter to prevent the loose between link thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0014">To achieve the previous mentioned objects, the present invention provides a SATA data connector, comprising: a male data connector comprising seven male connection pins having a power supplying pin, two ground pins, and four data pins, the power supplying pin being electrically connected with a power line of a circuit board; and a female data connector comprising seven female connection pins having a power receiving pin, two ground pins, and four data pins, wherein the female data connector can connect with the male data connector, and the power receiving pin of the female data connector can contact the power supplying pin of the male data connector, such that the power line of the circuit board, the power supplying pin of the male data connector, and the power receiving pin of the female data connector can form a power supply circuit.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0015">To achieve the previous mentioned objects, the present invention provides a SATA data connector, comprising a female data connector having a plurality of female connection pins and one of a power receiving line or a power receiving pin, wherein the female connection pins comprise at least one ground pin and a plurality of data pins.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0016">To achieve the previous mentioned objects, the present invention provides a SATA data connector, comprising a female data connector having a plurality of female connection pins, an applied device, and a power connection hole, the applied device connecting with the female connection pins and the power connection hole, the female connection pins comprising at least one ground pin and a plurality of data pins, wherein the applied device can be one of a memory, a control device, a circuit board, or a combination thereof, and the power connection hole can connect with a power supply via a SATA power cable.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0017">To achieve the previous mentioned objects, the present invention provides a SATA data connector, comprising: a male data connector comprising a plurality of male connection pins having at least one ground pin, a power supplying pin, and a plurality of data pins; and a female data connector comprising a plurality of female connection pins having at least one ground pin, a power receiving pin, and a plurality of data pins, wherein the female data connector can connect with the male data connector, such that the power supplying pin can contact with the power receiving pin to form a power supply circuit, and the male connector pin can be one of a gold finger, a pin header, or a female header, and the female connector pin can be one of a gold finger, a female header, or a pin header.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of the prior art due to that SATA transmission interface is applied.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of a preferred embodiment of the present invention regarding to a SATA data connector.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A to 5D</figref> are respectively the three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0025" num="0027">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a three-dimensional diagram of a preferred embodiment of the present invention regarding to a SATA data connector is showed. A SATA data connector comprises a male data connector <b>21</b> and a female data connector <b>22</b>, wherein the male data connector <b>21</b> set in a computer system, a motherboard, or a circuit board <b>20</b> has a male signal interface <b>211</b> that comprises a plurality of male connection pins <b>212</b>. In accordance with the male data connector <b>21</b>, the female data connector <b>22</b> has a female signal interface <b>211</b> that comprises a plurality of female pins <b>222</b>, and the female connection pin <b>222</b> can be electrically connected with the female connection pin <b>221</b>, since the female data connector <b>22</b> connects with the male data connector <b>21</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0028">In general, the SATA data connector has seven pins, as shown at <b>212</b> and <b>222</b> of the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, wherein the first pin (<b>2121</b>, S<b>1</b>), the fourth pin (<b>2122</b>, S<b>4</b>), and seventh pin (<b>2123</b>, S<b>7</b>) are ground pins, and other pins (<b>2142</b>, S<b>2</b>, S<b>3</b>, S<b>5</b>, S<b>6</b>) are data pins (A+/A&#x2212;/B+/B&#x2212;). In the present invention, one of S<b>1</b>, S<b>4</b>, or S<b>7</b> within the male connection pin <b>212</b> can be defined a power supplying pin for supplying the operating power, such as the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> (S<b>1</b>) is the power supplying pin in the embodiment. Besides, one of the ground pins (S<b>1</b>, S<b>4</b>, or S<b>7</b>) within the female connection pin <b>222</b> can be defined a power receiving pin <b>2221</b> that corresponds to the position of the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> within the male connection pin <b>212</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0029">As the male signal interface <b>211</b> connects with the female signal interface <b>221</b>, the power supplying pin <b>2121</b>/power receiving pin <b>2221</b>, ground pin <b>2122</b>,<b>2123</b>/<b>2222</b>,<b>2223</b>, and data pin <b>2124</b>/<b>2224</b> can respectively connect each other. Due to the male data connector <b>21</b> is set on the circuit board <b>20</b>, the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> of the male data connector <b>21</b> is electrically connected with a power line <b>205</b> of the circuit board <b>20</b>. Therefore, the power line <b>205</b> of the circuit board <b>20</b>, the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> and the power receiving pin <b>2221</b> can form a power supply circuit to supply the operating power to the female data connector <b>22</b>. The female data connector <b>22</b> can work without the external SATA power cable, and the volume and the amount of the SATA power cable can be decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0030">The conventional female data connector (<b>22</b>) of SATA data connector doesn't have the power receiving pin (<b>2221</b>), and a ground pin is used to replace the power receiving pin (<b>2221</b>). Once a conventional female data connector (<b>22</b>) connects to the male data connector <b>21</b> with power supplying pin <b>2121</b>, the SATA data connector may be damaged. Thus, a protective device <b>213</b> set on the circuit board <b>20</b> is used to connect between the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> of the male data connector <b>21</b> and the power line <b>205</b> for protecting the SATA device and the external device. In another word, as the conventional SATA female data connector (<b>22</b>) connects with the male data connector <b>21</b> of the invention, the protective device <b>213</b> can break the power supply circuit, such that the conventional SATA female data connector (<b>22</b>) can work regularly.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0031">The protective device <b>213</b> can be an automatic resettable fuse, a diode, a switch device, such as a relay, or a circuit breaker to form a broken circuit, and the conventional SATA female data connector (<b>22</b>) can work regularly.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0032">The efficacy of above mentioned broken circuit can be described as follows, for example, the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> can't supply power to the power receiving pin (<b>2221</b>), while the conventional SATA female data connector (<b>22</b>) connects to the male data connector <b>21</b> of the invention, since the protective device <b>213</b> is an automatic resettable fuse. At this time, the automatic resettable fuse <b>213</b> has to overload and trip, and the conventional SATA female data connector (<b>22</b>) can work normally. Once the female data connector (<b>22</b>) is removed from the male data connector <b>21</b>, the automatic resettable fuse <b>213</b> can connect with the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> again, and the theory thereof is according to the usual fuse for protecting the extended line. Of course, the other device or circuit that can form a broken circuit can be used in the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0033">In another embodiment of the present invention, the protective device <b>225</b> can be set within the female data connector <b>22</b> to connect with the power receiving pin <b>2221</b>. As the female data connector <b>22</b> with the power receiving pin <b>2221</b> connects to the conventional male data connector (<b>21</b>) without the power supplying pin <b>2121</b>, the operating power can't transmit to the computer system or the circuit board <b>20</b> via the power receiving pin <b>2221</b> of the female data connector <b>22</b> and the ground pin <b>2121</b> of the male data connector (<b>21</b>) due to the protective device <b>225</b>, so the protective device <b>225</b> can protect the female data connector <b>22</b>, male data connector (<b>21</b>), or the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0034">The female data connector <b>22</b> can connect with an external device <b>24</b> or an applied device <b>223</b>, <b>2235</b> via a transmission line <b>23</b>, wherein the applied device <b>223</b> or <b>2235</b> can be a memory, a control device, or a circuit board, and the transmission line <b>23</b> can comprise a power circuit and a data circuit. Besides, the protective device <b>225</b> can be set within the external device <b>24</b> or the applied device <b>223</b>, <b>2235</b> to be another protective device <b>245</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0035">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention is showed. Due to the volume of the applied device <b>323</b>, such as circuit board, control device, or memory, is more and more small, the previous mentioned external device (<b>24</b>) or applied device (<b>223</b>) can be set within the female data connector <b>32</b> to be an applied device <b>323</b> within the female data connector <b>32</b>. Therefore, the female data connector <b>32</b> can be a SATA applied device <b>32</b> that can be used to connect with the male data connector <b>21</b>, such that the volume and amount of the cable can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0036">For example, as the applied device <b>323</b> is a memory, the SATA applied device <b>32</b> can be as a storage device that is similar to a flash disk. On the contrary, as the applied device <b>323</b> is a circuit board or a control device, the SATA applied device <b>32</b> can be a device within a personal computer, an industry computer, or a small electric device.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0037">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the invention is showed. The male connection pin of the male data connector <b>41</b> can be a pin header <b>411</b> that is different from the foregoing gold finger (<b>212</b>). Besides, the female connection pin of the female data connector <b>42</b> can be a correlating female header <b>422</b> that is also different from the gold finger (<b>222</b>). As the male connector pin and the female connector pin are respectively the pin header <b>411</b> and the female header <b>422</b>, the contact area between that can be wider than the gold finger (<b>212</b>) leading to the link thereof can be tight and stable. Therefore, as the male data connector <b>41</b> connects to the female data connector <b>42</b>, the link of that can't be failure by an external force to ensure the stability and exactitude of the transmission data.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0038">In above embodiment of the present invention, the SATA male data connector (<b>21</b>) has seven pins, and the power supplying pin <b>2121</b> can be one of the three ground pins of the prior art. As shown in the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5A</figref>, in another embodiment of the present invention, the number of the male connector pin <b>512</b> of the SATA male data connector <b>51</b> can be eight, nine, ten or more than ten, such that the SATA male data connector <b>51</b> can comprise seven pins (three ground pins and four data pins) and the other pins that can be the power supplying pins (<b>5121</b> or <b>5122</b>) for supplying the operating power to the female data connector <b>52</b>. In accordance with the number of the male connector pin <b>512</b>, the number of the female connector pin <b>522</b> can be changed, as the number of the male connector pin <b>512</b> is larger than seven.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0039">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5B</figref>, the female data connector <b>52</b> comprises a device <b>5223</b>, and the position of male data connector <b>51</b> relative to the device <b>5223</b> doesn't set the male connector pin for having efficacy, as discussed earlier with reference to the &#x201c;broken circuit&#x201d; (note position of missing male connector pin <b>512</b> in male data connector <b>51</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0040">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5C</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5D</figref>, the female connector pin <b>522</b> of the female data connector <b>52</b> can be the pin header, and the male connector pin <b>512</b> of the male data connector <b>51</b> can be the female header. Of course, the male data connector <b>51</b> can comprise the foolproof device <b>5223</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0041">The female data connector <b>52</b> further comprises at least one hook <b>520</b> that is set on the side of the female data connector <b>52</b>, and an opening <b>510</b> that is relative to the hook <b>520</b> is set on the male data connector <b>51</b>. Therefore, the hook <b>520</b> can lodge in the opening <b>510</b>, and the female data connector <b>52</b> can connect with the male data connector <b>51</b> stably.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0042">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, the male data connector <b>61</b> further comprises a power supplying line <b>66</b>, and the female data connector <b>62</b> comprises a power receiving line <b>67</b> related to the power supplying line <b>66</b>. Therefore, the male data connector <b>61</b> can supply the operating power to the female data connector <b>62</b> via the power supplying line <b>66</b> and power receiving line <b>67</b>. Besides, the connection between the male data connector <b>61</b> and the female data connector <b>62</b> can be tighter due to the power supplying line <b>66</b> and the power receiving line <b>67</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0043">The male data connector <b>61</b> can connect with device <b>68</b>, such as CPU, set on the circuit board <b>60</b>. A male signal interface <b>611</b> is set within the male data connector <b>61</b>, and a shell <b>614</b> is set around the male data connector <b>61</b>. In addition, the shell <b>614</b> can comprise the power supplying line <b>66</b> that can receive the operating power form the circuit board <b>60</b> as the device <b>68</b>, and a foolproof groove <b>691</b> can be set on one side of the male data connector <b>61</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0044">In accordance with the male data connector <b>61</b>, the female data connector <b>62</b> comprises a female signal interface <b>621</b>, a power receiving line <b>67</b>, and a foolproof flange <b>692</b>. In the embodiment of the present invention, the power receiving line <b>67</b> can be made of a conductive material with elasticity, such as a metal leaf spring.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0045">The female data connector <b>62</b> can plug in the female data connector <b>61</b> safely by means of the foolproof groove <b>691</b> and the foolproof flange <b>692</b>. Preferably, as the power receiving line <b>67</b> is made of the leaf spring, the power receiving line <b>67</b> of the female data connector <b>62</b> can connect with the power supplying line <b>66</b> of the shell <b>614</b> stably to form a power supply circuit for supplying power to the female data connector <b>62</b>. Moreover, the connection between the female signal interface <b>621</b> of the female data connector <b>62</b> and the male signal interface <b>611</b> of the male data connector <b>61</b> will be tighter to prevent the female data connector <b>32</b> loosing.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0046">Referring to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, another embodiment of the invention is showed. The power supplying line <b>66</b> is set on one side of the SATA male data connector <b>61</b> or the shell <b>614</b>, and a power receiving line <b>77</b> that is relative to the power supplying line <b>66</b> is set on the SATA female data connector <b>72</b>, furthermore, a fixed leaf spring <b>75</b> is set on other side of the female data connector <b>72</b>. As the female data connector <b>72</b> connects with the male data connector <b>61</b>, both the female signal interface <b>721</b> and the power receiving line <b>77</b> of the female data connector <b>72</b> can respectively connect with the male signal interface <b>611</b> and the power supplying line <b>66</b> of the male data connector <b>61</b> tightly due to the fixed leaf spring <b>75</b>, such that the number of the SATA power cable can be reduced.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0047">In another embodiment of the present invention, the fixed leaf spring <b>75</b> can be set on the male data connector <b>61</b> or be omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0048">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, another embodiment of the present invention is showed. A base <b>893</b> is used to replace the shell <b>641</b>, and the SATA male data connector <b>81</b> can comprise the base <b>893</b>. A notch <b>815</b> is set on the base <b>893</b>, and a power supplying line <b>86</b> set within the notch <b>815</b> connect with the power supplying line <b>76</b> of the circuit board. Furthermore, the SATA applied device <b>82</b> has a power receiving line <b>87</b> that is formed by a leaf spring <b>824</b> with fixer <b>825</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0049">Once the SATA applied device <b>82</b> connects to the male data connector <b>81</b>, the fixer <b>825</b> of the SATA applied device <b>82</b> can insert to the notch <b>815</b> of the male data connector <b>81</b>, after that, the SATA applied device <b>82</b> can connect with the male data connector <b>81</b> tightly. Moreover, the fixer <b>825</b> can connect with the power supplying line <b>86</b> of the male data connector <b>81</b>, such that the male data connector <b>81</b> can supply the operating power to the SATA applied device <b>82</b> via the power supplying line <b>86</b> and the power receiving line <b>87</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0050">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, a three-dimensional diagram of another embodiment of the present invention is showed. The SATA male data connector <b>91</b> has nothing relative to the power supplying line (<b>66</b>), such that the SATA male data connector <b>91</b> can be suitable for the conventional circuit board or computer system. The SATA applied device <b>92</b> comprises a power connection hole <b>927</b> that can be used to connect with a SATA power cable <b>928</b>, thus, a power supply <b>929</b> can connect with the power connection hole <b>927</b> of the SATA applied device <b>92</b> via a SATA power cable <b>928</b> for supplying the operating power to the applied device <b>923</b> within the SATA applied device <b>92</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0051">On another hand, once the SATA applied device <b>92</b> comprises a power receiving line or a power receiving pin for being used to connect with the power connection hole <b>927</b>/SATA power cable <b>928</b> and the applied device <b>923</b>. In another word, the power receiving line or the power receiving pin of the female data connector <b>92</b> can be as a connection line set between the power connection hole <b>927</b> and the applied device <b>923</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0052">In another embodiment of the present invention, as the SATA applied device <b>92</b> comprises a power receiving pin <b>2221</b>, a protective device <b>925</b> can be used to connect with the power receiving pin <b>2221</b> within the SATA applied device <b>92</b> to prevent the operating power from the power supply <b>929</b> damaging the computer system or the circuit board.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0053">Although the SATA data connector is used to describe the structure of the invention in the previous mentioned embodiment, the feature and technique of the invention can be used in other type SATA data connector, such as the e-SATA data connector.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0054">While this invention has been described with reference to illustrative embodiments, this description is not intended to be construed in a limiting sense. Various modifications of the illustrative embodiments, as well as other embodiments of the invention, which are apparent to persons skilled in the art to which the invention pertains are deemed to lie within the spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A SATA data connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a male data connector consisting of one power supplying pin, two ground pins, and four data pins, said power supplying pin being electrically connected directly with a power line of a circuit board; wherein the power supplying pin replaces one of three ground pins initially disposed within the male data connector of the standard SATA data connector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a female data connector consisting of one power receiving pin, two ground pins, and four data pins, wherein said female data connector connects with said male data connector, and said power receiving pin of said female data connector contacts said power supplying pin of said male data connector, such that said power line of said circuit board, said power supplying pin of said male data connector, and said power receiving pin of said female data connector forms an uninterrupted integral power supply circuit; wherein the power receiving pin replaces one of three ground pins initially disposed within the female data connector of a standard SATA connector.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The SATA data connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said power receiving pin connects with a protective device, and said protective device can be one of an automatic resettable fuse, a diode, a switch device, or a circuit breaker.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The SATA data connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising a protective device being set between said power supplying pin and said power line of said circuit board, wherein said protective device can be one of an automatic resettable fuse, a diode, a switch device, or a circuit breaker.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The SATA data connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said male connector pin can be one of a gold finger, a pin header, or a female header, and said female connector pin can be one of a gold finger, a female header, or a pin header.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The SATA data connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said female data connector comprises an applied device, such that said female data connector can be as a SATA applied device, and said applied device can be one of a memory, a control device, a circuit board, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The SATA data connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein said female data connector comprises a power connection hole that connects with said power receiving pin, and said power connection hole connects with a power supply via a SATA power cable. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
