<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641486-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641486</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>12419388</doc-number>
<date>20090407</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>12</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>2008-108918</doc-number>
<date>20080418</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>01</class>
<subclass>R</subclass>
<main-group>13</main-group>
<subgroup>62</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439157</main-classification>
<further-classification>439372</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Lever-type connector and method of operating it</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6736655</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Martin et al.</name>
<date>20040500</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7568925</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Ciriello et al.</name>
<date>20090800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439157</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2001/0019908</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Zweigle</name>
<date>20010900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439157</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2003/0162413</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Shinozaki et al.</name>
<date>20030800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2005/0064749</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Stella et al.</name>
<date>20050300</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>439157</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0026705</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tyler</name>
<date>20070200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00007">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>2007/0224862</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<name>Tyler</name>
<date>20070900</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00008">
<document-id>
<country>DE</country>
<doc-number>8714016</doc-number>
<date>19871100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>13</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439157</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>439372</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>8</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090263997</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20091022</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Tonosaki</last-name>
<first-name>Takashi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Yokkaichi</city>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>JP</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Hespos</last-name>
<first-name>Gerald E.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Casella</last-name>
<first-name>Anthony J.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Sumitomo Wiring Systems, Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<country>JP</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Ta</last-name>
<first-name>Tho D</first-name>
<department>2839</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A first housing (<b>10</b>) and a second housing (<b>30</b>) are connected by leverage brought about by the engagement of pinions (<b>24</b>) of a lever (<b>20</b>) rotatably supported on the first housing (<b>10</b>) and racks <b>33</b> of the second housing (<b>30</b>). In the process of rotating the lever (<b>20</b>), cam action brought about by the engagement of cam grooves (<b>25</b>) of the lever (<b>20</b>) and cam followers (<b>37</b>) of the second housing (<b>30</b>) is exhibited. This cam action prevents the first housing (<b>10</b>) from being inclined with respect to the second housing (<b>30</b>) with engaged positions of the pinions (<b>24</b>) and the racks (<b>33</b>) as supports.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="170.52mm" wi="256.03mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="181.44mm" wi="137.33mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="165.10mm" wi="137.67mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="170.69mm" wi="136.40mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="164.08mm" wi="132.67mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="166.37mm" wi="144.36mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="160.19mm" wi="124.88mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="141.48mm" wi="109.73mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="184.23mm" wi="130.22mm" file="US07641486-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The invention relates to a lever-type connector and to a method of operating it, in particular connecting and/or separating it.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">U.S. Pat. No. 6,736,655 discloses a lever-type connector that has a first housing, a lever rotatably mounted on the first housing and a second housing that can be connected to the first housing by the rotation of the lever. The lever has a pinion concentric with a center of rotation of the lever and the second housing has a rack extending in connecting directions of the two housings. The pinion engages the rack and generates a leverage to connect the housings as the lever is rotated.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The center of rotation of the lever of the above-described connector is offset from an engaged position of the rack and pinion in a width direction that intersects the connecting directions of the two housings. Thus, the first housing may incline with respect to the second housing about the engaged position of the rack and pinion due to a reaction force generated between the rack and the pinion during a connecting process.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">The invention was developed in view of the above situation and an object thereof is to connect two housings to each other without being inclined.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">The invention relates to a lever-type connector with a first housing, a lever rotatably mounted on the first housing, and a second housing connectable with the first housing. The lever includes at least one pinion and the second housing includes a rack. The pinion engages the rack and generates forces for connecting or separating the housings as the lever is rotated. One of the lever and the second housing is formed with at least one cam groove and the other is formed with at least one cam follower. The cam groove and the cam follower engage in the process of rotating the lever.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A reaction force may be generated between the rack and the pinion during the connection process. The reaction force may act in a direction that could cause the first housing to incline relative to the second housing about the engaged position of the rack and pinion. However, the engagement of the cam groove and the cam follower prevents inclination of the first housing. Thus, the two housings are connected without being inclined.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Leverage caused by the engagement of the rack and the pinion preferably is exhibited in the entire rotational range from the start to the end of the rotation of the lever. The cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam groove and the cam follower preferably is exhibited only in a part of the rotational range from an intermediate position of the rotation of the lever to the completion of the rotation. Accordingly, the leverage brought about by the engagement of the rack and the pinion and the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam groove and the cam follower are exhibited at a final stage of the rotation of the lever, and the two housings are aligned properly when the connecting operation of the two housings is completed.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">The cam groove preferably is formed in an arm portion of the lever without fully penetrating the arm.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">An arcuate surface of the cam groove distant from a supporting shaft that supports the lever on the first housing preferably defines a separation restricting surface and/or an arcuate surface of the cam groove close to the supporting shaft serves as a connection restricting surface.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The cam groove preferably is displaced to incline the connection restricting surface and the separation restricting surface thereof gradually with respect to the connecting directions of the two housings.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The separation restricting surface of the cam groove preferably engages the cam follower from the front of the first housing at the side of the supporting shaft substantially opposite to the rack and pinion and in a direction inclined with respect to the connecting directions of the two housings.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">An engaged position of the rack and pinion and a position of a supporting shaft to support the lever on the first housing may be distanced from each other in a width direction intersecting the connecting directions of the two housings.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">The cam follower and the cam groove preferably are not engaged yet when the engagement of the rack and the pinion is started.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">The invention also relates to a method of operating a lever-type connector, such as the above-described connector. The method comprises providing a first housing with a lever rotatably mounted thereon, engaging a pinion on the lever with a rack on a second housing, rotating the lever so that the pinion and the rack move the housings toward one another and engaging a cam groove on one of the lever and the second housing with a cam follower on the other of the lever and the second housing for preventing the first housing from being inclined with respect to the second housing.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The method preferably comprises generating leverage between the rack and the pinion through an entire rotational range of the lever, and engaging the cam groove and the cam follower only in a part of the rotational range of the lever, and most preferably from an intermediate position of the rotation of the lever to the completion of the rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">These and other objects, features and advantages of the present invention will become more apparent upon reading of the following detailed description of preferred embodiments and accompanying drawings. It should be understood that even though embodiments are separately described, single features thereof may be combined to additional embodiments.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view showing a state where a first housing and a second housing are separated in one embodiment,</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a plan view showing a state where the first housing and the second housing are lightly connected with a lever held at a standby position,</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view showing a state where the first and second housings are further connected,</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a plan view showing a state where the first and second housings are even more connected,</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a plan view showing a state where the first and second housings are completely connected,</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref> is a side view of the lever,</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref> is a section along X-X of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>,</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> is a plan view of the lever, and</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a front view of the second housing.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A lever-type connector in accordance with the invention includes first and second housings identified generally by the numerals <b>10</b> and <b>30</b> in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The first housing <b>10</b> is a female housing made e.g. of synthetic resin and includes a substantially block-shaped main body <b>11</b>. Female terminal fittings (not shown) having a known form are accommodated in the main body <b>11</b>. Wires (not shown) are connected with the respective female terminal fittings and are drawn out from the wire draw-out surface at the rear of the main body <b>11</b> (upper surface in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>). A wire cover <b>12</b> is mounted on the wire draw-out surface for bending and at least partly covering the wires drawn out from the wire draw-out surface of the main body <b>11</b>. Thus, the wires extend substantially parallel with the wire draw-out surface of the housing main body <b>11</b> and are drawn out sideways. The housing <b>10</b> has a tubular protection wall <b>13</b> that surrounds the main body <b>11</b> over substantially the entire periphery. The protection wall <b>13</b> is connected with the main body <b>11</b> at opposite ends in a width direction, which is at right angles to connecting and separating directions of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>. A forwardly open accommodation space <b>14</b> is defined between the protection wall <b>13</b> and the main body <b>11</b> for accommodating a lever <b>20</b> to be described later and a receptacle <b>32</b> of the second housing <b>30</b>. Rearwardly open slits are formed between the protection wall <b>13</b> and the outer surface (wall surface appearing in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>) of the upper wall of the main body <b>11</b> and between the protection wall <b>13</b> and the outer surface of the lower wall (wall surface hidden in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>) of the main body <b>11</b> to enable arms <b>22</b> of the lever <b>20</b> to be assembled from behind.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Substantially cylindrical supporting shafts <b>15</b> project into the accommodation space <b>14</b> from opposite upper and lower surfaces (surface appearing in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref> and the opposite hidden surface) of the main body <b>11</b>. The supporting shafts <b>15</b> extend substantially orthogonal to the connecting directions of the housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> and define a center of rotation of the lever <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The lever <b>20</b> is mounted rotatably on the first housing <b>10</b>. The lever <b>20</b> is made unitarily e.g. of synthetic resin and has an operable portion <b>21</b> and two vertically symmetrical plate-like arms <b>22</b> that extend substantially parallel with one another from opposite ends of the operable portion <b>21</b>. Substantially concentric circular bearing holes <b>23</b> penetrate the arms <b>22</b>. The bearing holes <b>23</b> engage the supporting shafts <b>15</b> so that the lever <b>20</b> rotatable about the supporting shafts <b>15</b> through a range of about 70&#xb0; between a standby position SP and a connection position CP with the arms <b>22</b> accommodated in the accommodation space <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">The operable portion <b>21</b> is obliquely behind the supporting shafts <b>15</b> when the lever <b>20</b> is at the standby position SP as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. However, the operable portion <b>21</b> can be displaced in the width direction along an arcuate path behind the supporting shafts <b>15</b> to rotate the lever <b>20</b> from the standby position SP to the connection position CP, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>. The operable portion <b>21</b> is at a side of the supporting shafts <b>15</b> opposite the position of the operable portion <b>21</b> at the standby position SP in the width direction when the lever <b>20</b> reaches the connection position CP, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The arms <b>22</b> include two vertically symmetrical pinions <b>24</b>, two substantially vertically symmetrical cam grooves <b>25</b> and two vertically symmetrical plates <b>26</b>. The cam grooves <b>25</b> are formed in the inner surfaces of the arms <b>22</b> so as not to penetrate to the outer surfaces, and are arcuate about the supporting shafts <b>15</b>. The starting end of each cam groove <b>25</b> opens at the outer peripheral edge of the arm <b>22</b> and the cam groove <b>25</b> is formed so that a distance to the supporting shaft <b>15</b> is shortened gradually from the starting end of the cam groove <b>25</b> to the back end thereof. A separating restricting surface <b>27</b> is formed by arcuate surface of the cam groove <b>25</b> distant from the supporting shaft <b>15</b> and a connection restricting surface <b>28</b> is defined by an arcuate surface of the cam groove <b>25</b> close to the supporting shaft <b>15</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The plate <b>26</b> is flat, normal to the supporting shaft <b>15</b>, parallel to a rotational path of the lever <b>20</b> and forms a wall surface of the cam groove <b>25</b> at the outer side. One piece of pinion <b>25</b> projects from the inner surface of the plate <b>26</b>. The pinion <b>24</b> projects along the plate <b>26</b> in a radial direction centered on the supporting shaft <b>15</b>. This pinion <b>24</b> and the cam groove <b>25</b> are arranged at substantially opposite sides of the supporting shaft <b>15</b> in the width direction in the range of substantially the entire rotation range between the standby position SP and the connection position CP of the lever <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">With the lever <b>20</b> at the standby position SP, the pinions <b>24</b> project obliquely forward with the supporting shafts <b>15</b> as centers and the projecting ends of the pinions <b>24</b> are closest to the supporting shafts <b>15</b> in the width direction, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>. Further, the starting ends of the cam grooves <b>25</b> wait on standby while facing forward so as to enable the entry of cam followers <b>37</b> to be described later. The connection restricting surfaces <b>28</b> and the separation restricting surfaces <b>27</b> of the cam grooves <b>25</b> extend substantially parallel to the connecting directions of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">Rotating the lever <b>20</b> from the standby position SP to the connection position CP displaces the pinions <b>24</b> back substantially parallel to the connecting directions of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref>. Further, the cam grooves <b>25</b> are displaced so that the connection restricting surfaces <b>28</b> and the separation restricting surfaces <b>27</b> gradually incline with respect to the connecting directions of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The pinions <b>24</b> are at the rearmost positions in forward and backward directions when the lever <b>20</b> is at the connection position CP shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>. Additionally, the connection restricting surfaces <b>28</b> and the separation restricting surfaces <b>27</b> of the cam grooves <b>25</b> are inclined to maximize angles to the connecting and separating directions of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">The second housing <b>30</b> is made unitarily e.g. of synthetic resin and has a wide substantially block-shaped terminal accommodating portion <b>31</b>. The receptacle <b>32</b> is a rectangular tube that projects forward (up in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>) from the terminal accommodating portion <b>31</b>. Unillustrated male terminal fittings having a known form are mounted in the terminal accommodating portion <b>31</b> and tabs at the front ends of the respective male terminal fittings project from the front surface of the terminal accommodating portion <b>31</b> to be surrounded in the receptacle <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">Racks <b>33</b> are formed symmetrically on the upper surface of the upper wall and the lower surface of the lower wall of the receptacle <b>32</b>. The racks <b>33</b> are displaced laterally from the center of the second housing <b>30</b> in the width direction and in the same direction as the displacing direction of the pinions <b>24</b> with respect to the supporting shafts <b>15</b>. The racks <b>33</b> have grooves <b>34</b> that open laterally toward the widthwise center substantially orthogonal to the connecting and separating directions of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>. A connection contact surface <b>35</b> is defined at the front of each groove <b>34</b> (upper surface in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 1 to 5</figref>) and a separation contact surface <b>36</b> is defined at the rear of each groove <b>34</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Substantially cylindrical cam followers <b>37</b> project from the upper surface of the upper wall and the lower surface of the lower wall of the receptacle <b>32</b> so that their axes are aligned vertically and substantially parallel with the axes of the supporting shafts <b>15</b>. The cam followers <b>37</b> are displaced toward a side of the center of the second housing <b>30</b> substantially opposite to the racks <b>33</b> in the width direction (i.e. at positions displaced toward the same side as the cam grooves <b>25</b> are displaced from the supporting shafts <b>15</b>). Thus, the cam followers <b>37</b> are at positions to face the openings of the starting ends of the cam grooves <b>25</b> when the lever <b>20</b> is at the standby position SP.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Upon connecting the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>, locking holes <b>29</b> extending in at positions of the arms <b>22</b> near the operable portion <b>21</b> are engaged with first stoppers <b>16</b> formed on the opposite upper and lower surfaces of the first housing <b>10</b> to hold the lever <b>20</b> at the standby position SP. The first housing <b>10</b> then is fit lightly into the receptacle <b>32</b> of the second housing <b>30</b> in this state. Thus, the upper and lower walls of the receptacle <b>32</b> are inserted into clearances between the housing main body <b>11</b> and the arms <b>22</b> in the accommodation space <b>14</b>. Further, the pinions <b>24</b> do not yet engage the racks <b>33</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> do not yet engage the cam grooves <b>25</b> when the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> are connected lightly with each other, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Thereafter, the lever <b>20</b> is rotated toward the connection position CP by operating (e.g. gripping) the operable portion <b>21</b>. As a result, the pinions <b>24</b> engage the edges of the connection contact surfaces <b>35</b> of the racks <b>33</b> at opening sides, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> and exhibit a lever action. This lever action between the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> pulls the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> toward each other. The cam followers <b>37</b> and the cam grooves <b>25</b> are not engaged yet when the engagement of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> is started.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Further rotation of the lever <b>20</b> causes the cam followers <b>37</b> to enter the starting ends of the cam grooves <b>25</b> while the pinions <b>24</b> and the racks <b>33</b> remain engaged as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. The connecting operation of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> then proceeds further due to the leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> and cam action brought about by the cam followers <b>37</b> and the cam grooves <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">The leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> while connecting the housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> pushes the supporting shafts <b>15</b> forward of the first housing <b>10</b> with the engaged positions of the pinions <b>24</b> and the racks <b>33</b> as supports. Thus, the first housing <b>10</b> is displaced forward toward the second housing <b>30</b>. The engaged positions of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> and the positions of the supporting shafts <b>15</b> are offset from each other in the width direction, which intersects the connecting directions of the housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>. Thus, the first housing <b>10</b> may be inclined to displace the supporting shafts <b>15</b> forward with respect to the second housing <b>30</b> with the engaged positions of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> as the supports. However, the connection restricting surfaces <b>28</b> of the cam grooves <b>25</b> engage the cam followers <b>37</b> from an oblique rear side of the first housing <b>10</b> at the side of the supporting shafts <b>15</b> opposite to the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> in the width direction. This engagement produces a cam action that prevents inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">Frictional resistance between the terminal fittings could act to incline the first housing <b>10</b> in a direction to displace the supporting shafts <b>15</b> backward with respect to the second housing <b>30</b> with the engaged positions of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> as the supports. However, the separation restricting surfaces <b>27</b> facing the connection restricting surfaces <b>28</b> engage the cam followers <b>37</b> from an oblique front side of the first housing <b>10</b>. This engagement produces a cam action that prevents inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">As described above, the leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> during the connecting operation can create a force to incline the first housing <b>10</b> with respect to the second housing <b>30</b>. However, the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> produces a force to correct the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>. Thus, the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b> is substantially prevented and the housings <b>10</b> and <b>30</b> are connected while being aligned properly to each other. Accordingly, the connection process is made more smooth thus increasing overall operability. The cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> continues until the lever <b>20</b> reaches a connection ending position.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> are connected properly when the lever <b>20</b> reaches the connection position CP shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> so that the male and female terminal fittings are connected electrically. At this time, the locking holes <b>29</b> engage the second stoppers <b>17</b> on the first housing <b>10</b> to hold the lever <b>20</b> at the connection position CP. Further, the cam followers <b>37</b> engage the back ends of the cam grooves <b>25</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">The operating portion <b>21</b> of the lever <b>20</b> can be gripped to rotate the lever <b>20</b> from the connection position CP to the standby position SP for separating the two properly connected housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>. This rotating process causes the pinions <b>24</b> to engage the separation contact surfaces <b>36</b> of the racks <b>33</b> and produces a leverage. Additionally, the engagement of the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> produces a cam action. The leverage and the cam action separate the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">The leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> while separating the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> pushes the supporting shafts <b>15</b> backward of the first housing <b>10</b> with the engaged positions of the pinions <b>24</b> and the racks <b>33</b> as the supports. As a result, the first housing <b>10</b> is displaced back and separated from the second housing <b>30</b>. However, the supporting shafts <b>15</b> are offset in the width direction from the engaged positions of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b>. Thus, the first housing <b>10</b> may be inclined to displace the supporting shafts <b>15</b> backward with respect to the second housing <b>30</b> with the engaged positions of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> as the supports. However, the separation restricting surfaces <b>27</b> of the cam grooves <b>25</b> engage the cam followers <b>37</b> from the oblique front side of the first housing <b>10</b> at the side of the supporting shafts <b>15</b> substantially opposite to the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> in the width direction. This engagement generates a cam action that prevents the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Frictional resistance between the terminal fittings may act to incline the first housing <b>10</b> in a direction to displace the supporting shafts <b>15</b> forward with respect to the second housing <b>30</b> with the engaged positions of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> as the supports. However, the connection restricting surfaces <b>28</b> engage the cam followers <b>37</b> from the oblique rear side of the first housing <b>10</b>. This engagement produces a cam action that prevents the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> during the separating operation can create forces that act to incline the first housing <b>10</b> with respect to the second housing <b>30</b>. However, the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> corrects the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>. Thus, the first housing <b>10</b> will not incline relative to the second housing <b>30</b>, and the housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> will separate in a proper alignment.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As described above, the connection of the first and second housings <b>10</b> and <b>30</b> is assisted by the leverage of the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b>, which engage at positions offset from the center of rotation of the lever <b>20</b> (supporting shafts <b>15</b>) in the width direction. Thus, the first housing <b>10</b> may incline. However, the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> is exhibited in a lateral region at the side of the supporting shafts <b>15</b> opposite to the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> and this cam action prevents the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b>. Thus, the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> can be connected while being aligned properly.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">The cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> preferably continues until a final stage in the rotational range of the lever <b>20</b>, i.e. until the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> reach a properly connected state. Accordingly, the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> align properly until the connecting operation is completed.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">As an alternative to the above-described operation, thought has been given to a connecting operation that alternately exhibits leverage by engaging the racks <b>33</b> and the pinions <b>24</b> and the cam action by engaging the cam grooves <b>25</b> and the cam followers <b>37</b> in the process of connecting the housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b>. Even in this case, the connecting operation proceeds while the inclination of the first housing <b>10</b> is corrected. Thus, the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> can be connected while being aligned.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">The lever-type connector requires the assembly of plural parts that are relatively movable. Thus, clearances must exist between the parts in an assembled state due to dimensional tolerances of the parts and assembling tolerances between the parts. Accordingly, exhibiting the leverage and the cam action sequentially instead of simultaneously may produce moments when neither the leverage nor the cam action is exhibited in the process of rotating the lever <b>20</b>. In this case, the connecting operation of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> stops even though the lever <b>20</b> is rotated. To avoid this, dimensional accuracy has to be improved by reducing tolerances, which results in a difficult design. However, the leverage and the cam action are exhibited simultaneously in the process of rotating the lever <b>20</b> in the preferred embodiment. Thus, there is no situation where the connecting operation of the two housings <b>10</b>, <b>30</b> does not proceed despite the rotation of the lever <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The invention is not limited to the above described and illustrated embodiment. For example, the following embodiments are also embraced by the technical scope of the present invention as defined by the claims.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">The leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks and the pinions and the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves and the cam followers are exhibited at the final stage of the rotation of the lever in the above embodiment. However, either one of the leverage and the cam action may be exhibited in the entire rotational range of the lever, and the other may be exhibited only in a partial rotational range from the middle of the rotation of the lever to the completion of the rotation. Alternatively, one of the leverage and the cam action may be exhibited in the entire rotational range of the lever, and the other may be exhibited only in a partial rotational range from the start of the rotation of the lever to the completion of the rotation. Still further, either one of the leverage and the cam action may exhibited in a partial rotational range from the start of the rotation of the lever to the completion of the rotation, and the other is exhibited only in a partial rotational range from a position before the one of the leverage and the cam action is completed during the rotation of the lever to the completion of the rotation.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">In the above embodiment, the leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks and the pinions is exhibited in the entire rotational range of the lever and the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves and the cam followers is exhibited only in a part of the rotational range of the lever. However, both the leverage brought about by the engagement of the racks and the pinions and the cam action brought about by the engagement of the cam grooves and the cam followers may be exhibited in the entire rotational region from the start to the end of the rotation of the lever.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">Although the first housing mounted with the lever is a female housing and the second housing is a male housing including the receptacle in the above embodiment, the invention also is applicable in the case where the second housing is a female housing and the first housing is a male housing including a receptacle.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">The cam grooves are formed in the lever and the cam followers are formed on the second housing in the above embodiment. However, the cam followers may be formed on the lever and the cam grooves may be formed in the second housing.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A lever-type connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a first housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lever mounted rotatably on the first housing, the lever including at least one pinion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second housing connectable with the first housing and including at least one rack, the pinion engaging the rack so that rotating the lever produces forces between the rack and the pinion for connecting the first and second housings; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>one of the lever and the second housing being formed with at least one cam groove and the other of the lever and the second housing being formed with at least one cam follower, the cam groove and the cam follower being engaged in the process of rotating the lever for preventing the first housing from being inclined with respect to the second housing about an engaged position of the pinion and the rack.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein:
<claim-text>leverage brought about by the engagement of the rack and the pinion is exhibited in an entire rotational range of the lever, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>cam action between the cam groove and the cam follower is exhibited only in a part of the rotational range of the lever from an intermediate rotational position of the lever to completion of the rotation.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cam groove is formed in an arm of the lever without fully penetrating the arm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first housing includes a supporting shaft, the lever being mounted rotatably on the supporting shaft, an arcuate separation restricting surface being defined in a portion of the cam groove distant from the supporting shaft and an arcuate connection restricting surface being defined in a portion of the cam groove closer than the separation restricting surface to the supporting shaft and opposed to the separation restricting surface.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the cam groove is displaced to incline the connection restricting surface and the separation restricting surface gradually with respect to the connecting directions of the two housings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein the separation restricting surface of the cam groove engages the cam follower obliquely from a front side of the first housing at a side of the supporting shaft substantially opposite to the rack and the pinion in a direction inclined with respect to connecting directions of the housings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00004">claim 4</claim-ref>, wherein an engaged position of the rack and the pinion and a position of a supporting shaft to support the lever on the first housing are offset from each other in a width direction intersecting with connecting directions of the housings.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cam follower and the cam groove are not engaged yet when engagement of the rack and the pinion is started.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. A lever-type connector, comprising:
<claim-text>a first housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lever mounted on the first housing for rotation about a rotational axis, at least one pinion formed on the lever at a location spaced from the rotational axis, at least one cam groove formed in the lever at a location spaced from rotational axis and from the pinion so that the rotational axis is between the pinion and at least part of the cam groove;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second housing connectable with the first housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one rack disposed on the second housing at a position for engagement by the pinion so that rotating the lever produces forces between the rack and the pinion for connecting the first and second housings; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one cam follower disposed on the second housing at a position for engaging the cam groove during a portion of the rotation of the lever, engagement of the cam follower with the cam groove preventing the first housing from being inclined with respect to the second housing about an engaged position of the pinion and the rack.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the pinion is offset to a first side of the rotational axis with respect to a connecting direction of the first and second housings and wherein the cam follower is offset to a second side of the rotational axis with respect to the rotational direction.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The lever-type connector of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref>, wherein the cam follower engages the cam groove after the pinion engages the rack.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. A method of connecting and separating a lever-type connector, comprising the following steps:
<claim-text>providing a first housing with a lever rotatably mounted thereon;</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a second housing for connection with the first housing so that a pinion on the lever is aligned for engaging a rack on the second housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>rotating the lever so that the pinion on the lever engages the rack on the second housing for moving the first and second housings toward one another; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>engaging a cam groove on one of the lever and the second housing with a cam follower on the other of the lever and the second housing for preventing the first housing from being inclined with respect to the second housing about an engaged position of the pinion and the rack.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the step of engaging the rack and the pinion continues through an entire rotational range of the lever, and wherein the step of engaging the cam groove and the cam follower continues through only a part of the rotational range of the lever from an intermediate position to completion of the rotation.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
