<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641776-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641776</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11078179</doc-number>
<date>20050310</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>926</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>21</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>5</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>20429701</main-classification>
<further-classification>20429707</further-classification>
<further-classification>20429708</further-classification>
<further-classification>205157</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">System and method for increasing yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6242337</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Okada</name>
<date>20010600</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>438622</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7294243</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Zimmerman et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204224 R</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>20429701</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>20429707</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>20429708</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205157</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>3</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060201802</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060914</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Nagar</last-name>
<first-name>Mohan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Shah</last-name>
<first-name>Shirish</first-name>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Cochran</last-name>
<first-name>William W.</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
<agent sequence="02" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Cochran Freund &#x26; Young LLC</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>LSI Corporation</orgname>
<role>02</role>
<address>
<city>Milpitas</city>
<state>CA</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Wilkins</last-name>
<first-name>Harry</first-name>
<department>1795</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Mendez</last-name>
<first-name>Zulmariam</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A system and method increase yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating. The aspects include a semiconductor wafer, the semiconductor wafer comprising a plurality of die areas. A plating ring for holding the semiconductor wafer in position during electroplating is also included, the plating ring substantially surrounding a circumference of the semiconductor wafer and having a width that varies in order to avoid overlap near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="124.29mm" wi="179.66mm" file="US07641776-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="249.51mm" wi="184.32mm" file="US07641776-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="261.20mm" wi="180.51mm" file="US07641776-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="156.80mm" wi="162.56mm" file="US07641776-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present invention relates to semiconductor wafer electroplating processes, and more particularly to increasing die yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating processes.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">As is commonly understood in the art, the fabrication of microcircuits requires the precise positioning of a number of appropriately doped regions in a semiconductor wafer, followed by effectuation of one or more interconnection patterns. These appropriately doped regions typically include a variety of diffusions and implants, cuts for metallizations and gates, and areas by which connections can be made to bonding pads. For each of these regions a sequence of steps is required, together with a specific pattern layout.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">A common method of patterning heretofore has involved a photolithographic transfer followed by etching. As is well known to those skilled in the art, photolithography effects transfer of a desired pattern onto the surface of a silicon wafer by selectively allowing light to strike a thin film of photosensitive material coated on the wafer, certain of which material can then be locally removed based upon its solubility, changed or unchanged, after exposure to the light. Removal of material from areas unprotected by the photosensitive material or &#x201c;photoresist&#x201d; is accomplished in an etching step. The etching processes used in integrated circuit (&#x201c;IC&#x201d;) fabrication can take place either in a liquid (&#x201c;wet etching&#x201d;) or gas (&#x201c;dry etching&#x201d;) phase. These processes can also be purely physical (e.g., wherein material is removed by bombardment which high-energy ions), purely chemical (e.g., wherein material is removed by dissolution), or a combination of both (e.g., wherein material is removed by bombardment with reactive ions which also react chemically with the etched material). Recognizing that all etching processes may be characterized by their selectivity (i.e., in materials attacked by the etching agent) and degree of anisotropy (i.e., etching in one direction only, as opposed to isotropic etching, wherein material is removed at the same rate in all directions), it should be appreciated that all etching processes involve some degree of compromise in selectivity, anisotropy, or both selectivity and anisotropy.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">As it has become desired to create increasingly accurate and dense pattern geometries, those skilled in the art have searched for methods of patterning that lack the &#x201c;bias-type&#x201d; compromises of etching processes. One such method that has been developed is electroplating, that is, the electrodeposition of an adherent coating upon an object. One of the advantages of additive patterning approaches, such as pattern electroforming, over subtractive methods, such as etching, that has been discovered is that very little bias in dimension occurs with electroforming and therefore very accurate and dense geometries can be fabricated.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">One of the patterning processes that has evolved to employ electroplating techniques is flip-chip processing. In order to help ensure proper performance during the electroplating, positioning of the wafer involves securing the wafer in position during the processing. In the standard approaches, a metal plating ring the circumference of a wafer and is used to help secure the wafer in position during the electroplating. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>illustrates a representation of a top view of an example of a standard wafer <b>100</b>, while <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b </i>illustrates a standard plating ring <b>110</b> that surrounds the wafer <b>100</b>. When positioned within the plating ring <b>110</b>, there is some amount of overlap by the plating ring <b>110</b> on the outside edge of the wafer <b>100</b>. Such overlapping can adversely affect the plating process. For example, in flip-chip processing, the formation of the solder bumps is adversely affected, including causing defects in the form of missing bumps, small bumps, and deformed bumps. These defects are seen most often in the areas of the corner dies <b>130</b> (individual die areas being represented by squares in the figures). As a result of these problems, the affected dies are unusable and yield loss is incurred on every wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">Accordingly, a need exists for a system and method of increasing die yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating. The present invention meets such a need.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Aspects of a system and method for increasing yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating are described. The aspects include a semiconductor wafer, the semiconductor wafer comprising a plurality of die areas. A plating ring for holding the semiconductor wafer in position during electroplating is also included, the plating ring substantially surrounding a circumference of the semiconductor wafer and having a width that varies in order to avoid overlap near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Through the present invention, a plating ring with a plurality of portions having less than a maximum ring width is provided. With the positioning of the plating ring such that overlap near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer is avoided, potential for defects on the edge dies is reduced. In this manner, yield loss problems associated with the edge dies are addressed in a straightforward and effective approach.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a </i>illustrates a top view of an example of a standard wafer.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b </i>illustrates a standard plating ring surrounding the wafer of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>a. </i></p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a </i>and <b>2</b><i>b </i>illustrate two embodiments of a plating ring in accordance with the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a table of steps for standard and selective process flows that utilize electroplating in which the plating ring of the present invention can find application.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">The present invention relates to increasing die yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating processes. The following description is presented to enable one of ordinary skill in the art to make and use the invention and is provided in the context of a patent application and its requirements. Various modifications to the preferred embodiments and the generic principles and features described herein will be readily apparent to those skilled in the art. Thus, the present invention is not intended to be limited to the embodiments shown, but is to be accorded the widest scope consistent with the principles and features described herein.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">In accordance with the present invention, a plating ring for use during electroplating processing for wafer bumping is provided that reduces the number of defects in edge dies on the wafer and thus increases yield. In a preferred embodiment, the plating ring of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref><i>b </i>is altered to reduce the deleterious impact on the dies of the wafer. Typically, the plating ring <b>110</b> has a width of about 5 mm (millimeters), while the wafer <b>100</b> includes an outside edge <b>120</b> of about 3 mm. The alteration performed is to vary the width of the ring from about 5 mm to about 3 mm along portions of the ring. The reduction in width can be achieved through any desired and appropriate techniques, e.g., by simply cutting out about 2 mm from a standard width ring, as is well understood in the art. The width provided in the altered ring maintains the ability to support the edge of the wafer but overlaps less deeply on the wafer near the edge dies in order to avoid bump defects on those dies. Examples of alternate embodiments of the altered ring are presented in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 2</figref><i>a </i>and <b>2</b><i>b. </i></p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>, a plating ring <b>200</b> has a reduced width at portions <b>202</b>, <b>204</b>, <b>206</b>, <b>208</b> corresponding to the edge areas at a top-most, bottom-most, left-most and right-most sections of the wafer <b>210</b>. As shown, the reduced width at the indicated portions runs a length, l, that substantially corresponds with the distance spanned by the dies on that section of the wafer <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>, the plating ring <b>212</b> has a reduced width at portions <b>214</b>, <b>216</b>, <b>218</b>, <b>220</b>, <b>222</b>, <b>224</b>, <b>226</b>, and <b>228</b> corresponding to the edge areas at the top-most, bottom-most, left-most and right-most sections of the wafer <b>210</b>, as well as portions approximately half-way between these sections. The greater number of portions of reduced width in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b</i>, as compared with <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>a</i>, allows the portions of reduced width in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref><i>b </i>to run a shorter length, l&#x2032;.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">In the use of electroplating for flip-chip processing, less defects in the form of missing bumps, small bumps, and deformed bumps result. By way of example, referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a table <b>300</b> is provided listing the steps of flip-chip processing flows during which electroplating is used. The right-hand side of the table provides steps of a typical selective process, while the left-hand side provides steps of a standard process, as is well appreciated by those skilled in the art. By reducing the ring width near edge dies on a wafer in accordance with the present invention, overlap near those dies is reduced during plating steps in the processing flows. In this manner, potential for defects on those dies during electroplating is lessened, and yield loss problems are addressed in a straightforward and effective approach.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Although the present invention has been described in accordance with the embodiments shown, one of ordinary skill in the art will readily recognize that there could be variations to the embodiments and those variations would be within the spirit and scope of the present invention. Accordingly, many modifications may be made by one of ordinary skill in the art without departing from the spirit and scope of the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>We claim:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A system for increasing yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating, the system comprising:
<claim-text>a plating ring for holding a semiconductor wafer in position during electroplating, the semiconductor wafer comprising a plurality of die areas, the plating ring substantially surrounding a circumference of the semiconductor wafer and overlapping an outside edge of the semiconductor wafer when the semiconductor wafer is positioned within the plating ring, the plating ring having a width that varies, the width narrowing near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer to reduce overlap by the plating ring near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer when the semiconductor wafer is positioned within the plating ring.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the plating ring further comprises a plurality of portions having less than a maximum ring width.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of portions further comprises four portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref> wherein the four portions avoid overlap with edge die areas on a top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most section of the semiconductor wafer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of portions further comprises eight portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00005">claim 5</claim-ref> wherein the eight portions avoid overlap with edge die areas on a top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most section of the semiconductor wafer, as well as edge die areas on sections approximately half-way between the top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The system of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref> wherein the plating ring has a width that varies between approximately 5 millimeters and approximately 3 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. A method for increasing yield from semiconductor wafer electroplating, the method comprising:
<claim-text>providing a plating ring with a plurality of portions having less than a maximum ring width; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>utilizing the plating ring for holding a semiconductor wafer in position during electroplating, the plating ring substantially surrounding a circumference of the semiconductor wafer and overlapping an outside edge of the semiconductor wafer when the semiconductor wafer is positioned within the plating ring during electroplating, the plurality of portions positioned near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer to reduce overlap by the plating ring near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer when the semiconductor wafer is positioned within the plating ring during electroplating.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of portions further comprises four portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00009">claim 9</claim-ref> wherein the four portions avoid overlap with edge die areas on a top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of portions further comprises eight portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref> wherein the eight portions avoid overlap with edge die areas on a top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer, as well as edge die areas on sections approximately half-way between the top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref> wherein the maximum width further comprises a width of approximately 5 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref> wherein each of the plurality of portions comprises a width of approximately 3 millimeters.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. An apparatus for use in holding a semiconductor wafer in position during electroplating, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a plating ring having a plurality of reduced width portions, the plating ring substantially surrounding a circumference of a semiconductor wafer and overlapping an outside edge of the semiconductor wafer when the semiconductor wafer is positioned within the plating ring, the plurality of reduced width portions positioned to reduce overlap by the plating ring near edge die areas of the semiconductor wafer when the semiconductor wafer is positioned within the plating ring to increase die yield.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of reduced width portions further comprises four portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref> wherein the four portions avoid overlap with edge die areas on a top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein the plurality of reduced width portions further comprises eight portions.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref> wherein the eight portions avoid overlap with edge die areas on a top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer, as well as edge die areas on sections approximately half-way between the top-most, bottom-most, left-most, and right-most sections of the semiconductor wafer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The apparatus of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref> wherein each of the plurality of reduced width portions comprises a width of approximately 3 millimeters. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
