<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641775-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641775</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11330517</doc-number>
<date>20060111</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2005-0003049</doc-number>
<date>20050112</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>755</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>25</class>
<subclass>D</subclass>
<main-group>17</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204202</main-classification>
<further-classification>204206</further-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e71">Apparatus for manufacturing electrolytic metal foil</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>3619400</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Eisner</name>
<date>19711100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>204216</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4073699</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Hutkin</name>
<date>19780200</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205 50</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4686016</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Held</name>
<date>19870800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205132</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5236572</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Lam et al.</name>
<date>19930800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205 75</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6153077</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Kato et al.</name>
<date>20001100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>205 77</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00006">
<document-id>
<country>JP</country>
<doc-number>56-139689</doc-number>
<date>19811000</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>7</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204199</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204202</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>204206</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205 67</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205 76</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205 77</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>205138</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>5</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>5</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20060151315</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20060713</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yang</last-name>
<first-name>Jin-Kyu</first-name>
<address>
<city>Gyeonggi-do</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoon</last-name>
<first-name>Yoea-Sang</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yoon</last-name>
<first-name>Jong-Seo</first-name>
<address>
<city>Seoul</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Jones Day</orgname>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>LS Mtron Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Anyang</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Nguyen</last-name>
<first-name>Nam X</first-name>
<department>1795</department>
</primary-examiner>
<assistant-examiner>
<last-name>Van</last-name>
<first-name>Luan V</first-name>
</assistant-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">Disclosed is an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil, which includes an electrolytic cell containing electrolyte; an upper drum installed in an upper portion of the electrolytic cell to be rotatable and to which a negative potential is applied; a lower drum soaked in the electrolyte of the electrolytic cell and installed to be rotatable together with the upper drum; a cathode belt mounted around outer circumferences of the upper and lower drums to move along an endless track and electrically connected to the upper drum so that the negative potential is applied thereto; and an anode unit installed to form a space from a metal electroplating surface of the cathode belt soaked in the electrolytic cell so that a positive potential is applied thereto, the anode unit having a slit for supplying the electrolytic to the space. This apparatus may increase a production rate of electrolytic metal foils.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="142.83mm" wi="224.96mm" file="US07641775-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="120.99mm" wi="154.86mm" file="US07641775-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="162.39mm" wi="129.71mm" file="US07641775-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="140.80mm" wi="130.22mm" file="US07641775-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="214.21mm" wi="123.27mm" file="US07641775-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="144.19mm" wi="97.87mm" file="US07641775-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil, and more particularly to an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil, which may increase an electroplating area in making a metal foil using an electrolytic manner.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">2. Description of the Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">A copper foil, a kind of electrolytic metal foil, is a basic element used for a printed circuit board (PCB) of electronic parts, and it is generally made using electrolysis. The copper foil made by electrolysis has good purity of electroplated substances though using a cheap electrolyte, and gives uniform thickness over a wide area.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> shows a conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device. Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>, the conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device includes an electrolytic cell <b>10</b> containing electrolyte <b>11</b>, a cathode drum <b>20</b> partially soaked in the electrolytic cell <b>10</b>, and an anode unit <b>50</b> installed around the cathode drum <b>20</b> with a space therefrom. The anode unit <b>50</b> has a slit <b>51</b> so that the electrolyte <b>11</b> is supplied to the spaced area between the anode unit <b>50</b> and the cathode drum <b>20</b> through the slit <b>51</b>. The conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device is connected to a power source <b>1</b>. In more detail, the cathode drum <b>20</b> is connected to a negative pole of the power source <b>1</b>, and the anode unit <b>50</b> is connected to a positive pole of the power source <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">With the cathode drum <b>20</b> and the anode unit <b>50</b> being connected to the power source <b>1</b> as mentioned above, if the device starts operation, the cathode drum <b>20</b> rotates at a constant speed, and metal ions in the electrolyte <b>11</b> is electroplated on the cathode drum <b>20</b> soaked in the electrolyte <b>11</b>. Electroplated substances <b>2</b> formed as mentioned above are moved upward above the surface of the electrolyte along with the rotation of the cathode drum <b>20</b>. After that, the electroplated substances <b>2</b> are separated from the cathode drum <b>20</b> by means of a separating roll <b>60</b>, and taken up by a take-up drum <b>70</b> installed out of the electrolytic cell <b>10</b> to complete an electrolytic metal foil <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In the conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device, in order to increase a production rate of electrolytic metal foils, it may be considered that an electroplating amount should be increased by raising the density of current applied to the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device, or that an electroplating area of the cathode drum <b>20</b> is enlarged to increase an electroplating rate. However, it is impossible to increase the density of current without a limit due to the structure of the device, and also a copper foil made by applying a high density of current has inferior quality. Thus, the way of enlarging an electroplating area of the cathode drum <b>20</b> should be considered. However, if a diameter of the cathode drum <b>20</b> is increased to enlarge the electroplating area of the cathode drum <b>20</b>, the entire size of the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device is increased too much, thereby deteriorating the efficiency of space utilization, and also the cost of the device is increased.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">The present invention is designed to solve the problems of the prior art, and therefore it is an object of the present invention to provide an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil, which may increase a production rate of electrolytic metal foils by enlarging an electroplating area of electrolyte without increasing an area occupied by the apparatus under the same density of current.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">In order to accomplish the above object, the present invention provides an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil, which includes an electrolytic cell containing electrolyte; an upper drum installed in an upper portion of the electrolytic cell to be rotatable and to which a negative (&#x2212;) electric potential is applied; a lower drum soaked in the electrolyte of the electrolytic cell and installed to be rotatable together with the upper drum; a cathode belt mounted around outer circumferences of the upper and lower drums to move along an endless track and electrically connected to the upper drum so that the negative (&#x2212;) electric potential is applied thereto; and an anode unit installed to form a space from a metal electroplating surface of the cathode belt soaked in the electrolytic cell so that a positive (+) electric potential is applied thereto, the anode unit having a slit for supplying the electrolytic to the space.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Preferably, the upper drum is made of conductive titanium, and the lower drum is made of non-conductive ebonite. In addition, the cathode belt may have a thickness of 1 to 3 mm.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to the present invention may further include a fixing member successively coupled to an entire side end of the cathode belt and slidably contacted with sides of the upper and lower drums.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">Preferably, the fixing member is made of non-conductive material, and the fixing member has a section of a &#x2018;&#x2282;&#x2019; shape to surround a side of the cathode belt.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">In addition, the apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil may further include an O-ring interposed in a concave groove formed at a border between the fixing member and an electroplated metal electroplated on the cathode belt. In this case, the apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to the present invention may further include a first roller for guiding the O-ring to be successively inserted into the concave groove before the cathode belt is soaked in the electrolyte; and a second roller for guiding the O-ring to be successively departed from the concave groove when the cathode belt moves up above a surface of the electrolyte.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">Meanwhile, the apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil may further include a separating roll installed out of the electrolytic cell to separate the metal electroplated on the cathode belt from the cathode belt; and a take-up drum for taking up the separated electrolytic metal foil.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">Other objects and aspects of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of embodiments with reference to the accompanying drawing in which:</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a sectional view showing a conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device;</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional view schematically showing an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a sectional view schematically showing an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to another embodiment of the present invention;</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial perspective view showing a cathode belt employed in the apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to the present invention; and</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional view taken along the line V-V&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">Hereinafter, preferred embodiments of the present invention will be described in detail referring to the accompanying drawings. Prior to the description, it should be understood that the terms used in the specification and appended claims should not be construed as limited to general and dictionary meanings, but interpreted based on the meanings and concepts corresponding to technical aspects of the present invention on the basis of the principle that the inventor is allowed to define terms appropriately for the best explanation. Therefore, the description proposed herein is just a preferable example for the purpose of illustrations only, not intended to limit the scope of the invention, so it should be understood that other equivalents and modifications could be made thereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a sectional view showing an apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, the apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to this embodiment includes an electrolytic cell <b>110</b>, an upper drum <b>120</b> installed in an upper portion of the electrolytic cell <b>110</b>, a lower drum <b>130</b> installed in the electrolytic cell <b>110</b>, a cathode belt <b>140</b> connecting outer circumferences of the upper drum <b>120</b> and the lower drum <b>130</b>, and an anode unit <b>150</b> installed around the cathode belt <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The electrolytic cell <b>110</b> contains electrolyte <b>111</b> and gives an area where electrolytic action arises. In addition, the electrolytic cell <b>110</b> has a case shape with an open upper end so that an electrolytic metal foil formed by electrolytic action may be extracted out.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The electrolyte <b>111</b> contains metal ions, it is electrolyzed when current is applied to the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus. In case the apparatus of the present invention is used for manufacturing an electrolytic copper foil that is a kind of electrolytic metal foil, the electrolytic copper foil is made by electroplating copper, so the electrolyte <b>111</b> uses a copper ion-contained solution that is mixed with an acid solution. For example, acid copper sulfate solution that is a mixture of copper sulfate solution (CuSO<sub>4</sub>, 5H<sub>2</sub>O) and sulphuric acid, or acid copper chloride solution that is a mixture of copper chloride (CuCl<sub>2</sub>) and hydrochloric acid is used. However, the electrolyte to be used for manufacture of an electrolytic copper foil is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Meanwhile, the kind of electrolyte usable in the apparatus of the present invention is varied depending on a final product. Those with ordinary skill in the art may easily select and use any kind of electrolyte conforming to a metal foil to be manufactured.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">The upper drum <b>120</b> is installed in the upper portion of the electrolytic cell <b>110</b> to be rotatable on a rotary shaft <b>121</b> without being soaked in the electrolyte <b>111</b>, and it is connected to a negative pole of the power source <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Preferably, the upper drum <b>120</b> is made of conductive titanium that allows flow of electric current and has strong corrosion resistance. However, the present invention is not limited to the above case, and various materials may be used within the scope of the invention by those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">The lower drum <b>130</b> is installed to rotate on a rotary shaft <b>131</b> with being soaked in the electrolyte <b>111</b> contained in the electrolytic cell <b>110</b>. The lower drum <b>130</b> is not connected to the power source, differently from the upper drum <b>120</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">Preferably, the lower drum <b>130</b> is made of non-conductive ebonite. However, the present invention is not limited to the above case, and various materials may be used within the scope of the invention by those skilled in the art.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The cathode belt <b>140</b> is mounted to an upper circumference of the upper drum <b>120</b> and a lower circumference of the lower drum <b>130</b> so as to form an endless track in contact with the outer circumferences of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>. In this embodiment, the cathode belt <b>140</b> moves along an endless track by a driving force of the upper drum <b>120</b>, and also the cathode belt <b>140</b> transmits a rotating force to the lower drum <b>130</b>. As an alternative, the endless track movement of the cathode belt <b>140</b> may also be dragged by means of a rotating force of the lower drum <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">While the cathode belt <b>140</b> makes an endless track movement, the cathode belt <b>140</b> is partially soaked in the electrolyte <b>111</b> successively. In addition, since the negative (&#x2212;) pole of the power source <b>1</b> is connected to the upper drum <b>120</b> as mentioned above, the cathode belt <b>140</b> rotating in contact with the upper drum <b>120</b> shows a negative (&#x2212;) electric potential.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">The cathode belt <b>140</b> preferably has a thickness of 1 to 3 mm so as to easily move along an endless track around the outer circumferences of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">The anode unit <b>150</b> is installed adjacent to a portion of the cathode belt <b>140</b> that is soaked in the electrolyte <b>111</b>. More particularly, the anode unit <b>150</b> faces the cathode belt <b>140</b> but is spaced apart from the cathode belt <b>140</b> by a predetermined distance. Thus, a space <b>112</b> is formed between the cathode belt <b>140</b> and the anode unit <b>150</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">In addition, a slit <b>151</b> is provided to the anode unit <b>150</b> so that the electrolyte <b>111</b> contained in the electrolytic cell <b>110</b> may be introduced into the space <b>112</b> between the anode unit <b>150</b> and the cathode belt <b>140</b>. Preferably, a plurality of slits <b>151</b> are prepared to facilitate better supply of electrolyte. The anode <b>150</b> shows a positive (+) electric potential in connection with the positive pole of the power source <b>1</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">If the negative (&#x2212;) potential is formed in the cathode belt <b>140</b> and the positive (+) potential is formed in the anode unit <b>150</b> as mentioned above, electric current flows in the space <b>112</b> between the cathode belt <b>140</b> and the anode unit <b>150</b>, and an electrolytic action arises on the surface of the cathode belt <b>140</b>. That is to say, on the surface of the cathode belt <b>140</b>, positive metal ions existing in the electrolyte <b>111</b> are restored and electroplated on the cathode belt <b>140</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">The electroplated substances <b>2</b> electroplated as mentioned above are separated from the cathode belt <b>140</b> and then become an electrolytic metal foil. For this purpose, the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus of the present invention further includes a separating roll <b>160</b>, and a take-up drum <b>170</b> installed out of the electrolytic cell <b>110</b> to be rotatable. The electroplated substances <b>2</b> are separated from the cathode belt <b>140</b> by means of the separating roll <b>160</b>, and then dried while being transferred to the take-up drum <b>170</b>. After that, the electroplated substances are taken up by the take-up drum <b>170</b> to make an electrolytic metal foil <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Meanwhile, the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus of the present invention may adjust a central length L of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> in various ways. The electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is set so that the central length L is about 2 D when each of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> have a diameter D. However, the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus of the present invention may also be designed so that the central length L of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> has a minimum value, namely D that is a diameter of the drum.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a partial perspective view showing the cathode belt <b>140</b> of the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus according to the present invention, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a partial sectional view taken along the line V-V&#x2032; of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, the same reference numeral as in the former drawings denotes the same component having the same function, and they are not described in detail, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 4 and 5</figref>, a fixing member <b>141</b> is successively installed to right and left side ends of the cathode belt <b>140</b>. The fixing member <b>141</b> is mounted to the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> so that the cathode belt <b>140</b> moving along an endless track may be continuously rotated smoothly without being deviated from the outer circumferences of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>. For this purpose, the fixing member <b>141</b> is successively coupled to the entire side end of the cathode belt <b>140</b>, and also slidably contacted with sides of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The fixing member <b>141</b> is preferably made of non-conductive material so that, when metal is electroplated on the cathode belt <b>140</b>, the metal is not electroplated on the surface of the fixing member <b>141</b>. For example, the fixing member <b>141</b> is made of plastic. In addition, the fixing member <b>141</b> preferably has a section of &#x201c;&#x2282;&#x201d; shape as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> to wrap the side of the cathode belt <b>140</b> so that the cathode belt <b>140</b> may rotate stably. Though specific configuration and material of the fixing member <b>141</b> have been explained, the present invention is not limited thereto but various modifications will be possible to those skilled in the art within the scope of the present invention.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Meanwhile, the electroplated substances <b>2</b> electroplated on the cathode belt <b>140</b> may be contacted with one side <b>141</b><i>a </i>of the fixing member. In this case, when the electroplated substances <b>2</b> are separated from the cathode belt <b>140</b> to generate an electrolytic metal foil, both sides of the electrolytic metal foil may not be treated smoothly. For solving this problem, it is preferable that a concave groove is prepared at a border of the electroplated substances <b>2</b> and the fixing member <b>141</b>, and an O-ring <b>142</b> is inserted therein.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Preferably, the O-ring <b>142</b> is guided by rollers <b>180</b>, <b>180</b>&#x2032; installed in contact with the cathode belt <b>140</b> as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> so as to be successively inserted into the concave groove. In more detail, before the rotating cathode belt <b>140</b> is soaked in the electrolyte <b>111</b>, the O-ring <b>142</b> is inserted into the concave groove by means of the first rollers <b>180</b>, <b>180</b>&#x2032;, and if the electroplated substances <b>2</b> are moved on a surface of the electrolyte <b>111</b> by means of successive rotation of the cathode belt <b>140</b>, the O-ring <b>142</b> is departed from the concave groove by means of second rollers <b>181</b>, <b>181</b>&#x2032;. From this, the electroplated substances <b>2</b> are separated from the cathode belt <b>140</b>, and when the electrolytic metal foil <b>3</b> is generated, its side end may be treated smoothly. However, the O-ring may be interposed in other ways, not limited to the above.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">Hereinafter, a production rate of the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus according to the present invention is compared with that of a conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device by means of mathematical calculation.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The example 1 is directed to an electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus having upper and lower drums as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> and in which a central length L between the upper and lower drums is 2 D. In addition, the example 2 is directed to an electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus in which a central length L between the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> is D as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">The following table 1 shows electroplating rates of the examples 1 and 2 and the conventional one, which are mathematically calculated. All drums have a diameter of D, and a width is W for all drums. Here, t is an electroplating time. In this calculation, &#x3c0; is set to be about 3.14.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">Meanwhile, the conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device shows electrolytic actions on the surface of the cathode drum <b>20</b> soaked in the electrolyte <b>11</b>, but the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus of the present invention shows electrolytic actions on the surface of the cathode belt <b>140</b>. Thus, an electroplating area is varied depending on the surface height of the electrolyte. In the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus according to the above examples, a production rate of electrolytic metal foils is calculated on the assumption that the surface of the electrolyte <b>111</b> is positioned near to the lower circumference of the upper drum <b>120</b>. In addition, in the conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device, a production rate of electrolytic copper foils is calculated on the assumption that the surface of the electrolyte <b>11</b> is positioned at a substantially central position of the cathode drum <b>20</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="4" rowsep="1">TABLE 1</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>Diameter</entry>
<entry>Central Length</entry>
<entry/>
<entry>Electroplating</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>of Drum</entry>
<entry>of Drum</entry>
<entry>Electroplating Area</entry>
<entry>Rate</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="4" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="5">
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="70pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="35pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="3" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<colspec colname="4" colwidth="84pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="5" colwidth="49pt" align="center"/>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry>Example 1</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>2D</entry>
<entry>(3D + D&#x3c0;/2) &#xd7; W &#x2248; 4.57D</entry>
<entry>4.57DW/t</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Example 2</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>(D + D&#x3c0;/2) &#xd7; W &#x2248; 2.57D</entry>
<entry>2.57DW/t</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>Conventional Device</entry>
<entry>D</entry>
<entry>&#x2014;</entry>
<entry>(D&#x3c0;/2) &#xd7; W &#x2248; 1.57D</entry>
<entry>1.57DW/t</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry namest="1" nameend="5" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Seeing the table 1, an electroplating rate of the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus of the example 1 is 4.57 DW/t, which is about three times as fast as an electroplating rate of the conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device, which is 1.57 DW/t. In addition, the electrolytic metal foil of the example 2 has a central length L of the upper and lower drums <b>120</b>, <b>130</b> in a minimal level, but its electroplating rate is 2.57 DW/t, which is about 1.6 times as fast as that of the conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">Thus, the electrolytic metal foil manufacturing apparatus of the present invention may increase an electroplating rate by enlarging an electroplating area without increasing a diameter of drum, in comparison to a conventional electrolytic metal foil manufacturing device.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">The present invention has been described in detail. However, it should be understood that the detailed description and specific examples, while indicating preferred embodiments of the invention, are given by way of illustration only, since various changes and modifications within the spirit and scope of the invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art from this detailed description.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">APPLICABILITY TO THE INDUSTRY</heading>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">As described above, the apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to the present invention may increase a production rate of electrolytic metal foils by enlarging an electroplating area of electrolyte without increasing an area occupied by equipments under the same density of current.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil, comprising:
<claim-text>an electrolytic cell containing electrolyte;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an upper drum installed in an upper portion of the electrolytic cell to be rotatable and to which a negative (&#x2212;) electric potential is applied;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lower drum soaked in the electrolyte of the electrolytic cell and installed to be rotatable together with the upper drum;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cathode belt mounted around outer circumferences of the upper and lower drums to move along an endless track and electrically connected to the upper drum so that the negative (&#x2212;) electric potential is applied thereto; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an anode unit installed to form a space from a metal electroplating surface of the cathode belt soaked in the electrolytic cell so that a positive (+) electric potential is applied thereto, the anode unit having a slit for supplying the electrolytic to the space;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a fixing member successively coupled to an entire side end of the cathode belt and slidably contacted with sides of the upper and lower drums;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an O-ring interposed in a concave groove formed at a border between the fixing member and an electroplated metal electroplated on the cathode belt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first roller for guiding the O-ring to be successively inserted into the concave groove before the cathode belt is soaked in the electrolyte; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second roller for guiding the O-ring to be successively departed from the concave groove when the cathode belt moves up above a surface of the electrolyte.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the upper drum is made of conductive titanium.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the lower drum is made of non-conductive ebonite.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the cathode belt has a thickness of 1 to 3 mm.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fixing member is made of non-conductive material.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the fixing member has a section of a &#x2018;&#x2282;&#x2019; shape to surround a side of the cathode belt.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The apparatus for manufacturing an electrolytic metal foil according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>a separating roll installed out of the electrolytic cell to separate the metal electroplated on the cathode belt from the cathode belt; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a take-up drum for taking up the separated electrolytic metal foil.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
