<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641938-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641938</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11986365</doc-number>
<date>20071121</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>CN</country>
<doc-number>2006 1 0060309</doc-number>
<date>20060414</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>23</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>16</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4272491</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e61">Method for manufacturing carbon nanotube composite material</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7160620</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20070100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7253442</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20070800</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by other</category>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7291396</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20071100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>428408</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00004">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7393428</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Huang et al.</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>156249</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00005">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>7396477</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<name>Hsiao</name>
<date>20080700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>216  2</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>20</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4272491</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427307</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>427309</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>9</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>9</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<division>
<relation>
<parent-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11309822</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20061003</date>
</document-id>
<parent-status>ABANDONED</parent-status>
</parent-doc>
<child-doc>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11986365</doc-number>
</document-id>
</child-doc>
</relation>
</division>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20080087646</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20080417</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Liu</last-name>
<first-name>Chang-Hong</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Yao</last-name>
<first-name>Yuan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Fan</last-name>
<first-name>Shou-Shan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CN</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
<agents>
<agent sequence="01" rep-type="attorney">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Bonderer</last-name>
<first-name>D. Austin</first-name>
<address>
<country>unknown</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</agent>
</agents>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Tsinghua University</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Beijing</city>
<country>CN</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Hon Hai Precision Industry Co., Ltd.</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Tu-Cheng, Taipei Hsien</city>
<country>TW</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Culbert</last-name>
<first-name>Roberts</first-name>
<department>1792</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube composite material includes the steps of: providing a substrate, the substrate having a surface; forming a catalyst film in a special predetermined pattern on the surface of the substrate; forming a carbon nanotube array on the catalyst film to obtain the carbon nanotube array having a special predetermined pattern; providing a pair of protective layers, the protective layers being attached on a corresponding portion of ends of CNT array; filling clearances existing among CNTs of the CNT array and between the two protective layers with a matrix material; and removing the protective layers from CNT array.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="88.73mm" wi="116.25mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="123.11mm" wi="116.50mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="95.00mm" wi="92.37mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="167.81mm" wi="161.71mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="169.84mm" wi="146.90mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="116.16mm" wi="96.94mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="116.84mm" wi="111.08mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="115.23mm" wi="108.97mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00008" num="00008">
<img id="EMI-D00008" he="103.89mm" wi="106.76mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00008.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00009" num="00009">
<img id="EMI-D00009" he="162.98mm" wi="148.84mm" file="US07641938-20100105-D00009.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application is a divisional application of U.S. Patent Application, entitled &#x201c;CARBON NANOTUBE COMPOSITE MATERIAL AND METHOD FOR MANUFACTURING THE SAME&#x201d; with application Ser. No. 11/309,822, filed on Oct. 3, 2006 and having the same assignee as the instant application. The content of the above-referenced application is hereby incorporated by reference.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">1. Field of the Invention</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">The present invention relates to methods for manufacturing composite materials and, particularly, to a method for manufacturing a carbon nanotube composite material.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">2. Discussion of Related Art</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">Carbon nanotubes (CNTs) are tube-shaped structures composed of graphite. CNTs have a high Young's modulus, a high thermal conductivity, and a high electrical conductivity, and other properties. Due to these and the other properties, it has been suggested that CNTs can play an important role in fields such as microelectronics, material science, biology, and chemistry.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">A kind of thermally conductive material that conducts heat by using CNTs has been developed. The thermally conductive material is formed by injection molding and has numerous CNTs dispersed in a matrix material. The thermally conductive material includes a first surface engaging with an electronic device, and a second surface engaging with a heat sink. The second surface has a larger area than the first one, so that heat can be uniformly spread out to the larger second surface. However, the thermally conductive material formed by injection molding is relatively thick, which increases a bulk of the thermally conductive material and reduces its flexibility. Furthermore, CNTs are dispersed in the matrix material randomly and are multidirectional in orientation, which results that heat tends to spread uniformly through the thermally conductive material, retaining much of the heat within the heat transfer material. Therefore, the heat does not spread efficiently from the first surface engaged with the electronic device to the second surface engaged with the heat sink.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">Therefore, a method for manufacturing a thin carbon nanotube composite material, with controlled nanotube orientation within one or more desired patterns and, thus, with good thermal/electrical conductivity, is desired.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">A method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube composite material includes the steps of: providing a substrate, the surbstrate having a surface; forming a catalyst film in a desired pattern on the surface of the substrate; forming a carton nanotube array on the catalyst film to obtain the carbon nanotube array having desired pattern, each carbon nanotube (CNT) in the carbon nanotube array having top and bottom end portions; forming a protective layer on the top end portion of the CNT array; filling clearances among the CNTs of the CNT array; and removing the protective layer and the substrate from the carbon nanotube array so as to exposing the top end portion and the bottom end portion of the bottom nanotube array.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">Other advantages and novel features will become more apparent from the following detailed description when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">Many aspects of the carbon nanotube composite material can be better understood with reference to the following drawings. The components in the drawings are not necessarily to scale, the emphasis instead being placed upon clearly illustrating the principles of the present carbon nanotube composite material. Moreover, in the drawings, like reference numerals designate corresponding parts throughout the several views.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic, isometric view of a carbon nanotube composite material according to a preferred embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic, side view of the carbon nanotube composite material of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a top view of the carbon nanotube composite material, in which several carbon nanotube array patterns are provided, according to a preferred embodiment;</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a flow chart of a method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube composite material of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref>;</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref> are schematic views illustrating the manufacturing steps 1-5 in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>; and</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref> is a diagram showing an electrical property of the carbon nanotube composite material according to a preferred embodiment.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The exemplifications set out herein illustrate a method for manufacturing carbon nanotube composite materials, and such exemplifications are not to be construed as limiting the scope of the invention in any manner.</p>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, a carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b>, according to an exemplary embodiment, includes a matrix material <b>12</b> and a carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> having a number of CNTs. The matrix material <b>12</b> has a first surface <b>102</b> and a second surface <b>104</b> opposite to the first surface <b>102</b>. The carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> is embedded in the matrix material <b>12</b>, and the CNTs of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> are uniformly dispersed in a desired pattern. Each CNT of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> has a first end portion <b>112</b> and a second end portion <b>114</b> opposite to the first end portion <b>112</b>. The two opposite end portions <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> advantageously extend out of at least the two opposite surfaces <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>, respectively, and, in order to facilitate a connection with other components, are, further advantageously, exposed. If not exposed, however, the first and second portions <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> can be beneficially protected by the surrounding matrix material <b>12</b> but do have the drawback of not being able to be as intimately connected to adjoining components as may be possible if exposed. The matrix material <b>12</b> is, advantageously, selected from the group consisting of silica gel, polyethylene glycol, polyester, epoxy resin, and acrylic.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The two opposite surfaces <b>102</b> and <b>104</b> are substantially parallel to each other. The carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> is beneficially in a form of an aligned carbon nanotube array. Each CNT of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> is substantially parallel to one another and further substantially perpendicular to the two opposite surfaces <b>102</b> and <b>104</b>. Thus, each CNT of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> can provide a direct, shortest-distance thermal conduction path and/or electrical transmission path from one surface to another of the matrix material <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref>, a patterned carbon nanotube composite material <b>20</b> includes a matrix material <b>22</b> having two opposite surfaces and a number of patterned carbon nanotube arrays <b>24</b> embedded therein. Each CNT of the carbon nanotube arrays <b>24</b> includes two opposite end portion that respectively extend from two opposite surfaces of the matrix material <b>22</b>. The carbon nanotube arrays <b>24</b> can be patterned in a desired position, e.g., of an Integrated Circuit (IC) chip and/or can be formed into a geometrical figure, such as a circle, rectangle, ellipse, square, or any combination thereof. The carbon nanotube array <b>24</b> is sandwiched between the IC chip and a printed circuit board (PCB) for improving electrical connection therebetween and/or thermal conduction from the IC chip to ambient and/or a heat sink.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">As shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref>, a method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> is provided. The method employs an in-situ injection molding process, which comprises the steps of:</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">Step 1, providing a substrate, the substrate having a surface;</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">Step 2, forming a catalyst film in a desired pattern on the surface of the substrate;</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">Step 3, forming a carbon nanotube array on the catalyst film to obtain the carbon nanotube array having a desired pattern;</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">Step 4, forming a first protective layer on the first end portions of the CNTs;</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Step 5, removing the substrate and forming a second protective layer on the second end portion of the CNTs;</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">Step 6, filling clearances among the CNTs between the first protective layer and the second protective layer with a matrix material; and</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">Step 7, removing the first and second protective layers from the CNT array so as to exposing the top end portion and the bottom end portion of the carbon nanotube array.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 5 through 8</figref>, the method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b>, in accordance with the preferred embodiment, is described below, in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">In step 1, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref>, a substrate <b>16</b> is provided and a patterned carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> is formed thereon. A number of clearances <b>116</b> are defined among the adjacent CNTs. The carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> can be formed, for example, by a chemical vapor deposition method.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031">The chemical vapor deposition method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> generally includes steps of: firstly, forming a catalyst film (not labeled) on the substrate <b>16</b> and then growing carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> thereon by providing a carbon source gas at high temperature. The substrate <b>16</b> is beneficially made from a material selected from the group consisting of glass, silicon, metal, and metal oxide. The catalyst film can, usefully, be made from material selected from the group consisting of iron (Fe), cobalt (Co), nickel (Ni), and an alloy thereof. The carbon source gas can be, e.g., methane, ethylene, propylene, acetylene, methanol, ethanol, or some mixtures thereof. In the preferred embodiment, a silicon wafer is used as the substrate <b>16</b>, iron as the catalyst film, and ethylene as the carbon source gas. An iron film pattern having a thickness of about 5 nanometers (nm) is formed on the substrate <b>16</b> and is annealed in air at 300&#xb0; C. Then, the substrate <b>16</b> with the iron film deposited thereon is placed into a chemical vapor deposition chamber (not labeled), an ethylene gas is provided therein at 700&#xb0; C., and then the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> is produced. The carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> grown is about 0.3 millimeters (mm) high and substantially perpendicularly to the substrate <b>16</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032">In step 4, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 6</figref>, a first protective layer <b>18</b> is formed on the first end portions <b>112</b> of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b>. The first protective layer <b>18</b> includes a polyester film <b>124</b> and a pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b> disposed thereon. In the preferred embodiment, the pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b> has a thickness about 0.05 mm and is coated on a side of the polyester film <b>124</b>. More specifically, the first protective layer <b>18</b> can be attached to the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> as follows: placing the first protective layer <b>18</b> on the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> with the pressure sensitive adhesive <b>122</b> facing towards the first end portions <b>112</b>; pressing the first end portions <b>112</b> of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> into the pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b>, thereby directly attaching the first protecting layer <b>18</b> to the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b>. The pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b> is a soft and adhesive material, which allows the first end portions <b>112</b> to be inserted thereinto when an external force is applied thereon. The pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b> used in this exemplary embodiment is YM881 (produced by Light Industry Institute, Fushun, China). The pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b> can, alternatively, be made of other adhesive materials with high viscosity, such as glue. Moreover, the polyester film <b>124</b> may be made of other polymers, such as polyethylene.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033">In another embodiment, the first protective layer <b>18</b> may only include the polyester film <b>124</b>. The polyester film <b>124</b> can be directly attached to the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> as follows: placing the polyester film <b>124</b> on the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b>; and pressing the first end portions <b>112</b> of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> into the polyester film <b>124</b>, thereby attaching the polyester film <b>124</b> to the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034">In step 5, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 7</figref>, the substrate <b>16</b> is removed from the second end portions <b>114</b>, and the second protective layer <b>18</b>&#x2032; is attached to the second end portions <b>114</b>.The second protective layer <b>18</b>&#x2032; includes a pressure sensitive adhesive layer <b>122</b>&#x2032; and a polyester film <b>124</b>&#x2032;. The step of attaching the second protective layer <b>18</b>&#x2032; to the second end portions <b>114</b> is similar to that of the first protective layer <b>18</b> in the step 3. Thereby, the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> along with the two protective layers <b>18</b> and <b>18</b>&#x2032; attached on the two opposite end portions <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> thereof constitute an injection mold.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035">It is noted that step 5 is an optional step. The carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> can be formed by an injection mold along with the first protective layer <b>18</b> attached to the first end portions <b>112</b> and the substrate <b>16</b> attached to the second end portions <b>114</b>. As a further alternative, the substrate <b>16</b> could be permitted to remain instead of being replaced with the second protective layer <b>18</b>&#x2032; and to thereby act as part of the injection mold.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">In step 6, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 8</figref>, the clearances <b>116</b> among the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> are filled with the matrix material <b>12</b>. This step can be performed in the following manner: immersing the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> with two attached protective layers <b>18</b> and <b>18</b>&#x2032; into a melt or solution of the matrix material <b>12</b>; taking the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b>, now having the matrix material <b>12</b> filled among the clearances <b>116</b>, out of the melted or solution of the matrix material <b>12</b>; and curing the matrix material <b>12</b> among the clearances <b>116</b> in vacuum at room temperature for 24 hours, thereby causing the matrix material <b>12</b> to become soft and elastic. The matrix material <b>12</b> is advantageously selected from the group consisting of silica gel, polyethylene glycol, polyester, epoxy resin, and acrylic. In the preferred embodiment, the matrix material <b>12</b> is made from the Sylgard 160, a type of a 2-part silicone elastomer, which is available from Dow Corning. The Sylgard 160 is supplied, as two separate liquid components comprised of part A and part B to be mixed in a 1:1 ratio by weight or volume. A mass percent of the CNTs in the carbon nanotube composite material is about 5 wt %.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">In step 7, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref>, both protective layers <b>18</b> and <b>18</b>&#x2032; are removed from the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b>. The protective layers <b>18</b> and <b>18</b>&#x2032; can be removed, for example, by directly stripping off or sequentially be dissolved away any of the remaining pressure sensitive adhesive layers <b>122</b> and <b>122</b>&#x2032;, by an organic solution. In the preferred embodiment, the organic solvent is xylene. Thus, the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> is finished, which has first and second end portions <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> exposing the first and second surfaces <b>102</b> and <b>104</b> of the matrix material <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">Preferably, the method for manufacturing the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> can further include a reactive ion etching (RIE) step or another selective material removal step to ensure the both end portions <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> (i.e., both end portions of the respective CNTs) of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> be sufficiently exposed. In the preferred embodiment, the RIE process is carried out using O2 plasma at a pressure of 6 pascals (Pa) and with a power of 150 watts (W) for 15 minutes (min) at each of the surfaces <b>102</b> and <b>104</b> of the matrix material <b>12</b>. Finally, a carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> having the both end portions <b>112</b> and <b>114</b> fully protruding out thereof is obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">The resulted carbon nanotube composite <b>10</b> can be further trimmed into any desired geometrical figure for used as, e.g., electrical and/or thermal conductive component. In addition, since the CNTs of the carbon nanotube composite <b>10</b> are bounded tightly within the matrix material <b>12</b>, a stability and reliability of the carbon nanotube composite <b>10</b> is improved.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 9</figref>, electrical conductivities of the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> are measured. The solid line represents axial conductivity along a direction parallel to longitudinal axes of the CNTs, and the dashed line represents lateral conductivity along a direction perpendicular to the longitudinal axes of the carbon nanotubes. As be expected to given the alignment of the CNTs, the axial conductivity, over the entire voltage range, is markedly higher than the lateral conductivity. As a result, when the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> is aligned, the maximum performance of thermal and/or electrical conduction and relative thereto along the axial direction can be expected.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">The first and second end portions <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> of the CNTs of the carbon nanotube array <b>14</b> are protruded out of first and second surfaces <b>102</b>, <b>104</b>. Thus, the first and second end portions <b>112</b>, <b>114</b> of CNTs form two thermal contact surfaces or electrical connection surfaces directly in the axial direction, and the overall electrical conductivity/thermal conductivity of the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> is improved. The carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> can be formed in a desired pattern, according to the application requirement, and can, e.g., be in a film form that makes them portable and integral. Moreover, the thickness and other dimensions of the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> can be chosen by the designer based on the use requirements and, thus, are not limited to thin film applications. For these reasons, the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> can, e.g., be applied in a large-scaled IC and furthermore in any large-scaled electronic component. Additional uses for the carbon nanotube composite material <b>10</b> beyond the electronics area (e.g., thermal transfer devices) are readily conceivable and are considered to be within the scope of the present composite material.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042">Finally, it is to be understood that the embodiments mentioned above are intended to illustrate rather than limit the invention. Variations may be made to the embodiments without departing from the spirit of the invention as claimed. The above-described embodiments illustrate the scope of the invention but do not restrict the scope of the invention.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. A method for manufacturing a carbon nanotube composite material, comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>providing a substrate, the substrate having a surface;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a catalyst film on the surface of the substrate, the catalyst film including a first portion having a first shape and a second portion having a second shape different from the first shape, the first portion being spaced from the second portion;</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a first carbon nanotube array on the first portion of the catalyst film to obtain the first carbon nanotube array having the first shape and a second carbon nanotube array on the second portion of the catalyst film to obtain the second carbon nanotube array having the second shape, the first and second carbon nanotube arrays defining a top end portion and a bottom end portion, the bottom end portion being attached to the substrate, the first and second carbon nanotube arrays having a plurality of clearances among neighboring carbon nanotubes of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays;</claim-text>
<claim-text>attaching a protective layer on the top end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays;</claim-text>
<claim-text>filling clearances among the carbon nanotubes with a matrix material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the first protective layer and the substrate from the first and second carbon nanotube arrays so as to expose the top end portion and the bottom end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further comprising the step of etching the matrix material adjacent the top end portion and the bottom end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays for further exposing the two end portions thereof.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first protective layer comprises a polyester film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00003">claim 3</claim-ref>, wherein the first protective layer further comprises a pressure sensitive adhesive layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the step of attaching the first protective layer comprises the steps of placing the first protective layer on the top end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays; and pressing the first protective layer into the top end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the clearances are further defined between the substrate and the first protective layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text>7. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the matrix material is selected from the group consisting of silica gel, polyethylene glycol, polyester, epoxy resin, and an acrylic.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text>8. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein before filling with the matrix material, further comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>removing the substrate from the bottom end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming a second protective layer on the bottom end portion of the first and second carbon nanotube arrays.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text>9. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second protective layer comprises a polyester film.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text>10. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the second protective layer further comprises a pressure sensitive adhesive layer.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text>11. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the filling of clearances is achieved by an injection molding process.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text>12. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, further includes etching the first and second surface of the matrix material via reactive ion etching.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text>13. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00012">claim 12</claim-ref>, wherein the reactive ion etching is carried out using O<sub>2 </sub>plasma.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text>14. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the reactive ion etching is carried out at pressure of about 6 pascals.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text>15. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the reactive ion etching is carried our wits power of about 150 watts.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text>16. The method as claimed in <b>1</b>, wherein a method for filling clearances among the carbon nanotubes with a matrix material includes:
<claim-text>immersing the first and carbon nanotube arrays with attached protective layer into a melt or solution of the matrix material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>taking out the first and second carbon nanotube arrays;</claim-text>
<claim-text>curing the matrix material amount the clearance in vacuum to cause the matrix material to become soft and elastic.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text>17. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00016">claim 16</claim-ref>, wherein a mass percent of the carbon nanotubes in the carbon nanotube composite material is about 5%.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text>18. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first shape is rectangle and the second shape is a curve.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text>19. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00018">claim 18</claim-ref>, wherein the second shape is a circle.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text>20. The method as claimed in <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the first and second carbon nanotube arrays are connected together by the matrix material. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
