<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE us-patent-grant SYSTEM "us-patent-grant-v42-2006-08-23.dtd" [ ]>
<us-patent-grant lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.2 2006-08-23" file="US07641849-20100105.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-grant" country="US" date-produced="20091221" date-publ="20100105">
<us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>07641849</doc-number>
<kind>B2</kind>
<date>20100105</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>11785597</doc-number>
<date>20070419</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>11</us-application-series-code>
<us-term-of-grant>
<us-term-extension>286</us-term-extension>
</us-term-of-grant>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>C</section>
<class>21</class>
<subclass>C</subclass>
<main-group>7</main-group>
<subgroup>00</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20100105</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>266216</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e53">Injector for injecting particulate material into metallurgical furnaces</invention-title>
<references-cited>
<citation>
<patcit num="00001">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>4002372</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Edwards et al.</name>
<date>19770100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>406 94</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00002">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>5649325</doc-number>
<kind>A</kind>
<name>Garrison et al.</name>
<date>19970700</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>588320</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
<citation>
<patcit num="00003">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>6322610</doc-number>
<kind>B1</kind>
<name>Pavlicevic et al.</name>
<date>20011100</date>
</document-id>
</patcit>
<category>cited by examiner</category>
<classification-national><country>US</country><main-classification>266222</main-classification></classification-national>
</citation>
</references-cited>
<number-of-claims>6</number-of-claims>
<us-exemplary-claim>1</us-exemplary-claim>
<us-field-of-classification-search>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>266216</main-classification>
</classification-national>
</us-field-of-classification-search>
<figures>
<number-of-drawing-sheets>1</number-of-drawing-sheets>
<number-of-figures>1</number-of-figures>
</figures>
<us-related-documents>
<us-provisional-application>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>60795650</doc-number>
<kind>00</kind>
<date>20060428</date>
</document-id>
</us-provisional-application>
<related-publication>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20090091068</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20090409</date>
</document-id>
</related-publication>
</us-related-documents>
<parties>
<applicants>
<applicant sequence="001" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Strelbisky</last-name>
<first-name>Michael J.</first-name>
<address>
<city>Burlington</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="002" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Balkos</last-name>
<first-name>Athanasios Tommy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Mississauga</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>CA</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
<applicant sequence="003" app-type="applicant-inventor" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Zeien</last-name>
<first-name>Timothy</first-name>
<address>
<city>Little Mountain</city>
<state>SC</state>
<country>US</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<nationality>
<country>omitted</country>
</nationality>
<residence>
<country>US</country>
</residence>
</applicant>
</applicants>
</parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>A.H. Tallman Bronze Company, Limited</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Burlington, ON</city>
<country>CA</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
<examiners>
<primary-examiner>
<last-name>Kastler</last-name>
<first-name>Scott</first-name>
<department>1793</department>
</primary-examiner>
</examiners>
</us-bibliographic-data-grant>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">An injector for injecting particulate material into a metallurgical furnace has a first tubular barrel and a housing defining a chamber having an inlet for particulate material, a first gas inlet and a particulate material/gas outlet connected to the rear end of the first barrel. The first air inlet has a first nozzle operable to inject gas into the chamber at a supersonic velocity when gas at suitable pressure is passed through the nozzle. A second tubular barrel surrounds the first barrel in spaced relationship therewith. The second barrel has a second gas inlet adjacent its rear end and a second nozzle adjacent its front end. Gas under pressure supplied to the second gas inlet passes between the barrels and is discharged at supersonic velocity from the front end thereof adjacent gas and entrained particulate material discharged from the first barrel so as to shroud the particulate material.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="72.73mm" wi="160.70mm" file="US07641849-20100105-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="74.93mm" wi="163.66mm" file="US07641849-20100105-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">RELATED APPLICATION</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">This application claims priority from U.S. Provisional Patent Application 60/695,650 filed Apr. 28, 2006.</p>
<?RELAPP description="Other Patent Relations" end="tail"?>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The present invention relates to injectors for injecting particulate material into metallurgical furnaces. The particulate material may be for example carbon powder and the metallurgical furnaces may for example be smelters, electric arc furnaces or steel ladles.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In present day metallurgical furnaces, particulate material such as carbon powder is injected into a melt at subsonic speeds through a so-called straight pipe. Unfortunately, with such an injector, a substantial amount of the particulate material becomes entrained in an off-gas suction system and is thus lost.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">It is therefore an object of this invention to provide an improved carbon powder injector which reduces the amount of lost particulate material.</p>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">The present invention provides an injector for injecting particulate material into a metallurgical furnace, the injector having:
<ul id="ul0001" list-style="none">
    <li id="ul0001-0001" num="0000">
    <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
        <li id="ul0002-0001" num="0006">a first elongated tubular barrel having a front end and a rear end,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0002" num="0007">a housing defining a chamber having an inlet for particulate material, a first gas inlet and a particulate material/gas outlet connected to the rear end of the first barrel,</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0003" num="0008">the first air inlet having a first nozzle operable to inject gas into the chamber at a supersonic velocity when gas at suitable pressure is passed through the nozzle, said first gas inlet being positioned so as to direct gas at supersonic velocity through the chamber to the outlet thereof so as to entrain particulate material while traveling through the chamber and then through the first barrel to cause the entrained particulate material to be discharged from the front end of the barrel, and</li>
        <li id="ul0002-0004" num="0009">a second elongated tubular barrel surrounding the first barrel in spaced relationship therewith and having a front end and a rear end, the front end of the second barrel being adjacent the front end of the first barrel, the second barrel having a second gas inlet adjacent its rear end and a second nozzle adjacent its front end whereby gas under pressure supplied to the second gas inlet passes between the first and second barrels and is discharged at supersonic velocity from the front end thereof adjacent the gas and entrained particulate material discharged from the front end of the first barrel so as to shroud the particulate material.</li>
    </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0010">The outlet from the chamber may be a conical portion tapering in the direction of flow of the particulate material/gas flow to facilitate passage of the particulate material/gas flow from the chamber to the first barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0011">The first nozzle may be adjustable in a forward/rearward direction relative to gas flow therethrough to optimize the flow of gas into the chamber. The second nozzle may be adjustable in a forward/rearward direction relative to the second barrel to optimize gas flow from the front end of the second barrel. The gas flow between the first and second barrels may also function to cool the first barrel.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0012">The first barrel may have a lining of abrasion resistant material. The lining may be a ceramic lining. The second barrel may be made of thermally conductive material, such as copper.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0013">The chamber inlet for particulate material may be positioned such that the particulate material passes into the chamber in a direction substantially perpendicular to the direction of travel of supersonic gas passing from the first inlet to the second outlet.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0014">The first nozzle may be adjustable in a forward/rearward direction relative to gas flow therethrough to optimize the flow of gas into the chamber. The second nozzle may be adjustable in a forward/rearward direction relative to the second barrel to optimize gas flow from the front end of the second barrel.</p>
<?BRFSUM description="Brief Summary" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0012" num="0015">One embodiment of the invention will now be described, by way of example, with reference to the accompanying drawing, in which:</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagrammatic side view of a carbon powder injector in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0006" level="1">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading>
<p id="p-0014" num="0017">Referring to the drawings, a carbon powder injector for an electric arc furnace has a first elongated tubular barrel <b>12</b> with a front end <b>14</b> and a rear end <b>16</b>. The first barrel <b>12</b> has a lining of abrasive resistant material, such as a ceramic lining. The injector also has a housing <b>18</b> defining a carbon powder chamber <b>20</b> having an inlet <b>22</b> for carbon powder, a first gas inlet <b>24</b> and a carbon powder/gas outlet <b>26</b> which is connected to the rear end of the first barrel <b>12</b>. The carbon powder inlet <b>22</b> is positioned so as to direct the carbon powder into the chamber <b>20</b> at any suitable angle, for example in a direction perpendicular to the direction of flow of gas from the first inlet <b>24</b> to the outlet <b>26</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0018">The gas inlet <b>24</b> has a first nozzle <b>28</b> in the form of a Laval nozzle operable to inject gas into the carbon powder chamber <b>20</b> at a supersonic velocity, for example about Mach 2, when gas at a suitable supply pressure is passed through the nozzle <b>28</b>. The gas inlet <b>24</b> is positioned so as to direct gas at supersonic velocity through the carbon powder chamber <b>20</b> to the outlet <b>26</b> so as to entrain carbon powder therein and cause the entrained carbon powder to be passed along the first barrel <b>12</b> and be discharged from the front end <b>14</b> thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0019">The nozzle <b>28</b> may be adjustable in a forward/rearward direction relative to the direction of air therethrough to optimize the flow of gas into the carbon powder chamber <b>20</b>. The outlet <b>26</b> from the carbon powder chamber <b>20</b> has a conical portion <b>30</b> tapering in the direction of the carbon powder/gas flow to facilitate passage of the carbon powder/gas from the carbon powder chamber <b>20</b> to the first barrel <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0020">A second elongated tubular barrel <b>32</b> made of a thermally conductive material such as copper surrounds the first barrel <b>12</b> in spaced relationship therewith to form an annular passage <b>34</b> between the second barrel <b>32</b> and the first barrel <b>12</b>. The second barrel <b>32</b> extends along most of the length of the first barrel <b>12</b>, the front end <b>36</b> of the second barrel <b>32</b> being adjacent the front end <b>14</b> of the first barrel <b>12</b> and the rear end <b>38</b> of the second barrel <b>32</b> being near the rear end <b>16</b> of the first barrel <b>12</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0021">The second barrel <b>32</b> has a second gas inlet <b>40</b> adjacent its rear end <b>38</b> and a second nozzle <b>42</b> adjacent its front end <b>36</b>. The second nozzle <b>42</b> is a CDC (Converging/Diverging/Converging) annular Laval nozzle. The rear end of the annular passage <b>34</b> may be welded in place or sealed by O-rings <b>44</b> carried by the second barrel <b>32</b> and engaging the first barrel <b>12</b>. gas under pressure supplied to the second air inlet <b>40</b> passes along the annular passage <b>34</b> and through the nozzle <b>42</b> and is discharged at supersonic velocity as an annular jet from the front end <b>36</b> of the second barrel <b>32</b> surrounding the carbon powder/gas jet discharged from the front end <b>14</b> of the first barrel <b>12</b>. The second nozzle <b>42</b> may be adjustable in a forward/rearward direction relative to the length of the first and second barrels <b>12</b>, <b>32</b> to optimize the gas flow from the front end of the outer barrel <b>32</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0022">The carbon powder is mostly shrouded by the gas to prevent the carbon powder from spreading and losing momentum. The gas supplied to inlet <b>40</b> functions primarily to shroud the carbon powder although some carbon powder does become entrained therein.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0023">The gas flow along the annular passage <b>34</b> also serves to cool the first barrel so that liquid cooling thereof is not required.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0024">Gas flow to the inlet nozzle <b>28</b> may for example be at a pressure in the range of from about 50 to about 200 psi with a flow rate in the range of from about 30 to about 20,000 scfm. Gas flow to the second inlet <b>40</b> may for example be at a pressure in the range of from about 50 to about 200 psi with a flow rate in the range of from about 50 to about 20,000 scfm.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0025">The gas supplied to the inlet nozzle <b>28</b> may be an inert gas such as nitrogen or argon or may be air. The preference is for air or nitrogen. The gas supplied to the second inlet <b>40</b> may be an inert gas or a non-inert gas, for example nitrogen, argon, air, oxygen, or natural gas. The preference is for air oxygen or nitrogen.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0026">In stead of being ceramic, the lining of the first barrel <b>12</b> may be of any suitable abrasion resistant material, such as a suitable alloyed steel. Also, instead of being copper, the second barrel <b>32</b> may be of any suitable thermally conductive material, for example alloys such as aluminum bronze or other suitable aluminum alloy.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0027">The advantages of the invention and other embodiments thereof will now be readily apparent to a person skilled in the art from the foregoing description, the scope of the invention being defined in the appended claims.</p>
<?DETDESC description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>The invention claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text>1. An injector for injecting particulate material into a metallurgical furnace, the injector comprising:
<claim-text>a first elongated tubular barrel extending between a front end and a rear end thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing defining a chamber comprising:
<claim-text>a particulate material inlet through which the particulate material enters the chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first gas inlet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outlet in fluid communication with the rear end of the first barrel;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first nozzle operable to inject gas through the first gas inlet into the chamber at a supersonic velocity when gas at suitable pressure is passed through the nozzle, said first gas inlet being positioned so as to direct said gas at supersonic velocity through the chamber to the outlet thereof, said gas entraining the particulate material as the gas moves through the chamber and through the first barrel and discharging the entrained particulate material from the front end of the barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second elongated tubular barrel surrounding the first barrel in spaced relationship therewith extending between a front end and a rear end thereof the front end of the second barrel being disposed proximal to the front end of the first barrel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second barrel comprising a second gas inlet adjacent its rear end and a second nozzle adjacent its front end whereby gas under pressure supplied to the second gas inlet passes between the first and second barrels and is discharged at supersonic velocity via the second nozzle from the front end thereof adjacent the gas and entrained particulate material discharged from the front end of the first barrel to shroud the particulate material as it is discharged from the front end of the first barrel, the second barrel being made of copper.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text>2. An injector for injecting particulate material into a metallurgical furnace, the injector comprising:
<claim-text>a first tubular barrel extending between front and rear ends thereof;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a housing defining a chamber therein;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first nozzle for injecting a first gas into the chamber;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the chamber comprising:
<claim-text>a first gas inlet through which the first gas exiting the first nozzle enters the chamber at a first predetermined flow rate and a first predetermined velocity;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a particulate material inlet through which the particulate material enters into the chamber, for entrainment of the particulate material with the first gas;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an outlet in communication with the rear end of the first barrel through which the first gas and the entrained particulate matter passes into the first barrel, to exit therefrom at the front end;</claim-text>
</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second tubular barrel coaxial with the first barrel to define an annular passage therebetween, the second barrel extending between a rear end thereof positioned proximal to the rear end of the first barrel and a front end thereof positioned proximal to the front end of the first barrel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second nozzle positioned between the first and second barrels proximal to the front ends thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second barrel comprising a second gas inlet proximal to the rear end thereof through which a second gas is injected at a second predetermined flow rate, such second gas being directed by the annular passage to exit therefrom via the second nozzle at a second predetermined velocity to shroud the first gas and entrained particulate matter exiting the first barrel.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text>3. An injector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> in which:
<claim-text>the first gas and the entrained particulate material exit the front end of the first barrel at an exit velocity; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second predetermined velocity is at least approximately equal to the exit velocity.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text>4. An injector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> in which the first nozzle is positionable relative to the first gas inlet for adjusting the first flow rate of the first gas into the chamber.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text>5. An injector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> in which the second nozzle is positionable relative to the front end of the second barrel for adjusting the second flow rate of the second gas as it exits the annular passage.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text>6. An injector according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref> in which the chamber additionally comprises a conical portion to facilitate passage of the first gas and the entrained particulate material into the first barrel. </claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-grant>
